1
00:00:00,330 --> 00:00:03,705
So whereas in transfer learning, you have a sequential process
在迁移学习中 你的步骤是串行的

2
00:00:03,705 --> 00:00:07,162
where you learn from task A and then transfer that to task B.
你从任务A里学到只是 然后迁移到任务B

3
00:00:07,162 --> 00:00:10,520
In multi-task learning, you start off simultaneously,
在多任务学习中 你是同时开始学习的

4
00:00:10,520 --> 00:00:13,650
trying to have one neural network do several things at the same time.
试图让单个神经网络同时做几件事情

5
00:00:13,650 --> 00:00:17,520
And then each of these task helps hopefully all of the other task.
然后希望这里每个任务都能帮到其他所有任务

6
00:00:17,520 --> 00:00:18,480
Let's look at an example.
我们来看一个例子

7
00:00:20,110 --> 00:00:24,140
Let's say you're building an autonomous vehicle, building a self driving car.
假设你在研发无人驾驶车辆

8
00:00:24,140 --> 00:00:27,251
Then your self driving car would need to detect several different things
那么你的无人驾驶车可能需要同时检测不同的物体

9
00:00:27,317 --> 00:00:34,164
such as pedestrians, detect other cars, detect stop signs.
比如检测行人 车辆 停车标志

10
00:00:37,312 --> 00:00:42,410
And also detect traffic lights and also other things.
还有交通灯 各种其他东西

11
00:00:43,670 --> 00:00:47,330
So for example, in this example on the left, there is a stop sign in this image
比如在左边这个例子中 图像里有个停车标志

12
00:00:47,330 --> 00:00:53,510
and there is a car in this image but there aren't any pedestrians or traffic lights.
然后图像中有辆车 但没有行人也没有交通灯

13
00:00:53,510 --> 00:00:58,200
So if this image is an input for an example, x^(i),
如果这是输入图像x^(i)

14
00:00:58,200 --> 00:01:02,770
then Instead of having one label y^(i), you would actually a four labels.
那么这里不再是一个标签y^(i) 而是有4个标签

15
00:01:02,770 --> 00:01:05,640
In this example, there are no pedestrians, there is a car,
在这个例子中 没有行人 有一辆车

16
00:01:05,640 --> 00:01:08,850
there is a stop sign and there are no traffic lights.
有一个停车标志 没有交通灯

17
00:01:08,850 --> 00:01:10,580
And if you try and detect other things,
然后如果你尝试检测其他物体

18
00:01:10,580 --> 00:01:12,634
then may be y^(i) has even more dimensions.
也许y^(i)的维数会更高

19
00:01:12,634 --> 00:01:14,385
But for now let's stick with these four.
现在我们就先用4个吧

20
00:01:14,385 --> 00:01:18,013
So y^(i) is a 4 by 1 vector.
所以y^(i)是个4*1向量

21
00:01:18,013 --> 00:01:22,444
And if you look at the training set labels as a whole,
如果你从整体来看这个训练集标签

22
00:01:22,444 --> 00:01:27,679
then similar to before, we'll stack the training data's labels horizontally
和以前类似 我们将训练集的标签水平堆叠起来

23
00:01:28,045 --> 00:01:32,116
as follows, y^(1) up to y^(m).
像这样 y^(1)一直到y^(m)

24
00:01:32,116 --> 00:01:39,470
Except that now y^(i) is a 4 by 1 vector so each of these is a tall column vector.
不过现在y^(i)是4*1向量 所以这些都是竖向的列向量

25
00:01:39,470 --> 00:01:45,530
And so this matrix Y is now a 4 by m matrix, whereas previously,
所以这个矩阵Y现在变成4*m矩阵 而之前

26
00:01:45,530 --> 00:01:49,810
when y was single real number, this would have been a 1 by m matrix.
当y是单实数时 这就是1*m矩阵

27
00:01:49,810 --> 00:01:55,122
So what you can do is now train a neural network to predict these values of y.
那么你现在可以做的是训练一个神经网络 来预测这些y值

28
00:01:55,122 --> 00:01:56,887
So you can have a neural network input x
你就得到这样的神经网络 输入x

29
00:01:56,941 --> 00:02:00,970
and output now a four dimensional value for y.
现在输出是一个四维向量y

30
00:02:00,970 --> 00:02:04,590
Notice here for the output there I've drawn four nodes.
请注意 这里输出我画了四个节点

31
00:02:04,590 --> 00:02:05,503
And so the first node
所以第一个节点

32
00:02:05,563 --> 00:02:10,610
when we try to predict is there a pedestrian in this picture.
就是我们想预测图中有没有行人

33
00:02:10,610 --> 00:02:13,470
The second output will predict is there a car here,
然后第二个输出节点预测的是有没有车

34
00:02:13,470 --> 00:02:18,870
predict is there a stop sign and this will predict maybe is there a traffic light.
这里预测有没有停车标志 这里预测有没有交通灯

35
00:02:20,850 --> 00:02:23,950
So y hat here is four dimensional.
所以这里y帽是四维的

36
00:02:26,110 --> 00:02:27,268
So to train this neural network,
要训练这个神经网络

37
00:02:27,341 --> 00:02:32,029
you now need to define the loss for the neural network.
你现在需要定义神经网络的损失函数

38
00:02:32,029 --> 00:02:39,190
And so given a predicted output y hat i which is 4 by 1 dimensional.
对于一个输出y帽 是个4维向量

39
00:02:39,190 --> 00:02:43,939
The loss averaged over your entire training set
对于整个训练集的平均损失

40
00:02:43,939 --> 00:02:48,209
would be 1 over m sum from i = 1 through m,
就是1除以m 对i=1到m求和

41
00:02:48,209 --> 00:02:55,349
sum from j = 1 through 4 of the losses of the individual predictions.
从j=1到4求和 这些单个预测的损失

42
00:02:59,030 --> 00:03:01,515
So it's just summing over  at the four components of
所以这就是对四个分量的求和

43
00:03:01,651 --> 00:03:04,253
pedestrian car stop sign traffic lights.
行人 车 停车标志 交通灯

44
00:03:04,253 --> 00:03:11,462
And this script L is the usual logistic loss.
而这个标志L指的是logistic损失

45
00:03:14,493 --> 00:03:15,497
So just to write this out,
我们就这么写

46
00:03:15,555 --> 00:03:28,349
this is -y_j^(i) log y hat_j^(i) - (1- y_j^(i)) log (1- y_hat^j(i)).
这是 -y_j^(i) log y 帽 _j(i) - (1 - y_j^(i) log (1- y帽_j^(i))

47
00:03:31,706 --> 00:03:36,018
And the main difference compared to the earlier finding cat classification examples is
和之前分类猫的例子主要区别在于

48
00:03:36,018 --> 00:03:38,760
that you're now summing over j equals 1 through 4.
现在你要对j=1到4求和

49
00:03:40,570 --> 00:03:44,303
And the main difference between this and softmax regression, is that
这与softmax回归的主要区别在于

50
00:03:44,343 --> 00:03:50,550
unlike softmax regression, which assigned a single label to single example.
与softmax回归不同 softmax将单个标签分配给单个样本

51
00:03:50,550 --> 00:03:53,370
This one image can have multiple labels.
而这张图可以有很多不同的标签

52
00:03:55,350 --> 00:04:01,668
So you're not saying that each image is either a picture of a pedestrian,
所以不是说每张图都只是一张行人图片

53
00:04:01,668 --> 00:04:04,780
or a picture of car, a picture of a stop sign, picture of a traffic light.
汽车图片 停车标志图片 或者交通灯图片

54
00:04:04,780 --> 00:04:07,177
You're asking for each picture, does it have a pedestrian,
你要知道每张照片是否有行人

55
00:04:07,230 --> 00:04:09,648
or a car, a stop sign or traffic light,
或汽车 停车标志或交通灯

56
00:04:09,649 --> 00:04:11,860
and multiple objects could appear in the same image.
多个物体可能同时出现在一张图里

57
00:04:11,860 --> 00:04:14,159
In fact, in the example on the previous slide,
实际上 在上一张幻灯片中

58
00:04:14,228 --> 00:04:17,481
we had both a car and a stop sign in that image,
那张图同时有车和停车标志

59
00:04:17,533 --> 00:04:19,400
but no pedestrians and traffic lights.
但没有行人和交通灯

60
00:04:19,400 --> 00:04:22,580
So you're not assigning a single label to an image,
所以你不是只给图片一个标签

61
00:04:22,580 --> 00:04:25,630
you're going through the different classes and asking
而是需要遍历不同类型

62
00:04:25,631 --> 00:04:27,278
for each of the classes does that class,
然后看看每个类型

63
00:04:27,359 --> 00:04:29,573
does that type of object appear in the image?
那类物体有没有出现在图中

64
00:04:31,420 --> 00:04:33,589
So that's why I'm saying that with this setting,
所以我就说在这个场合

65
00:04:33,640 --> 00:04:37,313
one image can have multiple labels.
一张图可以有多个标签

66
00:04:37,313 --> 00:04:42,281
If you train a neural network to minimize this cost function,
如果你训练了一个神经网络 试图最小化这个成本函数

67
00:04:42,281 --> 00:04:45,920
you are carrying out multi-task learning.
你做的就是多任务学习

68
00:04:45,920 --> 00:04:50,121
Because what you're doing is building a single neural network
因为你现在做的是建立单个神经网络

69
00:04:50,206 --> 00:04:53,860
that is looking at each image and basically solving four problems.
观察每张图 然后解决四个问题

70
00:04:53,860 --> 00:04:58,910
It's trying to tell you does each image have each of these four objects in it.
系统试图告诉你 每张图里面有没有这四个物体

71
00:05:00,250 --> 00:05:03,850
And one other thing you could have done is just train four separate neural networks,
另外你也可以训练四个不同的神经网络

72
00:05:03,850 --> 00:05:06,700
instead of train one network to do four things.
而不是训练一个网络做四件事情

73
00:05:06,700 --> 00:05:09,766
But if some of the earlier features in neural network
但神经网络一些早期特征

74
00:05:09,767 --> 00:05:12,157
can be shared between these different types of objects,
在识别不同物体时都会用到

75
00:05:12,209 --> 00:05:13,790
then you find that
然后你发现

76
00:05:13,790 --> 00:05:17,880
training one neural network to do four things results in better performance than
训练一个神经网络做四件事情

77
00:05:17,880 --> 00:05:21,760
training four completely separate neural networks to do the four tasks separately.
会比训练四个完全独立的神经网络分别做四件事性能要更好

78
00:05:23,040 --> 00:05:25,450
So that's the power of multi-task learning.
这就是多任务学习的力量

79
00:05:26,716 --> 00:05:28,590
And one other detail,
另一个细节

80
00:05:28,590 --> 00:05:33,440
so far I've described this algorithm as if every image had every single label.
到目前为止 我是这么描述算法的 好像每张图都有全部标签

81
00:05:33,440 --> 00:05:34,924
It turns out that multi-task learning
事实证明 多任务学习

82
00:05:34,978 --> 00:05:39,452
also works even if some of the images were label only some of the objects.
也可以处理图像只有部分物体被标记的情况

83
00:05:39,452 --> 00:05:41,996
So the first training example, let's say someone,
所以第一个训练样本 我们说有人

84
00:05:42,061 --> 00:05:44,459
your labeler had told you there's a pedestrian,
给数据贴标签的人告诉你里面有一个行人

85
00:05:44,459 --> 00:05:46,527
there's no car, but they didn't bother to label
没有车 但他们没有标记

86
00:05:46,565 --> 00:05:47,755
whether or not there's a stop sign
是否有停车标志

87
00:05:47,810 --> 00:05:49,072
or whether or not there's a traffic light.
或者是否有交通灯

88
00:05:49,072 --> 00:05:52,932
And maybe for the second example, there is a pedestrian, there is a car,
也许第二个例子中 有行人 有车，

89
00:05:52,932 --> 00:05:56,479
but again the labeler, when they looked at that image, they just didn't label it,
但是 当标记人看着那张图片时 他们没有加标签

90
00:05:56,479 --> 00:05:59,790
whether it had a stop sign or whether it had a traffic light, and so on.
没有标记是否有停车标志 是否有交通灯 等等

91
00:05:59,790 --> 00:06:03,496
And maybe some examples are fully labeled, and maybe some examples,
也许有些样本都有标记 但也许有些样本

92
00:06:03,496 --> 00:06:05,992
they were just labeling for the presence and absence of cars
他们只标记了有没有车

93
00:06:05,993 --> 00:06:08,858
so there's some question marks, and so on.
然后还有一些是问号

94
00:06:08,858 --> 00:06:13,050
So with a data set like this, you can still train your learning algorithm
即使是这样的数据集 你也可以在上面训练算法

95
00:06:13,050 --> 00:06:16,619
to do four tasks at the same time, even when some images
同时做四个任务 即使一些图像

96
00:06:16,620 --> 00:06:18,184
have only a subset of the labels
只有一小部分标签

97
00:06:18,237 --> 00:06:21,300
and others are sort of question marks or don't cares.
其他是问号 或者不管是什么

98
00:06:21,300 --> 00:06:22,429
And the way you train your algorithm,
然后你训练算法的方式

99
00:06:22,472 --> 00:06:25,885
even when some of these labels are question marks or really unlabeled
即使这里有些标签是问号 或者没有标记

100
00:06:25,932 --> 00:06:30,124
is that in this sum over j from 1 to 4,
这就是对j从1到4求和

101
00:06:30,192 --> 00:06:39,730
you would sum only over values of j with a 0 or 1 label.
你就只对带0和1标签的j值求和

102
00:06:41,354 --> 00:06:43,267
So whenever there's a question mark,
所以当有问号的时候

103
00:06:43,322 --> 00:06:46,571
you just omit that term from summation
你就在求和时忽略那个项

104
00:06:46,572 --> 00:06:51,480
but just sum over only the values where there is a label.
这样只对有标签的值求和

105
00:06:51,480 --> 00:06:54,720
And so that allows you to use datasets like this as well.
于是你就能利用这样的数据集

106
00:06:54,720 --> 00:06:57,390
So when does multi-task learning makes sense?
那么多任务学习什么时候有意义呢?

107
00:06:57,390 --> 00:06:59,471
So when does multi-task learning make sense?
多任务学习什么时候有意义？

108
00:06:59,471 --> 00:07:03,550
I'll say it makes sense usually when three things hold true.
当三件事为真时 它就是有意义的

109
00:07:03,550 --> 00:07:05,830
One is if your training on a set of tasks that could
第一 如果你训练的一组任务

110
00:07:05,831 --> 00:07:08,470
benefit from having shared low-level features.
可以共用低层次特征

111
00:07:08,470 --> 00:07:10,880
So for the autonomous driving example,
对于无人驾驶的例子

112
00:07:11,126 --> 00:07:14,855
it makes sense that recognizing traffic lights and cars and pedestrians,
同时识别交通灯 汽车和行人是有道理的

113
00:07:14,856 --> 00:07:16,879
those should have similar features
这些物体有相似的特征

114
00:07:16,917 --> 00:07:18,541
that could also help you recognize stop signs,
也许能帮你识别停车标志

115
00:07:18,588 --> 00:07:21,653
because these are all features of roads.
因为这些都是道路上的特征

116
00:07:23,120 --> 00:07:28,032
Second, this is less of a hard and fast rule, so this isn't always true.
第二 这个准则没有那么绝对 所以不一定是对的

117
00:07:28,032 --> 00:07:31,757
But what I see from a lot of successful multi-task learning settings is that
但我从很多成功的多任务学习案例中看到

118
00:07:31,757 --> 00:07:35,310
the amount of data you have for each task is quite similar.
如果每个任务的数据量很接近

119
00:07:35,310 --> 00:07:39,480
So if you recall from transfer learning, you learn from some task A and
你还记得迁移学习时 你从A任务学到知识

120
00:07:39,480 --> 00:07:41,930
transfer it to some task B.
然后迁移到B任务

121
00:07:41,930 --> 00:07:45,669
So if you have a million examples of task A
所以如果任务A有1百万个样本

122
00:07:45,669 --> 00:07:48,610
then and 1,000 examples for task B,
任务B只有1000个样本

123
00:07:48,665 --> 00:07:51,249
then all the knowledge you learned from that million examples
那么你从这1百万个样本学到的知识

124
00:07:51,249 --> 00:07:56,430
could really help augment the much smaller data set you have for task B.
真的可以帮你增强对更小数据集任务B的训练

125
00:07:56,430 --> 00:07:58,652
Well how about multi-task learning?
那么多任务学习又怎么样呢？

126
00:07:58,652 --> 00:08:01,520
In multi-task learning you usually have a lot more tasks than just two.
在多任务学习中 你通常有更多任务而不仅仅是两个

127
00:08:01,520 --> 00:08:07,678
So maybe you have, previously we had 4 tasks but let's say you have 100 tasks.
所以也许你有 以前我们有4个任务 但比如说你要完成100个任务

128
00:08:07,678 --> 00:08:09,178
And you're going to do multi-task learning to
而你要做多任务学习

129
00:08:09,216 --> 00:08:12,580
try to recognize 100 different types of objects at the same time.
尝试同时识别100种不同类型的物体

130
00:08:12,580 --> 00:08:17,165
So what you may find is that you may have 1,000 examples per task
你可能会发现 每个任务大概有1000个样本

131
00:08:18,007 --> 00:08:20,971
and so if you focus on the performance of just one task,
所以如果你专注加强单个任务的性能

132
00:08:20,971 --> 00:08:25,775
let's focus on the performance on the 100th task, you can call A100.
比如我们专注加强第100个任务的表现 我们用A100表示

133
00:08:25,775 --> 00:08:28,899
If you are trying to do this final task in isolation,
如果你试图单独去做这个最后的任务

134
00:08:28,899 --> 00:08:32,875
you would have had just a thousand examples to train this one task,
你只有1000个样本去训练这个任务

135
00:08:32,875 --> 00:08:34,208
this one of the 100 tasks
这是100项任务之一

136
00:08:34,208 --> 00:08:37,320
that by training on these 99 other tasks.
而通过在其他99项任务的训练

137
00:08:37,320 --> 00:08:42,810
These in aggregate have 99,000 training examples which could be a big boost,
这些加起来可以一共有99000个样本 这可能大幅提升算法性能

138
00:08:42,810 --> 00:08:46,597
could give a lot of knowledge to augment this otherwise,
可以提供很多知识来增强这个任务的性能

139
00:08:46,597 --> 00:08:52,040
relatively small 1,000 example training set that you have for task A100.
不然对于任务A100 只有1000个样本的训练集 效果可能会很差

140
00:08:52,040 --> 00:08:56,553
And symmetrically every one of the other 99 tasks can provide some data
如果有对称性 这其他99个任务 也许能提供一些数据

141
00:08:56,618 --> 00:08:57,457
or provide some knowledge
或提供一些知识

142
00:08:57,517 --> 00:09:01,197
that help every one of the other tasks in this list of 100 tasks.
来帮到这100个任务中的每一个任务

143
00:09:02,640 --> 00:09:07,940
So the second bullet isn't a hard and fast rule but what I tend to look at is
所以第二点不是绝对正确的准则 但我通常会看的是

144
00:09:07,940 --> 00:09:13,150
if you focus on any one task, for that to get a big boost for multi-task learning,
如果你专注于单项任务 如果想要从多任务学习得到很大性能提升

145
00:09:13,150 --> 00:09:15,547
the other tasks in aggregate need to have
那么其他任务加起来

146
00:09:15,548 --> 00:09:18,220
quite a lot more data than for that one task.
必须要有比单个任务大得多的数据量

147
00:09:18,220 --> 00:09:20,420
And so one way to satisfy that is if a lot of tasks
要满足这个条件 其中一种方法是

148
00:09:20,481 --> 00:09:23,352
like we have in this example on the right,
比如右边这个例子这样

149
00:09:23,353 --> 00:09:27,030
and if the amount of data you have in each task is quite similar.
或者如果每个任务中的数据量很相近

150
00:09:27,030 --> 00:09:31,558
But the key really is that if you already have 1,000 examples for 1 task,
但关键在于 如果对于单个任务你已经有1000个样本了

151
00:09:31,558 --> 00:09:35,660
then for all of the other tasks you better have a lot more than 1,000 examples
那么对于所有其他任务 你最好有超过1000个样本

152
00:09:35,713 --> 00:09:40,565
if those other other task are meant to help you do better on this final task.
这样其他任务的知识才能帮你改善这个任务的性能

153
00:09:40,565 --> 00:09:43,300
And finally multi-task learning tends to make more sense
最后多任务学习往往在以下场合更有意义

154
00:09:43,301 --> 00:09:45,830
when you can train a big enough neural network
当你可以训练一个足够大的神经网络

155
00:09:45,831 --> 00:09:47,640
to do well on all the tasks.
同时做好所有的工作

156
00:09:47,640 --> 00:09:50,259
So the alternative to multi-task learning would be
所以多任务学习的替代方法是

157
00:09:50,259 --> 00:09:52,767
to train a separate neural network for each task.
为每个任务训练一个单独的神经网络

158
00:09:52,767 --> 00:09:56,084
So rather than training one neural network for pedestrian, car, stop sign, and
所以 不是训练单个神经网络同时处理行人 汽车 停车标志和

159
00:09:56,084 --> 00:09:58,095
traffic light detection, you could have trained
交通灯检测 你可以训练

160
00:09:58,096 --> 00:09:59,958
one neural network for pedestrian detection,
一个用于行人检测的神经网络

161
00:09:59,959 --> 00:10:01,586
one neural network for car detection,
一个用于汽车检测的神经网络

162
00:10:01,587 --> 00:10:03,368
one neural network for stop sign detection,
一个用于停车标志检测的神经网络

163
00:10:03,423 --> 00:10:05,630
and one neural network for traffic light detection.
和一个用于交通信号灯检测的神经网络

164
00:10:06,640 --> 00:10:10,140
So what a researcher, Rich Carona, found many years ago was that
那么研究员Rich Carona几年前发现的是什么呢？

165
00:10:10,141 --> 00:10:13,454
the only times multi-task learning hurts performance
多任务学习会降低性能的唯一情况

166
00:10:13,455 --> 00:10:16,220
compared to training separate neural networks is
和训练单个神经网络相比性能更低的情况

167
00:10:16,221 --> 00:10:18,590
if your neural network isn't big enough.
就是你的神经网络还不够大

168
00:10:18,590 --> 00:10:22,898
But if you can train a big enough neural network, then multi-task learning
但如果你可以训练一个足够大的神经网络 那么多任务学习

169
00:10:22,898 --> 00:10:26,476
certainly should not or should very rarely hurt performance.
肯定不会 或者很少会降低性能

170
00:10:26,476 --> 00:10:29,405
And hopefully it will actually help performance compared to if you
我们都希望它可以提升性能

171
00:10:29,405 --> 00:10:33,640
were training neural networks to do these different tasks in isolation.
比单独训练神经网络来单独完成各个任务性能要更好

172
00:10:33,640 --> 00:10:35,860
So that's it for multi-task learning.
所以这就是多任务学习

173
00:10:35,860 --> 00:10:40,410
In practice, multi-task learning is used much less often than transfer learning.
在实践中 多任务学习的使用频率要低于迁移学习

174
00:10:40,410 --> 00:10:42,978
I see a lot of applications of transfer learning
我看到很多迁移学习的应用

175
00:10:42,979 --> 00:10:46,150
where you have a problem you want to solve with a small amount of data.
你需要解决一个问题 但你的训练数据很少

176
00:10:46,150 --> 00:10:49,435
So you find a related problem with a lot of data to learn something
所以你需要找一个数据很多的相关问题 来预先学习

177
00:10:49,436 --> 00:10:51,802
and transfer that to this new problem.
并将知识迁移到这个新问题上

178
00:10:51,802 --> 00:10:54,688
But multi-task learning is just more rare that
但多任务学习比较少见

179
00:10:54,746 --> 00:10:57,820
you have a huge set of tasks you want to use that you want to do well on,
就是你需要同时处理很多任务 都要做好

180
00:10:57,820 --> 00:11:00,390
you can train all of those tasks at the same time.
你可以同时训练所有这些任务

181
00:11:00,390 --> 00:11:02,254
Maybe the one example is computer vision.
也许计算机视觉是一个例子

182
00:11:02,254 --> 00:11:06,265
In object detection I see more applications of multi-task learning
在物体检测中 我们看到更多使用多任务学习的应用

183
00:11:06,319 --> 00:11:09,716
where one neural network trying to detect a whole bunch of objects at the same time
其中一个神经网络尝试检测一大堆物体

184
00:11:09,716 --> 00:11:13,700
works better than different neural networks trained separately to detect objects.
比分别训练不同的神经网络检测物体更好

185
00:11:13,700 --> 00:11:17,870
But I would say that on average transfer learning is used much more today
但我说 平均来说 目前迁移学习使用频率更高

186
00:11:17,870 --> 00:11:22,610
than multi-task learning, but both are useful tools to have in your arsenal.
比多任务学习频率要高 但两者都可以成为你的强力工具

187
00:11:22,610 --> 00:11:23,685
So to summarize,
所以总结一下

188
00:11:23,685 --> 00:11:28,270
multi-task learning enables you to train one neural network to do many tasks and
多任务学习能让你训练一个神经网络来执行许多任务

189
00:11:28,270 --> 00:11:32,630
this can give you better performance than if you were to do the tasks in isolation.
这可以给你更高的性能 比单独完成各个任务更高的性能

190
00:11:32,630 --> 00:11:37,410
Now one note of caution, in practice I see that transfer learning is used
但要注意 实际上迁移学习

191
00:11:37,410 --> 00:11:39,790
much more often than multi-task learning.
比多任务学习使用频率更高

192
00:11:39,790 --> 00:11:43,262
So I do see a lot of tasks where if you want to solve a machine learning problem
我看到很多任务都是 如果你想解决一个机器学习问题

193
00:11:43,262 --> 00:11:47,197
but you have a relatively small data set, then transfer learning can really help.
但你的数据集相对较小 那么迁移学习真的能帮到你

194
00:11:47,197 --> 00:11:50,172
Where if you find a related problem but you have a much bigger data set,
就是如果你找到一个相关问题 其中数据量要大得多

195
00:11:50,172 --> 00:11:52,290
you can train in your neural network from there and
你就能以它为基础训练你的神经网络

196
00:11:52,290 --> 00:11:54,830
then transfer it to the problem where we have very low data.
然后迁移到这个数据量很少的任务上来

197
00:11:54,830 --> 00:11:57,460
So transfer learning is used a lot today.
今天我们学到了很多和迁移学习有关的问题

198
00:11:57,460 --> 00:12:01,785
There are some applications of transfer multi-task learning as well, but
还有一些迁移学习和多任务学习的应用

199
00:12:01,785 --> 00:12:05,730
multi-task learning I think is used much less often than transfer learning.
但多任务学习 我觉得使用频率比迁移学习要少得多

200
00:12:05,730 --> 00:12:09,230
And maybe the one exception is computer vision object detection,
也许其中一个例外是计算机视觉 物体检测

201
00:12:09,230 --> 00:12:12,180
where I do see a lot of applications of training a neural network
在那些任务中 人们经常训练一个神经网络

202
00:12:12,180 --> 00:12:13,980
to detect lots of different objects.
同时检测很多不同物体

203
00:12:13,980 --> 00:12:16,660
And that works better than training separate neural networks and
这比训练单独的神经网络

204
00:12:16,660 --> 00:12:18,150
detecting the visual objects.
来检测视觉物体要更好

205
00:12:18,150 --> 00:12:21,385
But on average I think that even though transfer learning and
但平均而言 我认为即使迁移学习和

206
00:12:21,385 --> 00:12:26,130
multi-task learning often you're presented in a similar way, in practice I've
多任务学习工作方式类似 实际上

207
00:12:26,130 --> 00:12:30,130
seen a lot more applications of transfer learning than of multi-task learning.
我看到用迁移学习比多任务学习要更多

208
00:12:30,130 --> 00:12:34,489
I think because often it's just difficult to set up or to find so many different tasks
我觉得这是因为你很难找到那么多相似且数据量对等的任务

209
00:12:34,490 --> 00:12:37,120
that you would actually want to train a single neural network for.
可以用单一神经网络训练

210
00:12:37,120 --> 00:12:39,050
Again, with some sort of computer vision,
再次 在计算机视觉领域

211
00:12:39,050 --> 00:12:43,000
object detection examples being the most notable exception.
物体检测这个例子是最显著的例外情况

212
00:12:43,000 --> 00:12:45,465
So that's it for multi-task learning.
所以这就是多任务学习

213
00:12:45,465 --> 00:12:46,821
Multi-task learning and transfer learning
多任务学习和迁移学习

214
00:12:46,901 --> 00:12:50,350
are both important tools to have in your tool bag.
都是你的工具包中的重要工具

215
00:12:50,350 --> 00:12:54,730
And finally, I'd like to move on to discuss end-to-end deep learning.
最后 我想继续讨论端到端深度学习

216
00:12:54,730 --> 00:12:57,620
So let's go onto the next video to discuss end-to-end learning.
所以我们来看下一个视频来讨论端到端学习

