1
00:00:00,000 --> 00:00:02,820
Let's say in building a machine learning system you're trying to
假设你正在搭建一个机器学习系统

2
00:00:02,820 --> 00:00:05,690
decide whether or not to use an end-to-end approach.
你要决定是否使用端对端方法

3
00:00:05,690 --> 00:00:09,594
Let's take a look at some of the pros and cons of end-to-end deep learning
我们来看看端到端深度学习的一些优缺点

4
00:00:09,595 --> 00:00:12,024
so that you can come away with some guidelines 
这样你就可以根据一些准则

5
00:00:12,096 --> 00:00:17,040
on whether or not an end-to-end approach seems promising for your application.
判断你的应用程序是否有希望使用端到端方法

6
00:00:17,040 --> 00:00:20,265
Here are some of the benefits of applying end-to-end learning.
这里是应用端到端学习的一些好处

7
00:00:20,265 --> 00:00:25,435
First is that end-to-end learning really just lets the data speak.
首先端到端学习真的只是让数据说话

8
00:00:25,435 --> 00:00:29,010
So if you have enough x,y data
所以如果你有足够多的x,y数据

9
00:00:29,010 --> 00:00:33,450
then whatever is the most appropriate function mapping from x to y,
那么不管从x到y最适合的函数映射是什么

10
00:00:33,450 --> 00:00:35,475
if you train a big enough neural network,
如果你训练一个足够大的神经网络

11
00:00:35,475 --> 00:00:38,395
hopefully the neural network will figure it out.
希望这个神经网络能自己搞清楚

12
00:00:38,395 --> 00:00:41,040
And by having a pure machine learning approach,
而使用纯机器学习方法

13
00:00:41,040 --> 00:00:44,550
your neural network learning input from x to y may be
直接从x到y输入去训练的神经网络

14
00:00:44,550 --> 00:00:48,540
more able to capture whatever statistics are in the data,
可能更能够捕获数据中的任何统计信息

15
00:00:48,540 --> 00:00:52,800
rather than being forced to reflect human preconceptions.
而不是被迫引入人类的成见

16
00:00:52,800 --> 00:00:55,695
So for example, in the case of speech recognition
例如 在语音识别领域

17
00:00:55,695 --> 00:00:58,530
earlier speech systems had this notion of
早期的识别系统有这个音位概念

18
00:00:58,530 --> 00:01:04,240
a phoneme which was a basic unit of sound like C, A, and T for the word cat.
就是基本的声音单元 如cat单词的C A T

19
00:01:04,240 --> 00:01:09,890
And I think that phonemes are an artifact created by human linguists.
我觉得这个音位是人类语言学家生造出来的

20
00:01:09,890 --> 00:01:12,757
I actually think that phonemes are a fantasy of linguists
我实际上认为音位其实是语音学家的幻想

21
00:01:12,758 --> 00:01:15,690
that are a reasonable description of language,
用音位描述语言也还算合理

22
00:01:15,690 --> 00:01:21,785
but it's not obvious that you want to force your learning algorithm to think in phonemes.
但是不要强迫你的学习算法以音位为单位思考 这点有时没那么明显

23
00:01:21,785 --> 00:01:23,441
And if you let your learning algorithm
如果你让你的学习算法 

24
00:01:23,509 --> 00:01:26,228
learn whatever representation it wants to learn
学习它想学习的任意表示方式

25
00:01:26,229 --> 00:01:30,675
rather than forcing your learning algorithm to use phonemes as a representation,
而不是强迫你的学习算法使用音位作为表示方式

26
00:01:30,675 --> 00:01:34,645
then its overall performance might end up being better.
那么其整体表现可能会更好

27
00:01:34,645 --> 00:01:37,387
The second benefit to end-to-end deep learning is that
端到端深度学习的第二个好处就是这样 

28
00:01:37,388 --> 00:01:40,480
there's less hand designing of components needed.
所需手工设计的组件更少

29
00:01:40,480 --> 00:01:43,960
And so this could also simplify your design work flow,
所以这也许能够简化你的设计工作流程

30
00:01:43,960 --> 00:01:47,655
that you just don't need to spend a lot of time hand designing features,
你不需要花太多时间去手工设计功能

31
00:01:47,655 --> 00:01:51,040
hand designing these intermediate representations.
手工设计这些中间表示方式

32
00:01:51,040 --> 00:01:52,650
How about the disadvantages.
那么缺点呢?

33
00:01:52,650 --> 00:01:54,335
Here are some of the cons.
这里有一些缺点

34
00:01:54,335 --> 00:01:57,010
First, it may need a large amount of data.
首先 它可能需要大量的数据

35
00:01:57,010 --> 00:02:00,225
So to learn this x to y mapping directly,
要直接学到这个x到y的映射

36
00:02:00,225 --> 00:02:03,463
you might need a lot of data of x, y
你可能需要大量x,y数据

37
00:02:03,463 --> 00:02:06,600
and we were seeing in a previous video some examples of
我们在以前的视频里看过一个例子

38
00:02:06,600 --> 00:02:10,720
where you could obtain a lot of data for subtasks.
其中你可以收集大量子任务数据

39
00:02:10,720 --> 00:02:13,675
Such as for face recognition,
比如人脸识别

40
00:02:13,675 --> 00:02:17,310
we could find a lot data for finding a face in the image,
我们可以收集很多数据 用来分辨图像中的人脸

41
00:02:17,310 --> 00:02:20,510
as well as identifying the face once you found a face,
当你找到一张脸后 也可以找得到很多人脸识别数据

42
00:02:20,510 --> 00:02:24,780
but there was just less data available for the entire end-to-end task.
但是对于整个端到端任务 可能只有更少的数据可用

43
00:02:24,780 --> 00:02:32,989
So x, this is the input end of the end-to-end learning and y is the output end.
所以x 这是端到端学习的输入端 y是输出端

44
00:02:33,547 --> 00:02:36,180
And so you need a lot of the data x y with
所以你需要很多这样的xy数据

45
00:02:36,180 --> 00:02:40,540
both the input end and the output end in order to train these systems,
在输入端和输出端都有数据 这样可以训练这些系统

46
00:02:40,540 --> 00:02:43,552
and this is why we call it end-to-end learning as well 
这就是为什么我们称之为端到端学习

47
00:02:43,616 --> 00:02:48,938
because you're learning a direct mapping from one end of the system
因为你直接学习出从系统的一端

48
00:02:48,939 --> 00:02:52,690
all the way to the other end of the system.
到系统的另一端

49
00:02:52,690 --> 00:02:58,960
The other disadvantage is that it excludes potentially useful hand designed components.
另一个缺点是 它排除了可能有用的手工设计组件

50
00:02:58,960 --> 00:03:04,510
So machine learning researchers tend to speak disparagingly of hand designing things.
机器学习研究人员一般都很鄙视手工设计的东西

51
00:03:04,510 --> 00:03:06,880
But if you don't have a lot of data,
但如果你没有很多数据

52
00:03:06,880 --> 00:03:09,490
then your learning algorithm doesn't have
你的学习算法

53
00:03:09,490 --> 00:03:13,450
that much insight it can gain from your data if your training set is small.
就没办法从很小的训练集数据中获得洞察力

54
00:03:13,450 --> 00:03:16,794
And so hand designing a component can really be a way
所以手工设计组件在这种情况

55
00:03:16,877 --> 00:03:21,138
for you to inject manual knowledge into the algorithm,
可能是把人类知识直接注入算法的途径

56
00:03:21,138 --> 00:03:24,035
and that's not always a bad thing.
这总不是一件坏事

57
00:03:24,035 --> 00:03:28,060
I think of a learning algorithm as having two main sources of knowledge.
我觉得学习算法有两个主要的知识来源

58
00:03:28,060 --> 00:03:33,590
One is the data and the other is whatever you hand design,
一个是数据 另一个是你手工设计的任何东西

59
00:03:33,590 --> 00:03:37,070
be it components, or features, or other things.
可能是组件 功能 或者其他东西

60
00:03:37,070 --> 00:03:39,273
And so when you have a ton of data 
所以当你有成吨数据时

61
00:03:39,274 --> 00:03:44,125
it's less important to hand design things but when you don't have much data,
手工设计的东西就不太重要了 但是当你没有太多的数据时

62
00:03:44,125 --> 00:03:46,962
then having a carefully hand-designed system 
构造一个精心设计的系统

63
00:03:46,963 --> 00:03:51,555
can actually allow humans to inject a lot of knowledge about the problem
实际上可以将人类对这个问题的很多认识直接注入到问题里

64
00:03:51,555 --> 00:03:54,985
into an algorithm and that should be very helpful.
进入算法里 应该挺有帮助的

65
00:03:54,985 --> 00:03:58,200
So one of the downsides of end-to-end deep learning is
所以端到端深度学习的弊端之一是

66
00:03:58,200 --> 00:04:02,605
that it excludes potentially useful hand-designed components.
它把可能有用的人工设计的组件排除在外了

67
00:04:02,605 --> 00:04:06,490
And hand-designed components could be very helpful if well designed.
精心设计的人工组件可能非常有用

68
00:04:06,490 --> 00:04:09,660
They could also be harmful if it really limits your performance,
但它们也有可能真的伤害到你的算法表现

69
00:04:09,660 --> 00:04:12,960
such as if you force an algorithm to think in phonemes
例如 强制你的算法以音位为单位思考

70
00:04:12,960 --> 00:04:16,770
when maybe it could have discovered a better representation by itself.
也许让算法自己找到更好的表示方法更好

71
00:04:16,770 --> 00:04:19,110
So it's kind of a double edged sword that could
所以这是一把双刃剑 

72
00:04:19,110 --> 00:04:21,660
hurt or help but it does tend to help more,
可能有坏处 可能有好处 但往往好处更多

73
00:04:21,660 --> 00:04:23,332
hand-designed components tend to help more
手工设计的组件往往在

74
00:04:23,381 --> 00:04:26,320
when you're training on a small training set.
训练集更小的时候帮助更大

75
00:04:26,320 --> 00:04:29,250
So if you're building a new machine learning system and you're trying to
如果你在构建一个新的机器学习系统 而你在尝试

76
00:04:29,250 --> 00:04:32,535
decide whether or not to use end-to-end deep learning,
决定是否使用端到端深度学习

77
00:04:32,535 --> 00:04:34,500
I think the key question is,
我认为关键的问题是 

78
00:04:34,500 --> 00:04:36,023
do you have sufficient data 
你有足够的数据

79
00:04:36,024 --> 00:04:41,340
to learn the function of the complexity needed to map from x to y?
能够直接学到从x映射到y 足够复杂的函数吗?

80
00:04:41,340 --> 00:04:46,277
I don't have a formal definition of this phrase, complexity needed,
我还没有正式定义过这个词 必要复杂度

81
00:04:46,337 --> 00:04:52,140
but intuitively, if you're trying to learn a function from x to y,
但直觉上 如果你想从x到y的数据学习出一个函数

82
00:04:52,140 --> 00:04:54,685
that is looking at an image like this
就是看着这样的图像

83
00:04:54,685 --> 00:04:57,495
and recognizing the position of the bones in this image,
识别出图像中所有骨头的位置

84
00:04:57,495 --> 00:04:58,812
then maybe this seems like 
那么也许这像是

85
00:04:58,859 --> 00:05:02,864
a relatively simple problem to identify the bones of the image
识别图中骨头这样相对简单的问题

86
00:05:02,930 --> 00:05:06,030
and maybe they won't need that much data for that task.
也许系统不需要那么多数据来学会处理这个任务

87
00:05:06,030 --> 00:05:12,020
Or given a picture of a person,
或给出一张人物照片

88
00:05:12,020 --> 00:05:18,995
maybe finding the face of that person in the image doesn't seem like that hard a problem,
也许在图中把人脸找出来不是什么难事

89
00:05:18,995 --> 00:05:23,420
so maybe you don't need too much data to find the face of a person.
所以你也许不需要太多数据去找到人脸

90
00:05:23,420 --> 00:05:28,465
Or at least maybe you can find enough data to solve that task, whereas in contrast,
或者至少你可以找到足够数据去解决这个问题 相对来说

91
00:05:28,465 --> 00:05:34,732
the function needed to look at the hand and map that directly to the age of the child,
把手的x射线照片直接映射到孩子的年龄 直接去找这种函数

92
00:05:34,732 --> 00:05:38,995
that seems like a much more complex problem that intuitively maybe you need
直觉上似乎是更为复杂的问题

93
00:05:38,995 --> 00:05:45,815
more data to learn if you were to apply a pure end-to-end deep learning approach.
如果你用纯端到端方法 需要很多数据去学习 

94
00:05:45,815 --> 00:05:50,185
So let me finish this video with a more complex example.
视频最后我讲一个更复杂的例子

95
00:05:50,185 --> 00:05:52,645
you may know that I've been spending time helping out
你可能知道我一直在花时间帮忙 

96
00:05:52,645 --> 00:05:55,360
an autonomous driving company, Drive.ai.
主攻无人驾驶技术的公司drive.ai

97
00:05:55,360 --> 00:06:00,108
So I'm actually very excited about autonomous driving.
无人驾驶技术的发展其实让我相当激动

98
00:06:00,108 --> 00:06:03,950
So how do you build a car that drives itself?
你怎么造出一辆自己能行驶的车呢?

99
00:06:03,950 --> 00:06:06,065
Well, here's one thing you could do,
好 这里你可以做一件事

100
00:06:06,065 --> 00:06:08,795
and this is not an end-to-end deep learning approach.
这不是端到端的深度学习方法

101
00:06:08,795 --> 00:06:15,620
you can take as input an image of what's in front of your car, maybe radar, LIDAR
你可以把你车前方的雷达 激光雷达

102
00:06:15,620 --> 00:06:17,075
other sensor readings as well,
或者其他传感器的读数 看成是输入图像

103
00:06:17,075 --> 00:06:20,030
but to simplify the description,
但是为了说明起来简单

104
00:06:20,030 --> 00:06:24,700
let's just say you take a picture of what's in front or what's around your car.
我们就说拍一张车前方或者周围的照片

105
00:06:24,700 --> 00:06:29,444
And then to drive your car safely you need to detect other cars
然后驾驶要安全的话 你必须能检测到附近的车

106
00:06:29,445 --> 00:06:33,135
and you also need to detect pedestrians.
你也需要检测到行人

107
00:06:33,135 --> 00:06:35,840
you need to detect other things, of course,
你需要检测其他的东西 当然

108
00:06:35,840 --> 00:06:39,033
but we'll just present a simplified example here.
我们这里提供的是高度简化的例子

109
00:06:39,033 --> 00:06:42,625
Having figured out where are the other cars and pedestrians,
弄清楚其他车和形如的位置之后

110
00:06:42,625 --> 00:06:48,783
you then need to plan your own route.
你就需要计划你自己的路线

111
00:06:48,783 --> 00:06:50,305
So in other words,
所以换句话说

112
00:06:50,305 --> 00:06:54,880
if you see where are the other cars,
当你看到其他车子在哪

113
00:06:54,880 --> 00:06:58,300
where are the pedestrians, you need to decide how to steer your own car,
行人在哪里 你需要决定如何摆方向盘

114
00:06:58,300 --> 00:07:02,110
what path to steer your own car for the next several seconds.
在接下来的几秒钟内 引导车子的路径

115
00:07:02,110 --> 00:07:08,185
And having decided that you're going to drive a certain path,
如果你决定了要走特定的路径

116
00:07:08,185 --> 00:07:14,725
maybe this is a top down view of a road and that's your car.
也许这是道路的俯视图 这是你的车

117
00:07:14,725 --> 00:07:17,625
Maybe you've decided to drive that path,
也许你决定了要走那条路线

118
00:07:17,625 --> 00:07:20,066
that's what a route is,
这是一条路线

119
00:07:20,066 --> 00:07:25,405
then you need to execute this by generating the appropriate steering,
那么你就需要摆动你的方向盘到合适的角度

120
00:07:25,405 --> 00:07:28,850
as well as acceleration and braking commands.
还要发出合适的加速和制动指令

121
00:07:28,850 --> 00:07:34,030
So in going from your image or your sensory inputs to detecting cars and pedestrians,
所以从传感器或图像输入 到检测行人和车辆

122
00:07:34,030 --> 00:07:37,630
that can be done pretty well using deep learning,
深度学习可以做得很好 

123
00:07:37,630 --> 00:07:40,870
but then having figured out where the other cars and pedestrians are going,
但一旦知道其他车辆和行人的位置 或者动向

124
00:07:40,870 --> 00:07:45,220
to select this route to exactly how you want to move your car,
选择一条车要走的路

125
00:07:45,220 --> 00:07:47,420
usually that's not to done with deep learning.
这通常用的不是深度学习

126
00:07:47,420 --> 00:07:51,715
Instead that's done with a piece of software called Motion Planning.
而是用所谓的运动规划软件完成的

127
00:07:51,715 --> 00:07:55,420
And if you ever take a course in robotics you'll learn about motion planning.
如果你学过机器人课程 你一定知道运动规划

128
00:07:55,420 --> 00:07:59,240
And then having decided what's the path you want to steer your car through,
然后决定了你的车子要走的路径之后

129
00:07:59,240 --> 00:08:00,880
there'll be some other algorithm,
还会有一些其他算法

130
00:08:00,880 --> 00:08:06,355
we're going to say it's a control algorithm that then generates the exact decision,
我们说这是一个控制算法 可以产生精确的决策

131
00:08:06,355 --> 00:08:10,018
that then decides exactly how much to turn the steering wheel
确定方向盘应该精确地转多少度

132
00:08:10,019 --> 00:08:13,160
and how much to step on the accelerator or step on the brake.
油门或刹车上应该用多少力

133
00:08:13,160 --> 00:08:16,990
So I think what this example illustrates is that
所以这个例子就表明了

134
00:08:16,990 --> 00:08:20,778
you want to use machine learning or use deep learning 
如果你想使用机器学习或者深度学习

135
00:08:20,779 --> 00:08:22,849
to learn some individual components 
来学习某些单独的组件

136
00:08:27,027 --> 00:08:30,640
and when applying supervised learning you should
那么当你应用监督学习时 你应该

137
00:08:30,640 --> 00:08:40,782
carefully choose what types of x to y mappings you want to learn
仔细选择要学习的x到y映射类型 

138
00:08:40,783 --> 00:08:48,875
depending on what task you can get data for.
这取决于那些任务你可以收集数据

139
00:08:48,875 --> 00:08:51,765
And in contrast, it is exciting to talk about
相比之下 空谈纯端到端深度学习方法

140
00:08:51,765 --> 00:08:53,691
a pure end-to-end deep learning approach 
是很激动人心的

141
00:08:53,765 --> 00:08:57,180
where you input the image and directly output a steering.
你输入图像 直接得出方向盘转角

142
00:09:02,712 --> 00:09:04,570
But given data availability
但是就目前能收集到的数据而言

143
00:09:04,570 --> 00:09:08,140
and the types of things we can learn with neural networks today,
还有我们今天能够用神经网络学习的数据类型而言

144
00:09:08,140 --> 00:09:12,076
this is actually not the most promising approach 
这实际上不是最有希望的方法 

145
00:09:12,077 --> 00:09:18,170
or this is not an approach that I think teams have gotten to work best.
或者说这个方法并不是团队想出的最好用的方法

146
00:09:18,170 --> 00:09:22,780
And I think this pure end-to-end deep learning approach is actually
而我认为这种纯粹的端到端深度学习方法

147
00:09:22,780 --> 00:09:27,170
less promising than more sophisticated approaches like this,
其实前景不如这样更复杂的多步方法

148
00:09:27,170 --> 00:09:32,260
given the availability of data and our ability to train neural networks today.
因为目前能收集到的数据 还有我们现在训练神经网络的能力 是有局限的

149
00:09:32,260 --> 00:09:35,055
So that's it for end-to-end deep learning.
这就是端到端的深度学习。

150
00:09:35,055 --> 00:09:36,918
It can sometimes work really well
有时候效果拔群

151
00:09:36,976 --> 00:09:42,453
but you also have to be mindful of where you apply end-to-end deep learning.
但你也要注意应该在什么时候使用端到端深度学习

152
00:09:42,453 --> 00:09:46,985
Finally, thank you and congrats on making it this far with me.
最后 谢谢你 恭喜你坚持到现在

153
00:09:46,985 --> 00:09:49,970
If you finish last week's videos and this week's videos 
如果你学完了上周的视频和本周的视频

154
00:09:49,971 --> 00:09:53,860
then I think you will already be much smarter and much more strategic
那么我认为你已经变得更聪明 更具战略性

155
00:09:53,860 --> 00:09:57,135
and much more able to make good prioritization decisions 
并能够做出更好的优先分配任务的决策

156
00:09:57,136 --> 00:10:01,138
in terms of how to move forward on your machine learning project,
更好地推动你的机器学习项目

157
00:10:01,138 --> 00:10:03,520
even compared to a lot of machine learning engineers
也许比很多机器学习工程师

158
00:10:03,520 --> 00:10:06,310
and researchers that I see here in Silicon Valley.
还和我在硅谷看到的研究人员都强

159
00:10:06,310 --> 00:10:09,232
So congrats on all that you've learned so far and
所以恭喜你学到这里

160
00:10:09,233 --> 00:10:12,548
I hope you now also take a look at this week's homework problems
我希望你能看看本周的作业

161
00:10:12,549 --> 00:10:16,218
which should give you another opportunity to practice these ideas
应该能再给你一个机会去实践这些理念

162
00:10:16,219 --> 00:10:17,395
and make sure that you're mastering them.
并确保你掌握它们

