1
00:00:00,000 --> 00:00:06,985
The data for your supervised learning problem comprises input X and output labels Y.
你的监督学习问题的数据由输入X和输出标签Y构成

2
00:00:06,985 --> 00:00:09,730
What if you going through your data and you find that some of
如果你观察一下你的数据 并发现有些输出标签Y是错的

3
00:00:09,730 --> 00:00:12,240
these output labels Y are incorrect,
这些输出标签Y是错的

4
00:00:12,240 --> 00:00:14,740
you have data which is incorrectly labeled?
你的数据有些标签是错的

5
00:00:14,740 --> 00:00:19,540
Is it worth your while to go in to fix up some of these labels? Let's take a look.
是否值得花时间去修正这些标签呢? 我们看看

6
00:00:19,540 --> 00:00:21,640
In the cat classification problem,
在猫分类问题中

7
00:00:21,640 --> 00:00:25,295
Y equals one for cats and zero for non cats.
图片是猫Y=1 不是猫Y=0

8
00:00:25,295 --> 00:00:28,560
So, let's say you're looking through some data and that's a cat,
所以假设你看了一些数据样本 这是猫

9
00:00:28,560 --> 00:00:30,400
that's not a cat, that's a cat,
这不是猫 这是猫

10
00:00:30,400 --> 00:00:33,275
that's a cat, that's not a cat, that's at a cat.
那是猫 那不是猫 那是猫

11
00:00:33,275 --> 00:00:35,480
No, wait. That's actually not a cat.
等等 这其实不是猫

12
00:00:35,480 --> 00:00:41,310
So this is an example with an incorrect label.
所以这是标记错误的例子

13
00:00:41,310 --> 00:00:43,900
So I've used the term, mislabeled examples,
我用了这个词 标记错误的例子

14
00:00:43,900 --> 00:00:48,235
to refer to if your learning algorithm outputs the wrong value of Y.
来表示你的学习算法输出了错误的Y值

15
00:00:48,235 --> 00:00:50,800
But I'm going to say, incorrectly labeled examples,
但我要说的是 对于标记错误的例子

16
00:00:50,800 --> 00:00:54,180
to refer to if in the data set you have
参考你的数据集

17
00:00:54,181 --> 00:00:58,161
in the training set or the dev set or the test set, the label for Y,
在训练集或者测试集 Y的标签

18
00:00:58,161 --> 00:01:00,989
whatever a human label assigned to this piece of data,
人类给这部分数据加的标签

19
00:01:00,990 --> 00:01:02,228
is actually incorrect.
实际上是错的

20
00:01:02,228 --> 00:01:06,430
And that's actually a dog so that Y really should have been zero.
这实际上是一只狗 所以Y其实应该是0

21
00:01:06,430 --> 00:01:10,115
But maybe the labeler got that one wrong.
也许做标记的那人疏忽了

22
00:01:10,115 --> 00:01:14,755
So if you find that your data has some incorrectly labeled examples,
如果你发现你的数据有一些标记错误的例子

23
00:01:14,755 --> 00:01:16,440
what should you do?
你该怎么办?

24
00:01:16,440 --> 00:01:21,177
Well, first, let's consider the training set.
首先 我们来考虑训练集

25
00:01:21,177 --> 00:01:24,170
It turns out that deep learning algorithms
事实证明 深度学习算法

26
00:01:24,170 --> 00:01:27,610
are quite robust to random errors in the training set.
对于训练集中的随机错误是相当健壮的

27
00:01:27,610 --> 00:01:32,450
So long as your errors or your incorrectly labeled examples,
只要你的标记出错的例子

28
00:01:32,450 --> 00:01:35,420
so long as those errors are not too far from random,
只要这些错误例子离随机错误不太远

29
00:01:35,420 --> 00:01:41,495
maybe sometimes the labeler just wasn't paying attention or they accidentally,
有时可能做标记的人没有注意 或者不小心

30
00:01:41,495 --> 00:01:44,205
randomly hit the wrong key on the keyboard.
按错键了

31
00:01:44,205 --> 00:01:46,400
If the errors are reasonably random,
如果错误足够随机

32
00:01:46,400 --> 00:01:50,566
then it's probably okay to just leave the errors as they are
那么放着这些错误不管可能也没问题

33
00:01:50,567 --> 00:01:53,065
and not spend too much time fixing them.
而不要花太多时间修复它们

34
00:01:53,065 --> 00:01:55,876
There's certainly no harm to going into your training set
当然你浏览一下训练集

35
00:01:55,877 --> 00:01:57,920
and be examining the labels and fixing them.
检查一下这些标签 并修正它们也没什么害处

36
00:01:57,920 --> 00:02:02,285
Sometimes that is worth doing but your effort might be okay even if you don't.
有时候修正这些错误是有价值的 有时候放着不管也可以

37
00:02:02,285 --> 00:02:05,937
So long as the total data set size is big enough
只要总数据集总足够大

38
00:02:05,938 --> 00:02:10,470
and the actual percentage of errors is maybe not too high.
实际错误率可能不会太高

39
00:02:10,470 --> 00:02:15,230
So I see a lot of machine learning algorithms that trained even when we know that
我见过一大批机器学习算法训练的时候

40
00:02:15,230 --> 00:02:21,115
there are few X mistakes in the training set labels and usually works okay.
明知训练集里有X个错误标签 但最后训练出来也没问题

41
00:02:21,115 --> 00:02:23,957
There is one caveat to this 
有我这里先警告一下

42
00:02:23,958 --> 00:02:28,500
which is that deep learning algorithms are robust to random errors.
深度学习算法对随机误差很健壮

43
00:02:28,500 --> 00:02:34,955
They are less robust to systematic errors.
但对系统性的错误就没那么健壮了

44
00:02:34,955 --> 00:02:40,555
So for example, if your labeler consistently labels white dogs as cats,
所以比如说 如果做标记的人一直把白色的狗标记成猫

45
00:02:40,555 --> 00:02:43,390
then that is a problem because your classifier will
那就成问题了 因为你的分类器

46
00:02:43,390 --> 00:02:46,970
learn to classify all white colored dogs as cats.
学习之后 会把所有白色的狗都分类为猫

47
00:02:46,970 --> 00:02:50,260
But random errors or near random errors are
但随机错误或近似随机错误

48
00:02:50,260 --> 00:02:54,575
usually not too bad for most deep learning algorithms.
对于大多数深度学习算法来说 不成问题

49
00:02:54,575 --> 00:02:57,730
Now, this discussion has focused on what to do
现在 之前的讨论集中在

50
00:02:57,730 --> 00:03:00,905
about incorrectly labeled examples in your training set.
训练集中的标记出错的例子

51
00:03:00,905 --> 00:03:04,895
How about incorrectly labeled examples in your dev set or test set?
那么如果是开发集和测试集中有这些标记出错的例子呢?

52
00:03:04,895 --> 00:03:07,195
If you're worried about the impact of
如果你担心

53
00:03:07,195 --> 00:03:10,445
incorrectly labeled examples on your dev set or test set,
开发集或测试集上标记出错的例子带来的影响

54
00:03:10,445 --> 00:03:13,375
what they recommend you do is during error analysis
他们一般建议你在错误分析时

55
00:03:13,427 --> 00:03:17,846
to add one extra column so that you can also count up
添加一个额外的列 这样你也可以统计

56
00:03:17,931 --> 00:03:22,080
the number of examples where the label Y was incorrect.
标签Y错误的例子数

57
00:03:22,080 --> 00:03:25,180
So for example, maybe when you count up
所以比如说 也许你统计一下

58
00:03:25,181 --> 00:03:29,075
the impact on a 100 mislabeled dev set examples,
对100个标记出错的例子的影响

59
00:03:29,075 --> 00:03:30,554
so you're going to find a 100 examples 
所以你会找到100个例子 

60
00:03:30,612 --> 00:03:35,595
where your classifier's output disagrees with the label in your dev set.
其中你的分类器的输出和开发集的标签不一致

61
00:03:35,595 --> 00:03:38,440
And sometimes for a few of those examples,
有时对于其中的少数例子

62
00:03:38,440 --> 00:03:42,175
your classifier disagrees with the label because the label was wrong,
你的分类器输出和标签不同 是因为标签错了

63
00:03:42,175 --> 00:03:44,220
rather than because your classifier was wrong.
而不是你的分类器出错

64
00:03:44,220 --> 00:03:46,030
So maybe in this example,
所以也许在这个例子中

65
00:03:46,030 --> 00:03:49,415
you find that the labeler missed a cat in the background.
你发现标记的人漏了背景里的一只猫

66
00:03:49,415 --> 00:03:55,810
So put the check mark there to signify that example 98 had an incorrect label.
所以那里打个勾 来表示例子98标签出错了

67
00:03:55,810 --> 00:03:57,600
And maybe for this one,
也许这张图

68
00:03:57,600 --> 00:04:01,845
the picture is actually a picture of a drawing of a cat rather than a real cat.
实际上是猫的画 而不是一只真正的猫

69
00:04:01,845 --> 00:04:06,865
Maybe you want the labeler to have labeled that Y equals zero rather than Y equals one.
也许你希望标记数据的人将它标记为Y=0 而不是Y=1

70
00:04:06,865 --> 00:04:09,940
And so put another check mark there.
然后再在那里打个勾

71
00:04:09,940 --> 00:04:14,146
And just as you count up the percent of errors due to other categories
当你统计出其他错误类型的百分比后

72
00:04:14,199 --> 00:04:15,670
like we saw in the previous video,
就像我们在之前的视频中看到的那样

73
00:04:15,670 --> 00:04:20,800
you'd also count up the fraction of percentage of errors due to incorrect labels.
你还可以统计因为标签错误所占的百分比

74
00:04:20,800 --> 00:04:23,553
Where the Y value in your dev set was wrong
你的开发集里的Y值是错的

75
00:04:23,554 --> 00:04:25,940
and that accounted for why your learning algorithm
这就解释了 为什么你的学习算法

76
00:04:25,940 --> 00:04:32,140
made a prediction that differed from what the label on your data says.
做出和数据集里的标记不一样的预测1

77
00:04:32,140 --> 00:04:33,835
So the question now is,
所以现在问题是

78
00:04:33,835 --> 00:04:41,045
is it worthwhile going in to try to fix up this 6% of incorrectly labeled examples.
是否值得修正这6%标记出错的例子

79
00:04:41,045 --> 00:04:44,466
My advice is, if it makes a significant difference
我的建议是 如果这些标记错误

80
00:04:44,467 --> 00:04:47,560
to your ability to evaluate algorithms on your dev set,
严重影响了你在开发集上评估算法的能力

81
00:04:47,560 --> 00:04:50,740
then go ahead and spend the time to fix incorrect labels.
那么就应该去花时间修正错误的标签

82
00:04:50,740 --> 00:04:53,648
But if it doesn't make a significant difference to your ability
但是 如果它们没有严重影响到

83
00:04:53,649 --> 00:04:56,125
to use the dev set to evaluate cost bias,
你用开发集评估成本偏差的能力

84
00:04:56,125 --> 00:04:58,810
then it might not be the best use of your time.
那么可能就不应该花宝贵的时间去处理

85
00:04:58,810 --> 00:05:02,075
Let me show you an example that illustrates what I mean by this.
我给你看一个例子 解释清楚我的意思

86
00:05:02,075 --> 00:05:05,320
So, three numbers I recommend you look at to try to decide 
所以我建议你看3个数字 来确定

87
00:05:05,376 --> 00:05:09,305
if it's worth going in and reducing the number of mislabeled examples are the following.
是否值得去人工修正标记出错的数据

88
00:05:09,305 --> 00:05:12,755
I recommend you look at the overall dev set error.
我建议你看看整体的开发集错误率

89
00:05:12,755 --> 00:05:16,570
And so in the example we had from the previous video,
在我们以前的视频中的例子

90
00:05:16,570 --> 00:05:20,680
we said that maybe our system has 90% overall accuracy.
我们说也许我们的系统达到了90%整体准确度

91
00:05:20,680 --> 00:05:22,995
So 10% error.
所以有10%错误率

92
00:05:22,995 --> 00:05:26,408
Then you should look at the number of errors 
那么你应该看看错误标记引起的

93
00:05:26,409 --> 00:05:30,495
or the percentage of errors that are due to incorrect labels.
错误的数量或者百分比

94
00:05:30,495 --> 00:05:32,695
So it looks like in this case,
所以在这种情况下

95
00:05:32,695 --> 00:05:35,730
6% of the errors are due to incorrect labels.
6％的错误来自标记出错

96
00:05:35,730 --> 00:05:40,990
So 6% of 10% is 0.6%.
所以10%的6%就是0.6%

97
00:05:40,990 --> 00:05:45,600
And then you should look at errors due to all other causes.
也许你应该看看其他原因导致的错误

98
00:05:45,600 --> 00:05:48,426
So if you made 10% error on your dev set
如果你的开发集上有10%错误

99
00:05:48,496 --> 00:05:51,580
and 0.6% of those are because the labels is wrong,
其中0.6%是因为标记出错

100
00:05:51,580 --> 00:05:54,430
then the remainder, 9.4% of them,
剩下的占9.4%

101
00:05:54,430 --> 00:05:58,016
are due to other causes such as misrecognizing dogs being cats,
是其他原因导致的 比如把狗误认为猫

102
00:05:58,071 --> 00:06:01,420
great cats and their images.
大猫图片 

103
00:06:01,420 --> 00:06:08,380
So in this case, I would say there's 9.4% worth of error that you could focus on fixing,
所以在这种情况下 我说有9.4%错误率需要集中精力修正

104
00:06:08,380 --> 00:06:12,370
whereas the errors due to incorrect labels is
而标记出错导致的错误

105
00:06:12,370 --> 00:06:16,360
a relatively small fraction of the overall set of errors.
是总体错误的一小部分而已

106
00:06:16,360 --> 00:06:17,860
So by all means,
所以如果你一定要这么做

107
00:06:17,860 --> 00:06:20,605
go in and fix these incorrect labels if you want
你也可以手工修正各种错误标签

108
00:06:20,605 --> 00:06:24,455
but it's maybe not the most important thing to do right now.
但也许这不是当下最重要的任务

109
00:06:24,455 --> 00:06:26,830
Now, let's take another example.
我们再看另一个例子

110
00:06:26,830 --> 00:06:30,040
Suppose you've made a lot more progress on your learning problem.
假设你在学习问题上取得了很大进展

111
00:06:30,040 --> 00:06:31,896
So instead of 10% error,
所以现在错误率不再是10%了

112
00:06:31,896 --> 00:06:35,065
let's say you brought the errors down to 2%,
假设你把错误率降到了2％

113
00:06:35,065 --> 00:06:43,300
but still 0.6% of your overall errors are due to incorrect labels.
但总体错误中的0.6%还是标记出错导致的

114
00:06:43,300 --> 00:06:47,755
So now, if you want to examine a set of mislabeled dev set images,
所以现在 如果你想检查一组标记出错的开发集图片

115
00:06:47,755 --> 00:06:52,600
set that comes from just 2% of dev set data you're mislabeling,
开发集数据有2%标记错误了

116
00:06:52,600 --> 00:06:59,315
then a very large fraction of them, 0.6 divided by 2%,
那么其中很大一部分 0.6除以2%

117
00:06:59,315 --> 00:07:05,235
so that is actually 30% rather than 6% of your labels.
实际上变成30%标签而不是6%标签了

118
00:07:05,235 --> 00:07:09,145
Your incorrect examples are actually due to incorrectly label examples.
有那么多错误例子其实是因为标记出错导致的

119
00:07:09,145 --> 00:07:12,815
And so errors due to other causes are now 1.4%.
所以现在其他原因导致的错误是1.4%

120
00:07:12,815 --> 00:07:19,354
When such a high fraction of your mistakes
当测得的那么大一部分的错误

121
00:07:19,401 --> 00:07:23,640
as these are measured on your dev set due to incorrect labels,
都是开发集标记出错导致的

122
00:07:23,640 --> 00:07:30,825
then it maybe seems much more worthwhile to fix up the incorrect labels in your dev set.
那似乎修正开发集里的错误标签似乎更有价值

123
00:07:30,825 --> 00:07:32,800
And if you remember the goal of the dev set,
如果你还记得设立开发集的目标的话

124
00:07:32,800 --> 00:07:34,890
the main purpose of the dev set is,
开发集的主要目的是

125
00:07:34,890 --> 00:07:39,520
you want to really use it to help you select between two classifiers A and B.
你希望用它来从两个分类器A和B中选择一个

126
00:07:39,520 --> 00:07:42,030
So you're trying out two classifiers A and B,
所以当你测试两个分类器A和B时

127
00:07:42,030 --> 00:07:49,740
and one has 2.1% error and the other has 1.9% error on your dev set.
在开发集上一个有2.1%错误率 另一个有1.9%错误率

128
00:07:49,740 --> 00:07:53,529
But you don't trust your dev set anymore to be correctly telling you
但是你不能再信任开发集了 因为它无法告诉你

129
00:07:53,530 --> 00:07:56,523
whether this classifier is actually better than this 
这个分类器是否比这个好

130
00:07:56,591 --> 00:08:02,215
because your 0.6% of these mistakes are due to incorrect labels.
因为0.6%的错误率是标记出错导致的

131
00:08:02,215 --> 00:08:06,720
Then there's a good reason to go in and fix the incorrect labels in your dev set.
那么现在你就有很好的理由去修正开发集里的错误标签

132
00:08:06,720 --> 00:08:10,770
Because in this example on the right is just having a very large impact
因为在右边这个例子中 标记出错

133
00:08:10,770 --> 00:08:13,820
on the overall assessment of the errors of the algorithm,
对算法错误的整体评估标准有严重的影响

134
00:08:13,879 --> 00:08:15,393
whereas example on the left, 
而左边的例子中

135
00:08:15,443 --> 00:08:21,055
the percentage impact is having on your algorithm is still smaller.
标记出错对你算法影响的百分比还是相对较小的

136
00:08:21,055 --> 00:08:24,040
Now, if you decide to go into a dev set and
现在如果你决定要去修正开发集数据

137
00:08:24,040 --> 00:08:28,285
manually re-examine the labels and try to fix up some of the labels,
手动重新检查标签 并尝试修正一些标签

138
00:08:28,285 --> 00:08:33,505
here are a few additional guidelines or principles to consider.
这里还有一些额外的方针和原则需要考虑

139
00:08:33,505 --> 00:08:36,850
First, I would encourage you to apply
首先 我鼓励你 不管用什么修正手段

140
00:08:36,850 --> 00:08:41,320
whatever process you apply to both your dev and test sets at the same time.
都要同时作用到开发集和测试集上

141
00:08:41,320 --> 00:08:44,110
We've talk previously about why you want
我们之前讨论过 为什么

142
00:08:44,110 --> 00:08:47,335
to dev and test sets to come from the same distribution.
开发和测试集必须来自相同的分布

143
00:08:47,335 --> 00:08:50,890
The dev set is tagging you into target and when you hit it,
开发集确定了你的目标 当你击中目标后

144
00:08:50,890 --> 00:08:53,320
you want that to generalize to the test set.
你希望算法能够推广到测试集上

145
00:08:53,320 --> 00:08:56,158
So your team really works more efficiently
这样你的团队能够更高效的

146
00:08:56,159 --> 00:08:59,195
to dev and test sets come from the same distribution.
在来自同一分布的开发集和测试集上迭代

147
00:08:59,195 --> 00:09:01,620
So if you're going in to fix something on the dev set,
如果你打算修正开发集上的部分数据

148
00:09:01,620 --> 00:09:03,746
I would apply the same process to the test set 
那么最好也对测试集做同样的修正

149
00:09:03,747 --> 00:09:07,170
to make sure that they continue to come from the same distribution.
以确保它们继续来自相同的分布

150
00:09:07,170 --> 00:09:10,690
So we hire someone to examine the labels more carefully.
所以我们雇佣了一个人来仔细检查这些标签

151
00:09:10,690 --> 00:09:13,125
Do that for both your dev and test sets.
但必须同时检查开发集和测试集

152
00:09:13,125 --> 00:09:16,260
Second, I would urge you to consider examining
其次 我强烈建议你要考虑

153
00:09:16,261 --> 00:09:20,920
examples your algorithm got right as well as ones it got wrong.
同时检验算法判断正确和判断错误的例子

154
00:09:20,920 --> 00:09:24,370
It is easy to look at the examples your algorithm got wrong
要检查算法出错的例子很容易

155
00:09:24,370 --> 00:09:26,875
and just see if any of those need to be fixed.
只需要看看那些例子是否需要修正

156
00:09:26,875 --> 00:09:30,463
But it's possible that there are some examples that you haven't got right,
但还有可能有些例子算法没判断对**

157
00:09:30,463 --> 00:09:32,000
that should also be fixed.
那些也需要修正

158
00:09:32,000 --> 00:09:34,560
And if you only fix ones that your algorithms got wrong,
如果你只修正算法出错的例子

159
00:09:34,560 --> 00:09:38,905
you end up with more bias estimates of the error of your algorithm.
你对算法的偏差估计可能会变大

160
00:09:38,905 --> 00:09:42,450
It gives your algorithm a little bit of an unfair advantage.
这会让你的算法有一点不公平的优势

161
00:09:42,450 --> 00:09:44,784
We just try to double check what it got wrong 
我们就需要再次检查出错的例子

162
00:09:44,844 --> 00:09:48,139
but you don't also double check what it got right
但也需要再次检查做对的例子

163
00:09:48,194 --> 00:09:50,910
because it might have gotten something right,
因为算法有可能因为运气好

164
00:09:50,910 --> 00:09:52,933
that it was just lucky on 
把某个东西判断对了

165
00:09:52,934 --> 00:09:59,160
fixing the label would cause it to go from being right to being wrong, on that example.
在那个特例里 修正那些标签可能会让算法从判断对变成判断错

166
00:09:59,160 --> 00:10:01,995
The second bullet isn't always easy to do,
这第二点不是很容易做

167
00:10:01,995 --> 00:10:03,865
so it's not always done.
所以通常不会这么做

168
00:10:03,865 --> 00:10:08,055
The reason it's not always done is because if you classifier's very accurate,
通常不会这么做的原因是 如果你的分类器很准确

169
00:10:08,055 --> 00:10:11,940
then it's getting fewer things wrong than right.
那么判断错的次数比判断正确的次数要少得多

170
00:10:11,940 --> 00:10:15,120
So if your classifier has 98% accuracy,
所以如果你的分类器有98％的准确度

171
00:10:15,120 --> 00:10:19,660
then it's getting 2% of things wrong and 98% of things right.
那么就有2%出错 98%都是对的

172
00:10:19,660 --> 00:10:25,112
So it's much easier to examine and validate the labels on 2% of the data
所以更容易检查2％数据上的标签

173
00:10:25,113 --> 00:10:30,345
and it takes much longer to validate labels on 98% of the data,
然而检查98％数据上的标签要花的时间长得多

174
00:10:30,345 --> 00:10:31,840
so this isn't always done.
所以通常不这么做

175
00:10:31,840 --> 00:10:34,365
That's just something to consider.
但也是要考虑到的

176
00:10:34,365 --> 00:10:41,275
Finally, if you go into a dev and test data to correct some of the labels there,
最后 如果你进入到一个开发集和测试集去修正这里的部分标签

177
00:10:41,275 --> 00:10:46,410
you may or may not decide to go and apply the same process for the training set.
你可以会 也可能不会去对训练集做同样的事情

178
00:10:46,410 --> 00:10:48,154
Remember we said that at this other video that 
还记得我们在其他视频里讲过

179
00:10:48,199 --> 00:10:51,485
it's actually less important to correct the labels in your training set.
修正训练集中的标签其实相对没那么重要

180
00:10:51,485 --> 00:10:55,978
And it's quite possible you decide to just correct the labels in your dev and test set
你可能决定只修正开发集和测试集中的标签

181
00:10:55,978 --> 00:10:59,242
which are also often smaller than a training set
因为它们通常比训练集小得多

182
00:10:59,243 --> 00:11:02,148
and you might not invest all that extra effort needed
你可能不想把所有额外的精力

183
00:11:02,149 --> 00:11:06,025
to correct the labels in a much larger training set.
投入到修正大得多的训练集中的标签

184
00:11:06,025 --> 00:11:07,365
This is actually okay.
所以这样其实是可以的

185
00:11:07,365 --> 00:11:11,775
We'll talk later this week about some processes
我们将在本周晚些时候讨论一些步骤

186
00:11:11,775 --> 00:11:13,686
for handling when your training data 
用于处理你的训练数据

187
00:11:13,756 --> 00:11:17,435
is different in distribution than you dev and test data.
分布和开发与测试数据不同的情况

188
00:11:17,435 --> 00:11:20,190
Learning algorithms are quite robust to that.
学习算法其实相当健壮

189
00:11:20,190 --> 00:11:25,175
It's super important that your dev and test sets come from the same distribution.
你的开发集和测试集来自同一分布非常重要

190
00:11:25,175 --> 00:11:28,530
But if your training set comes from a slightly different distribution,
但如果你的训练集来自稍微不同的分布

191
00:11:28,530 --> 00:11:31,170
often that's a pretty reasonable thing to do.
通常这是一件很合理的事情

192
00:11:31,170 --> 00:11:34,060
I will talk more about how to handle this later this week.
我会在本周晚些时候谈谈如何处理这个问题

193
00:11:34,060 --> 00:11:37,705
So I'd like to wrap up with just a couple of pieces of advice.
最后我讲几个建议

194
00:11:37,705 --> 00:11:41,265
First, deep learning researchers sometimes like to say things like,
首先 深度学习研究人员有时会喜欢这样说

195
00:11:41,265 --> 00:11:42,920
"I just fed the data to the algorithm.
“我只是把数据提供给算法

196
00:11:42,920 --> 00:11:44,897
I trained in and it worked."
我训练过了 效果拔群“

197
00:11:44,897 --> 00:11:48,035
There is a lot of truth to that in the deep learning error.
这话说出了很多深度学习错误的真相

198
00:11:48,035 --> 00:11:51,172
There is more of feeding data in algorithm and just training it
更多时候 我们把数据喂给算法 然后训练它

199
00:11:51,173 --> 00:11:54,685
and doing less hand engineering and using less human insight.
并减少人工干预 减少使用人类的见解

200
00:11:54,685 --> 00:11:57,780
But I think that in building practical systems,
但我认为 在构造实际系统时

201
00:11:57,780 --> 00:12:01,965
often there's also more manual error analysis and more human insight
通常需要更多的人工错误分析 更多的人类见解

202
00:12:01,965 --> 00:12:07,270
that goes into the systems than sometimes deep learning researchers like to acknowledge.
来架构这些系统 尽管深度学习的研究人员不愿意承认这点

203
00:12:07,270 --> 00:12:11,307
Second is that somehow I've seen some engineers and researchers
第二 不知道为什么 我看一些工程师和研究人员

204
00:12:11,308 --> 00:12:14,415
be reluctant to manually look at the examples.
不愿意亲自去看这些例子

205
00:12:14,415 --> 00:12:16,510
Maybe it's not the most interesting thing to do,
也许做这些事情很无聊

206
00:12:16,510 --> 00:12:19,632
to sit down and look at a 100 or a couple hundred examples
坐下来看100或几百个例子

207
00:12:19,633 --> 00:12:21,465
to counter the number of errors.
来统计错误数量

208
00:12:21,465 --> 00:12:23,865
But this is something that I so do myself.
但我经常亲自这么做

209
00:12:23,865 --> 00:12:25,308
When I'm leading a machine learning team 
当我带领一个机器学习团队时

210
00:12:25,309 --> 00:12:27,240
and I want to understand what mistakes it is making,
我想知道它所犯的错误

211
00:12:27,240 --> 00:12:29,267
I would actually go in and look at the data myself
我会亲自去看看这些数据

212
00:12:29,268 --> 00:12:31,820
and try to counter the fraction of errors.
尝试和一部分错误作斗争

213
00:12:31,820 --> 00:12:34,540
And I think that because these minutes 
我想就因为花了这几分钟

214
00:12:34,604 --> 00:12:36,934
or maybe a small number of hours of counting data
或者几个小时去亲自统计数据

215
00:12:37,003 --> 00:12:40,005
can really help you prioritize where to go next.
真的可以帮你找到需要优先处理的任务

216
00:12:40,005 --> 00:12:41,881
I find this a very good use of your time
我发现花时间亲自检查数据非常值得

217
00:12:41,933 --> 00:12:43,992
and I urge you to consider doing it 
所以我强烈建议你们考虑去做

218
00:12:43,993 --> 00:12:45,918
if those machines are in your system
如果那些机器在你的系统中

219
00:12:45,975 --> 00:12:51,585
and you're trying to decide what ideas or what directions to prioritize things.
然后你想确定应该优先尝试哪些想法 或者哪些方向

220
00:12:51,585 --> 00:12:55,620
So that's it for the error analysis process.
这就是错误分析过程

221
00:12:55,620 --> 00:13:00,060
In the next video, I want to share a view of some thoughts on how error analysis
在下一个视频中 我想分享一下错误分析

222
00:13:00,060 --> 00:13:05,000
fits in to how you might go about starting out on the new machine learning project.
是如何在启动新的机器学习项目中发挥作用的




