1
00:00:00,760 --> 00:00:03,277
Estimating the bias and variance of your learning algorithm
估计学习算法的偏差和方差 

2
00:00:03,326 --> 00:00:06,650
really helps you prioritize what to work on next.
真的可以帮你确定接下来应该优先做的方向

3
00:00:06,650 --> 00:00:11,220
But the way you analyze bias and variance changes when your training set
但是 当你的训练集来自和开发集和测试集不同分布时

4
00:00:11,220 --> 00:00:14,570
comes from a different distribution than your dev and test sets.
分析偏差和方差的方式可能不一样

5
00:00:14,570 --> 00:00:15,140
Let's see how.
我们来看为什么

6
00:00:16,480 --> 00:00:19,650
Let's keep using our cat classification example and
我们继续用猫分类器为例

7
00:00:19,650 --> 00:00:22,880
let's say humans get near perfect performance on this.
我们说人类在这个任务上能做到几乎完美

8
00:00:22,880 --> 00:00:28,620
So, Bayes error, or Bayes optimal error, we know is nearly 0% on this problem.
所以 贝叶斯错误率 或者说贝叶斯最优错误率 我们知道这个问题里几乎是0%

9
00:00:28,620 --> 00:00:33,530
So, to carry out error analysis you usually look at the training error and
所以要进行错误率分析 你通常需要看训练错误

10
00:00:33,530 --> 00:00:37,030
also look at the error on the dev set.
也要看看开发集的错误

11
00:00:37,030 --> 00:00:41,490
So let's say, in this example that your training error is 1%,
比如说 在这个例子中 你的训练集错误是1%

12
00:00:41,490 --> 00:00:45,040
and your dev error is 10%.
你的开发集错误是10%

13
00:00:45,040 --> 00:00:49,725
If your dev data came from the same distribution as your training set,
如果你的开发集来自和训练集一样的分布

14
00:00:49,725 --> 00:00:53,125
you would say that here you have a large variance problem,
你可能会说 这里存在很大的方差问题

15
00:00:53,125 --> 00:00:56,615
that your algorithm's just not generalizing well from the training set
你的算法不能很好的从训练集出发泛化

16
00:00:56,615 --> 00:01:01,795
which it's doing well, on to the dev set, which it's suddenly doing much worse on.
它处理训练集很好 但处理开发集就突然间效果很差了

17
00:01:01,795 --> 00:01:04,669
But in the setting where your training data and your dev data 
但如果你的训练数据和开发数据

18
00:01:04,743 --> 00:01:06,357
comes from a different distribution,
来自不同的分布

19
00:01:06,443 --> 00:01:09,658
you can no longer safely draw this conclusion.
你就不能再放心下这个结论了

20
00:01:09,658 --> 00:01:13,820
In particular, maybe it's doing just fine on the dev set,
特别是 也许算法在开发集上做得不错

21
00:01:13,820 --> 00:01:15,877
it's just that the training set was really easy
可能因为训练集很容易识别 

22
00:01:15,940 --> 00:01:18,250
because it was high res,
因为训练集都是高分辨率图片

23
00:01:18,250 --> 00:01:21,880
very clear images, and maybe the dev set is just much harder.
很清晰的图像 但开发集要难以识别得多

24
00:01:23,492 --> 00:01:27,610
So maybe there isn't a variance problem and this just reflects that
所以也许软件没有方差问题 这只不过反映了

25
00:01:27,610 --> 00:01:32,030
the dev set contains images that are much more difficult to classify accurately.
开发集包含更难准确分类的图片

26
00:01:33,610 --> 00:01:38,220
So the problem with this analysis is that when you went from the training error to
所以这个分析的问题在于 当你看训练错误

27
00:01:38,220 --> 00:01:41,980
the dev error, two things changed at a time.
再看开发错误 有两件事变了

28
00:01:41,980 --> 00:01:47,450
One is that the algorithm saw data in the training set but not in the dev set.
首先算法只见过训练集数据 没见过开发集数据

29
00:01:47,450 --> 00:01:51,080
Two, the distribution of data in the dev set is different.
第二 开发集数据来自不同的分布

30
00:01:51,080 --> 00:01:52,866
And because you changed two things at the same time,
而且因为你同时改变了两件事情

31
00:01:52,928 --> 00:01:56,857
it's difficult to know of this 9% increase in error,
很难确认这增加的9%错误率

32
00:01:56,917 --> 00:02:01,709
how much of it is because the algorithm didn't see the data in the dev set,
有多少是因为算法没看到开发集中的数据导致的

33
00:02:01,710 --> 00:02:04,660
so that's some of the variance part of the problem.
这是问题方差的部分

34
00:02:04,660 --> 00:02:07,670
And how much of it, is because the dev set data is just different.
有多少是因为开发集数据就是不一样

35
00:02:09,300 --> 00:02:13,846
So, in order to tease out these two effects, 
为了弄清楚哪个因素影响更大

36
00:02:13,847 --> 00:02:17,610
and if you didn't totally follow what these two different effects are, don't worry,
如果你完全不懂这两种影响到底是什么 别担心

37
00:02:17,610 --> 00:02:19,490
we will go over it again in a second.
我们马上会再讲一遍

38
00:02:19,490 --> 00:02:21,281
But in order to tease out these two effects 
但为了分辨清楚两个因素的影响

39
00:02:21,339 --> 00:02:24,252
it will be useful to define a new piece of data
定义一组新的数据是有意义的

40
00:02:24,317 --> 00:02:26,970
which we'll call the training-dev set.
我们称之为训练-开发集

41
00:02:26,970 --> 00:02:29,430
So, this is a new subset of data,
所以这是一个新的数据子集

42
00:02:29,430 --> 00:02:33,844
which we carve out that should have the same distribution as training sets,
我们应该从训练集的分布里挖出来

43
00:02:33,845 --> 00:02:37,630
but you don't explicitly train in your network on this.
但你不会用来训练你的网络

44
00:02:37,630 --> 00:02:38,690
So here's what I mean.
我的意思是

45
00:02:40,330 --> 00:02:45,220
Previously we had set up some training sets and
我们已经设立过这样的训练集

46
00:02:45,220 --> 00:02:50,920
some dev sets and some test sets as follows.
开发集和测试集了

47
00:02:50,920 --> 00:02:53,228
And the dev and test sets have the same distribution,
并且开发集和测试集来自相同的分布

48
00:02:53,229 --> 00:02:56,710
but the training sets will have some different distribution.
但训练集来自不同的分布

49
00:02:56,710 --> 00:03:00,290
What we're going to do is randomly shuffle the training sets 
我们要做的是随机打散训练集

50
00:03:00,291 --> 00:03:09,180
and then carve out just a piece of the training set to be the training-dev set.
然后分出一部分训练集作为 训练-开发集

51
00:03:09,180 --> 00:03:12,576
So just as the dev and test set have the same distribution, 
就像开发集和测试集来自同一分布

52
00:03:12,652 --> 00:03:18,750
the training set and the training-dev set, also have the same distribution.
训练集和训练-开发集 也来自同一分布

53
00:03:21,290 --> 00:03:24,940
But, the difference is that now you train your neural network,
但不同的地方是 现在你只在

54
00:03:24,940 --> 00:03:27,920
just on the training set proper.
训练集训练你的神经网络

55
00:03:27,920 --> 00:03:29,330
You won't let the neural network,
你不会让神经网络

56
00:03:29,330 --> 00:03:34,660
you won't run backpropagation on the training-dev portion of this data.
在训练-开发集上跑后向传播

57
00:03:34,660 --> 00:03:36,290
To carry out error analysis,
为了进行错误分析

58
00:03:36,290 --> 00:03:39,996
what you should do is now look at the error of your classifier on the training set,
你应该做的是看看分类器在训练集上的错误

59
00:03:40,050 --> 00:03:43,320
on the training-dev set, as well as on the dev set.
训练-开发集上的错误 还有开发集上的错误

60
00:03:44,500 --> 00:03:51,281
So let's say in this example that your training error is 1%.
比如说这个例子中 训练错误是1%

61
00:03:53,020 --> 00:04:00,695
And let's say the error on the training-dev set is 9%,
我们说训练-开发集上的错误是9%

62
00:04:00,695 --> 00:04:07,910
and the error on the dev set is 10%, same as before.
然后开发集错误是10% 和以前一样

63
00:04:08,910 --> 00:04:10,991
What you can conclude from this is that 
你就可以从这里得到结论

64
00:04:11,047 --> 00:04:15,168
when you went from training data to training dev data
当你从训练数据变到训练-开发集数据时

65
00:04:15,235 --> 00:04:17,680
the error really went up a lot.
错误率真的上升了很多

66
00:04:17,680 --> 00:04:23,068
And only the difference between the training data and the training-dev data
而训练数据和训练-开发数据的差异在于

67
00:04:23,068 --> 00:04:27,280
is that your neural network got to sort the first part of this.
你的神经网络能看到第一部分数据

68
00:04:27,280 --> 00:04:30,216
It was trained explicitly on this, 
并直接在上面做了训练

69
00:04:30,294 --> 00:04:34,840
but it wasn't trained explicitly on the training-dev data.
但没有在训练-开发集上直接训练

70
00:04:34,840 --> 00:04:38,320
So this tells you that you have a variance problem.
这就告诉你 算法存在方差问题

71
00:04:40,006 --> 00:04:41,225
Because the training-dev error 
因为训练-开发集的错误率

72
00:04:41,295 --> 00:04:46,290
was measured on data that comes from the same distribution as your training set.
是在和训练集来自同一分布的数据中测得的

73
00:04:46,290 --> 00:04:50,490
So you know that even though your neural network does well in a training set,
所以你知道 尽管你的神经网络在训练集中表现良好

74
00:04:50,490 --> 00:04:55,254
it's just not generalizing well to data in the training-dev set
但无法泛化到来自相同分布的

75
00:04:55,255 --> 00:04:57,377
which comes from the same distribution, 
训练-开发集里

76
00:04:57,378 --> 00:04:59,454
but it's just not generalizing well to 
它无法很好地泛化推广到

77
00:04:59,479 --> 00:05:02,530
data from the same distribution that it hadn't seen before.
来自同一分布 但以前没见过的数据中

78
00:05:04,020 --> 00:05:07,200
So in this example we have really a variance problem.
所以在这个例子中我们确实有一个方差问题

79
00:05:09,680 --> 00:05:11,510
Let's look at a different example.
我们来看一个不同的例子

80
00:05:11,510 --> 00:05:17,613
Let's say the training error is 1%, and the training-dev error is 1.5%,
假设训练错误为1% 训练-开发错误为1.5%

81
00:05:17,613 --> 00:05:21,360
but when you go to the dev set your error is 10%.
但当你开始处理开发集时 错误率上升到10%

82
00:05:21,360 --> 00:05:25,307
So now, you have actually a pretty low variance problem,
现在你的方差问题就很小了

83
00:05:25,385 --> 00:05:29,798
because when you went from training data that you've seen to the training-dev data
因为当你从见过的训练数据转到训练-开发集数据

84
00:05:29,798 --> 00:05:34,399
that the neural network has not seen, the error increases only a little bit, 
神经网络还没有看到的数据 错误率只上升了一点点

85
00:05:34,400 --> 00:05:37,550
but then it really jumps when you go to the dev set.
但当你转到开发集时 错误率就大大上升了

86
00:05:37,550 --> 00:05:43,100
So this is a data mismatch problem, where data mismatched.
所以这是数据不匹配的问题 数据不匹配

87
00:05:44,810 --> 00:05:51,840
So this is a data mismatch problem,
所以这是一个数据不匹配的问题

88
00:05:51,840 --> 00:05:53,571
because your learning algorithm 
因为你的学习算法 

89
00:05:53,641 --> 00:05:58,061
was not trained explicitly on data from training-dev or dev,
没有直接在训练-开发集或者开发集训练过

90
00:05:58,061 --> 00:06:00,610
but these two data sets come from different distributions.
但是这两个数据集来自不同的分布

91
00:06:00,610 --> 00:06:01,850
But whatever algorithm it's learning,
但不管算法在学习什么

92
00:06:01,850 --> 00:06:06,230
it works great on training-dev but it doesn't work well on dev.
它在训练-开发集上做的很好 但开发集上做的不好

93
00:06:06,230 --> 00:06:10,407
So somehow your algorithm has learned to do well on a different distribution
所以总之你的算法擅长处理和你关心的数据不同的分布

94
00:06:10,407 --> 00:06:14,462
than what you really care about, so we call that a data mismatch problem.
我们称之为数据不匹配的问题

95
00:06:17,505 --> 00:06:20,112
Let's just look at a few more examples.
我们再来看几个例子

96
00:06:20,112 --> 00:06:24,663
I'll write this on the next row since I'm running out of space on top.
我会在下一行里写出来 因上面没空间了

97
00:06:24,663 --> 00:06:31,326
So Training error, Training-Dev error, and Dev error.
所以训练错误 训练-开发错误 还有开发错误

98
00:06:33,618 --> 00:06:36,332
Let's say that training error is 10%,
我们说训练错误是10%

99
00:06:36,376 --> 00:06:42,210
training-dev error is 11%, and dev error is 12%.
训练-开发错误是11% 开发错误为12%

100
00:06:42,210 --> 00:06:50,100
Remember that human level proxy for Bayes error is roughly 0%.
要记住 人类水平对贝叶斯错误率的估计大概是0%

101
00:06:50,100 --> 00:06:56,020
So if you have this type of performance, then you really have a bias,
如果你得到了这种等级的表现 那就真的存在偏差问题了

102
00:06:56,020 --> 00:07:02,920
an avoidable bias problem, because you're doing much worse than human level.
存在可避免偏差问题 因为算法做的比人类水平差很多

103
00:07:02,920 --> 00:07:05,810
So this is really a high bias setting.
所以这里的偏差真的很高

104
00:07:07,440 --> 00:07:08,830
And one last example.
最后一个例子

105
00:07:08,830 --> 00:07:14,211
If your training error is 10%, your training-dev error is 11% 
如果你的训练集错误率是10% 你的训练-开发错误率是11%

106
00:07:14,211 --> 00:07:19,706
and your dev error is 20 %, then it looks like this actually has two issues.
开发错误率是20% 那么这其实有两个问题

107
00:07:19,706 --> 00:07:24,070
One, the avoidable bias is quite high,
第一 可避免偏差相当高

108
00:07:24,070 --> 00:07:26,940
because you're not even doing that well on the training set.
因为你在训练集上都没有做得很好

109
00:07:26,940 --> 00:07:31,860
Humans get nearly 0% error, but you're getting 10% error on your training set.
而人类能做到接近0%错误率 但你的算法在训练集上错误率为10%

110
00:07:31,860 --> 00:07:36,710
The variance here seems quite small,
这里方差似乎很小

111
00:07:38,110 --> 00:07:43,910
but this data mismatch is quite large.
但数据不匹配问题很大

112
00:07:43,910 --> 00:07:48,724
So for for this example I will say, you have a large bias or avoidable bias problem
所以对于这个例子 我说 如果你有很大的偏差 或者可避免偏差问题

113
00:07:48,724 --> 00:07:54,001
as well as a data mismatch problem.
还有数据不匹配问题

114
00:07:56,479 --> 00:07:59,462
So let's take what we've done on this slide and
我们看看这张幻灯片里做了什么

115
00:07:59,462 --> 00:08:01,710
write out the general principles.
然后写出一般的原则

116
00:08:02,810 --> 00:08:05,438
The key quantities I would look at are 
我们要看的关键数据是

117
00:08:06,856 --> 00:08:14,931
human level error, your training set error,
人类水平错误率 你的训练集错误率

118
00:08:14,931 --> 00:08:19,620
your training-dev set error.
训练-开发集错误率

119
00:08:21,630 --> 00:08:23,769
So that's the same distribution as the training set, 
所以这分布和训练集一样

120
00:08:23,770 --> 00:08:25,880
but you didn't train explicitly on it.
但你没有直接在上面训练

121
00:08:25,880 --> 00:08:31,422
Your dev set error, and depending on the differences between these errors,
你的开发集错误率 取决于这些错误率之间差距有多大

122
00:08:31,422 --> 00:08:35,034
you can get a sense of how big is the avoidable bias, the variance,
你可以大概知道 可避免偏差 方差

123
00:08:35,034 --> 00:08:36,940
the data mismatch problems.
数据不匹配问题各自有多大

124
00:08:38,840 --> 00:08:40,880
So let's say that human level error is 4%.
我们说人类水平错误率是4%的话

125
00:08:40,880 --> 00:08:43,573
Your training error is 7%.
你的训练错误率是7%

126
00:08:43,573 --> 00:08:46,660
And your training-dev error is 10%.
而你的训练-开发错误是10%

127
00:08:46,660 --> 00:08:48,984
And the dev error is 12%.
而开发错误是12%

128
00:08:49,035 --> 00:08:54,100
So this gives you a sense of the avoidable bias.
这样你就大概知道可避免偏差有多大

129
00:08:55,170 --> 00:08:58,032
because you know, you'd like your algorithm to do at least as well or
因为你知道 你希望你的算法至少要在

130
00:08:58,032 --> 00:09:01,420
approach human level performance maybe on the training set.
训练集上的表现接近人类

131
00:09:01,420 --> 00:09:04,460
This is a sense of the variance.
而这大概表明了方差大小

132
00:09:04,460 --> 00:09:08,790
So how well do you generalize from the training set to the training-dev set?
所以你从训练集泛化推广到训练-开发集时效果如何?

133
00:09:10,540 --> 00:09:15,550
This is the sense of how much of a data mismatch problem have you have.
而这告诉你数据不匹配的问题大概有多大

134
00:09:15,550 --> 00:09:18,180
And technically you could also add one more thing,
技术上你还可以再加入一个数字

135
00:09:18,180 --> 00:09:21,410
which is the test set performance, and we'll write test error.
就是测试集表现 我们写成测试集错误率

136
00:09:21,410 --> 00:09:23,477
You shouldn't be doing development on your test set 
你不应该在测试集上开发

137
00:09:23,478 --> 00:09:25,625
because you don't want to overfit your test set.
因为你不希望对测试集过拟合

138
00:09:25,625 --> 00:09:26,671
But if you also look at this, 
但如果你看看这个

139
00:09:26,724 --> 00:09:36,212
then this gap here tells you the degree of overfitting to the dev set.
那么这里的差距就说明你对开发集过拟合的程度

140
00:09:38,297 --> 00:09:41,460
So if there's a huge gap between your dev set performance and
所以如果开发集表现

141
00:09:41,460 --> 00:09:45,820
your test set performance, it means you maybe overtuned to the dev set.
和测试集表现有很大差距 那么你可能对开发集过拟合了

142
00:09:45,820 --> 00:09:49,450
And so maybe you need to find a bigger dev set, right?
所以也许你需要一个更大的开发集 对吧

143
00:09:49,450 --> 00:09:53,450
So remember that your dev set and your test set come from the same distribution.
要记住 你的开发集和测试集来自同一分布

144
00:09:53,450 --> 00:09:57,170
So the only way for there to be a huge gap here, for it to do much better on the dev
所以这里存在很大差距的话 如果算法在开发集上做的很好

145
00:09:57,170 --> 00:10:01,304
set than the test set, is if you somehow managed to overfit the dev set.
比测试集好得多 那么你就可能对开发集过拟合了

146
00:10:01,304 --> 00:10:04,486
And if that's the case, what you might consider doing is going back and
如果是这种情况 那么你可能要往回退一步

147
00:10:04,567 --> 00:10:06,650
just getting more dev set data.
然后收集更多开发集数据

148
00:10:06,650 --> 00:10:08,760
Now, I've written these numbers,
现在我写出这些数字

149
00:10:08,760 --> 00:10:13,830
as you go down the list of numbers, always keep going up.
这数字列表越往后 数字越大

150
00:10:13,830 --> 00:10:17,650
Here's one example of numbers that doesn't always go up,
这里还有个例子 其中数字并没有一直变大

151
00:10:17,650 --> 00:10:22,166
maybe human level performance is 4%, training error is 7%,
也许人类的表现是4% 训练错误率是7%

152
00:10:22,166 --> 00:10:26,080
training-dev error is 10%, but let's say that we go to the dev set.
训练-开发错误率是10% 但我们看看开发集

153
00:10:26,080 --> 00:10:30,430
You find that you actually, surprisingly, do much better on the dev set.
你发现 很意外 算法在开发集上做的更好

154
00:10:30,430 --> 00:10:34,052
Maybe this is 6%, 6% as well.
也许是6% 

155
00:10:36,500 --> 00:10:40,833
So you have seen effects like this, working on 
所以如果你见到这种现象

156
00:10:40,834 --> 00:10:43,634
for example a speech recognition task, 
比如说在处理语音识别任务时发现这样

157
00:10:43,635 --> 00:10:45,430
where the training data
其中训练数据

158
00:10:45,430 --> 00:10:48,730
turned out to be much harder than your dev set and test set.
其实比你的开发集和测试集难识别得多

159
00:10:48,730 --> 00:10:53,840
So these two were evaluated on your training set distribution and
所以这两个是从训练集分布评估的

160
00:10:53,840 --> 00:10:57,960
these two were evaluated on your dev/test set distribution.
而这两个是从开发测试集分布评估的

161
00:10:57,960 --> 00:11:00,887
So sometimes if your dev/test set distribution
所以有时候如果你的开发测试集分布

162
00:11:00,956 --> 00:11:04,665
is much easier for whatever application you're working on
比你应用实际处理的数据要容易得多

163
00:11:04,666 --> 00:11:07,062
then these numbers can actually go down.
那么这些错误率可能真的会下降

164
00:11:07,062 --> 00:11:08,768
So if you see funny things like this,
所以如果你看到这样的有趣的事情

165
00:11:08,768 --> 00:11:13,350
there's an even more general formulation of this analysis that might be helpful.
可能需要比这个分析更普适的分析

166
00:11:13,350 --> 00:11:15,129
Let me quickly explain that on the next slide.
我在下一张幻灯片里快速解释一下

167
00:11:17,420 --> 00:11:26,900
So, let me motivate this using the  speech activated rear-view mirror example.
所以 我们就以语音激活后视镜为例子

168
00:11:26,900 --> 00:11:32,229
It turns out that the numbers we've been writing down can be placed into a table
事实证明 我们一直写出的数字可以放到一张表里

169
00:11:32,274 --> 00:11:36,935
where on the horizontal axis, I'm going to place different data sets.
在水平轴上 我要放入不同的数据集

170
00:11:36,935 --> 00:11:42,119
So for example, you might have data from your general speech recognition task.
比如说 你可能从一般语音识别任务里得到很多数据

171
00:11:43,570 --> 00:11:47,090
So you might have a bunch of data that you just 
所以你可能会有一堆数据 

172
00:11:47,147 --> 00:11:51,646
collected from a lot of speech recognition problems you worked on from small speakers,
来自小型智能音箱的语音识别问题的数据

173
00:11:51,646 --> 00:11:53,740
data you have purchased and so on.
你购买的数据等等

174
00:11:53,740 --> 00:12:00,970
And then you all have the rear view mirror specific speech data,
然后你收集了和后视镜有关的语音数据

175
00:12:00,970 --> 00:12:02,120
recorded inside the car.
在车里录的

176
00:12:04,450 --> 00:12:09,890
So on this x axis on the table, I'm going to vary the data set.
所以这是表格的x轴 不同的数据集

177
00:12:09,890 --> 00:12:11,152
On this other axis, 
在另一条轴上

178
00:12:11,216 --> 00:12:18,470
I'm going to label different ways or algorithms for examining the data.
我要标记处理数据不同的方式或算法

179
00:12:18,470 --> 00:12:21,350
So first, there's human level performance,
首先 人类水平

180
00:12:21,350 --> 00:12:25,980
which is how accurate are humans on each of these data sets?
人类处理这些数据集时准确度是多少

181
00:12:27,010 --> 00:12:34,520
Then there is the error on the examples that
然后这是神经网络训练过的数据集上

182
00:12:34,520 --> 00:12:36,210
your neural network has trained on.
达到的错误率

183
00:12:38,870 --> 00:12:45,052
And then finally there's error on the examples that
然后还有神经网络没有训练过的数据集上

184
00:12:45,102 --> 00:12:47,412
your neural network has not trained on.
达到的错误率

185
00:12:50,036 --> 00:12:54,913
So turns out that what we're calling on a human level on the previous slide,
所以结果我们上一张幻灯片说是人类水平的错误率

186
00:12:54,973 --> 00:12:57,199
there's the number that goes in this box,
数字填入这个单元格里

187
00:12:57,277 --> 00:13:03,320
which is how well do humans do on this category of data.
人类对这一类数据处理得有多好

188
00:13:03,320 --> 00:13:05,901
Say data from all sorts of speech recognition tasks,
比如来自各种语音识别系统的数据

189
00:13:05,959 --> 00:13:10,832
the thousand utterances that you could into your training set.
那些进入你的训练集的成千上万的语音片段

190
00:13:10,832 --> 00:13:13,490
And the example in the previous slide is this 4%.
而上一张幻灯片中的例子是4%

191
00:13:13,490 --> 00:13:20,670
This number here was our, maybe the training error.
这个数字 可能是我们的训练错误率

192
00:13:23,320 --> 00:13:26,922
Which in the example in the previous slide was 7%
在上一张幻灯片中的例子中是7%

193
00:13:29,705 --> 00:13:32,510
Right, if you're learning algorithm has seen this example,
是的 如果你的学习算法见过这个样本

194
00:13:32,511 --> 00:13:34,600
performed gradient descent on this example,
在这个样本上跑过梯度下降

195
00:13:34,601 --> 00:13:37,831
and this example came from your training set distribution,
这个样本来自你的训练集分布

196
00:13:37,831 --> 00:13:39,800
or some general speech recognition distribution.
或一般的语音识别数据分布

197
00:13:39,800 --> 00:13:43,980
How well does your algorithm do on the example it has trained on?
你的算法在训练过的数据中表现如何呢?

198
00:13:45,114 --> 00:13:53,122
Then here is the training-dev set error.
然后这就是训练-开发集错误

199
00:13:53,122 --> 00:13:58,040
It's usually a bit higher, which is for data from this distribution,
通常来自这个分布的错误率会高一点

200
00:13:58,040 --> 00:14:02,950
from general speech recognition, if your algorithm did not train explicitly on
一般的语音识别数据 如果你的算法没在

201
00:14:02,950 --> 00:14:05,870
some examples from this distribution, how well does it do?
来自这个分布的样本上训练过 它的表现如何呢?

202
00:14:05,870 --> 00:14:08,520
And that's what we call the training dev error.
这就是我们说的训练-开发集错误

203
00:14:10,700 --> 00:14:12,224
And then if you move over to the right, 
如果你移到右边去

204
00:14:13,059 --> 00:14:17,446
this box here is the dev set error,
这个单元格是开发集错误

205
00:14:17,446 --> 00:14:19,200
or maybe also the test set error.
也可能是测试集错误

206
00:14:22,424 --> 00:14:25,310
Which was 6% in the example just now.
在刚刚的例子中是6%

207
00:14:25,310 --> 00:14:28,260
And dev and test error, it's actually technically two numbers, but
而开发集和测试集 实际上是两个数字

208
00:14:28,260 --> 00:14:30,890
either one could go into this box here.
但都可以放入这个单元格里

209
00:14:32,870 --> 00:14:35,785
And this is if you have data from your rearview mirror, 
如果你有来自后视镜的数据

210
00:14:35,786 --> 00:14:39,692
from actually recorded in the car from the rearview mirror application,
来自从后视镜应用在车里实际录得的数据

211
00:14:39,693 --> 00:14:44,202
but your neural network did not perform back propagation on this example,
但你的神经网络没有在这些数据上做过反向传播

212
00:14:44,203 --> 00:14:45,350
what is the error?
那么错误率是多少呢?

213
00:14:46,940 --> 00:14:50,030
So what we're doing in the analysis in the previous slide was 
我们在上一张幻灯片作的分析是

214
00:14:50,069 --> 00:14:53,069
look at differences between these two numbers,
观察这两个数字之间的差异

215
00:14:53,070 --> 00:14:55,940
these two numbers, and these two numbers.
还有这两个数字之间 这两个数字之间

216
00:14:57,380 --> 00:15:01,880
And this gap here is a measure of avoidable bias.
这个差距衡量了可避免偏差大小

217
00:15:03,630 --> 00:15:07,713
This gap here is a measure of variance, 
这个差距衡量了方差大小

218
00:15:07,714 --> 00:15:12,580
and this gap here was a measure of data mismatch.
而这个差距衡量了数据不匹配问题的大小

219
00:15:13,920 --> 00:15:16,023
And it turns out that it could be useful to 
事实证明 把剩下的两个数字

220
00:15:16,074 --> 00:15:20,010
also throw in the remaining two entries in this table.
也放到这个表格里 也是有用的

221
00:15:21,340 --> 00:15:24,995
And so if this turns out to be also 6%, 
如果结果这也是6%

222
00:15:24,996 --> 00:15:27,067
and the way you get this number is 
那么你获得这个数字的方式是

223
00:15:27,068 --> 00:15:30,178
you ask some humans to label their rearview mirror speech data
你让一些人类自己标记他们的后视镜语音识别数据

224
00:15:30,222 --> 00:15:33,390
and just measure how good humans are at this task.
看看人类在这个任务里能做多好

225
00:15:33,390 --> 00:15:35,471
And maybe this turns out also to be 6%.
也许结果也是6%

226
00:15:35,471 --> 00:15:39,260
And the way you do that is you take some rearview mirror speech data,
做法就是 你收集一些后视镜语音识别数据

227
00:15:39,260 --> 00:15:42,466
put it in the training set so the neural network learns on it as well,
把它放在训练集中 让神经网络去学习

228
00:15:42,467 --> 00:15:46,060
and then you measure the error on that subset of the data.
然后测量那个数据子集上的错误率

229
00:15:46,060 --> 00:15:50,090
But if this is what you get, then, well, it turns out that you're actually already
但如果你得到这样的结果 好吧 那就是说你已经

230
00:15:50,090 --> 00:15:54,495
performing at the level of humans on this rearview mirror speech data, 
在后视镜语音数据上达到人类水平了

231
00:15:54,496 --> 00:15:58,550
so maybe you're actually doing quite well on that distribution of data.
所以也许你对那个数据分布做的已经不错了

232
00:15:58,550 --> 00:16:00,482
When you do this more subsequent analysis, 
当你继续进行更多分析时

233
00:16:00,543 --> 00:16:04,511
it doesn't always give you one clear path forward,
分析并不一定会给你指明一条前进道路

234
00:16:04,555 --> 00:16:07,190
but sometimes it just gives you additional insights as well.
但有时候你可能洞察到一些特征

235
00:16:07,190 --> 00:16:11,085
So for example, comparing these two numbers in this case tells us that 
比如 比较这两个数字

236
00:16:11,130 --> 00:16:15,811
for humans, the rearview mirror speech data is actually harder  than
告诉我们对于人类来说 后视镜的语音数据实际上比

237
00:16:15,812 --> 00:16:21,550
for general speech recognition, because humans get 6% error, rather than 4% error.
一般语音识别更难 因为人类都有6%的错误 而不是4%的错误

238
00:16:21,550 --> 00:16:27,732
But then looking at these differences as well may help you understand bias and variance
但看看这个差值 你就可以了解到偏差和方差

239
00:16:27,733 --> 00:16:30,865
and data mismatch problems in different degrees.
还有数据不匹配这些问题的不同程度

240
00:16:30,865 --> 00:16:35,760
So this more general formulation is something I've used a few times.
所以更一般的分析方法是 我已经用过几次了

241
00:16:35,760 --> 00:16:39,438
I've not used it, but for a lot of problems you find that 
我还没用过 但对于很多问题来说

242
00:16:39,478 --> 00:16:42,393
examining this subset of entries,
检查这个子集的条目

243
00:16:43,510 --> 00:16:47,129
kind of looking at this difference and this difference and this difference,
看看这个差值 这个差值 还有这个差值

244
00:16:47,130 --> 00:16:51,230
that that's enough to point you in a pretty promising direction.
已经足够让你往相对有希望的方向前进了

245
00:16:51,230 --> 00:16:54,840
But sometimes filling out this whole table can give you additional insights.
但有时候填满整个表格 你可能会洞察到更多特征

246
00:16:55,910 --> 00:17:02,535
Finally, we've previously talked a lot about ideas for addressing bias.
最后 我们以前讲过很多处理偏差的手段

247
00:17:02,535 --> 00:17:04,695
Talked about techniques on addressing variance, 
讲过处理方差的手段

248
00:17:04,743 --> 00:17:08,720
but how do you address data mismatch?
但怎么处理数据不匹配呢?

249
00:17:08,720 --> 00:17:12,600
In particular training on data that comes from different distribution
特别是开发集测试集和你的训练集数据

250
00:17:12,600 --> 00:17:15,094
that your dev and test set can get you more data
来自不同分布时 这样可以用更多训练数据

251
00:17:15,154 --> 00:17:17,760
and really help your learning algorithm's performance.
真正帮你提高学习算法性能

252
00:17:17,760 --> 00:17:20,310
But rather than just bias and variance problems,
但是 如果问题不仅来自偏差和方差

253
00:17:20,310 --> 00:17:24,210
you now have this new potential problem of data mismatch.
你现在又有了这个潜在的新问题 数据不匹配

254
00:17:24,210 --> 00:17:28,460
What are some good ways that you could use to address data mismatch?
有什么好办法可以处理数据不匹配的呢?

255
00:17:28,460 --> 00:17:30,563
I'll be honest and say there actually aren't great
实话说 并没有很通用

256
00:17:30,564 --> 00:17:34,130
or at least not very systematic ways to address data mismatch.
或者至少说是系统解决数据不匹配问题的方法

257
00:17:34,130 --> 00:17:36,540
But there are some things you could try that could help.
但你可以做一些尝试 可能会有帮助

258
00:17:36,540 --> 00:17:38,790
Let's take a look at them in the next video.
我们在下一个视频里看看这些尝试

259
00:17:38,790 --> 00:17:43,200
So what we've seen is that by using training data that can come from
所以我们讲了如何使用来自和开发集测试集不同分布的

260
00:17:43,200 --> 00:17:47,690
a different distribution as a dev and test set, this could give you a lot more data
训练数据 可能可以给你提供更多训练数据

261
00:17:47,690 --> 00:17:50,630
and therefore help the performance of your learning algorithm.
因此有助于提高你的学习算法的性能

262
00:17:50,630 --> 00:17:55,070
But instead of just having bias and variance as two potential problems,
但是 潜在问题就不只是偏差和方差问题

263
00:17:55,070 --> 00:17:58,518
you now have this third potential problem, data mismatch.
这样做会引入第三个潜在问题 数据不匹配

264
00:17:58,518 --> 00:18:02,200
So what if you perform error analysis and conclude that data mismatch
如果你做了错误分析 并发现数据不匹配

265
00:18:02,200 --> 00:18:05,840
is a huge source of error, how do you go about addressing that?
是大量错误的来源 那么你怎么解决这个问题呢?

266
00:18:05,840 --> 00:18:07,288
It turns out that unfortunately 
但结果很不幸

267
00:18:07,339 --> 00:18:11,084
there aren't super systematic ways to address data mismatch,
并没有特别系统的方法去解决数据不匹配问题

268
00:18:11,085 --> 00:18:14,120
but there are a few things you can try that could help.
但你可以做一些尝试 可能会有帮助

269
00:18:14,120 --> 00:18:15,820
Let's take a look at them in the next video.
我们来看下一段视频

