1
00:00:00,000 --> 00:00:04,182
If you're working on a brand new machine learning application,
如果你正在开发全新的机器学习应用

2
00:00:04,182 --> 00:00:06,840
one of the piece of advice I often give people is that,
我通常会给你这样的建议

3
00:00:06,840 --> 00:00:11,005
I think you should build your first system quickly and then iterate.
你应该尽快建立你的第一个系统原型 然后快速迭代

4
00:00:11,005 --> 00:00:14,895
Let me show you what I mean. I've worked on speech recognition for many years.
让我告诉你我的意思 我在语音识别领域研究了很多年

5
00:00:14,895 --> 00:00:18,385
And if you're thinking of building a new speech recognition system,
如果你正在考虑建立一个新的语音识别系统

6
00:00:18,385 --> 00:00:20,430
there's actually a lot of directions you could
其实你可以走很多方向

7
00:00:20,430 --> 00:00:22,976
go and a lot of things you could prioritize.
可以优先考虑很多事情

8
00:00:22,976 --> 00:00:25,590
For example, there are specific techniques for making
比如 有一些特定的技术

9
00:00:25,590 --> 00:00:29,235
speech recognition systems more robust to noisy background.
可以让语音识别系统对嘈杂的背景更加健壮

10
00:00:29,235 --> 00:00:32,340
And noisy background could mean cafe noise,
嘈杂的背景可能是说咖啡店的噪音

11
00:00:32,340 --> 00:00:35,430
like a lot of people talking in the background or car noise,
背景里有很多人在聊天 或者车辆的噪音

12
00:00:35,430 --> 00:00:38,930
the sounds of cars and highways or other types of noise.
高速上汽车的噪音 或者其他类型的噪音

13
00:00:38,930 --> 00:00:43,440
There are ways to make a speech recognition system more robust to accented speech.
有一些方法可以让语音识别系统在处理带口音时更健壮

14
00:00:43,440 --> 00:00:48,311
There are specific problems associated with speakers that are far from the microphone,
还有特定的问题和麦克风与说话人距离很远有关

15
00:00:48,311 --> 00:00:50,705
this is called far-field speech recognition.
就是所谓的远场语音识别

16
00:00:50,705 --> 00:00:53,610
Young children speech poses special challenges,
儿童的语音识别带来特殊的挑战

17
00:00:53,610 --> 00:00:56,193
both in terms of how they pronounce individual words 
挑战来自单词发音方面 

18
00:00:56,194 --> 00:00:59,820
as well as their choice of words and the vocabulary they tend to use.
还有他们选择的词汇 他们倾向于使用的词汇

19
00:00:59,820 --> 00:01:07,679
And if sometimes the speaker stutters or if they use nonsensical phrases like oh, ah, um, 
还有比如说 说话人口吃 或者说了很多无意义的短语 比如哦 啊之类的

20
00:01:07,679 --> 00:01:10,565
there are different choices and different techniques
你可以选择很多不同的技术

21
00:01:10,652 --> 00:01:15,310
for making the transcript that you output, still read more fluently.
让你听写下来的文本可读性更强

22
00:01:15,310 --> 00:01:20,338
So, there are these and many other things you could do
所以你可以做很多事情

23
00:01:20,338 --> 00:01:22,710
to improve a speech recognition system.
来改进语音识别系统

24
00:01:22,710 --> 00:01:26,693
And more generally, for almost any machine learning application,
一般来说 对于几乎所有的机器学习程序

25
00:01:26,693 --> 00:01:30,030
there could be 50 different directions you could go in
可能会有50个不同的方向可以前进

26
00:01:30,030 --> 00:01:34,650
and each of these directions is reasonable and would make your system better.
并且每个方向都是相对合理的 可以改善你的系统

27
00:01:34,650 --> 00:01:35,955
But the challenge is,
但挑战在于

28
00:01:35,955 --> 00:01:38,990
how do you pick which of these to focus on.
你如何选择一个方向集中精力处理

29
00:01:38,990 --> 00:01:42,970
And even though I've worked in speech recognition for many years,
即使我已经在语音识别领域工作多年了

30
00:01:42,970 --> 00:01:46,075
if I'm building a new system for a new application domain,
如果我要为一个新应用程序域构建新系统

31
00:01:46,075 --> 00:01:48,730
I would still find it maybe a little bit difficult to
我还是觉得很难不花时间

32
00:01:48,730 --> 00:01:52,625
pick without spending some time thinking about the problem.
去思考这个问题就直接选择方向

33
00:01:52,625 --> 00:01:54,550
So what we recommend you do,
所以我建议你们

34
00:01:54,550 --> 00:01:58,570
if you're starting on building a brand new machine learning application,
如果你想搭建全新的机器学习程序

35
00:01:58,570 --> 00:02:02,277
is to build your first system quickly and then iterate.
就是快速搭好你的第一个系统 然后开始迭代

36
00:02:02,277 --> 00:02:04,720
What I mean by that is I recommend that
我的意思是我建议 

37
00:02:04,720 --> 00:02:08,470
you first quickly set up a dev/test set and metric.
你快速设立开发集和测试集还有指标

38
00:02:08,470 --> 00:02:12,360
So this is really deciding where to place your target.
这样就决定了你的目标所在

39
00:02:12,360 --> 00:02:14,560
And if you get it wrong, you can always move it later,
如果你的目标定错了 之后改也是可以的

40
00:02:14,560 --> 00:02:16,695
but just set up a target somewhere.
但一定要设立某个目标

41
00:02:16,695 --> 00:02:20,920
And then I recommend you build an initial machine learning system quickly.
然后我建议你马上搭好一个机器学习系统原型

42
00:02:20,920 --> 00:02:23,248
Find the training set, train it and see.
然后找到训练集 训练一下 看看效果

43
00:02:23,248 --> 00:02:25,616
Start to see and understand how well you're doing
开始理解你的算法表现如何

44
00:02:25,617 --> 00:02:29,475
against your dev/test set and your evaluation metric.
在开发集测试集 你的评估指标上表现如何

45
00:02:29,475 --> 00:02:32,633
When you build your initial system,
当你建立第一个系统后

46
00:02:32,633 --> 00:02:37,600
you then be able to use bias/variance analysis which we talked about earlier
你就可以马上用到之前说的偏差方差分析

47
00:02:37,601 --> 00:02:42,470
as well as error analysis which we talked about just in the last several videos,
还有之前最后几个视频讨论的错误分析

48
00:02:42,470 --> 00:02:45,260
to prioritize the next steps.
来确定下一步优先做什么

49
00:02:45,260 --> 00:02:49,320
In particular, if error analysis
特别是如果错误分析 

50
00:02:49,320 --> 00:02:52,780
causes you to realize that a lot of the errors are
让你了解到大部分的错误的来源

51
00:02:52,780 --> 00:02:55,675
from the speaker being very far from the microphone,
是说话人远离麦克风

52
00:02:55,675 --> 00:02:58,342
which causes special challenges to speech recognition,
这对语音识别构成特殊挑战

53
00:02:58,342 --> 00:03:03,990
then that will give you a good reason to focus on techniques to address this called
那么你就有很好的理由去集中精力研究这些技术

54
00:03:03,990 --> 00:03:06,250
far-field speech recognition 
所谓远场语音识别的技术

55
00:03:06,251 --> 00:03:10,865
which basically means handling when the speaker is very far from the microphone.
这基本上就出处理说话人离麦克风很远的情况

56
00:03:10,865 --> 00:03:14,693
Of all the value of building this initial system,
建立这个初始系统的所有意义在于

57
00:03:14,693 --> 00:03:16,737
it can be a quick and dirty implementation,
它可以是一个快速和肮脏的实现

58
00:03:16,737 --> 00:03:18,120
you know, don't overthink it,
你知道的 别想太多

59
00:03:18,120 --> 00:03:22,690
but all the value of the initial system is having some learned system,
初始系统的全部意义在于 有一个学习过的系统

60
00:03:22,690 --> 00:03:26,497
having some trained system allows you to localize bias/variance,
有一个训练过的系统 让你确定偏差方差的范围

61
00:03:26,497 --> 00:03:28,255
to try to prioritize what to do next,
就可以知道下一步应该优先做什么

62
00:03:28,255 --> 00:03:30,270
allows you to do error analysis,
让你能够进行错误分析

63
00:03:30,270 --> 00:03:31,480
look at some mistakes,
可以观察一些错误

64
00:03:31,480 --> 00:03:34,630
to figure out all the different directions you can go in,
然后想出所有能走的方向

65
00:03:34,630 --> 00:03:37,822
which ones are actually the most worthwhile.
哪些是实际上最有希望的方向

66
00:03:37,822 --> 00:03:44,125
So to recap, what I recommend you do is build your first system quickly, then iterate.
所以回顾一下 我建议你们快速建立你的第一个系统 然后迭代

67
00:03:44,125 --> 00:03:47,050
This advice applies less strongly if you're working on
不过如果你在这个应用程序领域有很多经验

68
00:03:47,050 --> 00:03:52,300
an application area in which you have significant prior experience.
这个建议适用程度要低一些

69
00:03:52,300 --> 00:03:56,080
It also implies to build less strongly if there's a significant body of
还有一种情况适应程度更低 当这个领域

70
00:03:56,080 --> 00:03:58,480
academic literature that you can draw on
有很多可以借鉴的学术文献

71
00:03:58,480 --> 00:04:01,425
for pretty much the exact same problem you're building.
处理的问题和你要解决的几乎完全相同

72
00:04:01,425 --> 00:04:05,810
So, for example, there's a large academic literature on face recognition.
所以 比如说 人脸识别就有很多学术文献

73
00:04:05,810 --> 00:04:08,185
And if you're trying to build a face recognizer,
如果你尝试搭建一个人脸识别设备

74
00:04:08,185 --> 00:04:11,725
it might be okay to build a more complex system from the get-go
那么可以从现有大量学术文献为基础出发

75
00:04:11,725 --> 00:04:16,595
by building on this large body of academic literature.
一开始就搭建比较复杂的系统

76
00:04:16,595 --> 00:04:19,990
But if you are tackling a new problem for the first time,
但如果你第一次处理某个新问题

77
00:04:19,990 --> 00:04:23,235
then I would encourage you to really not
那我真的不鼓励你 

78
00:04:23,235 --> 00:04:27,010
overthink or not make your first system too complicated.
想太多 或者把第一个系统弄得太复杂

79
00:04:27,010 --> 00:04:30,070
Well, just build something quick and dirty and then use that
我建议你们构建一些快速而肮脏的实现 然后用来

80
00:04:30,070 --> 00:04:33,447
to help you prioritize how to improve your system.
帮你找到改善系统要优先处理的方向

81
00:04:33,447 --> 00:04:36,209
So I've seen a lot of machine learning projects 
我见过很多机器学习项目

82
00:04:36,210 --> 00:04:38,901
and I've seen some teams overthink the solution 
我觉得有些团队的解决方案想太多了

83
00:04:38,901 --> 00:04:40,465
and build something too complicated.
他们造出了过于复杂的系统

84
00:04:40,465 --> 00:04:44,335
I've also seen some teams underthink and then build something maybe too simple.
我也见过有限团队想的不够 然后造出过于简单的系统

85
00:04:44,335 --> 00:04:46,535
Well on average, I've seen a lot more teams
平均来说 我见到更多的团队

86
00:04:46,536 --> 00:04:49,315
overthink and build something too complicated.
想太多 构建太复杂的系统

87
00:04:49,315 --> 00:04:52,275
And I've seen teams build something too simple.
我也见过构建系统太简单的团队

88
00:04:52,275 --> 00:04:53,920
So I hope this helps,
所以我希望这些策略有帮助

89
00:04:53,920 --> 00:04:58,583
and if you are applying to your machine learning algorithms to a new application,
如果你将机器学习算法应用到新的应用程序里

90
00:04:58,583 --> 00:05:01,840
and if your main goal is to build something that works,
你的主要目标是弄出能用的系统

91
00:05:01,840 --> 00:05:04,720
as opposed to if your main goal is to invent
你的主要目标并不是

92
00:05:04,720 --> 00:05:08,020
a new machine learning algorithm which is a different goal,
发明全新的机器学习算法 这是完全不同的目标

93
00:05:08,020 --> 00:05:11,075
then your main goal is to get something that works really well.
那时你的目标应该是想出某种效果非常好的算法

94
00:05:11,075 --> 00:05:13,360
I'd encourage you to build something quick and dirty.
所以我鼓励你们搭建快速而肮脏的实现

95
00:05:13,360 --> 00:05:15,363
Use that to do bias/variance analysis,
然后用它做偏差/方差分析

96
00:05:15,363 --> 00:05:17,890
use that to do error analysis and
用它做错误分析

97
00:05:17,890 --> 00:05:23,510
use the results of those analysis to help you prioritize where to go next.
然后用分析结果确定下一步优先要做的方向

