1
00:00:00,000 --> 00:00:02,880
One of the most exciting recent developments in deep learning,
深度学习中最令人振奋的最新动态之一

2
00:00:02,880 --> 00:00:05,765
has been the rise of end-to-end deep learning.
就是端到端深度学习的兴起

3
00:00:05,765 --> 00:00:07,570
So what is the end-to-end learning?
那么端到端学习到底是什么呢？

4
00:00:07,570 --> 00:00:10,510
Briefly, there have been some data processing systems,
简而言之 以前有一些数据处理系统

5
00:00:10,510 --> 00:00:13,880
or learning systems that require multiple stages of processing.
或者学习系统 它们需要多个阶段的处理

6
00:00:13,880 --> 00:00:15,330
And what end-to-end deep learning does,
那么端到端深度学习

7
00:00:15,330 --> 00:00:17,625
is it can take all those multiple stages,
就是忽略所有这些不同的阶段

8
00:00:17,625 --> 00:00:20,968
and replace it usually with just a single neural network.
用单个神经网络代替它

9
00:00:20,968 --> 00:00:24,170
Let's look at some examples.
我们来看一些例子

10
00:00:24,170 --> 00:00:26,460
Take speech recognition as an example,
以语音识别为例

11
00:00:26,460 --> 00:00:30,975
where your goal is to take an input x such an audio clip,
你的目标是输入x 比如说一段音频

12
00:00:30,975 --> 00:00:33,015
and map it to an output y,
然后把它映射到一个输出y

13
00:00:33,015 --> 00:00:37,230
which is a transcript of the audio clip.
就是这段音频的听写文本

14
00:00:37,230 --> 00:00:41,550
So traditionally, speech recognition required many stages of processing.
所以传统上 语音识别需要很多阶段的处理

15
00:00:41,550 --> 00:00:44,085
First, you will extract some features,
首先你会提取一些特征

16
00:00:44,085 --> 00:00:46,045
some hand-designed features of the audio.
一些手工设计的音频特征

17
00:00:46,045 --> 00:00:48,885
So if you've heard of MFCC,
也许你听过MFCC

18
00:00:48,885 --> 00:00:53,570
that's an algorithm for extracting a certain set of hand designed features for audio.
这种算法是用来从音频中提取一组特定的人工设计的特征

19
00:00:53,570 --> 00:00:55,845
And then having extracted some low level features,
在提取出一些低层次特征之后

20
00:00:55,845 --> 00:00:58,260
you might apply a machine learning algorithm,
你可以应用机器学习算法

21
00:00:58,260 --> 00:01:01,530
to find the phonemes in the audio clip.
在音频片段中找到音位

22
00:01:01,530 --> 00:01:04,390
So phonemes are the basic units of sound.
所以音位是声音的基本单位

23
00:01:04,390 --> 00:01:07,810
So for example, the word cat is made out of three sounds.
比如说 Cat这个词是三个音节构成的

24
00:01:07,810 --> 00:01:10,690
The Cu- Ah- and Tu- so they extract those.
Cu-Ah-和Tu- 算法就把这三个音位提取出来

25
00:01:10,690 --> 00:01:13,630
And then you string together phonemes to form individual words.
然后你将音位串在一起构成独立的词

26
00:01:13,630 --> 00:01:19,356
And then you string those together to form the transcripts of the audio clip.
然后你将词串起来构成音频片段的听写文本

27
00:01:19,356 --> 00:01:23,365
So, in contrast to this pipeline with a lot of stages,
所以和这种有很多阶段的流水线相比

28
00:01:23,365 --> 00:01:24,940
what end-to-end deep learning does,
端到端深度学习做的是

29
00:01:24,940 --> 00:01:28,735
is you can train a huge neural network to just input the audio clip,
你训练一个巨大的神经网络 输入就是一段音频

30
00:01:28,735 --> 00:01:32,670
and have it directly output the transcript.
输出直接是听写文本

31
00:01:32,670 --> 00:01:35,800
One interesting sociological effect in AI is
AI的其中一个有趣的社会学效应是

32
00:01:35,800 --> 00:01:39,085
that as end-to-end deep learning started to work better,
随着端到端深度学习系统表现开始更好

33
00:01:39,085 --> 00:01:41,545
there were some researchers that had for example spent
有一些花了大量时间 或者整个事业生涯

34
00:01:41,545 --> 00:01:44,830
many years of their career designing individual steps of the pipeline.
设计出流水线各个步骤的研究员

35
00:01:44,830 --> 00:01:50,249
So there were some researchers in different disciplines not just in speech recognition.
还有其他领域的研究员 不只是语言识别领域的

36
00:01:50,249 --> 00:01:52,360
Maybe in computer vision, and other areas as well,
也许是计算机视觉 还有其他领域

37
00:01:52,360 --> 00:01:53,945
that had spent a lot of time you know,
他们花了大量的时间

38
00:01:53,945 --> 00:01:57,332
written multiple papers, maybe even built a large part of their career,
写了很多论文 有些甚至整个职业生涯的一大部分都投入到

39
00:01:57,332 --> 00:02:00,270
engineering features or engineering other pieces of the pipeline.
开发这个流水线的功能或者其他构件上去了

40
00:02:00,270 --> 00:02:03,985
And when end-to-end deep learning just took the last training set
而端到端深度学习就只需要把训练集拿过来

41
00:02:03,986 --> 00:02:06,475
and learned the function mapping from x and y directly,
直接学到了x和y之间的函数映射

42
00:02:06,475 --> 00:02:09,720
really bypassing a lot of these intermediate steps,
直接绕过了其中很多步骤

43
00:02:09,720 --> 00:02:13,300
it was challenging for some disciplines to come around to
对一些学科里的人来说 这点相当难以接受

44
00:02:13,300 --> 00:02:17,255
accepting this alternative way of building AI systems.
他们无法接受这样构建AI系统

45
00:02:17,255 --> 00:02:20,110
Because it really obsoleted in some cases,
因为有些情况 端到端方法完全取代了旧系统

46
00:02:20,110 --> 00:02:23,665
many years of research in some of the intermediate components.
某些投入了多年研究的中间件也许已经过时了

47
00:02:23,665 --> 00:02:27,070
It turns out that one of the challenges of end-to-end deep learning is
事实证明 端到端深度学习的挑战之一是

48
00:02:27,070 --> 00:02:30,670
that you might need a lot of data before it works well.
你可能需要大量数据才能让系统表现良好

49
00:02:30,670 --> 00:02:32,755
So for example, if you're training on
比如 你只有3000小时数据

50
00:02:32,756 --> 00:02:35,935
3,000 hours of data to build a speech recognition system,
去训练你的语音识别系统

51
00:02:35,935 --> 00:02:37,600
then the traditional pipeline,
那么传统的流水线

52
00:02:37,600 --> 00:02:40,675
the full traditional pipeline works really well.
传统的流水线效果真的很好

53
00:02:40,675 --> 00:02:42,745
It's only when you have a very large data set,
但当你拥有非常大的数据集时

54
00:02:42,745 --> 00:02:45,290
you know one to say 10,000 hours of data,
比如10000小时数据

55
00:02:45,290 --> 00:02:49,000
anything going up to maybe 100,000 hours of data that
或者100,000小时数据

56
00:02:49,000 --> 00:02:53,350
the end-to end-approach then suddenly starts to work really well.
这样端到端方法突然开始很厉害了

57
00:02:53,350 --> 00:02:55,000
So when you have a smaller data set,
所以当你的数据集较小的时候

58
00:02:55,000 --> 00:02:58,990
the more traditional pipeline approach actually works just as well.
传统流水线方法其实效果也不错

59
00:02:58,990 --> 00:03:00,700
Often works even better.
通常做得更好

60
00:03:00,700 --> 00:03:06,855
And you need a large data set before the end-to-end approach really shines.
你需要大数据集 才能让端到端方法真正发出耀眼光芒

61
00:03:06,855 --> 00:03:08,850
And if you have a medium amount of data,
如果你的数据量适中

62
00:03:08,850 --> 00:03:12,365
then there are also intermediate approaches where maybe you input audio
那么也可以用中间件方法 你可能输入还是音频

63
00:03:12,365 --> 00:03:16,420
and bypass the features and just learn to output the phonemes of the neural network,
然后绕过特征提取 直接尝试从神经网络输出音位

64
00:03:16,420 --> 00:03:17,765
and then at some other stages as well.
然后也可以在其他阶段用

65
00:03:17,765 --> 00:03:19,420
So this will be a step toward end-to-end learning,
所以这是往端到端学习迈出的一小步

66
00:03:19,420 --> 00:03:21,127
but not all the way there.
但还没有到那里

67
00:03:29,925 --> 00:03:34,855
So this is a picture of a face recognition turnstile built by a researcher,
这张图上是一个研究员做的人脸识别门禁

68
00:03:34,855 --> 00:03:36,600
yuanqing Lin at Baidu,
是百度的林元庆研究员做的

69
00:03:36,600 --> 00:03:41,050
where this is a camera and it looks at the person approaching the gate,
这是一个相机 它会拍下接近门禁的人

70
00:03:41,050 --> 00:03:43,135
and if it recognizes the person then,
如果它认出了那个人

71
00:03:43,135 --> 00:03:46,645
you know the turnstile automatically lets them through.
门禁系统就自动打开 让他通过

72
00:03:46,645 --> 00:03:51,170
So rather than needing to swipe an RFID badge to enter this facility,
所以你不需要刷一个RFID工卡就能进入这个设施

73
00:03:51,170 --> 00:03:53,691
in increasingly many offices in China
系统部署在越来越多的中国办公室

74
00:03:53,692 --> 00:03:56,270
and hopefully more and more in other countries as well,
希望在其他国家也可以部署更多

75
00:03:56,270 --> 00:03:59,234
you can just approach the turnstile and if it recognizes your face
你可以接近门禁 如果它认出你的脸

76
00:03:59,294 --> 00:04:04,155
it just lets you through without needing you to carry an RFID badge.
它就直接让你通过 你不需要带RFID工卡

77
00:04:04,155 --> 00:04:07,385
So, how do you build a system like this?
那么 怎么搭建这样的系统呢?

78
00:04:07,385 --> 00:04:12,590
Well, one thing you could do is just look at the image that the camera is capturing.
你可以做的第一件事是 看看相机拍到的照片

79
00:04:12,590 --> 00:04:14,645
Right? So, I guess this is my bad drawing,
对吧? 我想我画的不太好

80
00:04:14,645 --> 00:04:16,190
but maybe this is a camera image.
但也许这是相机照片

81
00:04:16,190 --> 00:04:19,390
And you know, you have someone approaching the turnstile.
你知道 有人接近门禁了

82
00:04:19,390 --> 00:04:23,810
So this might be the image x that you that your camera is capturing.
所以这可能是相机拍到的图像x

83
00:04:23,810 --> 00:04:26,950
And one thing you could do is try to learn a function mapping
有件事你可以做 就是尝试直接学习

84
00:04:26,950 --> 00:04:31,470
directly from the image x to the identity of the person y.
图像x到人物y身份的函数映射

85
00:04:31,470 --> 00:04:34,580
It turns out this is not the best approach.
事实证明这不是最好的方法

86
00:04:34,580 --> 00:04:36,395
And one of the problems is that you know,
其中一个问题是

87
00:04:36,395 --> 00:04:39,835
the person approaching the turnstile can approach from lots of different directions.
人可以从很多不同的角度接近门禁

88
00:04:39,835 --> 00:04:41,945
So they could be green positions,
他们可能在绿色位置

89
00:04:41,945 --> 00:04:43,195
they could be in blue position.
可能在蓝色位置

90
00:04:43,195 --> 00:04:45,245
you know, sometimes they're closer to the camera,
有时他们更靠近相机

91
00:04:45,245 --> 00:04:47,020
so they appear bigger in the image.
所以他们看起来更大

92
00:04:47,020 --> 00:04:49,225
And sometimes they're already closer to the camera,
有时候他们非常接近相机

93
00:04:49,225 --> 00:04:51,600
so that face appears much bigger.
那照片中脸就很大了

94
00:04:51,600 --> 00:04:54,205
So what it has actually done to build these turnstiles,
在实际研制这些门禁系统时

95
00:04:54,205 --> 00:04:56,350
is not to just take the raw image and
他不是直接将原始照片

96
00:04:56,350 --> 00:04:59,315
feed it to a neural net to try to figure out a person's identity.
喂到一个神经网络 试图找出一个人的身份

97
00:04:59,315 --> 00:05:02,005
Instead, the best approach to date,
相反 迄今为止最好的方法

98
00:05:02,005 --> 00:05:05,140
seems to be a multi-step approach, where first,
似乎是一个多步方法 首先

99
00:05:05,140 --> 00:05:09,210
you run one piece of software to detect the person's face.
你运行一个软件来检测人脸

100
00:05:09,210 --> 00:05:12,820
So this first detector to figure out where's the person's face.
所以第一个检测器找的是人脸位置

101
00:05:12,820 --> 00:05:14,785
Having detected the person's face,
检测到人脸

102
00:05:14,785 --> 00:05:17,193
you then zoom in to that part of the image
然后放大图像的那部分

103
00:05:22,618 --> 00:05:29,340
and crop that image so that the person's face is centered.
并裁剪图像 使人脸居中显示

104
00:05:30,673 --> 00:05:34,757
Then, it is this picture that I guess I drew here in red,
然后就是这里红线框起来的照片

105
00:05:34,757 --> 00:05:36,583
this is then fed to the neural network,
再喂到神经网络里

106
00:05:36,583 --> 00:05:38,010
to then try to learn,
让网络去学习

107
00:05:38,010 --> 00:05:40,485
or estimate the person's identity.
或估计那人的身份

108
00:05:40,485 --> 00:05:42,150
And what researchers have found,
研究人员发现

109
00:05:42,150 --> 00:05:45,615
is that instead of trying to learn everything on one step,
比起一步到位 一步学习

110
00:05:45,615 --> 00:05:48,780
by breaking this problem down into two simpler steps,
把这个问题分解成两个更简单的步骤

111
00:05:48,780 --> 00:05:51,490
first is figure out where is the face.
首先是弄清楚脸在哪里

112
00:05:51,490 --> 00:05:54,890
And second, is look at the face and figure out who this actually is.
第二步是看着脸 弄清楚这是谁

113
00:05:54,890 --> 00:05:58,010
This second approach allows the learning algorithm or really two learning algorithms
这第二种方法让学习算法 或者说两个学习算法

114
00:05:58,010 --> 00:06:03,560
to solve two much simpler tasks and results in overall better performance.
分别解决两个更简单的任务 并在整体上得到更好的表现

115
00:06:04,316 --> 00:06:05,930
By the way, if you want to know how
顺便说一句 如果你想知道

116
00:06:05,930 --> 00:06:08,975
the second step actually works I've simplified the discussion.
第二步实际是怎么工作的 我这里其实省略了很多

117
00:06:08,975 --> 00:06:11,865
By the way, if you want to know how step two here actually works,
顺便说一下 如果你想知道第二步实际怎么工作的

118
00:06:11,865 --> 00:06:13,605
I've actually simplified the description a bit.
我其实省略了很多细节

119
00:06:13,605 --> 00:06:15,470
The way the second step is actually trained,
训练第二步的方式

120
00:06:15,470 --> 00:06:16,730
as you train in your network,
训练网络的方式

121
00:06:16,730 --> 00:06:18,920
that takes as input two images,
就是输入两张图片

122
00:06:18,920 --> 00:06:22,230
and what then your network does is it takes
然后你的网络做的就是

123
00:06:22,230 --> 00:06:29,553
this input two images and it tells you if these two are the same person or not.
将输入的两张图比较一下 判断是否是同一个人

124
00:06:30,217 --> 00:06:34,700
So if you then have say 10,000 employees IDs on file,
比如你记录了10000个员工ID

125
00:06:34,700 --> 00:06:36,430
you can then take this image in red,
你可以把红色框起来的图像

126
00:06:36,430 --> 00:06:38,545
and quickly compare it against maybe all
快速比较..也许是

127
00:06:38,545 --> 00:06:41,795
10,000 employee IDs on file to try to figure out if
全部10,000个员工记录在案的ID 看看

128
00:06:41,795 --> 00:06:44,810
this picture in red is indeed one of your 10000 employees that you
这张红线内的照片 是不是那10000个员工之一

129
00:06:44,810 --> 00:06:48,640
should allow into this facility or that should allow into your office building.
应该允许进入这个设施 或者进入这个办公楼

130
00:06:48,640 --> 00:06:52,436
This is a turnstile that is giving employees access to a workplace.
这是一个门禁系统 允许员工进入工作场所的门禁

131
00:06:53,168 --> 00:06:55,970
So why is it that the two step approach works better?
为什么两步法更好呢?

132
00:06:55,970 --> 00:06:58,605
There are actually two reasons for that.
实际上有两个原因

133
00:06:58,605 --> 00:07:02,020
One is that each of the two problems you're solving is actually much simpler.
一是你解决的两个问题 每个问题实际上要简单得多

134
00:07:02,020 --> 00:07:10,360
But second, is that you have a lot of data for each of the two sub-tasks.
但第二 两个子任务的训练数据都很多

135
00:07:11,613 --> 00:07:16,950
In particular, there is a lot of data you can obtain for face detection,
具体来说 有很多数据可以用于人脸识别训练

136
00:07:16,950 --> 00:07:18,720
for task one over here,
对于这里的任务1来说

137
00:07:18,720 --> 00:07:21,050
where the task is to look at an image and figure out
任务就是观察一张图 找出人脸所在的位置

138
00:07:21,051 --> 00:07:23,415
where is the person's face and the image.
把人脸图像框出来

139
00:07:23,415 --> 00:07:25,695
So there is a lot of data.
所以有很多数据

140
00:07:25,695 --> 00:07:27,965
There is a lot of label data x, comma y
有很多标签数据x,y

141
00:07:27,966 --> 00:07:31,420
where x is a picture and y shows the position of the person's face.
其中x是图片 y是表示人脸的位置

142
00:07:31,420 --> 00:07:35,100
So you could build a neural network to do task one quite well.
你可以建立一个神经网络 可以很好地处理任务1

143
00:07:35,100 --> 00:07:37,854
And then separately, there's a lot of data for task two as well.
然后任务2 也有很多数据可用

144
00:07:39,011 --> 00:07:41,710
Today, leading companies have let's say,
今天 业界领先的公司拥有 比如说

145
00:07:41,710 --> 00:07:44,525
hundreds of millions of pictures of people's faces.
数百万张人脸照片

146
00:07:44,525 --> 00:07:46,845
So given a closely cropped image,
所以输入一张裁剪得很紧凑的照片

147
00:07:46,845 --> 00:07:49,275
like this red image or this one down here,
比如这张红色照片 下面这个

148
00:07:49,275 --> 00:07:51,555
today leading face recognition teams have
今天业界领先的人脸识别团队有

149
00:07:51,555 --> 00:07:53,466
at least hundreds of millions of images
至少数亿的图像

150
00:07:53,518 --> 00:07:55,449
that they could use to look at two images
他们可以用来观察两张图片

151
00:07:55,516 --> 00:07:56,852
and try to figure out the identity
并试图判断照片里人的身份

152
00:07:56,908 --> 00:07:58,765
or to figure out if it's the same person or not.
确定是否同一个人

153
00:07:58,765 --> 00:08:02,310
So there's also a lot of data for task two.
所以任务2还有很多数据

154
00:08:02,310 --> 00:08:07,155
But in contrast, if you were to try to learn everything at the same time,
相比之下 如果你想一步到位

155
00:08:07,155 --> 00:08:10,680
there is much less data of the form x comma y.
这样x,y的数据对就少得多

156
00:08:10,680 --> 00:08:13,175
Where x is image like this taken from the turnstile,
其中x是门禁系统拍摄的图像

157
00:08:13,175 --> 00:08:16,390
and y is the identity of the person.
y是那人的身份

158
00:08:16,390 --> 00:08:21,610
So because you don't have enough data to solve this end-to-end learning problem,
因为你没有足够多的数据去解决这个端到端学习问题

159
00:08:21,610 --> 00:08:27,410
but you do have enough data to solve sub-problems one and two, in practice,
但你却有足够多的数据来解决子问题1和子问题2 实际上

160
00:08:27,410 --> 00:08:29,740
breaking this down to two sub-problems results in
把这个分成两个子问题

161
00:08:29,740 --> 00:08:34,260
better performance than a pure end-to-end deep learning approach.
比纯粹的端到端深度学习方法 那达到更好的表现

162
00:08:34,987 --> 00:08:37,575
Although if you had enough data for the end-to-end approach,
不过如果你有足够多的数据来做端到端学习

163
00:08:37,575 --> 00:08:40,470
maybe the end-to-end approach would work better,
也许端到端方法效果更好

164
00:08:40,470 --> 00:08:44,240
but that's not actually what works best in practice today.
但在今天的实践中 并不是最好的方法

165
00:08:44,240 --> 00:08:46,886
Let's look at a few more examples.
我们再来看几个例子

166
00:08:46,886 --> 00:08:49,000
Take machine translation.
比如机器翻译

167
00:08:49,000 --> 00:08:54,390
Traditionally, machine translation systems also had a long complicated pipeline,
传统上 机器翻译系统也有一个很复杂的流水线

168
00:08:54,390 --> 00:08:56,230
where you first take say English,
比如英语机翻

169
00:08:56,230 --> 00:08:58,955
text and then do text analysis.
得到文本 然后做文本分析

170
00:08:58,955 --> 00:09:01,990
Basically, extract a bunch of features off the text, and so on.
基本上 要从文本中提取一些特征 之类的

171
00:09:01,990 --> 00:09:04,630
And after many many steps you'd end up with say,
经过很多步骤 你最后会..

172
00:09:04,630 --> 00:09:07,900
a translation of the English text into French.
将英文文本翻译成法文

173
00:09:07,900 --> 00:09:10,030
Because, for machine translation,
因为 对于机器翻译来说

174
00:09:10,030 --> 00:09:13,990
you do have a lot of pairs of English comma French sentences.
的确有很多(英文,法文)的数据对

175
00:09:13,990 --> 00:09:17,640
End-to-end deep learning works quite well for machine translation.
端到端深度学习在机器翻译领域非常好用

176
00:09:17,640 --> 00:09:20,140
And that's because today,
那是因为在今天

177
00:09:20,140 --> 00:09:24,350
it is possible to gather large data sets of x-y pairs where that's
可以收集x-y对的大数据集

178
00:09:24,350 --> 00:09:28,780
the English sentence and that's the corresponding French translation.
就是英文句子和对应的法语翻译

179
00:09:28,780 --> 00:09:29,955
So in this example,
所以在这个例子中

180
00:09:29,955 --> 00:09:32,320
end-to-end deep learning works well.
端到端深度学习效果很好

181
00:09:32,320 --> 00:09:35,200
One last example, let's say that you
最后一个例子 比如说你希望

182
00:09:35,200 --> 00:09:38,220
want to look at an x-ray picture of a hand of a child,
观察一个孩子手部的x光照片

183
00:09:38,220 --> 00:09:40,215
and estimate the age of a child.
并估计一个孩子的年龄

184
00:09:40,215 --> 00:09:41,830
you know, when I first heard about this problem,
你知道 当我第一次听到这个问题的时候

185
00:09:41,830 --> 00:09:45,460
I thought this is a very cool crime scene investigation task
我以为这是一个非常酷的犯罪现场调查任务

186
00:09:45,460 --> 00:09:48,610
where you find maybe tragically the skeleton of a child,
你可能悲剧的发现了一个孩子的骨架

187
00:09:48,610 --> 00:09:50,980
and you want to figure out how the child was.
你想弄清楚孩子在生时是怎么样的

188
00:09:50,980 --> 00:09:54,445
It turns out that typical application of this problem,
事实证明 这个问题的典型应用

189
00:09:54,445 --> 00:09:57,010
estimating age of a child from an x-ray is
从x射线图估计孩子的年龄

190
00:09:57,010 --> 00:09:59,995
less dramatic than this crime scene investigation I was picturing.
是我想太多了 没有我想象的犯罪现场调查脑洞那么大

191
00:09:59,995 --> 00:10:02,890
It turns out that pediatricians use
结果这是儿科医生用来

192
00:10:02,890 --> 00:10:06,925
this to estimate whether or not a child is growing or developing normally.
判断一个孩子的发育是否正常

193
00:10:06,925 --> 00:10:09,460
But a non end-to-end approach to this,
处理这个例子的一个非端到端方法

194
00:10:09,460 --> 00:10:14,045
would be you locate an image and then you segment out or recognize the bones.
就是照一张图 然后分割出每一块骨头

195
00:10:14,045 --> 00:10:16,730
So, just try to figure out where is that bone segment?
所以就是分辨出那段骨头应该在哪里

196
00:10:16,730 --> 00:10:17,849
Where is that bone segment?
那段骨头在哪里

197
00:10:17,849 --> 00:10:20,290
Where is that bone segment? And so on. And then.
那段骨头在哪里? 等等 然后

198
00:10:20,290 --> 00:10:22,285
Knowing the lengths of the different bones,
知道不同骨骼的长度

199
00:10:22,285 --> 00:10:24,396
you can sort of go to a look up table
你可以去查表

200
00:10:24,397 --> 00:10:26,933
showing the average bone lengths in a child's hand
查到儿童手中骨头的平均长度

201
00:10:27,013 --> 00:10:30,615
and then use that to estimate the child's age.
然后用它来估计孩子的年龄

202
00:10:30,615 --> 00:10:32,800
And so this approach actually works pretty well.
所以这种方法实际上很好

203
00:10:32,800 --> 00:10:37,960
In contrast, if you were to go straight from the image to the child's age,
相比之下 如果你直接从图像去判断孩子的年龄

204
00:10:37,960 --> 00:10:43,030
then you would need a lot of data to do that directly and as far as I know,
那么你需要大量的数据去直接训练 据我所知

205
00:10:43,030 --> 00:10:45,543
this approach does not work as well today
这种做法今天还是不行的

206
00:10:45,544 --> 00:10:50,515
just because there isn't enough data to train this task in an end-to-end fashion.
因为没有足够的数据来用端到端的方式来训练这个任务

207
00:10:50,515 --> 00:10:56,326
Whereas in contrast, you can imagine that by breaking down this problem into two steps.
相比之下 你可以想象一下如何将这个问题分解成两个步骤

208
00:10:56,326 --> 00:10:58,780
Step one is a relatively simple problem.
第一步是一个比较简单的问题

209
00:10:58,780 --> 00:11:00,345
Maybe you don't need that much data.
也许你不需要那么多数据

210
00:11:00,345 --> 00:11:03,455
Maybe you don't need that many x-ray images to segment out the bones.
也许你不需要许多x射线图像来切分骨骼

211
00:11:03,455 --> 00:11:08,225
And task two, by collecting statistics of a number of children's hands,
而任务二 收集儿童手部的骨头长度的统计数据

212
00:11:08,225 --> 00:11:11,280
you can also get decent estimates of that without too much data.
你不需要太多数据也能做出相当准确的估计

213
00:11:11,280 --> 00:11:14,125
So this multi-step approach seems promising.
所以这个多步方法看起来很有希望

214
00:11:14,125 --> 00:11:16,420
Maybe more promising than the end-to-end approach,
也许比端对端方法更有希望

215
00:11:16,420 --> 00:11:20,635
at least until you can get more data for the end-to-end learning approach.
至少直到你能获得更多端到端学习的数据之前

216
00:11:20,635 --> 00:11:22,840
So an end-to-end deep learning works.
所以端到端深度学习系统是可行的

217
00:11:22,840 --> 00:11:26,263
It can work really well and it can really simplify the system
它表现可以很好 也可以简化系统架构

218
00:11:26,264 --> 00:11:30,875
and not require you to build so many hand-designed individual components.
让你不需要搭建那么多手工设计的单独组件

219
00:11:30,875 --> 00:11:32,773
But it's also not panacea,
但它也不是灵丹妙药

220
00:11:32,773 --> 00:11:34,315
it doesn't always work.
并不是每次都能成功

221
00:11:34,315 --> 00:11:35,650
In the next video,
在下一个视频中

222
00:11:35,650 --> 00:11:39,530
I want to share with you a more systematic description of when you should,
我想与你分享一个更系统的描述 什么时候你应该使用

223
00:11:39,530 --> 00:11:42,415
and maybe when you shouldn't use end-to-end deep learning
或者不应该使用端到端的深度学习

224
00:11:42,416 --> 00:11:47,000
and how to piece together these complex machine learning systems.
以及如何组装这些复杂的机器学习系统

