1
00:00:00,560 --> 00:00:04,440
Deep learning algorithms have a huge hunger for training data.
深度学习算法对训练数据的胃口很大

2
00:00:04,440 --> 00:00:06,970
They just often work best when you can find enough
当你收集到足够多带标签的数据

3
00:00:06,970 --> 00:00:10,294
label training data to put into the training set.
构成训练集时 算法效果最好

4
00:00:10,294 --> 00:00:14,154
This has resulted in many teams sometimes taking whatever data you can find and
这导致很多团队用尽一切办法收集数据

5
00:00:14,154 --> 00:00:18,120
just shoving it into the training set just to get it more training data.
然后把它们堆到训练集里 让训练的数据量更大

6
00:00:18,120 --> 00:00:21,720
Even if some of this data, or even maybe a lot of this data,
即使有些数据 甚至是大部分数据

7
00:00:21,720 --> 00:00:25,870
doesn't come from the same distribution as your dev and test data.
都来自和开发集 测试集不同分布

8
00:00:25,870 --> 00:00:30,330
So in a deep learning era, more and more teams are now training on data
在深度学习时代 越来越多的团队

9
00:00:30,330 --> 00:00:34,325
that comes from a different distribution than your dev and test sets.
都用来自和开发集和测试集分布不同的数据来训练

10
00:00:34,325 --> 00:00:37,385
And there's some subtleties and some best practices for
这里有一些微妙的地方 一些最佳做法

11
00:00:37,385 --> 00:00:41,825
dealing with when your train and test distributions differ from each other.
来处理训练集和测试集存在差异的情况

12
00:00:41,825 --> 00:00:43,315
Let's take a look.
我们来看看

13
00:00:43,315 --> 00:00:48,630
Let's say that you're building a mobile app where users will upload
假设你在开发一个手机应用 用户会上传

14
00:00:48,630 --> 00:00:51,970
pictures taken from their cell phones, and you want to recognize whether the pictures
他们用手机拍摄的照片 你想识别

15
00:00:51,970 --> 00:00:56,470
that your users upload from the mobile app is a cat or not.
用户从应用中上传的图片是不是猫

16
00:00:56,470 --> 00:00:59,580
So you can now get two sources of data.
现在你有两个数据来源

17
00:00:59,580 --> 00:01:03,940
One which is the distribution of data you really care about, this data from a mobile app
一个是你真正关心的数据分布 来自应用上传的数据

18
00:01:03,940 --> 00:01:07,940
like app on the right, which tends to be less professionally shot,
比如右边的应用 这些照片一般更业余

19
00:01:07,940 --> 00:01:12,800
less well framed, maybe even blurrier because it's shot by amateur users.
取景不太好 有些甚至很模糊 因为它们都是业余用户拍的

20
00:01:12,800 --> 00:01:16,760
The other source of data you can get is you can crawl the web and just download
另一个数据来源就是你可以用爬虫程序挖掘网页 直接下载

21
00:01:16,760 --> 00:01:21,635
a lot of, for the sake of this example, let's say you can download a lot of very
就这个例子而言 可以下载很多

22
00:01:21,635 --> 00:01:27,250
professionally framed, high resolution, professionally taken images of cats.
取景专业 高分辨率 拍摄专业的猫图片

23
00:01:27,250 --> 00:01:29,950
And let's say you don't have a lot of users yet for your mobile app.
如果你的应用用户数还不多

24
00:01:29,950 --> 00:01:35,632
So maybe you've gotten 10,000 pictures uploaded from the mobile app.
也许你只收集到10,000张用户上传的照片

25
00:01:35,632 --> 00:01:40,320
But by crawling the web you can download huge numbers of cat pictures, and
但通过爬虫挖掘网页 你可以下载到海量猫图

26
00:01:40,320 --> 00:01:45,322
maybe you have 200,000 pictures of cats downloaded off the Internet.
也许你从互联网上下载了超过20万张猫图

27
00:01:48,079 --> 00:01:51,012
So what you really care about is that your final system 
而你真正关心的算法表现是 你的最终系统

28
00:01:51,066 --> 00:01:58,311
does well on the mobile app distribution of images, right?
处理来自应用程序的这个图片分布时 效果好不好

29
00:01:58,311 --> 00:01:59,182
Because in the end, 
因为最后

30
00:01:59,241 --> 00:02:02,003
your users will be uploading pictures like those on the right
你的用户会上传类似右边这些图片

31
00:02:02,004 --> 00:02:04,230
and you need your classifier to do well on that.
你的分类器必须在这个任务中表现良好

32
00:02:04,230 --> 00:02:06,817
But you now have a bit of a dilemma 
现在你就陷入困境了

33
00:02:06,866 --> 00:02:08,942
because you have a relatively small dataset,
因为你有一个相对小的数据集

34
00:02:09,001 --> 00:02:12,970
just 10,000 examples drawn from that distribution.
只有10,000个样本来自那个分布

35
00:02:12,970 --> 00:02:16,754
And you have a much bigger dataset that's drawn from a different distribution.
而你还有一个大得多的数据集 来自另一个分布

36
00:02:16,754 --> 00:02:19,986
There's a different appearance of image than the one you actually want.
图片的外观和你真正想要处理的并不一样

37
00:02:19,986 --> 00:02:24,505
So you don't want to use just those 10,000 images because it ends up
但你又不想直接用这10,000张图片 因为这样

38
00:02:24,505 --> 00:02:27,330
giving you a relatively small training set.
你的训练集就太小了

39
00:02:28,466 --> 00:02:31,724
And using those 200,000 images seems helpful, but
使用这20万张图片似乎有帮助 但是

40
00:02:31,724 --> 00:02:37,550
the dilemma is this 200,000 images isn't from exactly the distribution you want.
困境在于 这20万张图片并不完全来自你想要的分布

41
00:02:37,550 --> 00:02:38,471
So what can you do?
那么你可以怎么做呢?

42
00:02:39,824 --> 00:02:42,221
Well, here's one option.
这里有一种选择

43
00:02:43,340 --> 00:02:47,669
One thing you can do is put both of these data sets together so
你可以做的一件事是 将两组数据合并在一起

44
00:02:47,669 --> 00:02:50,910
you now have 210,000 images.
这样你就有21万张照片

45
00:02:50,910 --> 00:02:54,039
And you can then take the 210,000 images 
你可以把这21万张照片

46
00:02:54,040 --> 00:03:03,470
and randomly shuffle them into a train, dev, and test set.
 随机分配到训练 开发和测试集中

47
00:03:03,470 --> 00:03:05,095
And let's say for the sake of argument that 
为了说明观点 我们假设

48
00:03:05,143 --> 00:03:11,380
you've decided that your dev and test sets will be 2,500 examples each.
你已经确定开发集和测试集各包含2500个样本

49
00:03:11,380 --> 00:03:16,360
So your training set will be 205,000 examples.
所以你的训练集有205000个样本

50
00:03:17,450 --> 00:03:23,520
Now so set up your data this way has some advantages but also disadvantages.
现在这么设立你的数据集有一些好处 也有坏处

51
00:03:23,520 --> 00:03:26,910
The advantage is that now you're training, dev and test sets will all come
好处在于 你的训练集 开发集和测试集

52
00:03:26,910 --> 00:03:30,400
from the same distribution, so that makes it easier to manage.
都来自同一分布 这样更好管理

53
00:03:30,400 --> 00:03:33,470
But the disadvantage, and this is a huge disadvantage,
但坏处在于 这坏处还不小

54
00:03:33,470 --> 00:03:38,010
is that if you look at your dev set, of these 2,500 examples,
就是如果你观察开发集 看看这2500个样本

55
00:03:38,010 --> 00:03:42,680
a lot of it will come from the web page distribution of images,
其中很多图片都来自网页下载的图片

56
00:03:42,681 --> 00:03:44,392
rather than what you actually care about, 
那并不是你真正关心的数据分布

57
00:03:44,434 --> 00:03:46,660
which is the mobile app distribution of images.
你真正要处理的是来自手机的图片

58
00:03:48,520 --> 00:03:53,150
So it turns out that of your total amount of data, 200,000, so
所以结果你的数据总量 这200,000个样本

59
00:03:53,150 --> 00:03:57,309
I'll just abbreviate that 200k, out of 210,000,
我就用200k缩写表示 除以210,000

60
00:03:57,309 --> 00:04:01,169
we'll write that as 210k, that comes from web pages.
我把它写成210k 那些是来自网页下载的

61
00:04:01,169 --> 00:04:06,951
So all of these 2,500 examples on expectation,
所以对于这2500个样本 数学期望值是

62
00:04:06,951 --> 00:04:13,430
I think 2,381 of them will come from web pages.
有2381张图 来自网页下载

63
00:04:13,430 --> 00:04:17,580
This is on expectation, the exact number will vary around depending on
这是期望值 确切数目会变化

64
00:04:17,580 --> 00:04:20,290
how the random shuttle operation went.
取决于具体的随机分配操作

65
00:04:20,290 --> 00:04:25,931
But on average, only 119 will come from mobile app uploads.
但平均而言 只有119张图来自手机上传

66
00:04:27,600 --> 00:04:30,973
So remember that setting up your dev set is 
要记住 设立开发集的目的是

67
00:04:31,019 --> 00:04:33,800
telling your team where to aim the target.
告诉你的团队去瞄准的目标

68
00:04:33,800 --> 00:04:35,150
And the way you're aiming your target,
而你瞄准目标的方式

69
00:04:35,150 --> 00:04:37,077
you're saying spend most of the time 
你的大部分精力

70
00:04:37,078 --> 00:04:39,839
optimizing for the web page distribution of images,
都用在优化来自网页下载的图片

71
00:04:39,840 --> 00:04:41,550
which is really not what you want.
这其实不是你想要的

72
00:04:42,780 --> 00:04:45,430
So I would recommend against option one,
所以我真的不建议使用第一个选项

73
00:04:45,430 --> 00:04:50,010
because this is setting up the dev set to tell your team to optimize for
因为这样设立开发集 就是告诉你的团队

74
00:04:50,010 --> 00:04:53,160
a different distribution of data than what you actually care about.
针对不同于你实际关心的数据分布去优化

75
00:04:54,210 --> 00:04:55,232
So instead of doing this,
所以不要这么做

76
00:04:55,232 --> 00:05:01,704
I would recommend that you instead take another option, which is the following.
我建议你走另外一条路 就是这样

77
00:05:01,704 --> 00:05:05,273
The training set, let's say it's still 205,000 images,
训练集 比如说还是205,000张图片

78
00:05:06,178 --> 00:05:15,985
I would have the training set have all 200,000 images from the web.
我们的训练集 是来自网页下载的200,000张图片

79
00:05:15,985 --> 00:05:21,970
And then you can, if you want, add in 5,000 images from the mobile app.
然后如果需要的话 再加上5000张来自手机上传的图片

80
00:05:21,970 --> 00:05:24,344
And then for your dev and test sets,
然后对于开发集和测试集

81
00:05:24,344 --> 00:05:27,599
I guess my data sets size aren't drawn to scale.
这数据集的大小不是按比例画的

82
00:05:27,599 --> 00:05:34,993
Your dev and test sets would be all mobile app images.
你的开发集和测试集都是手机图

83
00:05:38,870 --> 00:05:44,405
So the training set will include 200,000 images from the web and
而训练集包含了来自网页的20万张图片

84
00:05:44,405 --> 00:05:46,560
5,000 from the mobile app.
还有5000张来自应用的图片

85
00:05:46,560 --> 00:05:51,990
The dev set will be 2,500 images from the mobile app, and
开发集就是2500张来自应用的图片

86
00:05:51,990 --> 00:05:58,680
the test set will be 2,500 images also from the mobile app.
测试集也是2500张来自应用的图片

87
00:05:58,680 --> 00:06:03,480
The advantage of this way of splitting up your data into train, dev, and test,
这样将数据分成训练集 开发集和测试集的好处在于

88
00:06:03,480 --> 00:06:07,410
is that you're now aiming the target where you want it to be.
现在你瞄准的目标就是你想要处理的目标

89
00:06:07,410 --> 00:06:12,930
You're telling your team, my dev set has data uploaded from the mobile app and
你告诉你的团队 我的开发集包含的数据全部来自手机上传

90
00:06:12,930 --> 00:06:15,480
that's the distribution of images you really care about, 
这是你真正关心的图片分布

91
00:06:15,481 --> 00:06:19,110
so let's try to build a machine learning system that does really well on
我们试试搭建一个学习系统 让系统在

92
00:06:19,110 --> 00:06:21,750
the mobile app distribution of images.
处理手机上传图片分布时效果良好

93
00:06:21,750 --> 00:06:25,190
The disadvantage, of course, is that now your training
缺点在于 当然了 现在你的训练集分布

94
00:06:25,190 --> 00:06:30,870
distribution is different from your dev and test set distributions.
和你的开发集和测试集分布并不一样

95
00:06:30,870 --> 00:06:35,036
But it turns out that this split of your data into train, dev and test
但事实证明 这样把数据分成训练 开发和测试集

96
00:06:35,037 --> 00:06:38,227
will get you better performance over the long term.
在长期能给你带来更好的系统性能

97
00:06:38,227 --> 00:06:40,601
And we'll discuss later some specific techniques
我们以后会讨论一些特殊的技巧

98
00:06:40,659 --> 00:06:43,690
for dealing with your training sets coming from different distribution
可以处理 训练集的分布和

99
00:06:43,762 --> 00:06:45,088
than your dev and test sets.
开发集和测试集分布不一样的情况

100
00:06:46,448 --> 00:06:49,110
Let's look at another example.
我们来看另一个例子

101
00:06:49,110 --> 00:06:50,912
Let's say you're building a brand new product,
假设你正在开发一个全新的产品

102
00:06:50,993 --> 00:06:58,610
a speech activated rearview mirror for a car.
一个语音激活汽车后视镜

103
00:06:58,610 --> 00:07:01,368
So this is a real product in China.
这在中国是个真实存在的产品

104
00:07:01,368 --> 00:07:05,668
It's making its way into other countries but you can build a rearview mirror to
它正在进入其他国家 但这就是造一个后视镜

105
00:07:05,668 --> 00:07:10,521
replace this little thing there, so that you can now talk to the rearview mirror
把这个小东西换掉 现在你就可以和后视镜对话了

106
00:07:10,521 --> 00:07:13,488
and basically say, dear rearview mirror, please help me find
然后只需要说 亲爱的后视镜 请帮我找找

107
00:07:13,488 --> 00:07:17,760
navigational directions to the nearest gas station and it'll deal with it.
到最近的加油站的导航方向 然后后视镜就会处理这个请求

108
00:07:19,620 --> 00:07:21,011
So this is actually a real product, 
所以这实际上是一个真正的产品

109
00:07:21,012 --> 00:07:23,530
and let's say you're trying to build this for your own country.
假设现在你要为你自己的国家研制这个产品

110
00:07:27,160 --> 00:07:32,489
So how can you get data to train up a speech recognition system for this product?
那么你怎么收集数据去训练这个产品语言识别模块呢?

111
00:07:32,489 --> 00:07:35,654
Well, maybe you've worked on speech recognition for a long time 
嗯 也许你已经在语音识别领域上工作了很久

112
00:07:35,720 --> 00:07:39,785
so you have a lot of data from other speech recognition applications,
所以你有很多来自其他语音识别应用的数据

113
00:07:39,785 --> 00:07:43,185
just not from a speech activated rearview mirror.
它们并不是来自语音激活后视镜的数据

114
00:07:43,185 --> 00:07:47,164
Here's how you could split up your training and your dev and test sets.
现在我讲讲如何分配训练集 开发集和测试集

115
00:07:47,164 --> 00:07:50,780
So for your training, you can take all the speech data you have that
对于你的训练集 你可以将你拥有的所有语音数据

116
00:07:50,780 --> 00:07:53,278
you've accumulated from working on other speech problems,
从其他语音识别问题收集来的数据

117
00:07:53,308 --> 00:07:55,777
such as data you purchased over the years
比如这些年你从

118
00:07:55,823 --> 00:07:59,060
from various speech recognition data vendors.
各种语音识别数据供应商买来的数据

119
00:07:59,060 --> 00:08:03,410
And today you can actually buy data from vendors of x, y pairs,
今天你可以直接买到成x,y对的数据

120
00:08:03,410 --> 00:08:06,130
where x is an audio clip and y is a transcript.
其中x是音频剪辑 y是听写记录

121
00:08:06,130 --> 00:08:11,182
Or maybe you've worked on smart speakers, smart voice activated speakers, 
或者也许你研究过智能音箱 语音激活音箱

122
00:08:11,182 --> 00:08:12,990
so you have some data from that.
所以你有一些数据

123
00:08:12,990 --> 00:08:17,040
Maybe you've worked on voice activated keyboards and so on.
也许你做过语音激活键盘的开发 之类的

124
00:08:17,040 --> 00:08:21,515
And for the sake of argument, maybe you have 500,000
举例来说 也许你从这些来源收集了

125
00:08:21,515 --> 00:08:25,330
utterences from all of these sources.
500,000段录音

126
00:08:25,330 --> 00:08:30,078
And for your dev and test set, maybe you have a much smaller data set that
对于你的开发集和测试集 也许数据集小得多

127
00:08:30,078 --> 00:08:33,892
actually came from a speech activated rearview mirror.
比如实际上来自语音激活后视镜的数据

128
00:08:34,950 --> 00:08:39,284
Because users are asking for navigational queries 
因为用户要查询导航信息

129
00:08:39,284 --> 00:08:41,590
or trying to find directions to various places.
或试图找到通往各个地方的路线

130
00:08:41,590 --> 00:08:46,560
This data set will maybe have a lot more street addresses, right?
这个数据集可能会有很多街道地址 对吧?

131
00:08:46,560 --> 00:08:49,250
Please help me navigate to this street address, or
请帮我导航到这个街道地址 或者说

132
00:08:49,250 --> 00:08:51,980
please help me navigate to this gas station.
请帮助我导航到这个加油站

133
00:08:51,980 --> 00:08:56,040
So this distribution of data will be very different than these on the left.
所以这个数据的分布和左边大不一样

134
00:08:58,140 --> 00:09:00,193
But this is really the data you care about, 
但这真的是你关心的数据

135
00:09:00,194 --> 00:09:02,729
because this is what you need your product to do well on,
因为这些数据是你的产品必须处理好的

136
00:09:02,786 --> 00:09:08,082
so this is what you set your dev and test set to be.
所以你就应该把它设成你的开发和测试集

137
00:09:08,082 --> 00:09:12,868
So what you do in this example is set your training set to be
在这个例子中 你应该这样设立你的训练集

138
00:09:12,868 --> 00:09:17,328
the 500,000 utterances on the left, 
左边有500,000段语音

139
00:09:17,328 --> 00:09:22,567
and then your dev and test sets which I'll abbreviate D and T,
 然后你的开发集和测试集 我把它简写成D和T

140
00:09:22,567 --> 00:09:26,380
these could be maybe 10,000 utterances each.
可能每个集包含10,000段语音

141
00:09:26,380 --> 00:09:31,064
That's drawn from actual the speech activated rearview mirror.
是从实际的语音激活后视镜收集的

142
00:09:31,064 --> 00:09:35,305
Or alternatively, if you think you don't need to put all 20,000 examples
或者换种方式 如果你觉得不需要将20000段

143
00:09:35,306 --> 00:09:39,470
from your speech activated rearview mirror into the dev and test sets,
来自语音激活后视镜的录音全部放进开发和测试集

144
00:09:39,470 --> 00:09:42,470
maybe you can take half of that and put that in the training set.
也许你可以拿一半 把它放在训练集里

145
00:09:43,730 --> 00:09:49,085
So then the training set could be 510,000 utterances,
那么训练集可能是51万段语音

146
00:09:49,085 --> 00:09:55,662
including all 500 from there and 10,000 from the rearview mirror.
包括来自那里的50万段语音 还有来自后视镜的1万段语音

147
00:09:58,046 --> 00:10:04,500
And then the dev and test sets could maybe be 5,000 utterances each.
然后开发集和测试集也许各自有5000段语音

148
00:10:04,500 --> 00:10:09,934
So of the 20,000 utterances, maybe 10k goes into the training set and
所以有2万段语音 也许1万段语音放入了训练集

149
00:10:09,934 --> 00:10:14,490
5k into the dev set and 5,000 into the test set.
5000放入开发集 5000放入测试集

150
00:10:14,490 --> 00:10:16,273
So this would be another reasonable way of 
所以这是另一种

151
00:10:16,330 --> 00:10:20,360
splitting your data into train, dev, and test.
将你的数据分成训练 开发和测试的方式

152
00:10:20,360 --> 00:10:24,376
And this gives you a much bigger training set, over 500,000 utterances, 
这样你的训练集大得多 大概有50万段语音

153
00:10:24,427 --> 00:10:31,297
than if you were to only use speech activated rearview mirror data for your training set.
比只用语音激活后视镜数据作为训练集要大得多

154
00:10:31,297 --> 00:10:36,243
So in this video, you've seen a couple examples of when allowing your training set data
所以在这个视频中 你们见到几组例子 让你的训练集数据

155
00:10:36,244 --> 00:10:39,342
to come from a different distribution than your dev and test set
来自和开发集测试集不同的分布

156
00:10:39,343 --> 00:10:41,980
allows you to have much more training data.
这样你就可以有更多的训练数据

157
00:10:41,980 --> 00:10:45,990
And in these examples, it will cause your learning algorithm to perform better.
在这些例子中 这将改善你的学习算法

158
00:10:45,990 --> 00:10:50,100
Now one question you might ask is, should you always use all the data you have?
现在你可能会问 是不是应该把收集到的数据都用掉?

159
00:10:50,100 --> 00:10:52,850
The answer is subtle, it is not always yes.
答案很微妙 不一定都是肯定的答案

160
00:10:52,850 --> 00:10:54,910
Let's look at a counter-example in the next video.
我们在下段视频看看一个反例

