1
00:00:00,000 --> 00:00:05,250
One of the most powerful ideas in deep learning is that sometimes you can take knowledge
深度学习中 最强大的理念之一就是 有的时候

2
00:00:05,250 --> 00:00:07,203
the neural network has learned from one task 
神经网络可以从一个任务中习得知识

3
00:00:07,272 --> 00:00:10,560
and apply that knowledge to a separate task.
 并将这些知识应用到另一个独立的任务中

4
00:00:10,560 --> 00:00:12,815
So for example, maybe you could have the neural network
所以例如 也许你已经训练好一个神经网络

5
00:00:12,815 --> 00:00:15,720
learn to recognize objects like cats and then use
能够识别像猫这样的对象 然后使用

6
00:00:15,720 --> 00:00:18,085
that knowledge or use part of that knowledge to
那些知识 或者部分习得的知识

7
00:00:18,085 --> 00:00:21,300
help you do a better job reading x-ray scans.
去帮助您更好地阅读x射线扫描图

8
00:00:21,300 --> 00:00:24,920
This is called transfer learning. Let's take a look.
这就是所谓的迁移学习 我们来看看

9
00:00:24,920 --> 00:00:30,180
Let's say you've trained your neural network on image recognition.
假设你已经训练好一个图像识别神经网络

10
00:00:30,180 --> 00:00:34,395
So you first take a neural network and train it on X Y pairs,
所以你首先用一个神经网络 并在x y对上训练

11
00:00:34,395 --> 00:00:37,700
where X is an image and Y is some object.
其中x是图像 y是某些对象

12
00:00:37,700 --> 00:00:41,340
An image is a cat or a dog or a bird or something else.
图像是猫或狗 鸟或其他东西

13
00:00:41,340 --> 00:00:43,960
If you want to take this neural network and adapt,
如果你把这个神经网络拿来 然后让它适应

14
00:00:43,960 --> 00:00:45,465
or we say transfer,
或者说迁移

15
00:00:45,465 --> 00:00:47,670
what is learned to a different task,
在不同任务中学到的知识

16
00:00:47,670 --> 00:00:51,750
such as radiology diagnosis,
比如放射科诊断

17
00:00:51,750 --> 00:00:54,780
meaning really reading X-ray scans,
就是说阅读X射线扫描图

18
00:00:54,780 --> 00:00:59,160
what you can do is take this last output layer of the neural network and
你可以做的是 把神经网络最后的输出层拿走

19
00:00:59,160 --> 00:01:03,885
just delete that and delete also the weights feeding into that last output layer
就把它删掉 还有进入到最后一层的权重删掉

20
00:01:03,885 --> 00:01:08,880
and create a new set of randomly initialized weights just for the last layer
然后为最后一层重新赋予随机权重

21
00:01:08,880 --> 00:01:15,000
and have that now output radiology diagnosis.
然后让它在放射诊断数据上训练

22
00:01:15,000 --> 00:01:17,561
So to be concrete, during the first phase of training
具体来说 在第一阶段训练过程中

23
00:01:17,562 --> 00:01:19,795
when you're training on an image recognition task,
当你进行图像识别任务训练时

24
00:01:19,795 --> 00:01:22,960
you train all of the usual parameters for the neural network, 
你可以训练神经网络的所有常用参数

25
00:01:23,012 --> 00:01:24,537
all the weights, all the layers
所有的权重 所有的层

26
00:01:25,750 --> 00:01:32,680
and you have something that now learns to make image recognition predictions.
然后你就得到了一个能够做图像识别预测的网络

27
00:01:32,680 --> 00:01:35,370
Having trained that neural network,
在训练了这个神经网络后

28
00:01:35,370 --> 00:01:41,540
what you now do to implement transfer learning is swap in a new data set X Y,
要实现迁移学习 你现在要做的是 把数据集换成新的x y对

29
00:01:41,540 --> 00:01:44,022
where now these are radiology images.
现在这些变成放射科图像

30
00:01:47,120 --> 00:01:51,565
And y are the diagnoses you want to predict
而y是你想要预测的诊断

31
00:01:53,421 --> 00:01:58,340
and what you do is initialize the last layers' weights.
你要做的是初始化最后一层的权重

32
00:01:58,340 --> 00:02:02,360
Let's call that w[l] and b[l]. randomly.
让我们称之为w^[l]和b^[l] 随机初始化

33
00:02:02,360 --> 00:02:07,175
And now, retrain the neural network on this new data set,
现在 我们在这个新数据集上重新训练网络

34
00:02:07,175 --> 00:02:09,320
on the new radiology data set.
在新的放射科数据集上训练网络

35
00:02:09,320 --> 00:02:14,260
You have a couple options of how you retrain neural network with radiology data.
要用放射科数据集从新训练神经网络有几种做法

36
00:02:14,260 --> 00:02:16,905
You might, if you have a small radiology dataset,
你可能 如果你的放射科数据集很小

37
00:02:16,905 --> 00:02:20,172
you might want to just retrain the weights of the last layer, 
你可能只需要重新训练最后一层的权重

38
00:02:20,173 --> 00:02:22,620
just w[l], b[l], and keep the rest of the parameters fixed.
就是w^[l] b^[l] 并保持其他参数不变

39
00:02:22,620 --> 00:02:23,975
If you have enough data,
如果你有足够多的数据

40
00:02:23,975 --> 00:02:28,060
you could also retrain all the layers of the rest of the neural network.
你可以重新训练神经网络中剩下的所有层

41
00:02:29,507 --> 00:02:32,535
And the rule of thumb is maybe if you have a small data set,
经验规则是 如果你有一个小数据集 

42
00:02:32,535 --> 00:02:35,560
then just retrain the one last layer at the output layer.
就只训练输出层前的最后一层 

43
00:02:35,560 --> 00:02:37,070
Or maybe that last one or two layers.
或者也许是最后一两层

44
00:02:37,070 --> 00:02:38,755
But if you have a lot of data,
但是如果你有很多数据

45
00:02:38,755 --> 00:02:42,490
then maybe you can retrain all the parameters in the network.
那么也许你可以重新训练网络中的所有参数

46
00:02:42,490 --> 00:02:45,775
And if you retrain all the parameters in the neural network,
如果你重新训练神经网络中的所有参数

47
00:02:45,775 --> 00:02:49,270
then this initial phase of training on
那么这个在图像识别数据的初期训练阶段

48
00:02:49,270 --> 00:02:53,938
image recognition is sometimes called pre-training,
有时称为预训练

49
00:02:53,938 --> 00:02:57,355
because you're using image recognitions data
因为你再用图像识别数据

50
00:02:57,355 --> 00:03:01,745
to pre-initialize or really pre-train the weights of the neural network.
去预先初始化 或者预训练神经网络的权重

51
00:03:01,745 --> 00:03:04,545
And then if you are updating all the weights afterwards,
然后 如果你以后更新所有权重

52
00:03:04,545 --> 00:03:09,885
then training on the radiology data sometimes that's called fine tuning.
然后在放射科数据上训练 有时这个过程叫微调

53
00:03:09,885 --> 00:03:15,185
So you hear the words pre-training and fine tuning in a deep learning context,
如果你在深度学习文献中看到预训练和微调

54
00:03:15,185 --> 00:03:17,530
this is what they mean when they refer to
你就知道它们说的是这个意思

55
00:03:17,530 --> 00:03:21,050
pre-training and fine tuning weights in a transfer learning source.
预训练和微调迁移学习来源的权重

56
00:03:21,050 --> 00:03:22,585
And what you've done in this example,
在这个例子中你做的是

57
00:03:22,585 --> 00:03:25,435
is you've taken knowledge learned from
把图像识别中学到的知识

58
00:03:25,435 --> 00:03:31,285
image recognition and applied it or transferred it to radiology diagnosis.
应用或迁移到放射科诊断上来

59
00:03:31,285 --> 00:03:33,490
And the reason this can be helpful is that
为什么这样做有效果呢?

60
00:03:33,490 --> 00:03:36,570
a lot of the low level features such as detecting edges,
有很多 低层次特征 比如说边缘检测

61
00:03:36,570 --> 00:03:39,400
detecting curves, detecting positive objects.
曲线检测 阳性对象**检测

62
00:03:39,400 --> 00:03:43,045
Learning from that, from a very large image recognition data set,
从非常大的图像识别数据库中习得这些能力

63
00:03:43,045 --> 00:03:47,736
might help your learning algorithm do better in radiology diagnosis.
可能有助于你的学习算法在放射科诊断中做得更好

64
00:03:47,736 --> 00:03:52,640
It's just learned a lot about the structure and the nature of how images look like
算法学到了很多结构信息 图像形状的信息

65
00:03:52,641 --> 00:03:56,465
and some of that knowledge will be useful.
其中一些知识可能会很有用

66
00:03:56,465 --> 00:03:58,545
So having learned to recognize images,
所以学会了图像识别

67
00:03:58,545 --> 00:04:00,910
it might have learned enough about you know,
它就可能学到足够多的信息 可以了解

68
00:04:00,910 --> 00:04:03,135
just what parts of different images look like,
不同图像的组成部分是怎样的

69
00:04:03,135 --> 00:04:05,880
that that knowledge about lines,
学到线条

70
00:04:05,880 --> 00:04:07,725
dots, curves, and so on,
点 曲线 这些知识

71
00:04:07,725 --> 00:04:09,555
maybe small parts of objects,
也许对象的一小部分

72
00:04:09,555 --> 00:04:13,223
that knowledge could help your radiology diagnosis network
这些知识有可能帮助你的放射科诊断网络

73
00:04:13,274 --> 00:04:15,910
learn a bit faster or learn with less data.
学习更快一些 或者需要更少的学习数据

74
00:04:15,910 --> 00:04:17,545
Here's another example.
这里是另一个例子 

75
00:04:17,545 --> 00:04:20,730
Let's say that you've trained a speech recognition system so
假设你已经训练出一个语音识别系统

76
00:04:20,730 --> 00:04:24,398
now x is input of audio or audio snippets,
现在x是音频或音频片段输入

77
00:04:24,398 --> 00:04:27,545
and y is some ink transcript.
而y是听写文本

78
00:04:27,545 --> 00:04:34,200
So you've trained in speech recognition system to output your transcripts.
所以你已经训练了语音识别系统 让它输出听写文本

79
00:04:34,200 --> 00:04:42,474
And let's say that you now want to build a "wake words" or a "trigger words"
现在我们说你想搭建一个“唤醒词”或“触发词”

80
00:04:43,859 --> 00:04:45,345
detection system.
检测系统

81
00:04:45,345 --> 00:04:49,580
So, recall that a wake word or the trigger word are the words we say
所谓唤醒词或触发词就是我们说的一句话

82
00:04:49,580 --> 00:04:54,100
in order to wake up speech control devices in our houses such as saying
可以唤醒家里的语音控制设备 比如你说

83
00:04:54,100 --> 00:04:58,610
"Alexa" to wake up an Amazon Echo or "OK Google" to wake up a Google device or
“Alexa”可以唤醒一个亚马逊Echo设备 或用“OK Google”来唤醒Google设备

84
00:04:58,610 --> 00:05:03,590
"hey Siri" to wake up an Apple device or saying "Ni hao baidu" to wake up a baidu device.
用"Hey Siri"来唤醒苹果设备 用"你好百度"唤醒一个百度设备

85
00:05:03,590 --> 00:05:05,120
So in order to do this,
要做到这点

86
00:05:05,120 --> 00:05:10,573
you might take out the last layer of the neural network again
你可能需要去掉神经网络的最后一层

87
00:05:10,574 --> 00:05:13,435
and create a new output node.
然后加入新的输出节点

88
00:05:13,435 --> 00:05:18,995
But sometimes another thing you could do is actually create not just a single new output,
但有时你可以不只加入一个新节点

89
00:05:18,995 --> 00:05:23,120
but actually create several new layers to your neural network to try
或者甚至往你的神经网络加入几个新层 

90
00:05:23,120 --> 00:05:28,215
to put the labels Y for your wake word detection problem.
然后把唤醒词检测问题的标签Y喂进去训练

91
00:05:28,215 --> 00:05:30,425
Then again, depending on how much data you have,
再次 这取决于你有多少数据

92
00:05:30,425 --> 00:05:34,400
you might just retrain the new layers of the network or maybe
你可能只需要重新训练网络的新层 也许你需要

93
00:05:34,400 --> 00:05:38,925
you could retrain even more layers of this neural network.
重新训练神经网络中更多的层

94
00:05:38,925 --> 00:05:42,150
So, when does transfer learning make sense?
那么迁移学习什么时候是有意义的呢?

95
00:05:42,150 --> 00:05:43,910
Transfer learning makes sense 
迁移学习起作用的场合是

96
00:05:43,911 --> 00:05:48,250
when you have a lot of data for the problem you're transferring from
迁移来源问题你有很多数据

97
00:05:48,251 --> 00:05:52,430
and usually relatively less data for the problem you're transferring to.
但迁移目标问题你没有那么多数据

98
00:05:52,430 --> 00:05:58,030
So for example, let's say you have a million examples for image recognition task.
例如 假设图像识别任务中你有1百万个样本

99
00:05:58,030 --> 00:06:00,605
So that's a lot of data to learn a lot of
所以这里数据相当多

100
00:06:00,605 --> 00:06:03,095
low level features or to learn a lot of
可以学习低层次特征 可以在神经网络的

101
00:06:03,095 --> 00:06:06,385
useful features in the earlier layers in neural network.
前面几层学到如何识别很多有用的特征

102
00:06:06,385 --> 00:06:08,240
But for the radiology task,
但是对于放射科任务

103
00:06:08,240 --> 00:06:12,005
maybe you have only a hundred examples.
也许你只有一百个样本

104
00:06:12,005 --> 00:06:15,650
So you have very low data for the radiology diagnosis problem,
所以你的放射学诊断问题数据很少

105
00:06:15,650 --> 00:06:17,530
maybe only 100 x-ray scans.
也许只有100次X射线扫描

106
00:06:17,530 --> 00:06:23,070
So a lot of knowledge you learn from image recognition can be transferred and can
所以你从图像识别训练中学到的很多知识可以迁移

107
00:06:23,070 --> 00:06:24,560
really help you get going with
并且真正帮你加强

108
00:06:24,560 --> 00:06:29,360
radiology recognition even if you don't have all the data for radiology.
放射科识别任务的性能 即使你的放射科数据很少

109
00:06:29,360 --> 00:06:31,800
For speech recognition, maybe you've trained
对于语音识别 也许你已经用10000小时数据

110
00:06:31,800 --> 00:06:35,110
the speech recognition system on 10000 hours of data.
训练过你的语言识别系统

111
00:06:35,110 --> 00:06:38,359
So, you've learned a lot about what human voices sounds like
所以你从这10000小时数据学到了很多人类声音的特征

112
00:06:38,360 --> 00:06:41,270
from that 10000 hours of data, which really is a lot.
这数据量其实很多了

113
00:06:41,270 --> 00:06:43,220
But for your trigger word detection,
但对于触发字检测

114
00:06:43,220 --> 00:06:45,735
maybe you have only one hour of data.
也许你只有1小时数据

115
00:06:45,735 --> 00:06:48,800
So, that's not a lot of data to fit a lot of parameters.
所以这数据太小 不能用来拟合很多参数

116
00:06:48,800 --> 00:06:53,215
So in this case, a lot of what you learn about what human voices sound like,
所以在这种情况下 预先学到很多人类声音的特征

117
00:06:53,215 --> 00:06:56,450
what are components of human speech and so on,
人类语言的组成部分等等知识

118
00:06:56,450 --> 00:07:00,300
that can be really helpful for building a good wake word detector,
可以帮你建立一个很好的唤醒字检测器

119
00:07:00,300 --> 00:07:03,220
even though you have a relatively small dataset or
即使你的数据集相对较小

120
00:07:03,220 --> 00:07:08,005
at least a much smaller dataset for the wake word detection task.
对于唤醒词任务来说 至少数据集要小得多

121
00:07:08,005 --> 00:07:09,440
So in both of these cases,
所以在这两种情况下

122
00:07:09,440 --> 00:07:11,946
you're transferring from a problem with a lot of data
你从数据量很多的问题 迁移到

123
00:07:11,947 --> 00:07:15,610
to a problem with relatively little data.
数据量相对小的问题

124
00:07:15,610 --> 00:07:19,480
One case where transfer learning would not make sense,
然后反过来的话

125
00:07:19,480 --> 00:07:22,330
is if the opposite was true.
迁移学习可能就没有意义了

126
00:07:22,330 --> 00:07:27,560
So, if you had a hundred images for image recognition and you had
比如 你用100张图训练图像识别系统

127
00:07:27,560 --> 00:07:34,120
100 images for radiology diagnosis or even a thousand images for radiology diagnosis,
然后有100甚至1000张图用于训练放射科诊断系统

128
00:07:34,120 --> 00:07:38,395
one would think about it is that to do well on radiology diagnosis,
人们可能会想 为了提升放射科诊断的性能

129
00:07:38,395 --> 00:07:41,830
assuming what you really want to do well on this radiology diagnosis,
假设你真的希望这个放射科诊断系统做得好

130
00:07:41,830 --> 00:07:47,670
having radiology images is much more valuable than having cat and dog and so on images.
那么用放射科图像训练 可能比使用猫和狗的图像更有价值

131
00:07:47,670 --> 00:07:52,060
So each example here is much more valuable than each example there,
所以这里的每个样本价值比这里要大得多

132
00:07:52,060 --> 00:07:55,935
at least for the purpose of building a good radiology system.
至少就建立性能良好的放射科系统而言是这样

133
00:07:55,935 --> 00:07:58,810
So, if you already have more data for radiology,
所以 如果你的放射科数据更多

134
00:07:58,810 --> 00:08:01,955
it's not that likely that having 100 images of
那么你这100张

135
00:08:01,955 --> 00:08:06,767
your random objects of cats and dogs and cars and so on will be that helpful,
猫猫狗狗或者随机物体的图片肯定不会有太大帮助

136
00:08:06,767 --> 00:08:10,219
because the value of one example of image
因为来自猫狗识别任务中

137
00:08:10,268 --> 00:08:12,322
from your image recognition task of cats and dogs
每一张图的价值

138
00:08:12,356 --> 00:08:16,470
is just less valuable than one example of an x-ray image
肯定不如一张X射线扫描图有价值

139
00:08:16,471 --> 00:08:19,870
for the task of building a good radiology system.
对于建立良好的放射科诊断系统而言是这样

140
00:08:19,870 --> 00:08:22,925
So, this would be one example where transfer learning, well,
所以 这是其中一个例子 说明迁移学习

141
00:08:22,925 --> 00:08:27,515
it might not hurt but I wouldn't expect it to give you any meaningful gain either.
可能不会有害 但也别指望这么做可以带来有意义的增益

142
00:08:27,515 --> 00:08:31,726
And similarly, if you'd built a speech recognition system on 10 hours of data
同样 如果你用10小时数据训练出一个语音识别系统

143
00:08:31,726 --> 00:08:34,660
and you actually have 10 hours or maybe even more,
然后你实际上有10个小时甚至更多

144
00:08:34,660 --> 00:08:38,330
say 50 hours of data for wake word detection,
比如说50个小时唤醒字检测的数据

145
00:08:38,330 --> 00:08:40,505
you know it won't, it may or may not hurt,
你知道迁移学习有可能会有帮助 也可能不会 

146
00:08:40,505 --> 00:08:44,010
maybe it won't hurt to include that 10 hours of data to your transfer learning,
也许把这10小时数据迁移学习不会有太大坏处

147
00:08:44,010 --> 00:08:47,350
but you just wouldn't expect to get a meaningful gain.
但是你也别指望会得到有意义的增益

148
00:08:47,350 --> 00:08:51,220
So to summarize, when does transfer learning make sense?
所以总结一下 什么时候迁移学习是有意义的？

149
00:08:51,220 --> 00:08:53,200
If you're trying to learn from
如果你想从任务A学习

150
00:08:53,200 --> 00:09:00,830
some Task A and transfer some of the knowledge to some Task B,
并迁移一些知识到任务B

151
00:09:00,830 --> 00:09:07,825
then transfer learning makes sense when Task A and B have the same input x.
那么当任务A和任务B都有同样的输入x时 迁移学习是有意义的 

152
00:09:07,825 --> 00:09:10,285
In the first example,
在第一个例子中

153
00:09:10,285 --> 00:09:12,455
A and B both have images as input.
A和B的输入都是图像

154
00:09:12,455 --> 00:09:13,585
In the second example,
在第二个例子中

155
00:09:13,585 --> 00:09:17,260
both have audio clips as input.
两者输入都是音频

156
00:09:17,260 --> 00:09:22,460
It tends to make sense when you have a lot more data for Task A than for Task B.
当任务A的数据比任务B多得多时 迁移学习意义更大

157
00:09:22,460 --> 00:09:27,345
All this is under the assumption that what you really want to do well on is Task B.
所有这些假设的前提都是 你希望提高任务B的性能

158
00:09:27,345 --> 00:09:32,023
And because data for Task B is more valuable for Task B,
因为任务B每个数据更有价值 对任务B来说

159
00:09:32,023 --> 00:09:36,765
usually you just need a lot more data for Task A because you know,
通常任务A的数据量必须大得多 才有帮助

160
00:09:36,765 --> 00:09:43,605
each example from Task A is just less valuable for Task B than each example for Task B.
因为任务A里单个样本的价值比任务B单个样本价值更大

161
00:09:43,605 --> 00:09:47,740
And then finally, transfer learning will tend to make more sense if you suspect
然后如果你觉得任务A的低层次特征

162
00:09:47,740 --> 00:09:52,300
that low level features from Task A could be helpful for learning Task B.
可以帮助任务B的学习 那迁移学习更有意义一些

163
00:09:52,300 --> 00:09:54,395
And in both of the earlier examples,
而在这两个前面的例子中

164
00:09:54,395 --> 00:09:57,010
maybe learning image recognition teaches you enough about
也许学习图像识别教给系统足够多图像相关的知识

165
00:09:57,010 --> 00:09:59,800
images to have a radiology diagnosis and maybe
让它可以进行放射科诊断

166
00:09:59,800 --> 00:10:02,200
learning speech recognition teaches you about
也许学习语音识别教给系统

167
00:10:02,200 --> 00:10:06,000
human speech to help you with trigger word or wake word detection.
足够多人类语言信息 能帮助你开发触发字或唤醒字检测器

168
00:10:06,000 --> 00:10:08,577
So to summarize, transfer learning has been most useful
所以总结一下 迁移学习最有用的场合是

169
00:10:08,627 --> 00:10:11,560
if you're trying to do well on some Task B,
如果你尝试优化任务B的性能

170
00:10:11,560 --> 00:10:14,480
usually a problem where you have relatively little data.
通常这个任务数据相对较少

171
00:10:14,480 --> 00:10:16,910
So for example, in radiology,
例如 在放射科中

172
00:10:16,910 --> 00:10:19,203
you know it's difficult to get that many x-ray scans
你知道很难收集很多x射线扫描图

173
00:10:19,267 --> 00:10:21,990
to build a good radiology diagnosis system.
来搭建一个性能良好的放射科诊断系统

174
00:10:21,990 --> 00:10:25,270
So in that case, you might find a related but different task,
所以在这种情况下 你可能会找一个相关但不同的任务

175
00:10:25,270 --> 00:10:26,645
such as image recognition,
如图像识别

176
00:10:26,645 --> 00:10:28,301
where you can get maybe a million images
其中你可能用1百万张图片训练过了

177
00:10:28,380 --> 00:10:30,850
and learn a lot of low level features from that,
并从中学到很多低层次特征

178
00:10:30,850 --> 00:10:35,486
so that you can then try to do well on Task B on your radiology task
所以那也许能帮助网络在任务B 在放射科任务上做得更好

179
00:10:35,487 --> 00:10:38,166
despite not having that much data for it.
尽管任务B没有这么多数据

180
00:10:38,166 --> 00:10:40,305
When transfer learning makes sense?
迁移学习什么时候是有意义的？

181
00:10:40,305 --> 00:10:43,690
It does help the performance of your learning task significantly.
它确实可以显著提高你的学习任务的性能

182
00:10:43,690 --> 00:10:47,865
But I've also seen sometimes seen transfer learning applied in settings where
但我有时候也见过 有些场合使用迁移学习时

183
00:10:47,865 --> 00:10:52,360
Task A actually has less data than Task B and in those cases,
任务A实际上数据量比任务B要少 这种情况下

184
00:10:52,360 --> 00:10:55,285
you kind of don't expect to see much of a gain.
增益可能不多

185
00:10:55,285 --> 00:10:57,485
So, that's it for transfer learning 
好 这就是迁移学习

186
00:10:57,525 --> 00:11:00,895
where you learn from one task and try to transfer to a different task.
你从一个任务中学习 然后尝试迁移到另一个不同任务中

187
00:11:00,895 --> 00:11:03,333
There's another version of learning from multiple tasks
从多个任务中学习还有另外一个版本

188
00:11:03,334 --> 00:11:05,080
which is called multitask learning,
就是所谓的多任务学习

189
00:11:05,080 --> 00:11:08,166
which is when you try to learn from multiple tasks at the same time
当你尝试从多个任务中并行学习

190
00:11:08,167 --> 00:11:11,373
rather than learning from one and then sequentially, or after that,
而不是串行学习 在训练了一个任务之后

191
00:11:11,422 --> 00:11:14,170
trying to transfer to a different task.
试图迁移到另一个任务

192
00:11:14,170 --> 00:11:15,450
So in the next video,
所以在下一个视频中

193
00:11:15,450 --> 00:11:17,340
let's discuss multitasking learning.
让我们来讨论多任务学习

