1
00:00:00,000 --> 00:00:02,700
If your training set comes from a different distribution,
如果您的训练集来自

2
00:00:02,700 --> 00:00:04,135
than your dev and test set,
和开发测试集不同的分布

3
00:00:04,135 --> 00:00:09,623
and if error analysis shows you that you have a data mismatch problem, what can you do?
如果错误分析显示你有一个数据不匹配的问题 该怎么办?

4
00:00:09,623 --> 00:00:13,105
There aren't completely systematic solutions to this,
这个问题没有完全系统的解决方案

5
00:00:13,105 --> 00:00:15,520
but let's look at some things you could try.
但我们可以看看一些可以尝试的事情

6
00:00:15,520 --> 00:00:19,107
If I find that I have a large data mismatch problem,
如果我发现有严重的数据不匹配问题

7
00:00:19,107 --> 00:00:23,865
what I usually do is carry out manual error analysis and try to
我通常会亲自做错误分析

8
00:00:23,865 --> 00:00:31,865
understand the differences between the training set and the dev/test sets.
尝试了解训练集和开发测试集的具体差异

9
00:00:31,865 --> 00:00:34,272
To avoid overfitting the test set,
技术上 为了避免对测试集过拟合

10
00:00:34,272 --> 00:00:35,800
technically for error analysis,
要做错误分析

11
00:00:35,800 --> 00:00:40,030
you should manually only look at a dev set and not at the test set.
你应该只人工去看开发集而不是测试集

12
00:00:40,030 --> 00:00:42,040
But as a concrete example,
但作为一个具体的例子

13
00:00:42,040 --> 00:00:47,020
if you're building the speech-activated rear-view mirror application,
如果你正在开发一个语音激活的后视镜应用

14
00:00:47,020 --> 00:00:50,020
you might look or, I guess if it's speech,
你可能要看看.. 我想如果是语音的话

15
00:00:50,020 --> 00:00:53,230
listen to examples in your dev set to try
你可能要听一下来自开发集的样本

16
00:00:53,230 --> 00:00:56,885
to figure out how your dev set is different than your training set.
尝试弄清楚开发集和训练集到底有什么不同

17
00:00:56,885 --> 00:00:58,890
So, for example, you might find
所以 比如说 你可能会发现

18
00:00:58,890 --> 00:01:03,745
that a lot of dev set examples are very noisy and there's a lot of car noise.
很多开发集样本噪音很多 有很多汽车噪音

19
00:01:03,745 --> 00:01:08,485
And this is one way that your dev set differs from your training set.
这是你的开发集和训练集差异之一

20
00:01:08,485 --> 00:01:11,350
And maybe you find other categories of errors.
也许你还会发现其他错误

21
00:01:11,350 --> 00:01:17,095
For example, in the speech-activated rear-view mirror in your car,
比如在你的车子里的语言激活后视镜

22
00:01:17,095 --> 00:01:20,650
you might find that it's often mis-recognizing
你发现它可能经常识别错误

23
00:01:20,650 --> 00:01:22,600
street numbers because there are
街道号码 因为那里

24
00:01:22,600 --> 00:01:25,450
a lot more navigational queries which will have street address.
有很多导航请求都有街道地址

25
00:01:25,450 --> 00:01:28,420
So, getting street numbers right is really important.
所以得到正确的街道号码真的很重要

26
00:01:28,420 --> 00:01:31,110
When you have insight into the nature of the dev set errors,
当你了解开发集错误的性质时

27
00:01:31,110 --> 00:01:33,089
or you have insight into
你就知道

28
00:01:33,090 --> 00:01:37,055
how the dev set may be different or harder than your training set,
开发集有可能跟训练集不同 或者更难识别

29
00:01:37,055 --> 00:01:41,645
what you can do is then try to find ways to make the training data more similar.
那么你可以尝试把训练数据变得更像开发集一点

30
00:01:41,645 --> 00:01:47,290
Or, alternatively, try to collect more data similar to your dev and test sets.
或者 你也可以收集更多类似你的开发集和测试集的数据

31
00:01:47,290 --> 00:01:53,940
So, for example, if you find that car noise in the background is a major source of error,
所以 比如说 如果你发现车辆背景噪音是主要的错误来源

32
00:01:53,940 --> 00:02:00,120
one thing you could do is simulate noisy in-car data.
那么你可以模拟车辆噪声数据

33
00:02:00,120 --> 00:02:03,580
So a little bit more about how to do this on the next slide.
我会在下一张幻灯片里详细讨论这个问题

34
00:02:03,580 --> 00:02:06,710
Or you find that you're having a hard time recognizing street numbers,
或者你发现很难识别街道号码

35
00:02:06,710 --> 00:02:10,280
maybe you can go and deliberately try to get more data of
也许你可以有意识地收集更多

36
00:02:10,280 --> 00:02:15,150
people speaking out numbers and add that to your training set.
人们说数字的音频数据 加到你的训练集里

37
00:02:15,150 --> 00:02:20,555
Now, I realize that this slide is giving a rough guideline for things you could try.
现在我知道这张幻灯片只给出了粗略的指南 列出一些你可以做的尝试

38
00:02:20,555 --> 00:02:23,525
This isn't a systematic process and,
这不是一个系统化的过程

39
00:02:23,525 --> 00:02:27,720
I guess, it's no guarantee that you get the insights you need to make progress.
我想 这不能保证你一定能取得进展

40
00:02:27,720 --> 00:02:32,045
But I have found that this manual insight,
但我发现这种人工见解

41
00:02:32,045 --> 00:02:35,870
together we're trying to make the data more similar on the dimensions that
我们可以一起尝试收集更多和真正重要的场合相似的数据

42
00:02:35,870 --> 00:02:39,765
matter that this often helps on a lot of the problems.
这通常有助于解决很多问题

43
00:02:39,765 --> 00:02:46,010
So, if your goal is to make the training data more similar to your dev set,
所以 如果你的目标是让训练数据更接近你的开发集

44
00:02:46,010 --> 00:02:48,620
what are some things you can do?
那么你可以怎么做呢?

45
00:02:48,620 --> 00:02:50,270
One of the techniques you can use is
你可以利用的其中一种技术是

46
00:02:50,270 --> 00:02:52,970
artificial data synthesis and let's discuss
人工合成数据 我们讨论一下

47
00:02:52,970 --> 00:02:56,810
that in the context of addressing the car noise problem.
在解决汽车噪音问题的场合

48
00:02:56,810 --> 00:02:59,240
So, to build a speech recognition system,
所以要建立语音识别系统

49
00:02:59,240 --> 00:03:01,970
maybe you don't have a lot of audio that was actually
也许实际上你没那么多

50
00:03:01,970 --> 00:03:05,030
recorded inside the car with the background noise of a car,
实际在汽车背景噪音下录得的音频

51
00:03:05,030 --> 00:03:07,040
background noise of a highway, and so on.
或者在高速公路背景噪音下录得的音频

52
00:03:07,040 --> 00:03:09,440
But, it turns out, there's a way to synthesize it.
但我们发现 你可以合成

53
00:03:09,440 --> 00:03:13,794
So, let's say that you've recorded a large amount of clean audio
所以假设你录制了大量清晰的音频

54
00:03:13,794 --> 00:03:15,620
without this car background noise.
不带车辆背景噪音的音频

55
00:03:15,620 --> 00:03:20,400
So, here's an example of a clip you might have in your training set.
所以 这可能是你的训练集里的一段音频

56
00:03:23,234 --> 00:03:26,702
By the way, this sentence is used a lot in AI for testing
顺便说一下 这个句子在AI测试中经常使用

57
00:03:26,703 --> 00:03:30,590
because this is a short sentence that contains every alphabet from A to Z,
因为这个短句包含了从a到z所有字母

58
00:03:30,590 --> 00:03:32,745
so you see this sentence a lot.
所以你会经常见到这个句子

59
00:03:32,745 --> 00:03:36,540
But, given that recording of "the quick brown fox jumps over the lazy dog," you
但是 有了这个“敏捷的棕色狐狸跳过懒狗”这段录音之后

60
00:03:36,540 --> 00:03:46,455
can then also get a recording of car noise like this.
你也可以收集一段这样的汽车噪音

61
00:03:46,455 --> 00:03:49,010
So, that's what the inside of a car sounds like,
这就是汽车内部的背景噪音

62
00:03:49,010 --> 00:03:50,595
if you're driving in silence.
如果你一言不发开车的话 就是这种声音

63
00:03:50,595 --> 00:03:53,460
And if you take these two audio clips and add them together,
如果你把两个音频片段放到一起

64
00:03:53,460 --> 00:03:55,595
you can then synthesize what
你就可以合成出

65
00:03:55,595 --> 00:03:58,835
saying "the quick brown fox jumps over the lazy dog" would sound like,
“敏捷的棕色狐狸跳过懒狗”

66
00:03:58,835 --> 00:04:06,870
if you were saying that in a noisy car. So, it sounds like this.
在汽车背景噪音中的效果 听起来像这样

67
00:04:06,870 --> 00:04:10,980
So, this is a relatively simple audio synthesis example.
所以这是一个相对简单的音频合成例子

68
00:04:10,980 --> 00:04:15,074
In practice, you might synthesize other audio effects like reverberation
在实践中 你可能会合成其他音频效果 比如混响

69
00:04:15,075 --> 00:04:19,700
which is the sound of your voice bouncing off the walls of the car and so on.
就是声音从汽车内壁上反弹叠加的效果

70
00:04:19,700 --> 00:04:22,370
But through artificial data synthesis,
但是通过人工数据合成

71
00:04:22,370 --> 00:04:26,288
you might be able to quickly create more data that
你可以快速制造更多的训练数据

72
00:04:26,334 --> 00:04:29,144
sounds like it was recorded inside the car
就像真的在车里录的那样

73
00:04:29,144 --> 00:04:32,540
without needing to go out there and collect tons of data,
那就不需要花时间实际出去收集数据

74
00:04:32,540 --> 00:04:36,187
maybe thousands or tens of thousands of hours of data in a car that's
比如说在实际行驶中的车子

75
00:04:36,224 --> 00:04:37,700
actually driving along.
录下上万小时的音频

76
00:04:37,700 --> 00:04:41,210
So, if your error analysis shows you that you should try to
所以 如果错误分析显示你应该尝试

77
00:04:41,210 --> 00:04:45,050
make your data sound more like it was recorded inside the car,
让你的数据听起来更像在车里录的

78
00:04:45,050 --> 00:04:47,705
then this could be a reasonable process for
那么人工合成那种音频

79
00:04:47,705 --> 00:04:51,310
synthesizing that type of data to give you a learning algorithm.
然后喂给你的机器学习算法 这样做是合理的

80
00:04:51,310 --> 00:04:54,292
Now, there is one note of caution
现在我们要提醒一下

81
00:04:54,293 --> 00:04:57,855
I want to sound on artificial data synthesis which is that,
人工数据合成有一个潜在问题

82
00:04:57,855 --> 00:05:04,814
let's say, you have 10,000 hours of data that was recorded against a quiet background.
比如说 你在安静的背景里录得10000小时音频数据

83
00:05:04,814 --> 00:05:11,915
And, let's say, that you have just one hour of car noise.
然后 比如说 你只录了一小时车辆背景噪音

84
00:05:11,915 --> 00:05:15,831
So, one thing you could try is take this one hour of car noise
那么 你可以这么做 将这1小时汽车噪音

85
00:05:15,832 --> 00:05:19,032
and repeat it 10,000 times in order to add to this
回放10000次 并叠加到

86
00:05:19,072 --> 00:05:24,695
10,000 hours of data recorded against a quiet background.
在安静的背景下录得的10,000小时数据

87
00:05:24,695 --> 00:05:29,355
If you do that, the audio will sound perfectly fine to the human ear,
如果你这么做了 人听起来这个音频没什么问题

88
00:05:29,355 --> 00:05:31,414
but there is a chance, there is a risk
但是有一个风险 有可能

89
00:05:31,462 --> 00:05:38,790
that your learning algorithm will over fit to the one hour of car noise.
你的学习算法对这1小时汽车噪音过拟合

90
00:05:39,569 --> 00:05:41,040
And, in particular,
特别是

91
00:05:41,123 --> 00:05:52,460
if this is the set of all audio that you could record in the car or,
如果这组汽车里录的音频

92
00:05:52,460 --> 00:05:56,195
maybe the sets of all car noise backgrounds you can imagine,
可能是你可以想象的所有汽车噪音背景的集合

93
00:05:56,195 --> 00:05:59,285
if you have just one hour of car noise background,
如果你只录了一小时汽车噪音

94
00:05:59,285 --> 00:06:03,660
you might be simulating just a very small subset of this space.
那你可能只模拟了全部数据空间的一小部分

95
00:06:03,660 --> 00:06:09,010
You might be just synthesizing from a very small subset of this space.
你可能只从汽车噪音的很小的子集来合成数据

96
00:06:09,010 --> 00:06:10,870
And to the human ear,
而对于人耳来说

97
00:06:10,870 --> 00:06:13,990
all these audio sounds just fine because one hour of car noise
这些音频听起来没什么问题 因为一小时的车辆噪音

98
00:06:13,990 --> 00:06:18,030
sounds just like any other hour of car noise to the human ear.
对人耳来说 听起来和其他任意一小时车辆噪音是一样的

99
00:06:18,030 --> 00:06:23,880
But, it's possible that you're synthesizing data from a very small subset of this space,
但你有可能从这整个空间很小的一个子集出发合成数据

100
00:06:23,880 --> 00:06:25,840
and the neural network might be
神经网络最后可能

101
00:06:25,840 --> 00:06:30,530
overfitting to the one hour of car noise that you may have.
对你这一小时汽车噪音过拟合

102
00:06:30,530 --> 00:06:33,355
I don't know if it will be practically feasible to
我不知道以较低成本

103
00:06:33,355 --> 00:06:36,614
inexpensively collect 10,000 hours of car noise
收集10,000小时的汽车噪音是否可行

104
00:06:36,615 --> 00:06:40,503
so that you don't need to repeat the same one hour of car noise over and over
这样你就不用一遍又一遍地回放那1小时汽车噪音

105
00:06:40,549 --> 00:06:43,349
but you have 10,000 unique hours of car noise
你就有10,000个小时永不重复的汽车噪音

106
00:06:43,350 --> 00:06:48,024
to add to 10,000 hours of unique audio recording against a clean background.
来叠加到10000小时安静背景下录得的永不重复的语音录音

107
00:06:48,024 --> 00:06:50,900
But it's possible, no guarantees.
这是可以做的 但不保证能做

108
00:06:50,900 --> 00:06:56,710
But it is possible that using 10,000 hours of unique car noise rather than just one hour,
但是使用10000小时永不重复的汽车噪音 而不是1小时重复

109
00:06:56,710 --> 00:07:01,167
that could result in better performance through learning algorithm.
学习算法有可能取得更好的性能

110
00:07:01,167 --> 00:07:05,650
And the challenge with artificial data synthesis is to the human ear,
人工数据合成的挑战在于 人耳的话

111
00:07:05,650 --> 00:07:07,340
as far as your ears can tell,
人耳是无法分辨的

112
00:07:07,340 --> 00:07:10,850
these 10,000 hours all sound the same as this one hour,
这10000个小时听起来和那1小时没什么区别

113
00:07:10,850 --> 00:07:13,175
so you might end up creating this
所以你最后可能会

114
00:07:13,175 --> 00:07:16,310
very impoverished synthesized data set from
制造出这个原始数据很少的

115
00:07:16,310 --> 00:07:19,890
a much smaller subset of the space without actually realizing it.
在一个小得多的空间子集合成的训练数据 但你自己没意识到

116
00:07:19,890 --> 00:07:23,265
Here's another example of artificial data synthesis.
这里有人工合成数据的另一个例子

117
00:07:23,265 --> 00:07:26,495
Let's say you're building a self driving car and so you want to really detect
假设你在研发无人驾驶汽车 你可能希望

118
00:07:26,495 --> 00:07:31,260
vehicles like this and put a bounding box around it let's say.
检测出这样的车 然后用这样的框包住它

119
00:07:31,260 --> 00:07:34,550
So, one idea that a lot of people have discussed is, well,
很多人都讨论过的一个思路是

120
00:07:34,550 --> 00:07:39,070
why should you use computer graphics to simulate tons of images of cars?
为什么不用计算机合成图像来模拟成千上万的车辆呢?

121
00:07:39,070 --> 00:07:41,045
And, in fact, here are a couple of pictures of
事实上 这里有几张车辆照片

122
00:07:41,045 --> 00:07:44,045
cars that were generated using computer graphics.
其实是用计算机合成的

123
00:07:44,045 --> 00:07:46,970
And I think these graphics effects are actually pretty good and I can
我想这个合成是相当逼真的

124
00:07:46,970 --> 00:07:50,210
imagine that by synthesizing pictures like these,
我想通过这样合成图片

125
00:07:50,210 --> 00:07:54,510
you could train a pretty good computer vision system for detecting cars.
你可以训练出一个相当不错的计算机视觉系统来检测车子

126
00:07:54,510 --> 00:07:58,545
Unfortunately, the picture that I drew on the previous slide
不幸的是 上一张幻灯片介绍的情况

127
00:07:58,546 --> 00:08:00,740
again applies in this setting.
也会在这里出现

128
00:08:00,740 --> 00:08:05,075
Maybe this is the set of all cars and,
比如这是所有车的集合

129
00:08:05,075 --> 00:08:10,200
if you synthesize just a very small subset of these cars,
如果你只合成这些车中很小的子集

130
00:08:10,200 --> 00:08:12,775
then to the human eye,
对于人眼来说

131
00:08:12,775 --> 00:08:15,145
maybe the synthesized images look fine.
也许这样合成图像没什么问题

132
00:08:15,145 --> 00:08:18,985
But you might overfit to this small subset you're synthesizing.
但你的学习算法可能会对合成的这一个小子集过拟合

133
00:08:18,985 --> 00:08:23,590
In particular, one idea that a lot of people have independently raised is,
特别是很多人都独立提出了一个想法

134
00:08:23,590 --> 00:08:26,950
once you find a video game with good computer graphics of cars and just
一旦你找到一个电脑游戏 里面车辆渲染的画面很逼真

135
00:08:26,950 --> 00:08:31,115
grab images from them and get a huge data set of pictures of cars,
那么就可以截图 得到数量巨大的汽车图片数据集

136
00:08:31,115 --> 00:08:33,805
it turns out that if you look at a video game,
事实证明 如果你仔细观察一个视频游戏

137
00:08:33,805 --> 00:08:38,065
if the video game has just 20 unique cars in the video game,
如果这个游戏只有20辆独立的车

138
00:08:38,065 --> 00:08:39,700
then the video game looks fine
那么这游戏看起来还行

139
00:08:39,700 --> 00:08:42,190
because you're driving around in the video game and you see
因为你是在游戏里开车

140
00:08:42,190 --> 00:08:47,065
these 20 other cars and it looks like a pretty realistic simulation.
你只看到这20辆车 这个模拟看起来相当逼真

141
00:08:47,065 --> 00:08:51,715
But the world has a lot more than 20 unique designs of cars,
但现实世界里车辆的设计可不只20种

142
00:08:51,715 --> 00:08:56,200
and if your entire synthesized training set has only 20 distinct cars,
如果你用着20量独特的车合成的照片去训练系统

143
00:08:56,200 --> 00:09:00,485
then your neural network will probably overfit to these 20 cars.
那么你的神经网络很可能对这20辆车过拟合

144
00:09:00,485 --> 00:09:03,985
And it's difficult for a person to easily tell that,
但人类很难分辨出来

145
00:09:03,985 --> 00:09:06,130
even though these images look realistic,
即使这些图像看起来很逼真

146
00:09:06,130 --> 00:09:11,780
you're really covering such a tiny subset of the sets of all possible cars.
你可能真的只用了所有可能出现的车辆的很小的子集

147
00:09:11,780 --> 00:09:15,310
So, to summarize, if you think you have a data mismatch problem,
所以 总而言之 如果你认为存在数据不匹配问题

148
00:09:15,310 --> 00:09:17,640
I recommend you do error analysis,
我建议你做错误分析

149
00:09:17,640 --> 00:09:18,820
or look at the training set,
或者看看训练集

150
00:09:18,820 --> 00:09:20,785
or look at the dev set to try this figure out,
或者看看开发集 试图找出

151
00:09:20,785 --> 00:09:24,685
to try to gain insight into how these two distributions of data might differ.
试图了解这两个数据分布到底有什么不同

152
00:09:24,685 --> 00:09:27,888
And then see if you can find some ways to get more training data
然后看看是否有办法收集更多

153
00:09:27,889 --> 00:09:30,025
that looks a bit more like your dev set.
看起来像开发集的数据作训练

154
00:09:30,025 --> 00:09:33,185
One of the ways we talked about is artificial data synthesis.
我们谈到其中一种办法是人工数据合成

155
00:09:33,185 --> 00:09:35,515
And artificial data synthesis does work.
人工数据合成确实有效

156
00:09:35,515 --> 00:09:39,630
In speech recognition, I've seen artificial data synthesis significantly
在语音识别中 我已经看到人工数据合成

157
00:09:39,630 --> 00:09:43,870
boost the performance of what were already very good speech recognition system.
显著提升了已经非常好的语音识别系统的表现

158
00:09:43,870 --> 00:09:45,505
So, it can work very well.
所以这是可行的

159
00:09:45,505 --> 00:09:47,675
But, if you're using artificial data synthesis,
但当你使用人工数据合成时

160
00:09:47,675 --> 00:09:51,505
just be cautious and bear in mind whether or not you might be accidentally
一定要谨慎 要记住你有可能

161
00:09:51,505 --> 00:09:57,105
simulating data only from a tiny subset of the space of all possible examples.
从所有可能性的空间只选了很小一部分去模拟数据

162
00:09:57,105 --> 00:10:01,990
So, that's it for how to deal with data mismatch.
所以这就是如何处理数据不匹配问题

163
00:10:01,990 --> 00:10:04,690
Next, I like to share with you some thoughts
接下来 我想和你分享一些想法

164
00:10:04,690 --> 00:10:08,390
on how to learn from multiple types of data at the same time.
就是如何从多种类型的数据同时学习

