1
00:00:00,350 --> 00:00:02,080
Hello, and welcome back.
你好 欢迎回来

2
00:00:02,080 --> 00:00:06,550
If you're trying to get a learning algorithm to do a task that humans can do.
如果你希望让学习算法能够胜任人类能做的任务

3
00:00:06,550 --> 00:00:10,490
And if your learning algorithm is not yet at the performance of a human.
但你的学习算法还没有达到人类的表现

4
00:00:10,490 --> 00:00:13,790
Then manually examining mistakes that your algorithm is making,
那么人工检查一下你的算法犯的错误

5
00:00:13,790 --> 00:00:16,240
can give you insights into what to do next.
也许可以让你了解接下来应该做什么

6
00:00:16,240 --> 00:00:19,040
This process is called error analysis.
这个过程称为错误分析

7
00:00:19,040 --> 00:00:20,890
Let's start with an example.
我们从一个例子开始讲吧

8
00:00:20,890 --> 00:00:25,438
Let's say you're working on your cat classifier, and you've achieved 90% accuracy,
假设你正在调试猫分类器 然后你取得了90%准确率

9
00:00:25,439 --> 00:00:29,390
or equivalently 10% error, on your dev set.
相当于10%错误 在你的开发集上做到这样

10
00:00:29,390 --> 00:00:32,820
And let's say this is much worse than you're hoping to do.
这离你希望的目标还有很远

11
00:00:32,820 --> 00:00:33,814
Maybe one of your teammates 
也许你的队员

12
00:00:33,859 --> 00:00:37,967
looks at some of the examples that the algorithm is misclassifying,
看了一下算法分类出错的例子

13
00:00:37,968 --> 00:00:42,340
and notices that it is miscategorizing some dogs as cats.
注意到算法将一些狗分类为猫

14
00:00:42,340 --> 00:00:46,080
And if you look at these two dogs, maybe they look a little bit like a cat,
你看看这两只狗 它们看起来是有点像猫

15
00:00:46,080 --> 00:00:47,628
at least at first glance.
至少乍一看是

16
00:00:47,628 --> 00:00:51,160
So maybe your teammate comes to you with a proposal for
所以也许你的队友给你一个建议 

17
00:00:51,160 --> 00:00:56,110
how to make the algorithm do better, specifically on dogs, right?
如何针对狗的图片优化算法

18
00:00:56,110 --> 00:01:00,891
You can imagine building a focus effort, maybe to collect more dog pictures,
试想一下 你可以针对狗 收集更多的狗图

19
00:01:00,892 --> 00:01:04,680
or maybe to design features specific to dogs, or something.
或者设计一些只处理狗的算法功能 之类的

20
00:01:04,680 --> 00:01:07,837
In order to make your cat classifier do better on dogs,
为了让你的猫分类器在狗图上做的更好

21
00:01:07,902 --> 00:01:11,070
so it stops misrecognizing these dogs as cats.
让算法不再将狗分类成猫

22
00:01:11,070 --> 00:01:12,125
So the question is, 
所以问题在于

23
00:01:12,198 --> 00:01:18,080
should you go ahead and start a project focus on the dog problem?
你是不是应该去开始做一个项目专门处理狗?

24
00:01:19,325 --> 00:01:23,740
There could be several months of works you could do in order to make your algorithm
这项目可能需要花费几个月的时间 才能让算法

25
00:01:23,740 --> 00:01:25,890
make few mistakes on dog pictures.
在狗图片上犯更少的错误

26
00:01:27,280 --> 00:01:29,550
So is that worth your effort?
这样做值得吗?

27
00:01:29,550 --> 00:01:32,475
Well, rather than spending a few months doing this,
或者 与其花几个月做这个项目

28
00:01:32,475 --> 00:01:36,175
only to risk finding out at the end that it wasn't that helpful.
有可能最后发现这样一点用都没有

29
00:01:36,175 --> 00:01:40,051
Here's an error analysis procedure that can let you very quickly tell 
这里有个错误分析流程 可以让你很快知道

30
00:01:40,052 --> 00:01:43,055
whether or not this could be worth your effort.
这个方向是否值得努力

31
00:01:43,055 --> 00:01:45,180
Here's what I recommend you do.
这是我建议你做的

32
00:01:45,180 --> 00:01:49,660
First, get about, say 100 mislabeled dev set examples, 
首先 收集一下 比如说100个错误标记的开发集例子

33
00:01:49,661 --> 00:01:51,860
then examine them manually.
然后手动检查

34
00:01:51,860 --> 00:01:54,684
Just count them up one at a time, to see 
一次只看一个 看看

35
00:01:54,770 --> 00:01:59,338
how many of these mislabeled examples in your dev set are actually pictures of dogs.
你的开发集里有多少错误标记的例子是狗

36
00:01:59,338 --> 00:02:02,160
Now, suppose that it turns out
现在 假设事实上

37
00:02:02,160 --> 00:02:07,700
that 5% of your 100 mislabeled dev set examples are pictures of dogs.
你的100个错误标记例子中只有5%是狗

38
00:02:07,700 --> 00:02:14,828
So, that is, if 5 out of 100 of these mislabeled dev set examples are dogs,
就是说在100个错误标记的开发集例子中 有5个是狗

39
00:02:14,829 --> 00:02:18,231
what this means is that of the 100 examples.
这意味着100个例子

40
00:02:18,231 --> 00:02:20,431
Of a typical set of 100 examples you're getting wrong, 
在典型的100个出错例子中

41
00:02:20,504 --> 00:02:23,353
even if you completely solve the dog problem,
即使你完全解决了狗的问题

42
00:02:23,421 --> 00:02:28,807
you will only get 5 out of 100 more correct.
你也只能修正这100个错误中的5个

43
00:02:28,807 --> 00:02:33,717
Or in other words, if only 5% of your errors are dog pictures, 
或者换句话说 如果只有5%的错误是狗图片

44
00:02:33,717 --> 00:02:36,256
then the best you could easily hope to do,
那么如果你在狗的问题上花了很多时间

45
00:02:36,256 --> 00:02:38,076
if you spend a lot of time on the dog problem.
那么你最多只能希望

46
00:02:38,076 --> 00:02:46,635
Is that your error might go down from 10% error, down to 9.5% error, right?
你的错误率从10%下降到9.5% 对吧

47
00:02:46,635 --> 00:02:53,455
So this a 5% relative decrease in error, from 10% down to 9.5%.
错误率下降了5% 那就是10%下降到9.5%

48
00:02:53,455 --> 00:02:58,220
And so you might reasonably decide that this is not the best use of your time.
你就可以确定这样花时间不好

49
00:02:58,220 --> 00:03:02,619
Or maybe it is, but at least this gives you a ceiling, right?
或者也许应该花时间 但至少这个分析给出了一个上限

50
00:03:02,692 --> 00:03:05,601
Upper bound on how much you could 
如果你继续处理狗的问题

51
00:03:05,643 --> 00:03:09,150
improve performance by working on the dog problem, right?
能够改善算法性能的上限 对吧

52
00:03:10,800 --> 00:03:15,870
In machine learning, sometimes we call this the ceiling on performance.
在机器学习中 有时我们称之为性能上限

53
00:03:15,870 --> 00:03:17,818
Which just means, what's in the best case?
就意味着 最好能到哪里

54
00:03:17,818 --> 00:03:20,720
How well could working on the dog problem help you?
完全解决狗的问题可以对你有多少帮助

55
00:03:22,690 --> 00:03:25,310
But now, suppose something else happens.
但现在 假设发生了另一件事

56
00:03:25,310 --> 00:03:28,590
Suppose that we look at your 100 mislabeled dev set examples,
假设我们观察一下这100个错误标记的开发集例子

57
00:03:28,590 --> 00:03:32,340
you find that 50 of them are actually dog images.
你发现实际有50张图都是狗

58
00:03:32,340 --> 00:03:35,620
So 50% of them are dog pictures.
所以有50%都是狗的照片 

59
00:03:35,620 --> 00:03:39,760
Now you could be much more optimistic about spending time on the dog problem.
现在花时间去解决狗的问题可能效果就很好

60
00:03:39,760 --> 00:03:41,517
In this case, if you actually solve the dog problem,
这种情况下 如果你真的解决了狗的问题

61
00:03:41,611 --> 00:03:47,158
your error would go down from this 10%, down to potentially 5% error.
那么你的错误率可能就从10%下降到5%了

62
00:03:47,158 --> 00:03:52,260
And you might decide that halving your error could be worth a lot of effort.
然后你可能觉得让错误率减半的方向值得一试

63
00:03:52,260 --> 00:03:56,150
Focus on reducing the problem of mislabeled dogs.
可以集中精力减少错误标记的狗图的问题

64
00:03:56,150 --> 00:03:58,092
I know that in machine learning, 
我知道在机器学习中

65
00:03:58,093 --> 00:04:01,682
sometimes we speak disparagingly of hand engineering things,
有时候我们很鄙视手工操作

66
00:04:01,683 --> 00:04:03,660
or using too much manual insight.
或者使用了太多人为数值

67
00:04:03,660 --> 00:04:09,280
But if you're building applied systems, then this simple counting procedure,
但如果你要搭建应用系统 那这个简单的人工统计步骤

68
00:04:09,280 --> 00:04:12,120
error analysis, can save you a lot of time.
错误分析 可以节省大量时间

69
00:04:12,120 --> 00:04:14,680
In terms of deciding what's the most important, 
可以迅速决定什么是最重要的

70
00:04:14,740 --> 00:04:17,309
or what's the most promising direction to focus on.
或者最有希望的方向

71
00:04:19,739 --> 00:04:23,122
In fact, if you're looking at 100 mislabeled dev set examples,
实际上 如果你观察100个错误标记的开发集例子

72
00:04:23,171 --> 00:04:27,620
maybe this is a 5 to 10 minute effort.
也许只需要5到10分钟的时间

73
00:04:27,620 --> 00:04:29,655
To manually go through 100 examples,
亲自看看这100个例子

74
00:04:29,694 --> 00:04:32,860
and manually count up how many of them are dogs.
并亲自统计一下有多少是狗

75
00:04:32,860 --> 00:04:34,481
And depending on the outcome, 
根据结果​​

76
00:04:34,482 --> 00:04:37,570
whether there's more like 5%, or 50%, or something else.
看看有没有占到5% 50% 或者其他东西

77
00:04:37,570 --> 00:04:39,580
This, in just 5 to 10 minutes,
这个 在5到10分钟之内

78
00:04:39,580 --> 00:04:44,310
gives you an estimate of how worthwhile this direction is.
就能给你估计这个方向有多少价值

79
00:04:44,310 --> 00:04:46,064
And could help you make a much better decision, 
并且可以帮助你做出更好的决定

80
00:04:46,065 --> 00:04:48,022
whether or not to spend the next few months
是不是把未来几个月的时间

81
00:04:48,078 --> 00:04:54,180
focused on trying to find solutions to solve the problem of mislabeled dogs.
投入到解决错误标记的狗图这个问题

82
00:04:54,180 --> 00:04:56,409
In this slide, we'll describe using error analysis 
在本幻灯片中 我们要描述一下 如何使用错误分析

83
00:04:56,465 --> 00:05:02,380
to evaluate whether or not a single idea, dogs in this case, is worth working on.
来评估某个想法 这个例子里狗的问题 是否值得解决

84
00:05:02,380 --> 00:05:08,260
Sometimes you can also evaluate multiple ideas in parallel doing error analysis.
有时你在做错误分析时 也可以同时并行评估几个想法

85
00:05:08,260 --> 00:05:12,920
For example, let's say you have several ideas in improving your cat detector.
比如 你有几个改善猫检测器的想法

86
00:05:12,920 --> 00:05:16,460
Maybe you can improve performance on dogs?
也许你可以改善针对狗图的性能

87
00:05:16,460 --> 00:05:19,281
Or maybe you notice that sometimes, what are called great cats,
或者有时候要注意 那些猫科动物 

88
00:05:19,281 --> 00:05:22,332
such as lions, panthers, cheetahs, and so on.
如狮子 豹 猎豹等等

89
00:05:22,332 --> 00:05:25,666
That they are being recognized as small cats, or house cats.
它们经常被分类成小猫 或者家猫

90
00:05:25,776 --> 00:05:28,031
So you could maybe find a way to work on that.
所以你也许可以想办法解决这个错误

91
00:05:28,031 --> 00:05:31,117
Or maybe you find that some of your images are blurry, 
或者也许你发现有些图像是模糊的

92
00:05:31,118 --> 00:05:33,665
and it would be nice if you could design something
如果你能设计出一些系统

93
00:05:33,726 --> 00:05:36,489
that just works better on blurry images.
能够更好地处理模糊图像

94
00:05:37,560 --> 00:05:39,280
And maybe you have some ideas on how to do that.
也许你有些想法 知道大概怎么处理这些问题

95
00:05:41,480 --> 00:05:45,430
So if carrying out error analysis to evaluate these three ideas,
要进行错误分析来评估这三个想法

96
00:05:45,430 --> 00:05:48,430
what I would do is create a table like this.
我会做的是建立这样一个表格

97
00:05:50,760 --> 00:05:53,718
And I usually do this in a spreadsheet, 
我通常用电子表格来做

98
00:05:53,719 --> 00:05:56,520
but using an ordinary text file will also be okay.
但普通文本文件也可以

99
00:05:57,610 --> 00:05:58,605
And on the left side,
在最左边

100
00:05:58,605 --> 00:06:02,430
this goes through the set of images you plan to look at manually.
人工过一遍你想分析的图像集

101
00:06:02,430 --> 00:06:06,010
So this maybe goes from 1 to 100, if you look at 100 pictures.
所以图像可能是从1到100 如果你观察100张图的话

102
00:06:06,010 --> 00:06:09,910
And the columns of this table, of the spreadsheet,
电子表格的一列

103
00:06:09,910 --> 00:06:12,570
will correspond to the ideas you're evaluating.
就对应你要评估的想法

104
00:06:12,570 --> 00:06:18,490
So the dog problem, the problem of great cats, and blurry images.
所以狗的问题 猫科动物的问题 模糊图像的问题

105
00:06:18,490 --> 00:06:23,870
And I usually also leave space in the spreadsheet to write comments.
我通常也在电子表格中留下空位来写评论

106
00:06:23,870 --> 00:06:25,724
So remember, during error analysis,
所以记住 在错误分析过程中

107
00:06:25,724 --> 00:06:29,610
you're just looking at dev set examples that your algorithm has misrecognized.
你就看看算法识别错误的开发集例子

108
00:06:30,670 --> 00:06:34,640
So if you find that the first misrecognized image is a picture of a dog,
如果你发现第一张识别错误的图片是狗图

109
00:06:34,640 --> 00:06:36,550
then I'd put a check mark there.
那么我就在那里打个勾

110
00:06:36,550 --> 00:06:39,540
And to help myself remember these images,
为了帮我自己记住这些图片

111
00:06:39,540 --> 00:06:41,672
sometimes I'll make a note in the comments.
有时我会在评论里注释

112
00:06:41,732 --> 00:06:44,380
So maybe that was a pit bull picture.
也许这是一张比特犬的图

113
00:06:44,380 --> 00:06:48,110
If the second picture was blurry, then make a note there.
如果第二张照片很模糊 也记一下

114
00:06:48,110 --> 00:06:53,317
If the third one was a lion, on a rainy day, in the zoo that was misrecognized.
如果第三张是在下雨天动物园里的狮子 被识别成猫了

115
00:06:53,317 --> 00:06:56,030
Then that's a great cat, and the blurry data.
这是大型猫科动物 还有图片模糊

116
00:06:56,030 --> 00:07:00,920
Make a note in the comment section, rainy day at zoo, and
在评论部分 写动物园下雨天

117
00:07:00,920 --> 00:07:03,620
it was the rain that made it blurry, and so on.
是雨天让图像模糊的 之类的

118
00:07:05,670 --> 00:07:08,167
Then finally, having gone through some set of images,
最后 这组图像过了一遍之后

119
00:07:08,222 --> 00:07:11,508
I would count up what percentage of these algorithms.
我可以统计这些算法(错误)的百分比

120
00:07:11,508 --> 00:07:16,951
Or what percentage of each of these error categories were attributed to the dog,
或者这里每个错误类型的百分比 有多少是狗

121
00:07:16,951 --> 00:07:19,360
or great cat, blurry categories.
大猫 或模糊这些错误类型

122
00:07:19,360 --> 00:07:23,589
So maybe 8% of these images you examine turn out be dogs, 
所以也许你检查的图像中8%是狗

123
00:07:23,665 --> 00:07:32,390
and maybe 43% great cats, and 61% were blurry.
可能43%属于大猫 61%属于模糊

124
00:07:32,390 --> 00:07:34,568
So this just means going down each column, 
这意味着扫过每一列

125
00:07:34,569 --> 00:07:39,290
and counting up what percentage of images have a check mark in that column.
并统计那一列有多少百分比图像打了勾

126
00:07:39,290 --> 00:07:41,567
As you're part way through this process,
在这个步骤做到一半时

127
00:07:41,567 --> 00:07:44,420
sometimes you notice other categories of mistakes.
有时你可能会发现其他错误类型

128
00:07:44,420 --> 00:07:51,763
So, for example, you might find that Instagram style filter, those fancy image filters,
比如说你可能发现有Instagram滤镜 那些花哨的图像滤镜

129
00:07:51,764 --> 00:07:55,420
are also messing up your classifier.
干扰了你的分类器

130
00:07:55,420 --> 00:07:55,940
In that case,
在这种情况下

131
00:07:55,940 --> 00:08:00,240
it's actually okay, part way through the process, to add another column like that.
实际上可以在错误分析途中 增加这样一列

132
00:08:00,240 --> 00:08:04,650
For the multi-colored filters, the Instagram filters, and the Snapchat filters.
比如多色滤镜 Instagram滤镜和Snapchat滤镜

133
00:08:04,650 --> 00:08:07,708
And then go through and count up those as well, 
然后再过一遍 也统计一下那些问题

134
00:08:07,709 --> 00:08:11,050
and figure out what percentage comes from that new error category.
并确定这个新的错误类型占了多少百分比

135
00:08:12,170 --> 00:08:15,218
The conclusion of this process gives you an estimate of 
这个分析步骤的结果可以给出一个估计

136
00:08:15,302 --> 00:08:19,880
how worthwhile it might be to work on each of these different categories of errors.
是否值得去处理每个不同的错误类型

137
00:08:19,880 --> 00:08:21,573
For example, clearly in this example, 
例如 在这个例子中

138
00:08:21,636 --> 00:08:24,516
a lot of the mistakes we made on blurry images,
有很多错误来自模糊图片

139
00:08:24,517 --> 00:08:28,780
and quite a lot on were made on great cat images.
也有很多错误类型是大猫图片

140
00:08:28,780 --> 00:08:35,750
And so the outcome of this analysis is not that you must work on blurry images.
所以这个分析的结果不是说你一定要处理模糊图片

141
00:08:35,750 --> 00:08:39,360
This doesn't give you a rigid mathematical formula that tells you what to do,
这个分析没有给你一个严格的数学公式 告诉你应该做什么

142
00:08:39,360 --> 00:08:43,140
but it gives you a sense of the best options to pursue.
但它能让你对应该选择那些手段有个概念

143
00:08:43,140 --> 00:08:44,650
It also tells you, for example,
它也告诉你 比如说

144
00:08:44,650 --> 00:08:50,065
that no matter how much better you do on dog images, or on Instagram images.
不管你对狗图片 或者Instagram图片处理得有多好

145
00:08:50,135 --> 00:08:55,130
You at most improve performance by maybe 8%, or 12%, in these examples.
在这些例子中 你最多只能取得8% 或者12%的性能提升

146
00:08:55,130 --> 00:08:57,700
Whereas you can to better on great cat images, or
而在大猫图片这一类型 你可以做得更好

147
00:08:57,700 --> 00:09:00,246
blurry images, the potential improvement.
或者模糊图像 这些类型有改进的潜力

148
00:09:00,246 --> 00:09:03,730
Now there's a ceiling in terms of how much you could improve performance,
这些类型里 性能提高的上限

149
00:09:03,730 --> 00:09:05,390
is much higher.
空间要大得多

150
00:09:05,390 --> 00:09:07,381
So depending on how many ideas you have for 
所以取决于你有多少改善性能的想法

151
00:09:07,382 --> 00:09:10,320
improving performance on great cats, on blurry images.
比如改善大猫图片 或者模糊图片的表现

152
00:09:10,320 --> 00:09:13,856
Maybe you could pick one of the two, or if you have enough personnel on your team,
也许你可以选择其中两个 或者你的团队成员足够多

153
00:09:13,856 --> 00:09:15,630
maybe you can have two different teams.
也许你把团队可以分成两个团队

154
00:09:15,630 --> 00:09:18,455
Have one work on improving errors on great cats, 
其中一个想办法改善大猫的识别

155
00:09:18,456 --> 00:09:22,120
and a different team work on improving errors on blurry images.
另一个团队想办法改善模糊图片的识别

156
00:09:27,184 --> 00:09:31,280
But this quick counting procedure, which you can often do in, at most,
但这个快速统计的步骤 你可以经常做 

157
00:09:31,280 --> 00:09:33,130
small numbers of hours.
最多需要几小时

158
00:09:33,130 --> 00:09:36,200
Can really help you make much better prioritization decisions,
就可以真正帮你选出高优先级任务

159
00:09:36,200 --> 00:09:39,410
and understand how promising different approaches are to work on.
并了解每种手段对性能有多大提升空间

160
00:09:40,940 --> 00:09:44,670
So to summarize, to carry out error analysis, you should find a set of
所以总结一下 进行错误分析 你应该找一组

161
00:09:44,670 --> 00:09:48,731
mislabeled examples, either in your dev set, or in your development set.
错误例子 可能在你的开发集里 或者测试集里

162
00:09:48,731 --> 00:09:53,420
And look at the mislabeled examples for false positives and false negatives.
观察错误标记的例子 看看假阳性和假阴性

163
00:09:53,420 --> 00:09:55,067
And just count up the number of errors 
统计属于不同错误类型的

164
00:09:55,123 --> 00:09:57,629
that fall into various different categories.
错误数量

165
00:09:57,629 --> 00:10:01,916
During this process, you might be inspired to generate new categories of errors,
在这个过程中 你可能会得到启发 归纳出新的错误类型

166
00:10:01,916 --> 00:10:02,597
like we saw.
就像我们看到的那样

167
00:10:02,597 --> 00:10:04,004
If you're looking through the examples and you say 
如果你过了一遍错误例子 然后说

168
00:10:04,047 --> 00:10:05,995
gee, there are a lot of Instagram filters,
天 有这么多Instagram滤镜

169
00:10:06,062 --> 00:10:09,071
or Snapchat filters, they're also messing up my classifier.
或Snapchat滤镜 这些滤镜干扰了我的分类器

170
00:10:09,071 --> 00:10:11,600
You can create new categories during that process.
你就可以在途中新建一个错误类型

171
00:10:11,600 --> 00:10:15,550
But by counting up the fraction of examples that are mislabeled in different ways,
总之 通过统计不同错误标记类型占总数的百分比

172
00:10:15,551 --> 00:10:17,234
often this will help you prioritize.
可以帮你发现哪些问题需要优先解决

173
00:10:17,311 --> 00:10:19,928
Or give you inspiration for new directions to go in.
或者给你构思新优化方向的灵感

174
00:10:19,991 --> 00:10:23,074
Now as you're doing error analysis,
在做错误分析的时候

175
00:10:23,074 --> 00:10:27,600
sometimes you notice that some of your examples in your dev sets are mislabeled.
有时你会注意到开发集里有些样本被错误标记了

176
00:10:27,600 --> 00:10:29,380
So what do you do about that?
这时应该怎么做呢?

177
00:10:29,380 --> 00:10:31,020
Let's discuss that in the next video.
我们下一个视频来讨论

