1
00:00:03,182 --> 00:00:06,580
Welcome, Rus, I'm really glad you could join us here today.
欢迎你 Rus 很高兴今天你能接受采访

2
00:00:06,580 --> 00:00:08,370
>> Thank you, thank you Andrew.
谢谢你 谢谢你Andrew

3
00:00:08,370 --> 00:00:11,520
>> So today you're the director of research at Apple, 
所以今天你是苹果公司的研究主管

4
00:00:11,521 --> 00:00:16,720
and you also have a faculty, a professor for Carnegie Mellon University.
你也有一个教职 卡内基梅隆大学的教授

5
00:00:16,720 --> 00:00:20,050
So I'd love to hear a bit about your personal story.
所以我很想听听你的个人故事

6
00:00:20,050 --> 00:00:24,350
How did you end up doing this deep learning work that you do?
你是如何一步步进入深度学习领域工作的呢?

7
00:00:24,350 --> 00:00:27,930
Yeah, it's actually, to some extent it was,
是的 其实 某种程度上

8
00:00:27,930 --> 00:00:32,040
I started in deep learning to some extent by luck.
我进入深度学习领域纯粹是运气

9
00:00:32,040 --> 00:00:35,710
I did my master's degree at Toronto, and then I took a year off.
我在多伦多大学读的硕士 然后我休学了一年

10
00:00:35,710 --> 00:00:37,860
I was actually working in the financial sector.
我实际上在金融领域工作

11
00:00:37,860 --> 00:00:40,161
It's a little bit surprising.
很意外吧

12
00:00:40,161 --> 00:00:44,047
And at that time, I wasn't quite sure whether I want to go for my PhD or not.
那时候 我不太清楚是否要去取得博士学位

13
00:00:44,047 --> 00:00:46,110
And then something happened, something surprising happened.
然后发生了一些事情 发生了一些意外的事情

14
00:00:46,110 --> 00:00:50,641
I was going to work one morning, and I bumped into Geoff Hinton.
有一天早上我要上班 路上遇到了Geoff Hinton

15
00:00:50,641 --> 00:00:55,153
And Geoff told me, hey, I have this terrific idea.
Geoff告诉我 嘿 我有这个好想法

16
00:00:55,153 --> 00:00:56,810
Come to my office, I'll show you.
来我办公室 我给你讲

17
00:00:56,810 --> 00:01:01,205
And so, we basically walked together and he started telling me about these
所以 我们基本上一起散步 然后他开始告诉我这些

18
00:01:01,205 --> 00:01:06,400
Boltzmann Machines and contrasting divergence, and some of the tricks which
波尔兹曼机器 对比散度法 还有其他算法

19
00:01:06,400 --> 00:01:09,080
I didn't at that time quite understand what he was talking about.
当时我并没有明白他在说什么

20
00:01:10,300 --> 00:01:15,320
But that really, really excited, that was very exciting and really excited me.
但真的 真的很激动 非常令人兴奋 让我非常兴奋

21
00:01:15,320 --> 00:01:20,340
And then basically, within three months I started my PhD with Geoff.
然后基本上 三个月内 我就跟着Geoff读博了

22
00:01:21,410 --> 00:01:28,743
So that was kind of the beginning, because that was back in 2005, 2006.
所以这是开始 因为那是2005 2006年的事了

23
00:01:28,743 --> 00:01:32,421
And this is where some of the original deep learning algorithms,
这是一些原始的深度学习算法

24
00:01:32,422 --> 00:01:37,810
using Restricted Boltz Machines, unsupervised pre-training, were kind of popping up.
使用受限玻尔兹曼机 无人监督的预训练 这些概念开始成熟

25
00:01:37,810 --> 00:01:41,969
And so that's how I started it, was really.
这就是一切的开始 真的是这样

26
00:01:41,969 --> 00:01:46,181
That one particular morning when I bumped into Geoff completely
那个特别的早晨 我偶然碰到了Geoff

27
00:01:46,181 --> 00:01:48,990
changed my future career moving forward.
完全改变了我未来的事业发展法向

28
00:01:48,990 --> 00:01:52,009
>> And then in fact you were co-author on 
>>然后你其实是

29
00:01:52,066 --> 00:01:55,070
one of the very early papers on Restricted Boltzmann Machines that
早期一篇关于受限玻尔兹曼机的论文的合著者

30
00:01:55,070 --> 00:02:00,430
really helped with this resurgence of neural networks and deep learning.
真正让神经网络和深度学习的概念涅槃重生

31
00:02:00,430 --> 00:02:03,873
Tell me a bit more what that was like working on that seminal-
你可以告诉我更多关于那个研讨会的工作吗?

32
00:02:03,874 --> 00:02:07,042
>> Yeah, this was actually a really, this was exciting,
>>是的 这其实真的很激动人心

33
00:02:07,043 --> 00:02:10,992
yeah, it was the first year, it was my first year as a PhD student.
是的 那是第一年 我的PhD生涯的第一年

34
00:02:10,992 --> 00:02:13,733
And Geoff and I were
Geoff和我

35
00:02:13,779 --> 00:02:17,075
trying to explore these ideas of using Restricted Boltz Machines
试图探索使用受限玻尔兹曼机的这些算法

36
00:02:17,076 --> 00:02:21,680
and using pre-training tricks to train multiple layers.
使用预训练等技巧训练多层网络

37
00:02:21,680 --> 00:02:25,934
And specifically we were trying to focus on auto-encoders,
具体来说 我们集中精力处理自动编码器

38
00:02:25,934 --> 00:02:29,880
how do we do a non-linear extension of PCA effectively?
我们应该怎么高效的去做PCA的非线性拉伸呢?

39
00:02:29,880 --> 00:02:34,416
And it was very exciting, because we got these systems to work on MNIST Digits
这是非常令人兴奋的 因为我们的系统能够处理MNIST数字

40
00:02:34,416 --> 00:02:37,296
which was exciting, but then the next steps for
这是令人兴奋的 但那之后我们走的路

41
00:02:37,296 --> 00:02:42,062
us were to really see whether we can extend these models to dealing with faces.
让我们看到这些模型真的可以推广到人脸识别

42
00:02:42,062 --> 00:02:45,069
I remember we had this Olivetti faces dataset.
我还记得那时我们有这个Olivetti人脸数据集

43
00:02:45,069 --> 00:02:48,000
And then we started looking at can we do compression for documents?
然后我们开始在想 是不是可以改善文档压缩

44
00:02:48,000 --> 00:02:51,032
And we started looking at all these different data,
我们开始观察所有这些不同的数据

45
00:02:51,077 --> 00:02:57,152
real value count, binary, and throughout a year,
实值计数 布尔代数 用了整整一年

46
00:02:57,152 --> 00:03:03,672
I was a first year PhD student, so it was a big learning experience for me.
我还是博士生第一年 所以那是很充实的学习经验

47
00:03:03,672 --> 00:03:07,287
But and really within six or seven months,
但是 真的 在六七个月内

48
00:03:07,287 --> 00:03:11,079
we were able to get really interesting results, I mean really good results.
我们已经能够得到非常有趣的结果 我是说非常好的结果

49
00:03:11,079 --> 00:03:14,765
I think that we were able to train these very deep auto-encoders.
我想我们能够训练这些层次非常深的自动编码器

50
00:03:14,765 --> 00:03:16,671
This is something that you couldn't do at that time
这是当时还做不到的事情

51
00:03:16,717 --> 00:03:22,077
using sort of traditional optimization techniques.
用传统的优化技术做不到的事情

52
00:03:22,077 --> 00:03:26,965
And then it turned out into really, really exciting period for us.
然后 那开始变成非常激动人心的时期

53
00:03:27,970 --> 00:03:33,520
That was super exciting, yeah, because it was a lot of learning for me,
那是超级激动人心的 是的 因为我那时不断在学习新知识

54
00:03:33,520 --> 00:03:38,230
but at the same time, the results turned out to be really,
但同时 我们的工作出来的结果

55
00:03:38,230 --> 00:03:40,710
really impressive for what we were trying to do.
真的很令人印象深刻 

56
00:03:42,210 --> 00:03:45,360
>> So in the early days of the resurgence of deep learning,
>>所以在深度学习复兴初期

57
00:03:45,360 --> 00:03:49,760
a lot of the activity was centered on Restricted Boltzmann Machines, and
很多研究都集中在受限玻尔兹曼机上

58
00:03:49,760 --> 00:03:52,340
then Deep Boltzmann Machines.
然后是深玻尔兹曼机

59
00:03:52,340 --> 00:03:54,842
There's still a lot of exciting research there being done,
还出来了很多令人兴奋的研究

60
00:03:54,842 --> 00:03:58,228
including some in your group, but what's happening with Boltzmann Machines and
包括你们组的一些研究 但玻尔兹曼机

61
00:03:58,228 --> 00:03:59,663
Restricted Boltzmann Machines?
还有受限玻尔兹曼机器现在怎么样了?

62
00:03:59,663 --> 00:04:00,900
>> Yeah, that's a very good question.
是的 这是一个很好的问题

63
00:04:00,900 --> 00:04:01,710
I think that,
我觉得

64
00:04:01,710 --> 00:04:07,032
in the early days, the way that we were using Restricted Boltz Machines
在早期 我们使用受限玻尔兹机器的方式

65
00:04:07,032 --> 00:04:10,940
is you sort of can imagine training a stack of these Restricted Boltz Machines
你可以想象一下训练一堆这些受限玻尔兹曼机

66
00:04:10,940 --> 00:04:14,715
that would allow you to learn effectively one layer at a time.
让你能够很有效的一次学习一层

67
00:04:14,715 --> 00:04:17,928
And there's a good theory behind when you add a particular layer,
有很好的理论基础 告诉你添加特定的一层之后

68
00:04:17,928 --> 00:04:21,010
it can prove variational bound and so forth under certain conditions.
你可以在特定条件上证明它是有变分界限之类的

69
00:04:21,010 --> 00:04:24,414
So there was a theoretical justification, and these models
所以是有理论支持的 这些模型

70
00:04:24,414 --> 00:04:28,697
were working quite well in terms of being able to pre-train these systems.
能够在预训练这些系统方面达到很好的效果

71
00:04:28,697 --> 00:04:35,013
And then around 2009, 2010, once the Computes started showing up,
然后在2009年左右 2010年 计算力量开始出现了

72
00:04:35,013 --> 00:04:41,618
GPUs, then a lot of us started realizing that actually directly optimizing these
GPU开始很强 我们很多人开始意识到 直接优化这些

73
00:04:41,618 --> 00:04:47,760
deep neural networks was giving similar results or even better results.
深层神经网络 可以得到类似的结果 甚至更好的结果

74
00:04:47,760 --> 00:04:50,336
>> So just standard backprop without the pre-training or
>>所以只是标准的反向传播 不带预训练的

75
00:04:50,336 --> 00:04:51,824
the Restricted Boltz Machine.
受限玻尔兹曼机

76
00:04:51,824 --> 00:04:52,700
>> That's right, that's right.
>> 没错 没错

77
00:04:52,700 --> 00:04:55,044
And that's sort of over three or four years, 
那大概过了三四年

78
00:04:55,085 --> 00:04:56,836
and it was exciting for the whole community,
整个社区都很兴奋

79
00:04:56,896 --> 00:04:58,050
because people felt that wow,
因为人们觉得 哇

80
00:04:58,050 --> 00:05:02,460
you can actually train these deep models using these pre-training mechanisms.
你真的可以用预训练机制这么训练深层模型

81
00:05:02,460 --> 00:05:06,930
And then, with more Computes people started realizing that you can just
然后 随着更多计算力量变强 人们突然发现

82
00:05:06,930 --> 00:05:08,160
basically do standard backpropagation, 
你可以直接做标准反向传播

83
00:05:08,205 --> 00:05:12,412
something that we couldn't do back in 2005 or 2004,
那是2005年或2004年我们做不到的事情

84
00:05:12,483 --> 00:05:17,240
because it would take us months to do it on CPU's.
因为CPU计算要几个月的时间

85
00:05:17,240 --> 00:05:20,330
And so that was a big change.
所以这是一个很大的变化

86
00:05:20,330 --> 00:05:24,050
The other thing that I think that we haven't really figured out
另一件事 我们还没想清楚的是

87
00:05:24,050 --> 00:05:28,108
what to do with Boltz Machines and Deep Boltzmann Machines.
如何使用玻尔兹曼机和深波尔兹漫机

88
00:05:28,108 --> 00:05:29,650
I believe they're very powerful models,
我相信他们是非常强大的模型

89
00:05:29,650 --> 00:05:32,010
because you can think of them generative models.
因为你们可以把它们看成是生成性模型

90
00:05:32,010 --> 00:05:36,000
They're trying to model coupling distributions in the data, 
它们试图对数据进行耦合分布建模

91
00:05:36,001 --> 00:05:40,440
but when we start looking at learning algorithms, learning algorithms right now,
但是当我们开始研究学习算法时 现在学习算法

92
00:05:40,440 --> 00:05:45,000
they require using Markov Chain Monte Carlo and variational learning and such,
他们需要使用马尔可夫链 蒙特卡罗和变分学习等

93
00:05:45,000 --> 00:05:48,832
which is not as scalable as backpropagation algorithms.
它们并不像反向传播算法那样可以轻松扩展

94
00:05:48,832 --> 00:05:55,480
So we yet have to figure out more efficient ways of training these models,
我们还没有想出更有效训练这类模型的方法

95
00:05:55,480 --> 00:05:57,920
and also the use of convolution,
还有卷积的使用

96
00:05:57,920 --> 00:06:02,830
it's something that's fairly difficult to integrate into these models.
这些模型有点难以适应到现在的计算硬件

97
00:06:02,830 --> 00:06:07,500
I remember some of your work on using probabilistic max pooling for
我还记得你当时有些工作用的是概率最大池化

98
00:06:07,500 --> 00:06:12,020
sort of building these generative models of different objects, and
来构建这些不同对象的生成模型

99
00:06:12,020 --> 00:06:16,970
using these ideas of convolution was also very, very exciting, but
使用这些卷积的概念非常非常激动人心 

100
00:06:16,970 --> 00:06:20,630
at the same time, it's still extremely hard to train these models, so.
但同时 训练这些模型还是很困难的

101
00:06:20,630 --> 00:06:21,488
>> How likely is work?
>>可行性有多高呢?

102
00:06:21,488 --> 00:06:22,720
>> Yes, how likely is work, right?
>>是啊 可行性有多高呢?

103
00:06:22,720 --> 00:06:24,990
And so we still have to figure out where.
我们还是要弄清楚怎么办

104
00:06:27,750 --> 00:06:31,014
On the other side, some of the recent work using variational auto-encoders,
另一方面 最近使用变分自动编码器的一些工作

105
00:06:31,015 --> 00:06:35,260
for example, which could be viewed as interactive versions of Bolzmann Machines.
例如 可以看成是可以看作是玻尔兹曼机的交互式版本

106
00:06:35,260 --> 00:06:40,491
We have figured out ways of training these modules, a work by Max Welling and
我们想出了训练这些模块的办法 是Max Welling

107
00:06:40,491 --> 00:06:44,800
Diederik Kingma, on using reparameterization tricks.
和Diederik Kingma的工作 或者使用重新参数化技巧

108
00:06:44,800 --> 00:06:50,720
And now we can use backpropagation algorithm within the stochastic system,
我们现在可以在随机系统内使用反向传播算法

109
00:06:50,720 --> 00:06:53,630
which is driving a lot of progress right now.
正在推动着各方面很大的进步

110
00:06:53,630 --> 00:06:59,199
But we haven't quite figured out how to do that in the case of Boltzmann Machines.
但是波尔兹曼机这边 我们还没想出应该怎么做到这点

111
00:06:59,199 --> 00:07:02,579
>> So that's actually a very interesting perspective I actually wasn't aware of,
>>这实际上是一个非常有趣的视角 我实际上并不知道

112
00:07:02,644 --> 00:07:07,727
which is that in an early era where computers were slower, that the RBM,
在计算机较慢的早期 RBM

113
00:07:07,770 --> 00:07:10,643
pre-training was really important,
预训练真的很重要

114
00:07:10,700 --> 00:07:17,920
it was only faster computation that drove switching to standard backprop.
只有计算硬件力量的上升才推动了到标准反向传播的转变

115
00:07:17,920 --> 00:07:21,370
In terms of the evolution of the community's thinking in deep learning and
在社区对深度学习思想的演变方面

116
00:07:21,370 --> 00:07:23,603
other topics, I know you spend a lot time thinking about this,
还有其他话题 我知道你花了很多时间思考这个

117
00:07:23,649 --> 00:07:28,870
the generative, unsupervised versus supervised approaches.
生成的 无监督方法 vs 监督的方法

118
00:07:28,870 --> 00:07:32,718
Do you share a bit about how your thinking about that has evolved over time?
你可以给我们分享一下 你的想法是如何随着时间推移演变的吗?

119
00:07:32,718 --> 00:07:37,407
>> Yeah, I think that's a really, I feel like it's a very important topic,
>>是的 我觉得这真是.. 非常重要的话题

120
00:07:37,407 --> 00:07:41,727
particularly if we think about unsupervised, semi-supervised or
特别是如果我们考虑无监督 半监督或

121
00:07:41,727 --> 00:07:46,493
generative models because to some extent a lot of successes that we've seen
生成模型.. 因为某种程度上我们最近看到的很多成功案例

122
00:07:46,493 --> 00:07:50,812
recently is due to supervised learning, and back in the early days,
是来自监督学习的 而在早期

123
00:07:50,812 --> 00:07:55,803
unsupervised learning was primarily viewed as unsupervised pre-training,
无监督学习主要被视为无监督预训练

124
00:07:55,803 --> 00:07:59,850
because we didn't know how to train these multi layer systems.
因为我们不知道如何训练这些多层系统

125
00:07:59,850 --> 00:08:04,320
And even today, if you're working in settings where you have lots and
即使在今天 如果你的系统面对的是

126
00:08:04,320 --> 00:08:08,488
lots of unlabeled data and a small fraction of labeled examples,
大量无标签数据和一小部分有标签数据的样本

127
00:08:08,488 --> 00:08:10,005
these unsupervised pre-training models,
这些无监督的预训练模型

128
00:08:10,058 --> 00:08:15,721
building these generative models, can help for supervised eyes.
建立这些生成模型 可以帮到监督训练

129
00:08:15,721 --> 00:08:20,863
So I think that a lot of us in the community, it kind of was the belief.
所以我觉我们社区里很多人 都抱有这样的信念

130
00:08:20,863 --> 00:08:25,838
When I started doing my PhD, was all about generative models and trying to learn
当我开始做博士后 做的都是生成模型 并试图学习

131
00:08:25,838 --> 00:08:30,900
these stacks of model because that was the only way for us to train these systems.
这些堆叠起来的模型 因为那时是训练这些系统的唯一途径

132
00:08:30,900 --> 00:08:35,720
Today, there is a lot of work right now in generative modeling.
今天 在生成建模领域里有很多工作

133
00:08:35,720 --> 00:08:38,530
If you look at Generative Adversarial Networks.
你们看看生成对抗网络

134
00:08:38,530 --> 00:08:40,397
If you look at variational auto-encoders,
你们看看变分自动编码器

135
00:08:40,397 --> 00:08:45,620
deep energy models is something that my lab is working on right now as well.
深度能量模型是我的实验室现在正在研究的

136
00:08:45,620 --> 00:08:50,660
I think it's very exciting research, but perhaps we haven't quite figured it out,
我认为这是非常令人兴奋的研究 但也许我们还没有把它弄清楚

137
00:08:50,660 --> 00:08:55,420
again, for many of you who are thinking about getting into deep learning field,
再次 对于正在考虑进入深度学习领域的许多人来说

138
00:08:55,420 --> 00:08:59,340
this is one area that's, I think we'll make a lot of progress in,
这个领域我觉的 我认为我们还会取得很大进展

139
00:08:59,340 --> 00:09:01,187
hopefully in the near future.
希望在不久的将来

140
00:09:01,187 --> 00:09:02,214
>> So, unsupervised learning.
>>所以无监督学习

141
00:09:02,214 --> 00:09:04,281
>> Unsupervised learning, right.
>>无监督的学习 对

142
00:09:04,281 --> 00:09:05,972
Or maybe you can think of it as unsupervised learning, or
或者你可以看成是无监督学习 或者

143
00:09:06,034 --> 00:09:12,886
semi-supervised learning, where you have, I give you some hints or some examples
半监督学习 其中我们会给一些提示或者例子

144
00:09:12,886 --> 00:09:18,240
of what different things mean and I throw you lots and lots of unlabeled data.
说明不同东西的含义 然后丢给你大量的无标签数据

145
00:09:18,240 --> 00:09:21,506
>> So that was actually a very important insight that in an earlier era of
>>所以这实际上是一个非常重要的见解 在深度学习的早期

146
00:09:21,506 --> 00:09:23,929
deep learning where computers where just slower,
那时计算机要慢一些

147
00:09:23,929 --> 00:09:27,763
the Restricted Boltzmann Machine and Deep Boltzmann Machine that was needed for
必需用到受限玻尔兹曼机和深玻尔兹曼机

148
00:09:27,763 --> 00:09:31,257
initializing the neural network weights, but as computers got faster,
初始化神经网络权重 但随着计算机变得更快

149
00:09:31,257 --> 00:09:34,700
straight backprop then started to work much better.
直接反向传播开始效果更好了

150
00:09:34,700 --> 00:09:39,220
So one other topic that I know you spend a lot of time thinking about is
还有一个话题我知道你花了很多时间去想的

151
00:09:39,220 --> 00:09:45,342
the supervised learning versus generative models, unsupervised learning approaches.
监督学习和生成模型 无监督学习的对比

152
00:09:45,342 --> 00:09:46,619
So how does your,
你的看法呢?

153
00:09:46,619 --> 00:09:51,920
tell me a bit about how your thinking on that debate has evolved over time?
可以告诉我们 关于这个争议的看法是怎么随时间演变的?

154
00:09:51,920 --> 00:09:56,780
>> I think that we all believe that we should be able to make progress there.
>>我们所有人都相信在那里可以取得进展

155
00:09:56,780 --> 00:10:03,990
It's just all the work on Boltz machines, variational auto-encoders, GANs.
就是这些玻尔兹曼机 变分自动编码器 GAN 所有工作

156
00:10:03,990 --> 00:10:07,582
You think a lot of these models as generative models, but
你认为这里很多模型都是生成模型 但是

157
00:10:07,628 --> 00:10:13,222
we haven't quite figured it out how to really make them work
我们还没有弄清楚如何真正让它们变得可行

158
00:10:13,223 --> 00:10:16,654
and how can you make use of large moments.
如何利用大量数据

159
00:10:16,654 --> 00:10:20,462
And even for, I see a lot of in IT sector,
即使对于.. 我在IT业界见到很多

160
00:10:23,002 --> 00:10:25,799
companies have lots and lots of data, lots of unlabeled data,
公司有大量的数据 大量的未标记的数据

161
00:10:25,849 --> 00:10:28,339
lots of efforts for going through annotations
有很多注释数据的努力

162
00:10:29,916 --> 00:10:33,350
because that's the only way for us to make progress right now.
因为现在这是取得进展的唯一途径

163
00:10:33,350 --> 00:10:37,618
And it seems like we should be able to make use of unlabeled data
我们应该能够利用这些无标签数据

164
00:10:37,667 --> 00:10:40,200
because it's just abundance of it.
因为实在太多了

165
00:10:40,200 --> 00:10:42,190
And we haven't quite figured out how to do that yet.
我们还没弄清楚如何做到

166
00:10:44,020 --> 00:10:48,300
>> So you mentioned for people wanting to enter deep learning research,
>>所以你提到 对于要进入深度学习领域的人

167
00:10:48,300 --> 00:10:50,920
unsupervised learning is exciting area.
无监督学习是令人兴奋的领域

168
00:10:50,920 --> 00:10:54,240
Today there are a lot of people wanting to enter deep learning,
今天有很多人想进入深度学习

169
00:10:54,240 --> 00:10:57,688
either research or applied work, so for this global community,
做研究或应用工作 对于这个全球性的社区来说

170
00:10:57,688 --> 00:11:01,490
either research or applied work, what advice would you have?
要做研究或应用工作 你会有什么建议?

171
00:11:01,490 --> 00:11:06,680
>> Yes, I think that one of the key advices I think I
>>是的 我认为最关键的建议之一

172
00:11:06,680 --> 00:11:10,620
should give is people entering that field,
要给进入这个领域新人的建议

173
00:11:10,620 --> 00:11:14,210
I would encourage them to just try different things and
我会鼓励他们尝试不同的事情 

174
00:11:14,210 --> 00:11:18,280
not be afraid to try new things, and not be afraid to try to innovate.
不要害怕尝试新事物 不要害怕尝试创新

175
00:11:18,280 --> 00:11:20,135
I can give you one example,
我可以给你一个例子

176
00:11:20,135 --> 00:11:24,975
which is when I was a graduate student, we were looking at neural nets,
当我是研究生时 我们正在研究神经网络

177
00:11:24,975 --> 00:11:29,680
and these are highly non-convex systems that are hard to optimize.
这些是非常难以优化的非凸系统

178
00:11:29,680 --> 00:11:33,780
And I remember talking to my friends within the optimization community.
我还记得在优化社区的朋友聊天

179
00:11:33,780 --> 00:11:38,711
And the feedback was always that, well, there's no way you can solve these problems
他们的反馈总是这样 这些问题你们解决不了的

180
00:11:38,712 --> 00:11:41,600
because these are non-convex, we don't understand optimization,
因为这些是非凸的 你们不了解优化

181
00:11:41,600 --> 00:11:46,470
how could you ever even do that compared to doing convex optimization?
凸优化都那么难做 你们还要做非凸优化?

182
00:11:46,470 --> 00:11:51,225
And it was surprising, because in our lab we never really
然后令人惊讶的是 在我们的实验室里

183
00:11:51,225 --> 00:11:55,520
cared that much about those specific problems.
我们从来不关心这么具体的问题

184
00:11:55,520 --> 00:11:58,005
We're thinking about how can we optimize and
我们正在考虑如何优化

185
00:11:58,005 --> 00:11:59,960
whether we can get interesting results.
看看能否获得有趣的结果

186
00:11:59,960 --> 00:12:04,150
And that effectively was driving the community so
这种心态有效地推动了社区的发展

187
00:12:04,150 --> 00:12:09,038
we we're not scared, maybe to some extent because we were
我们没有害怕 也许一定程度上是因为

188
00:12:09,038 --> 00:12:13,444
lacking actually the theory behind optimization.
我们没有认真研究优化背后的理论

189
00:12:13,444 --> 00:12:16,123
But I would encourage people to just try and
但我会鼓励人们尝试

190
00:12:16,123 --> 00:12:19,200
not be afraid to try to tackle hard problems.
不要害怕 要试试挑战一些困难的问题

191
00:12:19,200 --> 00:12:22,616
>> Yeah, and I remember you once said, don't learn to code just into high level
>>是的 我记得你曾经说过 不要只学编写高层次的

192
00:12:22,616 --> 00:12:25,740
deep learning frameworks, but actually understand deep learning.
深度学习框架 应该实际了解深度学习的底层

193
00:12:25,740 --> 00:12:26,370
>> Yes, that's right.
>>是的 没错

194
00:12:26,370 --> 00:12:31,309
I think that it's one of the things that I try to do when I teach a deep learning class
我认为 当我教深度学习课程时 我一直尝试去做的是

195
00:12:31,310 --> 00:12:35,182
is, one of the homeworks, I'm asking people to actually code
在作业里 我要求人们实际编写

196
00:12:35,182 --> 00:12:39,323
backpropogation algorithms for convolutional neural networks.
卷积神经网络的反向传播算法 **

197
00:12:39,323 --> 00:12:43,379
And it's painful, but at the same time, if you do it once,
那很痛苦 但如果你做过一次之后

198
00:12:43,379 --> 00:12:48,510
you'll really understand how these systems operate, and how they work.
你就真正了解这些系统背后的运作原理

199
00:12:49,540 --> 00:12:53,223
And how you can efficiently implement them on GPU, and
以及如何在GPU上高效实现它们

200
00:12:53,223 --> 00:12:58,266
I think it's important for you to, when you go into research or industry,
我认为 当你进入研究或工业界时 最重要的是

201
00:12:58,266 --> 00:13:03,013
you have a really good understanding of what these systems are doing.
你对这些系统实际在做的事情要有很深入的理解

202
00:13:03,013 --> 00:13:05,450
So it's important, I think.
所以这很重要 我想

203
00:13:05,450 --> 00:13:09,160
>> Since you have both academic experience as professor, and
>>既然你有学术界当教授的经验

204
00:13:09,160 --> 00:13:13,730
corporate experience, I'm curious, if someone wants to enter deep learning,
也有企业经验 我很好奇 如果有人想进入深度学习领域

205
00:13:13,730 --> 00:13:18,290
what are the pros and cons of doing a PhD versus joining a company?
读博和进入公司各有什么利弊?

206
00:13:18,290 --> 00:13:21,290
>> Yeah, I think that's actually a very good question.
>>是的 我认为这其实是个很好的问题

207
00:13:22,660 --> 00:13:25,780
In my particular lab, I have a mix of students.
特别是在我的实验室里 我有各种背景的学生

208
00:13:25,780 --> 00:13:28,850
Some students want to go and take an academic route.
有些学生想去走学术路线

209
00:13:28,850 --> 00:13:32,041
Some students want to go and take an industry route.
有些学生想走工业路线

210
00:13:32,041 --> 00:13:38,290
And it's becoming very challenging because you can do amazing research in industry,
现在变得非常有挑战性了 因为在工业里你也能做出一流的研究

211
00:13:38,290 --> 00:13:41,910
and you can also do amazing research in academia.
你也可以在学术界做出一流的研究

212
00:13:41,910 --> 00:13:46,480
But in terms of pros and cons, in academia,
但利弊方面 在学术界

213
00:13:46,480 --> 00:13:53,180
I feel like you have more freedom to work on long-term problems, or if you think
我觉得你有更多的自由来处理长期的问题 或者如果你喜欢

214
00:13:53,180 --> 00:13:59,150
about some crazy problem, you can work on it, so you have a little bit more freedom.
思考一些疯狂的问题 你想自由自在的工作 去研究

215
00:13:59,150 --> 00:14:03,940
At the same time the research that you're doing in industry is also very exciting
与此同时 在企业里的研究也很激动人心

216
00:14:03,940 --> 00:14:08,920
because in many cases with your research you can impact
因为很多情况下 你的研究可以直接

217
00:14:08,920 --> 00:14:14,470
millions of users if you develop a core AI technology.
影响到数百万用户 比如开发一个核心的AI技术

218
00:14:14,470 --> 00:14:19,473
And obviously, within the industry you have much more
显然 在企业里你有更多的计算资源

219
00:14:19,473 --> 00:14:26,120
resources in terms of Compute, and be able to do really amazing things.
能够做到非常惊人的事情

220
00:14:26,120 --> 00:14:30,260
So there are pluses and minuses, it really depends on what you want to do.
所以都有优缺点 这真的取决于你想做什么

221
00:14:30,260 --> 00:14:32,630
And right now it's interesting,
现在环境非常有趣

222
00:14:32,630 --> 00:14:36,860
very interesting environment where academics move to industry, and
有学术界转向工业界的

223
00:14:36,860 --> 00:14:40,450
then folks from industry move to academia, but not as much.
还有工业界的转向学术界的 虽然更少一点

224
00:14:40,450 --> 00:14:45,756
And so it's, it's very exciting times.
但现在是非常令人兴奋的时代

225
00:14:45,756 --> 00:14:49,244
>> It sounds like academic machine learning is great and corporate machine
>> 听起来学术界机器学习不错 企业界

226
00:14:49,244 --> 00:14:52,800
learning is great, and the most important thing is just jump in, right?
机器学习也很棒 最重要的是跳进去 对吧?

227
00:14:52,800 --> 00:14:54,070
Either one, just jump in.
选一个 跳进去

228
00:14:54,070 --> 00:14:58,870
>> It really depends on your preferences because you can do amazing research in
>>这真的取决于你的喜好 因为你在什么地方都可以

229
00:14:58,870 --> 00:14:59,800
either place.
做出惊人的研究

230
00:14:59,800 --> 00:15:04,260
>> So you've mentioned unsupervised learning is one exciting frontier for research.
>>所以你提到无监督学习是一个令人兴奋的研究前沿

231
00:15:04,260 --> 00:15:08,850
Are there other areas that you consider exciting frontiers for research?
你觉得还有其他领域你觉得是令人兴奋的研究前沿吗?

232
00:15:08,850 --> 00:15:09,700
>> Yeah, absolutely.
>>是的 当然了

233
00:15:09,700 --> 00:15:12,520
I think that what I see now, in the community right now,
我想我现在看到 在现在的社区里看到

234
00:15:12,520 --> 00:15:16,010
particularly in deep learning community, is there are a few trends.
特别是在深度学习社区 有几个趋势

235
00:15:17,400 --> 00:15:20,390
One particular area I think is really exciting
我认为有一个特别的趋于特别令人兴奋

236
00:15:20,390 --> 00:15:22,909
is the area of deep reinforcement learning.
是深度加强学习领域

237
00:15:24,110 --> 00:15:28,940
Because we were able to figure out how we could train agents in virtual worlds.
因为我们能够弄清楚 我们如何在虚拟世界中训练代理程序

238
00:15:28,940 --> 00:15:33,633
And this is something that in just the last couple of years, you see a lot,
这是过去几年里 我们看到很多的

239
00:15:33,633 --> 00:15:35,391
of lot of progress, of how can we scale these systems, 
有很多进展 我们是如何把这些系统推广到更大规模上

240
00:15:35,470 --> 00:15:37,188
how can we develop new algorithms,
我们如何开发新的算法

241
00:15:37,238 --> 00:15:40,820
how can we get agents to communicate to each other, with each other,
如何让代理程序互相沟通

242
00:15:40,885 --> 00:15:46,731
and I think that that area is, and in general,
我觉得这个领域 一般来说

243
00:15:46,731 --> 00:15:52,004
the settings where you're interacting with the environment is super exciting.
你能和环境交互这些场合是非常激动人心的

244
00:15:52,004 --> 00:15:55,230
The other area that I think is really exciting as
我认为还有另一个领域令人兴奋

245
00:15:55,230 --> 00:16:00,720
well is the area of reasoning and natural language understanding.
就是推理和自然语言理解的领域

246
00:16:00,720 --> 00:16:03,810
So can we build dialogue-based systems?
我们可以建立基于对话的系统吗?

247
00:16:03,810 --> 00:16:09,120
Can we build systems that can reason, that can read text and
我们可以建立能够推理 能够读懂文本的系统

248
00:16:09,120 --> 00:16:12,730
be able to answer questions intelligently.
能够智能回答问题的系统吗?

249
00:16:12,730 --> 00:16:17,670
I think this is something that a lot of research is focusing on right now.
我认为这是现在很多研究的重点

250
00:16:17,670 --> 00:16:21,832
And then there's another sort of sub-area also is
然后还有另一类子领域也是

251
00:16:21,832 --> 00:16:26,382
this area of being able to learn from few examples.
这个领域可以从很少的几个例子中学到知识

252
00:16:26,382 --> 00:16:31,210
So typically people think of it as one-shot learning or transfer learning,
所以通常人们说是一次学习或迁移学习

253
00:16:31,210 --> 00:16:36,970
a setting where you learn something about the world,
你从环境习得某种东西

254
00:16:36,970 --> 00:16:41,500
and I throw you a new task at you and you can solve this task very quickly.
然后我给你一个新的任务 你可以很快地解决这个任务

255
00:16:41,500 --> 00:16:46,770
Much like humans do without requiring lots and lots of labeled examples.
就像人类一样 而不需要很多很多带标签的样本

256
00:16:46,770 --> 00:16:52,338
And so this is something that's, a lot of us in the community are trying to figure out
所以这个概念是我们社区里很多人都想弄清楚的

257
00:16:52,339 --> 00:16:58,010
how we can do that and how can we come closer to human-like learning abilities.
我们应该如何做到 如何达到接近人类的学习能力

258
00:16:58,010 --> 00:17:00,790
>> Thank you, Rus, for sharing all the comments and insights.
>>谢谢Rus分享所有的评论和见解

259
00:17:00,790 --> 00:17:02,205
That was interesting to see,
更有趣的是

260
00:17:02,205 --> 00:17:04,870
hearing the story of your early days doing this as well.
能听到你的早年故事

261
00:17:04,870 --> 00:17:05,660
>> [LAUGH]. Thanks, Andrew, yeah.
>> [笑] 谢谢 Andrew 是的

262
00:17:07,100 --> 00:17:07,800
Thanks for having me,
谢谢你的采访

