1
00:00:00,000 --> 00:00:02,357
好 我想这是一个激动人心的视频
All right I think that's been an exciting video 

2
00:00:02,430 --> 00:00:05,542
在此视频中 你将看到梯度下降算法的具体实现
in this video you see  how to implement gradient descent

3
00:00:05,543 --> 00:00:08,158
如何处理单隐层神经网络
for your neural network with one hidden layer

4
00:00:08,214 --> 00:00:12,492
在这个视频中 我会给你提供所需的方程
In this video I'm going to just give you the equations you need to implement 

5
00:00:12,492 --> 00:00:15,830
来实现反向传播 或者说梯度下降算法
in order to get back propagation or to get gradient descent working 

6
00:00:15,830 --> 00:00:18,211
在下一个视频
and then in the video after this one 

7
00:00:18,255 --> 00:00:20,429
我会介绍更多推导
I'll give some more intuition about 

8
00:00:20,476 --> 00:00:23,972
介绍为什么这特定的几个方程是精准的方程
why these particular equations are the accurate equations 

9
00:00:24,022 --> 00:00:28,092
可以针对你的神经网络实现梯度下降的正确方程
or the correct equations for computing the gradients you need for your neural network 

10
00:00:28,902 --> 00:00:31,430
所以这是你的单隐层神经网络
so your neural network with a single hidden layer for now 

11
00:00:31,485 --> 00:00:38,917
会有这些参数W^[1] b^[1] W^[2]和b^[2]
will have parameters W^[1] b^[1] W^[2] and b^[2] 

12
00:00:38,993 --> 00:00:48,264
要记住你还有个n_x 有时也用n^[0]表示有那么多输入特征
and so as a reminder if you have n_x, or alternatively n^[0] input features,

13
00:00:48,265 --> 00:00:56,009
n^[1]个隐藏单元 n^[2]个输出单元
and n^[1] hidden units and n^[2] output units

14
00:00:56,009 --> 00:00:59,249
在我们的例子中 我们只介绍过n^[2]等于1的情况
in our example so far we've only have n^[2] equals 1 

15
00:00:59,311 --> 00:01:05,463
那么矩阵W^[1]维度就是(n^[1],n^[0])
then the matrix W^[1] will be n^[1] by n^[0] 

16
00:01:05,514 --> 00:01:08,592
b^[1]就是n^[1]维向量
b^[1] will be an n^[1] dimensional vector 

17
00:01:08,645 --> 00:01:13,946
所以你可以把它写成是(n^[1],1)维向量 就是一个列向量
so you can write that n^[1] by 1 dimensional matrix, really a column vector

18
00:01:13,946 --> 00:01:18,095
W^[2]的维度是(n^[2],n^[1])
the dimensions of W^[2] will be n^[2] by n^[1]

19
00:01:18,095 --> 00:01:26,000
然后b^[2]的维度就是(n^[2],1)
and the dimension of b^[2] will be n^[2] by 1 right 

20
00:01:26,056 --> 00:01:28,859
到目前为止 我们只见过n^[2]=1的例子
where again so far we've only seen examples where n^[2] is equal to 1 

21
00:01:28,904 --> 00:01:31,462
你只有一个隐藏单元
where you have just one a single hidden unit 

22
00:01:32,909 --> 00:01:39,048
你还有一个神经网络的成本函数
so you also have a cost function for a neural network 

23
00:01:39,114 --> 00:01:41,063
目前而言 我假设
and for now I'm just going to assume that 

24
00:01:41,118 --> 00:01:42,913
你在做二元分类
you're doing binary classification 

25
00:01:43,712 --> 00:01:49,790
在这种情况下 你的参数的成本是这么定的
so in that case the cost of your parameters as follows 

26
00:01:49,790 --> 00:01:56,545
就是1/m 然后对损失函数求平均
is going to be 1 over m of the average of that loss function 

27
00:01:56,603 --> 00:02:02,588
所以这里L表示当你的神经网络预测出y帽时的损失函数
and so L here is the loss when your new network predicts y hat, right 

28
00:02:02,641 --> 00:02:06,637
所以这其实是个a^[2] 然后基本真值标签等于y
this is really a a^[2] when the ground truth labels should equal to y

29
00:02:06,637 --> 00:02:08,292
如果你在做二元分类
and if you're doing binary classification 

30
00:02:08,354 --> 00:02:13,165
损失函数可能就和之前做logistic回归完全一样
the loss function can be exactly what you use for logistic regression earlier 

31
00:02:13,165 --> 00:02:18,761
所以要训练参数 你的算法需要做梯度下降
so to train the parameters your algorithms you need to perform gradient descent 

32
00:02:19,738 --> 00:02:24,363
在训练神经网络时 随机初始化参数很重要
when training a neural network, it is important to initialize the parameters randomly 

33
00:02:24,423 --> 00:02:25,976
而不是初始化成全零
rather than into all zeros 

34
00:02:26,035 --> 00:02:28,444
我们稍后会看到为什么会这样
we'll see later why that's the case 

35
00:02:28,516 --> 00:02:30,608
当你把参数初始化成某些值之后
but after initializing the parameter to something 

36
00:02:30,671 --> 00:02:33,856
每个梯度下降循环都会计算预测值
each loop of gradient descent would compute the predictions 

37
00:02:35,038 --> 00:02:41,223
所以基本上 你要计算i=1到m的预测值y帽
so you basically compute you know y hat i for i equals 1 through m say 

38
00:02:42,046 --> 00:02:44,272
然后你需要计算导数 
and then you need to compute the derivative 

39
00:02:44,335 --> 00:02:47,881
所以你需要计算dW^[1] 
so you need to compute dW^[1] 

40
00:02:47,919 --> 00:02:54,118
然后我们看到成本函数对参数W^[1]的导数
and that's we see the derivative of the cost function with respect to the parameter W^[1] 

41
00:02:54,174 --> 00:02:56,287
你需要计算另一个变量 
you need to compute another variable 

42
00:02:56,346 --> 00:02:58,029
就是db^[1]
which is going to call db^[1]

43
00:02:58,091 --> 00:03:02,239
这是你的成本函数 对变量b^[1]的
which is the derivative or the slope of your cost function

44
00:03:02,240 --> 00:03:06,139
导数或者说斜率
with respect to the variable b^[1] and so on

45
00:03:06,193 --> 00:03:09,424
类似 还有对其他参数 W^[2]和b^[2]的导数
similarly for the other parameters W^[2] and b^[2]

46
00:03:09,469 --> 00:03:12,580
然后梯度下降最后会更新..
and then finally the gradient descent update would be 

47
00:03:12,633 --> 00:03:17,455
将W^[1]更新成W^[1] - α 乘以..
to update W^[1] as W^[1] minus alpha 

48
00:03:17,519 --> 00:03:21,091
学习率乘以d w^[1] 
the learning rate times d w^[1] 

49
00:03:21,092 --> 00:03:23,632
然后b^[1]更新成
b^[1] gets updated as

50
00:03:23,689 --> 00:03:31,773
b^[1]减去学习率乘以d b^[1] 然后W^[2]和b^[2]也类似
b^[1] minus the learning rate times d  as similarly for W^[2] and b^[2] 

51
00:03:32,482 --> 00:03:35,418
有时候我用:= 有时候用=
and sometimes I use colon equals and sometimes equals 

52
00:03:35,466 --> 00:03:37,862
用哪种符号都行
as either either the notation works fine 

53
00:03:37,929 --> 00:03:40,610
所以这是梯度下降的一次迭代循环
and so this would be one iteration of gradient descent 

54
00:03:40,657 --> 00:03:42,775
然后你重复这些步骤很多次
and then your repeat this some number of times 

55
00:03:42,822 --> 00:03:44,760
直到你的参数看起来在收敛
until your parameters look like they're converging 

56
00:03:44,815 --> 00:03:48,760
在以前的视频里 我讨论过如何计算预测值
so in previous videos we talked about how to compute the predictions 

57
00:03:48,820 --> 00:03:50,097
如何计算输出
how to compute the outputs 

58
00:03:50,161 --> 00:03:52,734
我们也看到如何用向量化方式去做
and we saw how to do that in a vectorized way as well 

59
00:03:52,812 --> 00:03:57,499
所以关键在于 如何计算这些偏导项
so the key is to know how to compute these partial derivative terms 

60
00:03:57,586 --> 00:04:03,029
dW^[1] db^[1]以及导数dW^[2]和db^[2]
the d w^[1] d b^[1] as well as the derivatives dw^[2] and d b^[2]

61
00:04:03,029 --> 00:04:07,932
我想做的是 给出你需要的公式
so what I'd like to do is just give you the equations you need 

62
00:04:07,992 --> 00:04:10,433
求这些导数的公式
in order to compute these derivatives 

63
00:04:10,505 --> 00:04:12,918
而在下一个视频
and I'll defer to the next video 

64
00:04:12,975 --> 00:04:16,564
这是一个可选的视频 会深入介绍
which is an optional video to go great turn to greater into depth about 

65
00:04:16,629 --> 00:04:18,696
我们是怎么想出这些公式的
how we came up with those formulas 

66
00:04:18,768 --> 00:04:24,725
所以我再总结一下 正向传播的方程
so then just summarize again the equations for forward propagation 

67
00:04:24,800 --> 00:04:32,504
所以你有z^[1]等于W^[1] X + b^[1]
so you have z^[1] equals w^[1] X plus b^[1] 

68
00:04:32,504 --> 00:04:38,606
然后A^[1]等于该层中的激活函数
and then A^[1] equals the activation function in that layer 

69
00:04:38,666 --> 00:04:42,247
逐个元素作用到z^[1]上
applied element-wise z^[1]

70
00:04:42,247 --> 00:04:50,315
然后z^[2]等于W^[2] a^[1] + b^[2]
and then z^[2] equals w^[2] A^[1] plus b^[2] 

71
00:04:50,315 --> 00:04:55,285
最后这些公式都对整个训练集向量化
and then finally these are all vectorize across your training set right 

72
00:04:55,285 --> 00:05:00,536
A^[2]等于g^[2] (Z^[2])
A^[2] is equal to g^[2](z^[2])

73
00:05:00,536 --> 00:05:03,345
再次 现在假设我们在做二元分类
Again for now if we assume you're doing binary classification 

74
00:05:03,409 --> 00:05:06,918
那么这个激活函数其实应该是sigmoid函数
then this activation function really should be the sigmoid function 

75
00:05:06,978 --> 00:05:08,779
我就把它丢到这里
So I'm just throw that in here 

76
00:05:08,822 --> 00:05:10,692
所以这是正向传播 
so that's the forward propagation 

77
00:05:10,745 --> 00:05:14,495
或者你的神经网络从左到右正向传播计算
or the left-to-right forward computation for your neural network 

78
00:05:14,551 --> 00:05:16,441
接下来我们来计算导数
Next let's compute the derivatives

79
00:05:16,502 --> 00:05:20,973
所以这是反向传播的步骤 
so this is the back propagation step

80
00:05:22,250 --> 00:05:30,253
需要计算dz^[2] = A^[2]减去Y的基本真值
then it computes d z^[2] equals A^[2] minus the ground truth of Y 

81
00:05:30,636 --> 00:05:34,834
这里要提醒一下 这些都针对所有样本向量化
and just just as a reminder all this is vectorize across example 

82
00:05:34,895 --> 00:05:39,821
所以矩阵Y是1×m矩阵
so the matrix Y is this some 1 by m matrix 

83
00:05:39,870 --> 00:05:44,023
它将m个样本横向堆叠起来
that lists all of your m examples stacked horizontally 

84
00:05:44,083 --> 00:05:50,084
那么结果这个dW^[2]等于这个
then it turns out dw^[2] is equal to this 

85
00:05:50,881 --> 00:05:58,068
实际上 这三个方程和logistic回归的梯度下降
in fact um these first three equations are very similar to gradient descent 

86
00:05:58,127 --> 00:05:59,486
非常相似
for logistic regression, 

87
00:05:59,544 --> 00:06:07,922
然后 axis=1, keepdims = True
comma, axis is equals 1 comma um keepdims = True

88
00:06:08,564 --> 00:06:15,431
这里有个细节 np.sum是Python的numpy命令
and just a little detail this np.sum is a Python numpy commands 

89
00:06:15,494 --> 00:06:20,044
用来对矩阵的一个维度求和
for summing across one dimension of a matrix in this case 

90
00:06:20,044 --> 00:06:25,326
水平相加求和 而加上开关keepdims 就是防止python
summing horizontally and what keepdims does is it prevents python

91
00:06:25,382 --> 00:06:30,614
直接输出这些古怪的秩为1的数组
from outputting one of those funny rank 1 arrays

92
00:06:30,698 --> 00:06:33,189
它的维度是(n, ..)
where the dimensions was you know n comma 

93
00:06:33,253 --> 00:06:35,580
所以加上keepdims = true
so by having keepdims = true 

94
00:06:35,631 --> 00:06:43,336
确保Python输出的是矩阵 对于db^[2]这个向量输出的维度是(n,1)
this ensures that Python outputs, for d b^[2] a vector that is some n by one,

95
00:06:43,336 --> 00:06:46,864
其实 技术上 这应该是(n^[2],1)
in fact, technically this will be I guess n^[2] by 1

96
00:06:46,928 --> 00:06:49,539
这种情况下 就是(1,1) 一个数字
in this case is just a one by one number 

97
00:06:49,589 --> 00:06:51,031
所以也许没关系 
so maybe it doesn't matter 

98
00:06:52,306 --> 00:06:55,368
但以后我们会看到真正需要考虑多维的情况
but later on we'll see when it really matters

99
00:06:56,075 --> 00:06:59,337
到目前为止 我们所做的与Logistic回归非常相似
so far what we've done is very similar to logistic regression 

100
00:06:59,398 --> 00:07:03,599
但当你开始计算反向传播时
but now as you compute continue to run back propagation 

101
00:07:04,730 --> 00:07:16,235
你要计算这个 .. dz^[2]·g^[1]'(z^[1])
you would compute this d z^[2] times g^[1] prime of z^[1]

102
00:07:17,002 --> 00:07:20,453
所以这个量g^[1]'是
so this quantity g^[1]' is the derivative of 

103
00:07:20,504 --> 00:07:23,553
你用的隐藏层的激活函数的导数
whatever was the activation function you use for the hidden layer 

104
00:07:23,607 --> 00:07:26,509
对于输出层我假设 
and for the output layer I assume that 

105
00:07:26,566 --> 00:07:29,354
你正在使用Sigmoid函数进行二元分类
you're doing binary classification with the sigmoid function 

106
00:07:29,414 --> 00:07:32,446
这已经包含在dz^[2]的式子里了
so that's already baked into that formula for d z^[2]

107
00:07:32,446 --> 00:07:37,016
这是逐个元素乘积
and this times is a element-wise product 

108
00:07:37,790 --> 00:07:43,278
所以现在这里有个n^[1]×m矩阵
so this year there's going to be an n^[1] by m matrix 

109
00:07:43,341 --> 00:07:48,131
而这里这个逐个元素的导数
and this here this element wise derivative thing 

110
00:07:48,186 --> 00:07:51,386
就是一个n^[1]×m矩阵
is also going to be an n^[1] by m matrix 

111
00:07:51,386 --> 00:07:55,451
所以这个*乘积是两个矩阵的逐元素乘积
and so this times there is an element wise product of two matrices 

112
00:07:56,474 --> 00:08:05,716
最后dW^[1]等于那个 db^[1]等于这个
then finally dW^[1] is equal to that and d b^[1] is equal to this 

113
00:08:07,671 --> 00:08:20,303
然后np.sum dz^[1] x=1, keepdims = True
np.sum d z^[1] x is equals 1, keepdims = True

114
00:08:20,875 --> 00:08:26,366
之前如果n^[2]=1 那么keepdims可能没那么重要
so whereas previously the keepdims maybe matter less if n^[2] is equal to 1

115
00:08:26,412 --> 00:08:28,981
这只是1×1 是一个实数
so it's just a one by one thing is there's a real number 

116
00:08:29,040 --> 00:08:36,312
而这里db^[1]是个n^[1]×1向量
here d b^[1] will be a n^[1] by 1 vector 

117
00:08:36,360 --> 00:08:40,530
所以如果你想用Python 用np.sum输出这个维度的矩阵
and so you want Python you want np.sum output something of this dimension 

118
00:08:40,585 --> 00:08:45,030
而不是形式很怪的一维数组
rather than a funny looking one array of that dimension 

119
00:08:45,095 --> 00:08:49,216
那样可能会把后面的计算步骤搞乱
which could end up messing up some of your later calculations 

120
00:08:49,296 --> 00:08:52,525
还有一种办法是不需要用keepdims参数
the other way would be to not have to keepdims parameters 

121
00:08:52,585 --> 00:09:00,767
但要显式的调用reshape 把np.sum输出结果写成矩阵形式
but to explicitly call in a reshape to reshape the output of np.sum into this dimension 

122
00:09:02,244 --> 00:09:04,640
就是你希望db出现的矩阵形式
which you would like d b to have

123
00:09:04,640 --> 00:09:07,259
所以这是正向传播 一共有
so that was forward propagation in,

124
00:09:07,317 --> 00:09:11,288
四个方程 而反向传播
And I guess four equations and back propagation in 

125
00:09:11,358 --> 00:09:12,867
我想有六个方程
I guess six equations 

126
00:09:12,954 --> 00:09:15,232
我现在就直接写出这些式子
I know I just wrote down these equations 

127
00:09:15,286 --> 00:09:17,698
但在下一个可选视频里
but in the next optional video 

128
00:09:17,749 --> 00:09:20,273
我们来讲讲一些灵感来源
let's go over some intuitions for 

129
00:09:20,316 --> 00:09:24,363
我们是如何导出反向传播算法的六个式子的
how the six equations for the back propagation algorithm were derived 

130
00:09:24,432 --> 00:09:26,346
你们可以看看 也可以不看
please feel free to watch that or not 

131
00:09:26,405 --> 00:09:28,684
不过总之 如果你要实现这些算法
but either way if you implement these algorithms 

132
00:09:28,743 --> 00:09:32,754
你必须能够正确执行正向和反向传播运算
you will have a correct implementation of for forward prop and backprop

133
00:09:32,754 --> 00:09:35,598
你必须能够计算所有需要的导数 
and you'll be able to compute the derivatives you need 

134
00:09:35,652 --> 00:09:39,745
用梯度下降法来学习神经网络的参数
in order to apply gradient descent to learn the parameters of your neural network 

135
00:09:39,807 --> 00:09:43,151
你也可以直接实现这个算法
it is possible to implement this algorihtms

136
00:09:43,209 --> 00:09:45,779
让它工作起来 而不去了解很多微积分知识
and get it to work without deeply understanding the calculus 

137
00:09:45,844 --> 00:09:49,126
有很多成功的深度学习从业者是这样做的
a lot of successful deep learning practitioners do so 

138
00:09:49,126 --> 00:09:52,399
但如果你想了解一下 可以看下一个视频
but if you want you can also watch the next video 

139
00:09:52,458 --> 00:09:57,011
了解这些式子推导的直觉
just to get a bit more intuition about the derivation of these of these equations

