1
00:00:00,000 --> 00:00:03,180
在上一个视频中 你们看到了如何在
In the last video, you saw how to compute a prediction

2
00:00:03,180 --> 00:00:06,315
已知单个训练样本时 计算神经网络的预测
on a neural network given a single training example.

3
00:00:06,315 --> 00:00:11,100
在这个视频中 你们可以看到如何将不同训练样本向量化
In this video, you see how to vectorize across multiple training examples,

4
00:00:11,100 --> 00:00:15,114
输出结果和Logistic回归很相似
and the outcome will be quite similar to what you saw for logistic regression,

5
00:00:15,114 --> 00:00:19,651
如何将不同训练样本堆叠起来 放入矩阵的各列呢?
whereby stacking up different training examples in different columns of a matrix,

6
00:00:19,651 --> 00:00:23,224
你可以把上一个视频中的方程拿过来
you'll be able to take the equations you had from the previous video,

7
00:00:23,224 --> 00:00:25,230
然后稍微修改一下
and with very little modification,

8
00:00:25,230 --> 00:00:29,843
把输入方式变一下 让神经网络几乎同时
change them to make the neural network compute the outputs on all the examples,

9
00:00:29,843 --> 00:00:31,581
计算所有样本的输出
pretty much all at the same time.

10
00:00:31,581 --> 00:00:34,694
我们看看具体怎么做
So let's see the details of how to do that.

11
00:00:34,694 --> 00:00:38,785
这些是上一个视频的4个方程
These were the four equations we had from the previous video of

12
00:00:38,820 --> 00:00:41,226
如何计算z^[1],a^[1],z^[2]和a^[2]
how you compute z^[1], a^[1], z^[2] and a^[2].

13
00:00:41,760 --> 00:00:43,293
它们告诉你
And they tell you how,

14
00:00:43,351 --> 00:00:46,230
对于输入的特征向量x
given an input feature vector x,

15
00:00:46,284 --> 00:00:53,801
对于这单个训练样本 你可以用它们生成一个a^[2] = y_帽
you can use them to generate a^[2] equals y_hat for a single training example.

16
00:00:54,777 --> 00:00:57,593
现在 如果你有m个训练样本
Now, if you have m training examples,

17
00:00:57,688 --> 00:01:00,277
你可能需要重复这个过程 比如说
you need to repeat this process for, say,

18
00:01:00,323 --> 00:01:08,115
第一个训练样本 x^[1]来计算y_帽^[1]
the first training example x_superscript_round_brackets_1 to compute y_hat^[1],

19
00:01:08,162 --> 00:01:10,922
那是对你第一个训练样本的预测
that's the prediction on your first training example.

20
00:01:10,960 --> 00:01:16,142
然后x^[2] 用来生成预测y_帽 [2]
Then x^[2], use that to generate prediction y_hat[2],

21
00:01:16,205 --> 00:01:22,320
之类的 一直到x^[m] 生成预测y_帽^[m]
and so on down to x^[m] to generate prediction y_hat^[m].

22
00:01:22,367 --> 00:01:27,157
所以 要用激活函数来表示这些式子
And so, in order to write this with the activation function notation as well,

23
00:01:27,226 --> 00:01:32,071
我要把它写成a^[2](1)
I'm going to write this as a^[2]_square_brackets_round_bracket_1.

24
00:01:32,132 --> 00:01:38,726
这是[2](2)和a^[2](m)
This is [2](2) and a^[2](m).

25
00:01:38,794 --> 00:01:46,212
所以这个符号 a^[2](i)
So this notation, a_square_bracket_2_round_bracket_i,

26
00:01:46,212 --> 00:01:51,847
圆括号里的i表示指训练样本i
the round bracket_i refers to training example i

27
00:01:51,922 --> 00:01:57,140
方括号指的是第二层
and the square bracket_2 refers to layer two.

28
00:01:58,421 --> 00:02:02,555
这就是方括号圆括号写法的意义
So that's how the square bracket and the round bracket indices work.

29
00:02:03,331 --> 00:02:07,764
所以这表明如果你有一个没有向量化的实现 
And so this suggests that if you have an unvectorized implementation

30
00:02:07,764 --> 00:02:10,902
并想要计算所有训练样本的预测
and want to compute the prediction of all your training examples

31
00:02:10,903 --> 00:02:14,577
你需要对i=1到m遍历
you need to do for i equals 1 to m,

32
00:02:14,660 --> 00:02:17,922
然后基本实现这4个方程
then basically implement these 4 equations.

33
00:02:18,660 --> 00:02:28,969
因为z^[1](i)等于W^[1] x ^(i)+ b^[1]
because z^[1](i) equals W^[1] x^(i) + b^[1] 

34
00:02:29,039 --> 00:02:38,156
a^[1](i)等于σ(z^[1](i))
a^[1](i) equals sigmoid of z^[1](i)

35
00:02:38,237 --> 00:02:48,304
z^[2](i)等于W^[2] a^[1](i)+ b^[2]
z^[2](i) equals W^[2] a^[1](i) + b^[2].

36
00:02:48,304 --> 00:02:56,924
然后a^[2](i)等于σ(z^[2](i))
and a^[2](i) equals sigmoid of z^[2](i)

37
00:02:56,924 --> 00:02:59,357
对 所以基本上和上面四个方程一样
Right, so basically these four equations on top 

38
00:02:59,390 --> 00:03:04,122
不过需要添加上标圆括号i
by adding the superscript round bracket i

39
00:03:05,143 --> 00:03:08,777
来表示训练样本中的所有变量
to all the variables that depend on the training example,

40
00:03:08,871 --> 00:03:13,215
所以要往x z和a加上圆括号上标i
so adding the superscript round bracket i to x, z and a,

41
00:03:13,277 --> 00:03:15,014
如果你想计算
if you want to compute,

42
00:03:15,105 --> 00:03:17,608
所有m个训练样本的输出
all the outputs on your m training examples.

43
00:03:17,681 --> 00:03:23,824
我们一般喜欢将整个计算向量化 就可以去掉这些公式
What we like to do is vectorize this whole computation so as to get rid of this formula.

44
00:03:23,824 --> 00:03:28,509
顺便说一句 如果你觉得我讲的太多深奥的线性代数
And by the way, in case it seems like I'm getting a lot of nitty gritty linear algebra,

45
00:03:28,573 --> 00:03:31,695
事实上 能够正确实现这些算法
it turns out that being able to implement this correctly

46
00:03:31,696 --> 00:03:33,925
在深度学习时代很重要
is important in the deep learning era,

47
00:03:33,978 --> 00:03:38,173
在备课时 我很注意符号的选择
and we actually chose the notation very carefully for this course

48
00:03:38,174 --> 00:03:40,691
使得这些向量化过程越简单越好
and made these vectorizations as easy as possible.

49
00:03:40,766 --> 00:03:44,659
所以我希望详细讲解线性代数细节 能够帮你
So I hope that going through this nitty gritty will actually help you to

50
00:03:44,708 --> 00:03:49,723
快速正确地实现这些算法
more quickly get correct implementations of these algorithms working.

51
00:03:50,802 --> 00:03:56,180
好的 我们把这段代码复制到下一张幻灯片里
All right, so let me just copy this whole block of code to the next slide

52
00:03:56,180 --> 00:03:57,777
然后看看怎么向量化这个
and then we'll see how to vectorize this.

53
00:03:59,105 --> 00:04:00,932
所以这是我们从上一张幻灯片中的 
So here's what we have from the previous slide

54
00:04:00,933 --> 00:04:04,035
一个for循环 遍历所有的m训练样本
with a for loop going over all m training examples.

55
00:04:04,441 --> 00:04:09,740
还记得我们定义过矩阵X
So recall that we define the matrix X to be

56
00:04:09,794 --> 00:04:15,917
就是我们的训练样本堆到各列
equal to our training examples stacked up in these columns like so.

57
00:04:16,989 --> 00:04:20,099
所以把这些训练样本拿过来 堆到各列里
So take the training examples, stack them in columns,

58
00:04:20,163 --> 00:04:27,885
所以这也许就能做成一个n 或者n_x乘m维的矩阵
so this becomes a n or maybe n_x by m dimensional matrix.

59
00:04:27,959 --> 00:04:32,497
我直接把关键地方抖出来了 告诉你需要实现什么
I'm just going to give away the punchline and tell you what you need to implement

60
00:04:32,497 --> 00:04:35,792
才能把这个for循环变成向量化实现
in order to have a vectorized implementation of this for loop.

61
00:04:35,853 --> 00:04:45,615
实际上 你要计算的是Z^[1]等于W^[1] X + b^[1]
Turns out what you need to do is compute Z^[1] equals W^[1]X + b^[1],

62
00:04:47,781 --> 00:04:51,350
A^[1]等于σ(Z^[1])
A^[1] equals sigmoid of Z^[1],

63
00:04:52,358 --> 00:05:02,079
然后Z^[2就]等于W^[2]乘以A^[1] + b^[2]
then Z^[2] equals W^[2] times A^[1] + b^[2],

64
00:05:02,151 --> 00:05:09,640
然后A^[2]等于σ(Z^[2])
and then A^[2] equals sigmoid of Z^[2].

65
00:05:09,706 --> 00:05:15,782
所以如果你想的话 这就好比 把小x向量
So if you want, the analogy is that we went from lowercase vector x's

66
00:05:15,844 --> 00:05:22,732
堆叠到矩阵各列 构成大X矩阵
to this capital case X matrix by stacking up the lowercase x's in different columns.

67
00:05:22,822 --> 00:05:25,102
所以对于z 你也可以做同样的事情
So if you do the same thing for the z's,

68
00:05:25,179 --> 00:05:29,975
比如说 你可以取z^[1](1)
so for example, if you take z^[1](1),

69
00:05:29,975 --> 00:05:40,403
z^[1](2)等等 这些列向量一直排到z^[1](m)
z^[1](2) and so on and these are all columns vectors up to z^[1](m), right,

70
00:05:40,463 --> 00:05:42,786
所以这是第一个量
so that's this first quantity,

71
00:05:42,844 --> 00:05:45,555
但全部m个向量都以列向量堆叠起来
but all m of them and stack them in columns,

72
00:05:45,596 --> 00:05:50,054
这样就得到了矩阵Z^[1]
then this gives you the matrix Z^[1].

73
00:05:50,116 --> 00:05:55,858
同样 如果你看这个量 并且取a^[1](1)
And similarly, if you look at say this quantity and take a^[1](1),

74
00:05:56,844 --> 00:06:06,236
a^[1](2)等等一直到a^[1](m) 将它们以列向量堆叠起来
a^[1](2) and so on and a^[1](m) and stack them up in columns,

75
00:06:06,328 --> 00:06:11,550
这过程就和小x到大X的过程一样
then this, just as we went from lowercase x's to capital case X

76
00:06:11,550 --> 00:06:13,219
小z到大Z过程一样
and lowercase z to capital case Z,

77
00:06:13,277 --> 00:06:16,076
这样就从小a向量
this goes from the lower case a, which are vectors,

78
00:06:16,175 --> 00:06:21,901
变成那边的大A^[1]矩阵
to this capital A^[1] over there.

79
00:06:21,981 --> 00:06:26,017
同样 对于Z^[2]和A^[2]
And similarly, for Z^[2] and A^[2],

80
00:06:27,569 --> 00:06:29,010
也是通过
they're also obtained by taking

81
00:06:29,081 --> 00:06:32,940
将这些向量横向堆叠起来 然后
these vectors and stacking them horizontally and then taking

82
00:06:32,962 --> 00:06:34,820
再把这些向量横向堆叠起来
these vectors and stacking them horizontally 

83
00:06:34,892 --> 00:06:39,834
就得到大写Z^[2]和大写A^[2]矩阵
in order to get capital Z^[2] and capital A^[2].

84
00:06:40,700 --> 00:06:44,558
这种写法可以帮助你们去想
One of the property of this notation that might help you to think about it

85
00:06:44,558 --> 00:06:47,935
这些矩阵 比如说Z和A
is that these matrices say Z and A, 

86
00:06:47,935 --> 00:06:51,676
横向的话 我们有对所有训练样本用指标排序
horizontally we're going to index across training examples,

87
00:06:51,761 --> 00:06:56,692
所以横向指标就对应了不同的训练样本
so that's why the horizontal index corresponds to different training examples.

88
00:06:56,759 --> 00:06:59,512
当你从左到右扫的时候 就扫过了整个训练集
As you sweep from left to right, you're scanning through the training set.

89
00:06:59,582 --> 00:07:05,753
而在竖向 竖向指标就对应了神经网络里的不同节点
And vertically, this vertical index corresponds to different nodes in the neural network.

90
00:07:05,830 --> 00:07:11,093
所以例如 这个节点
So for example, this node,

91
00:07:11,152 --> 00:07:15,021
这个值位于矩阵的最左上角
this value at the top leftmost corner of the matrix

92
00:07:15,092 --> 00:07:19,947
对应第一个训练样本 第一个隐藏单元的激活函数  
corresponds to the activation of the first hidden unit on the first training example,

93
00:07:21,741 --> 00:07:23,322
下面一个值就对应了
one value down corresponds to

94
00:07:23,369 --> 00:07:27,156
第二个隐藏单元对第一个训练样本的激活函数
the activation in the second hidden unit on the first training example,

95
00:07:27,212 --> 00:07:31,312
还有第三个隐藏单元对第一个训练样本 以此类推
and the third hidden unit on the first training example and so on.

96
00:07:31,395 --> 00:07:32,853
所以当你扫下来时
So as you scan down,

97
00:07:32,924 --> 00:07:37,348
这是隐藏单元的指标
this is you indexing into the hidden unit's number,

98
00:07:38,856 --> 00:07:41,045
如果你往横向移动的话
whereas if you move horizontally,

99
00:07:41,147 --> 00:07:43,956
就从第一个训练样本的第一个隐藏单元
then you're going from the first hidden unit in the first training example

100
00:07:44,028 --> 00:07:47,158
移动到第二个训练样本的第一个隐藏单元
to now the first hidden unit in the second training example,

101
00:07:47,211 --> 00:07:49,193
再移动到第三个训练样本 等等
the third training example and so on 

102
00:07:49,264 --> 00:07:55,092
直到这里的节点对应最后第m个训练样本
until this node here corresponds to the activation of the first hidden unit

103
00:07:55,092 --> 00:07:58,959
第一个隐藏单元的激活函数为止
in the final training example in the mth training example.

104
00:07:59,852 --> 00:08:07,553
所以横向 矩阵A会扫过不同的训练样本
So the horizontal, the matrix A goes over our different training examples,

105
00:08:10,415 --> 00:08:12,362
竖向是矩阵A中的不同指标
and vertically, the different indices in the matrix A

106
00:08:22,259 --> 00:08:28,891
同样的形式也适用于矩阵Z和矩阵X
And a similar intuition holds true for the matrix Z as well as was for X,

107
00:08:28,951 --> 00:08:32,534
横向对应的是不同训练样本
where horizontally corresponds to different training examples and

108
00:08:32,558 --> 00:08:36,496
竖向对应不同的输入特征
vertically corresponds to different input features,

109
00:08:36,564 --> 00:08:40,955
这其实是神经网络输入层的不同节点
which are really different nodes in the input layer of the neural network.

110
00:08:42,028 --> 00:08:46,402
所以通过这些方程 你就知道如何实现
So, with these equations you know know how to implement a neural network 

111
00:08:46,402 --> 00:08:50,593
把不同样本向量化的神经网络算法
with vectorization that is the vectorization across multiple examples 

112
00:08:50,649 --> 00:08:54,114
在下一个视频中 我要给你们讲更多的理由 说明
In the next video, I'm gonna show you more justification about

113
00:08:54,186 --> 00:08:59,110
为什么这是向量化的正确实现
why this is a correct implementation of this type of vectorization 

114
00:08:59,110 --> 00:09:00,579
事实证明这些理由
It turns out that justification will be 

115
00:09:00,580 --> 00:09:03,797
和Logistics回归中见到的理由是很类似的
similar to what you had seen for logistics regression

116
00:09:03,797 --> 00:09:05,600
我们继续看下一个视频
Let's go on to the next video

