1
00:00:00,000 --> 00:00:03,390
之前你见过神经网络的大概图形 在本视频中
You've seen me draw a few pictures of your neural network in this video

2
00:00:03,464 --> 00:00:06,024
我们将讨论 这些图形的具体含义
we'll talk about exactly what those pictures means

3
00:00:06,078 --> 00:00:08,729
换句话说 就是我们画的这些神经网络
in other words exactly what those little neural networks

4
00:00:08,771 --> 00:00:10,703
到底代表什么
have been drawing on represent

5
00:00:10,750 --> 00:00:13,560
我们先集中精力看看
and we'll starts with focusing on the case of

6
00:00:13,626 --> 00:00:16,935
只有一个隐藏层的神经网络
neural networks with what's called a single hidden layer

7
00:00:16,985 --> 00:00:18,919
这是一张神经网络图
here's a picture of a neural network

8
00:00:18,993 --> 00:00:22,328
我们命名一下这张图的各部分
let's give different parts of these pictures some names

9
00:00:22,329 --> 00:00:26,572
我们有输入特征x1 x2 x3 竖向堆叠起来
we have the input features x1 x2 x3 stacked vertically

10
00:00:26,619 --> 00:00:30,793
这是神经网络的输入层
and this is called the input layer of the neural network

11
00:00:31,387 --> 00:00:32,643
没什么特别的
so maybe not surprisingly

12
00:00:32,685 --> 00:00:35,182
它包含了神经网络的输入
this contains the inputs to the neural network

13
00:00:35,230 --> 00:00:38,255
然后这里有另外一层的圆圈
then there's another layer of circles

14
00:00:38,291 --> 00:00:42,139
我们称之为神经网络的隐藏层
and this is called a hidden layer of the neural network

15
00:00:42,197 --> 00:00:45,132
我们马上会讲到 "隐藏"是什么意思
I'll come back in a second to say what the word hidden means

16
00:00:45,193 --> 00:00:47,663
这里的最后一层
but the final layer here is formed

17
00:00:47,701 --> 00:00:49,166
在这里只有一个节点
by in this case just one node

18
00:00:49,219 --> 00:00:53,087
而这个只带一个节点的层就是输出层
and this single note layer is called the output layer

19
00:00:53,131 --> 00:00:56,959
它负责输出 预测值y帽
and it's responsible for generating the predicted value y hat.

20
00:00:57,020 --> 00:01:00,124
在一个神经网络中 当你使用监督学习训练它的时候
In a neural network the you train with supervised learning

21
00:01:00,201 --> 00:01:03,204
训练集包含了输入x
the training set contains values of the inputs x

22
00:01:03,235 --> 00:01:05,350
还有目标输出y 
as well as the target outputs y

23
00:01:05,387 --> 00:01:08,519
“隐藏层”的含义是
so the term hidden layer refers to the fact that

24
00:01:08,562 --> 00:01:11,316
在训练集中 这些中间节点的真正数值
in a training set the true values for these nodes

25
00:01:11,374 --> 00:01:12,858
我们是不知道的
in the middle are not observed

26
00:01:12,925 --> 00:01:15,633
在训练集你看不到它们的数值
that is you don't see what they should be in the training set

27
00:01:15,675 --> 00:01:16,838
你能看到输入值
you see what the inputs are

28
00:01:16,891 --> 00:01:18,174
也能看见输出值
you see what the output should be

29
00:01:18,243 --> 00:01:19,513
但是隐藏层中的值
but the things in a hidden layer

30
00:01:19,576 --> 00:01:21,338
在训练集中 是无法看到的
are not seen in the training set

31
00:01:21,423 --> 00:01:24,422
这就是所谓的“隐藏层”
so that kind of explains the name hidden layer

32
00:01:24,486 --> 00:01:26,423
只是表示你无法在训练集中看到
just means you don't see it in a training set

33
00:01:26,504 --> 00:01:28,270
现在我们再引入几个符号
let's introduce a bit more notation 

34
00:01:28,347 --> 00:01:33,541
之前我们用向量x表示输入特征
whereas previously we were using the vector x to denote the input features

35
00:01:33,600 --> 00:01:37,941
输入特征的数值还有另外一种表示方式
an alternative notation for the values of the input features

36
00:01:37,993 --> 00:01:41,101
我们用a^[0]来表示
will be a superscript square bracket 0

37
00:01:41,196 --> 00:01:44,235
而这个a 也表示"激活"的意思
and the term a also stands for activations

38
00:01:44,294 --> 00:01:49,159
它意味着网络中不同层的值
and it refers to the values that different layers of the neural network

39
00:01:49,213 --> 00:01:51,656
会传递给后面的层
are passing on to the subsequent layers

40
00:01:51,720 --> 00:01:55,911
输入层将x的值 传递给隐藏层
so the input layer passes on the value x to the hidden layer

41
00:01:55,976 --> 00:01:57,294
我们将输入层的激活值
so we're going to call that

42
00:01:57,341 --> 00:02:01,481
称为a上标[0]
call the activations of the input layer a superscript 0

43
00:02:01,551 --> 00:02:02,868
下一层即隐藏层
the next layer the hidden layer

44
00:02:02,927 --> 00:02:06,006
也同样会产生一些激活值
will in turn generate some set of activations

45
00:02:06,070 --> 00:02:10,060
那么我将其记作 a^[1]
which I'm going to write as a superscript square bracket 1

46
00:02:10,089 --> 00:02:13,452
具体地 这里的第一个单元 或者说节点
so in particular this first unit or this first node

47
00:02:13,510 --> 00:02:18,059
我们将其表示为 a^[1]_1
we generate the value a superscript square bracket 1 subscript 1

48
00:02:18,120 --> 00:02:23,476
第二个节点 我们记为 a^[1]2 以此类推
this second node we generate the value now with a subscript 2 and so on

49
00:02:23,519 --> 00:02:25,976
这里的a^[1]
and so a superscript square bracket 1

50
00:02:26,025 --> 00:02:28,912
是一个四维向量
this is a four dimensional vector

51
00:02:28,971 --> 00:02:30,862
写成Python代码
or if you write it in Python

52
00:02:30,905 --> 00:02:34,231
它是一个4x1矩阵 或大小为4的列向量
it gives us a four by one matrix or four column vector

53
00:02:34,284 --> 00:02:36,564
就像我画的这样 它是四维的
which looks like this and it's four dimensional

54
00:02:36,634 --> 00:02:38,964
是因为在本例中 我们有四个节点
because in this case we have four nodes

55
00:02:39,021 --> 00:02:43,385
有四个单元 四个隐藏层单元
or four units or four hidden units in this hidden layer

56
00:02:43,446 --> 00:02:44,943
最后的输出层
then finally the output layer

57
00:02:45,001 --> 00:02:48,372
会产生某个数值a^[2] 是个实数
will generate some value a^[2] which is just a real number

58
00:02:48,421 --> 00:02:53,233
y帽的值就等于a^[2]
and so y hat is going to take on the value of a^[2]

59
00:02:53,291 --> 00:02:55,675
所以这和 logistic回归类似
so this is analogous to how in logistic regression

60
00:02:55,740 --> 00:02:59,264
在logistic回归中 y帽等于a
we have y hat equals a and in logistic regression

61
00:02:59,317 --> 00:03:02,290
我们只有一个输出层
we only had that one output layer

62
00:03:02,338 --> 00:03:04,726
所以没有用带方括号的上标 
so we didn't use the superscript square bracket 

63
00:03:04,785 --> 00:03:06,013
但是在神经网络中
but with a neural network

64
00:03:06,066 --> 00:03:08,498
我们将使用这种方括号上标
we're now going to use this superscript square bracket

65
00:03:08,546 --> 00:03:11,624
来明确地指出这些值来自哪一层
to explicitly indicate which layer it came from

66
00:03:11,676 --> 00:03:15,467
有趣的是 在约定俗成的符号中
one funny thing about notational conventions in neural networks

67
00:03:15,530 --> 00:03:17,687
在这里你看到的这个例子
is that this network that you're seeing here

68
00:03:17,741 --> 00:03:20,597
是所谓的双层神经网络
is called a two layer neural network

69
00:03:20,634 --> 00:03:24,423
当我们计算网络的层数时
and the reason is that when we count layers in neural networks

70
00:03:24,458 --> 00:03:26,635
不算入输入层的原因是
we don't count the input layer

71
00:03:26,677 --> 00:03:28,648
隐藏层是第一层
so the hidden layer is layer 1

72
00:03:28,712 --> 00:03:30,728
输出层是第二层 
and the output layer is layer two

73
00:03:30,781 --> 00:03:32,135
在我们的符号约定中
In our notational convention 

74
00:03:32,209 --> 00:03:34,119
我们将输入层称为第零层
we're calling the input layer layer 0

75
00:03:34,187 --> 00:03:35,990
所以在字面上可以说
so technically maybe there are 

76
00:03:36,041 --> 00:03:37,763
这是一个“三层的”神经网络
three layers in this neural network

77
00:03:37,816 --> 00:03:39,741
因为这里有输入层 隐藏层
because this is input layer the hidden layer

78
00:03:39,796 --> 00:03:42,155
还有输出层  但一般符号的约定是
and the output layer but in conventional users

79
00:03:42,198 --> 00:03:44,914
如果你阅读研究论文 或者在这门课中
if you read research papers and also in the course

80
00:03:44,965 --> 00:03:47,214
你会看到人们将这个神经网络
you see people refer to this particular neural network

81
00:03:47,256 --> 00:03:49,348
称为双层神经网络 
as a two layer neural network

82
00:03:49,406 --> 00:03:52,580
因为我们不把输入层 看作一个标准的层
because we don't count input layer as a as an official layer

83
00:03:52,638 --> 00:03:54,607
最后我们要知道
finally something that we'll get to later

84
00:03:54,671 --> 00:03:57,245
隐藏层 以及最后的输出层 
is that the hidden layer and the output layers 

85
00:03:57,303 --> 00:03:59,668
是带有参数的 
will have parameters associated with it

86
00:03:59,700 --> 00:04:04,649
这里的隐藏层有两个相关的参数W和b
so the hidden layer will have associated with their parameters w and b

87
00:04:04,730 --> 00:04:07,724
使用上标[1] 
and I'm going to write superscript square bracket 1

88
00:04:07,783 --> 00:04:09,860
表示这些参数
to indicate that these are parameters

89
00:04:09,919 --> 00:04:12,047
是和第一层这个隐藏层有关的
associated with layer 1 with a hidden layer

90
00:04:12,101 --> 00:04:15,852
之后我们会看到 W是一个4x3的矩阵
we'll see later that W will be a 4 by 3 matrix

91
00:04:15,910 --> 00:04:19,570
而b在这个例子中是一个4x1向量
and b will be a 4 by 1 vector in this example

92
00:04:19,632 --> 00:04:21,578
第一个数字4
where the first coordinate 4

93
00:04:21,641 --> 00:04:24,528
意思是有四个节点 或者说四个隐藏单元
comes from the fact that we have four nodes or four hidden units

94
00:04:24,580 --> 00:04:26,632
然后数字3来自
there and three comes from the fact

95
00:04:26,695 --> 00:04:28,594
这里有三个输入特征
that we have three input features

96
00:04:28,667 --> 00:04:31,197
之后会更加详细地 讨论这些矩阵的维数
we'll talk later about the dimensions of these matrices

97
00:04:31,235 --> 00:04:32,865
到那时 你可能就更明白了
and it might make more sense at that time

98
00:04:32,934 --> 00:04:35,893
类似地 输出层也有一些
but in similarly the output layer has associated with it 

99
00:04:35,894 --> 00:04:40,455
和它有关的参数W^[2]
also parameters w superscript square bracket 2

100
00:04:40,493 --> 00:04:42,389
以及b^[2]
and b superscript square bracket 2

101
00:04:42,437 --> 00:04:43,997
从维数来看
and it turns out that the dimensions of these

102
00:04:44,050 --> 00:04:46,170
分别是1x4以及1x1
are one by four and one by one

103
00:04:46,171 --> 00:04:49,560
这是1×4 是因为隐藏层有四个隐藏单元
 and this one by fours because the hidden layer has four hidden units

104
00:04:49,633 --> 00:04:51,597
而输出层只有一个单元
the output layer has just one unit

105
00:04:51,663 --> 00:04:53,775
之后的视频中 我们会对这些矩阵和向量的维度
and we're going we'll go over the dimensions

106
00:04:53,833 --> 00:04:55,924
做更加深入的解释
of these matrices and vectors in a later video

107
00:04:55,996 --> 00:04:59,936
所以你现在已经知道 一个双层神经网络是怎样的
so you've just seen what a two layer neural network looks like

108
00:05:00,004 --> 00:05:02,632
它是只有一个隐藏层的神经网络
that is a neural network with one hidden layer

109
00:05:02,701 --> 00:05:05,355
在下一个视频中 我们将更深入地
in the next video let's go deeper into exactly

110
00:05:05,509 --> 00:05:07,606
了解这个神经网络到底在计算什么
what this neural network is computing

111
00:05:07,675 --> 00:05:10,504
这个神经网络是怎么输入x
that is how this neural network inputs x

112
00:05:10,550 --> 00:05:13,774
然后又是怎么一直算下去得到y帽的
and goes all the way to computing this output y hat

