1
00:00:00,000 --> 00:00:02,687
当你对你的神经网络使用反向传播的时候
When you implement back-propagation for your neural network

2
00:00:02,739 --> 00:00:07,534
你真的需要计算激活函数的斜率或者导数
you need to really compute the slope or the derivative of the activation functions 

3
00:00:07,590 --> 00:00:10,930
我们看看激活函数的选择
So let's take a look at our choices of activation functions 

4
00:00:10,985 --> 00:00:14,289
以及如何计算这些函数的斜率
and how you can compute the slope of these functions 

5
00:00:14,400 --> 00:00:17,760
你可以看到很熟悉的sigmoid激活函数
you can see familiar sigmoid activation function 

6
00:00:17,824 --> 00:00:20,512
所以对于任意给定的z值
and so for any given value of z 

7
00:00:20,576 --> 00:00:23,561
也许这个z的函数会有
maybe this value of z this function will have 

8
00:00:23,626 --> 00:00:26,929
某个斜率和导数 对应于
some slope or some derivative corresponding to 

9
00:00:26,991 --> 00:00:30,684
如果你这里画一条线 用高度除以宽度
if you draw a little line there you know the height over width 

10
00:00:30,752 --> 00:00:32,319
这里有个小三角形
there's a little triangle here

11
00:00:32,384 --> 00:00:36,619
所以如果g(z)是sigmoid函数
so if g(z) is the sigmoid function 

12
00:00:36,684 --> 00:00:41,480
那么函数的斜率就是d/dz g(z)
then the slope of the function is d/dz g(z) 

13
00:00:41,480 --> 00:00:48,037
我们从微积分知道 这就是g(x)在z处的斜率
and so we know from calculus that the this slope of g(x) at z

14
00:00:48,037 --> 00:00:52,952
如果你很熟悉微积分 知道怎么求导
and if you are familiar with calculus and know how to take derivatives 

15
00:00:52,952 --> 00:00:55,807
如果你对sigmoid函数求导
if you take the derivative of the sigmoid function 

16
00:00:55,807 --> 00:00:59,789
那么你可以证明就等于这个公式
it is possible to show that it is equal to this formula 

17
00:00:59,848 --> 00:01:02,702
再次 我不打算具体去算微积分
and again I'm not going to do the calculus steps 

18
00:01:02,937 --> 00:01:06,359
如果你对微积分很熟 可以暂停视频
but if you're familiar with calculus be free  to pause the video

19
00:01:06,359 --> 00:01:07,686
自己去证明
and try to prove this yourself

20
00:01:07,745 --> 00:01:16,332
所以这等于g(z)·(1-g(x))
and so this is equal to just g(z) times 1 minus g(z) 

21
00:01:16,417 --> 00:01:21,012
我们看看这个式子是否合理
so let's just sanity check that this expression makes sense 

22
00:01:21,075 --> 00:01:25,601
首先 如果z非常大 比如说z=10
first if z is very large, so say z is equal to 10 

23
00:01:25,664 --> 00:01:30,367
那么g(z)就很接近1
then g(z) will be close to 1 

24
00:01:30,462 --> 00:01:33,501
左边的公式告诉我们 
and so the formula we have on the Left tells us that 

25
00:01:33,594 --> 00:01:38,460
d/dz g(z)必须很接近.. g(z)
d/dz g(z) must be close to g(z) which is equal to 

26
00:01:38,531 --> 00:01:46,319
这等于1·(1-1)  所以很接近0
1 times 1 minus 1 which is therefore very close to 0 

27
00:01:46,391 --> 00:01:49,242
这实际上是对的 因为当z很大的时候
And this is indeed correct because when z is very large 

28
00:01:49,308 --> 00:01:53,885
斜率接近0 相反如果z等于负10
the slope is close to 0, conversely if z is equal to minus 10 

29
00:01:53,951 --> 00:01:59,079
在很远的位置 那么g(z)很接近0
so that's way out there, then g(z) is close to 0 

30
00:01:59,145 --> 00:02:04,544
所以按左边的公式 告诉我们d/dz g(z)很接近g(x)
so the following on the left tells us d/dz g(z) will be close to g(z) 

31
00:02:04,615 --> 00:02:07,096
就是0·(1-0) 
which is 0 times 1 minus zero

32
00:02:07,147 --> 00:02:09,965
所以这边也很接近0 所以是正确的
and so this is also very close to 0 which is correct 

33
00:02:10,581 --> 00:02:17,265
最后在z=0处 g(z)=1/2
finally at z is equal to 0 then g(z) is equal to 1/2 

34
00:02:17,343 --> 00:02:18,873
这就是sigmoid函数
that's a sigmoid function right here 

35
00:02:18,940 --> 00:02:26,139
所以导数就等于1/2·(1-1/2)
and so the derivative is on equal to 1/2 times 1 minus 1/2 

36
00:02:26,202 --> 00:02:28,691
这等于1/4 
which is equal to 1/4 

37
00:02:28,758 --> 00:02:32,954
可以证明这是正确的导数值
and that actually is turns out to be the correct value of the derivative 

38
00:02:33,032 --> 00:02:36,077
或者z=0时正确的函数斜率
or the slope of this function when z is equal to 0 

39
00:02:36,151 --> 00:02:38,820
最后再介绍一个符号约定
Finally just to introduce one more piece of notation 

40
00:02:38,887 --> 00:02:42,622
有时我们不这样写
sometimes instead of writing this thing 

41
00:02:42,622 --> 00:02:46,014
导数可以用g'(z)表示
the shorthand for the derivative is g prime of z 

42
00:02:46,081 --> 00:02:52,217
所以在微积分中g'(z) 上面这一撇叫prime
so g prime of z in calculus the, the little dash on top is called prime 

43
00:02:52,298 --> 00:02:54,740
所以g'(z)就表示
but so g prime of z is a shorthand for the 

44
00:02:54,765 --> 00:03:00,379
在微积分中表示函数g对输入变量z的导数
in calculus for the derivative of the function of g with respect to the input variable z 

45
00:03:00,449 --> 00:03:04,983
然后在神经网络中 
um and then in a neural network 

46
00:03:05,034 --> 00:03:11,610
我们有a=g(z) 等于这个
we have a equals g(z) right equals this 

47
00:03:11,694 --> 00:03:17,197
这个公式就化简成a·(1-a)
then this formula also simplifies to a times 1 minus a 

48
00:03:17,900 --> 00:03:21,736
所以有时在实现的时候 你可能会见到这种
so sometimes the implementation you might see something like 

49
00:03:21,806 --> 00:03:25,096
式子g'(z)=a·(1-a)
g prime of z equals a times 1 minus a 

50
00:03:25,162 --> 00:03:27,005
那就表示
and that just refers to you 

51
00:03:28,561 --> 00:03:31,494
你知道g'表示导数
know the observation that g prime which is this derivative 

52
00:03:31,558 --> 00:03:33,182
就等于这边的式子
is equal to this over here 

53
00:03:33,245 --> 00:03:35,823
然后这个公式的优点在于
and the advantage of this formula is that 

54
00:03:35,886 --> 00:03:38,651
如果你已经计算出a值了
if you've already computed the value for a 

55
00:03:38,711 --> 00:03:40,488
那么用这个式子
then by using this expression 

56
00:03:40,558 --> 00:03:44,685
就可以很快算出g(z)的斜率
you can very quickly compute the value for the slope for g prime z

57
00:03:44,752 --> 00:03:47,530
好 所以这是sigmoid激活函数的导数
alright so that was the sigmoid activation function 

58
00:03:47,606 --> 00:03:51,020
我们来看看tanh激活函数
let's now look at the tanh activation function 

59
00:03:51,108 --> 00:03:52,945
和之前的讨论类似
similar to what we had previously 

60
00:03:53,974 --> 00:04:03,789
d/dz g(z)就是在特定点z上g(z)的斜率
the definition of d/dz g(z) is the slope of g(z) at a particular point of z 

61
00:04:03,789 --> 00:04:10,023
如果你观察一下双曲正切函数的式子
and if you look at the formula for the hyperbolic tangent function 

62
00:04:10,096 --> 00:04:13,509
如果你微积分学得不错 你就可以求导
and if you know calculus you can take derivatives 

63
00:04:13,580 --> 00:04:17,130
并证明这个式子可以简化成..
and show that this simplifies to this formula 

64
00:04:20,288 --> 00:04:23,813
我们可以用之前说的写法
and using the shorthand we have previously 

65
00:04:23,880 --> 00:04:26,806
我们将这个称为g'(z) 
when we call this g prime of z, again

66
00:04:26,870 --> 00:04:29,708
如果你想检查一下
so if you want you can sanity check that 

67
00:04:29,782 --> 00:04:31,941
这个公式有没有错 比如
this formula make sense so for example 

68
00:04:32,014 --> 00:04:36,907
如果z等于10 那么tanh(z)会很接近1
if z is equal to 10, tanh(z) will be very close to 1 

69
00:04:36,978 --> 00:04:41,665
这是从-1到1的函数
this goes from plus 1 to minus 1 

70
00:04:41,665 --> 00:04:48,146
然后根据这个式子 g'(z)大概就是1-1²
and then g prime of z according to this formula will be about 1 minus 1 squared 

71
00:04:48,221 --> 00:04:52,181
所以g'(z)很接近0 .. 所以当z很大的时候
so g'(z) closes zero so that was a z is very large 

72
00:04:52,181 --> 00:04:53,497
斜率接近0
the slope is close to zero 

73
00:04:53,579 --> 00:04:58,457
相对来说 如果z很小 比如说z=-10
conversely a z is very small, say z is equal to minus 10 

74
00:04:58,457 --> 00:05:02,367
那么tan(z)就很接近-1
then tanh(z) will be close to minus 1 

75
00:05:02,427 --> 00:05:08,841
所以g'(z)就很接近1-(-1)²
and so g prime of z will be close to 1 minus negative 1 squared 

76
00:05:08,904 --> 00:05:11,744
所以很接近1-1 很接近0
so it's close to 1 minus 1 which is also close to 0 

77
00:05:11,810 --> 00:05:18,398
最后z=0处 tanh(z)就等于0
and finally is equal to 0 then tanh(z) is equal to 0 

78
00:05:18,398 --> 00:05:21,505
然后斜率实际上等于1
and then the slope is actually equal to 1 

79
00:05:21,562 --> 00:05:25,359
在z=0处tanh()函数斜率为1
which is which is just the slope point on z is equal to 0 

80
00:05:25,359 --> 00:05:29,846
所以总结一下 如果a=g(z)
So just to summarize, if a is equal to g(z) 

81
00:05:29,906 --> 00:05:32,129
如果a等于这个tanh(z)
so if a is equal to this tanh(z)

82
00:05:32,198 --> 00:05:38,509
那么导数g'(z)就等于1-a²
then the derivative g prime of z is equal to 1 minus a squared 

83
00:05:38,562 --> 00:05:41,681
再次 如果你已经算出a的值了
so once again if you've already computed the value of a 

84
00:05:41,752 --> 00:05:45,721
那就可以用这个公式快速计算导数
you can use this formula to very quickly compute the derivative as well 

85
00:05:45,747 --> 00:05:48,875
最后 我们看看如何计算
Finally here's how you compute the derivatives for the

86
00:05:48,875 --> 00:05:51,206
ReLU和带泄漏的ReLU激活函数的导数
ReLU and leaky ReLU activation functions 

87
00:05:51,273 --> 00:05:57,190
对于ReLU g(x)=max(0,z)
for the value g(x) is equal to max of 0 comma z 

88
00:05:57,262 --> 00:06:04,881
如果z<0 导数就等于0
so the derivative is equal to you turns out to be 0 if z is less than 0 

89
00:06:04,947 --> 00:06:09,197
z>0 导数就等于1
and 1 if z is greater than 0 

90
00:06:09,266 --> 00:06:13,118
然后在z精确等于0处
and is actually our undefined technically undefined 

91
00:06:13,194 --> 00:06:15,770
斜率是没有定义的
the z is equal to exactly 0 

92
00:06:15,838 --> 00:06:19,127
但如果你在软件中实现这个算法
but um if you're implementing this in software 

93
00:06:19,183 --> 00:06:21,725
可能数学上不是百分之百正确
it might not be a hundred percent mathematically correct 

94
00:06:21,784 --> 00:06:26,319
但实际是能行的 如果z刚好在0
but the work just fine if z is exactly really zero 

95
00:06:26,319 --> 00:06:28,752
你可以令导数为1
if you set the derivative to be equal to 1 

96
00:06:28,827 --> 00:06:30,409
或者令导数为0
or set it to be 0 

97
00:06:30,466 --> 00:06:34,064
这其实无关紧要 如果你对优化术语很熟悉
it kind of doesn't matter if you're an experienced optimization technically 

98
00:06:34,129 --> 00:06:39,212
g'就变成所谓的激活函数g(z)的次梯度
g prime then becomes what's called a sub gradient of the activation function g(z) 

99
00:06:39,286 --> 00:06:41,171
这样梯度下降法仍然有效
which is why gradient descent still works 

100
00:06:41,244 --> 00:06:43,310
但是你可以这么想 
but you can think of it as that 

101
00:06:43,365 --> 00:06:48,904
z精确为0的概率非常非常小 
the chance of z being you know zero point exactly 0 0 0 0 0 is so small 

102
00:06:48,971 --> 00:06:52,562
所以你将z=0处的导数设成哪个值
that it almost doesn't matter what you set the derivative to be equal to

103
00:06:52,641 --> 00:06:54,150
实际无关紧要
when z is equal to zero 

104
00:06:54,234 --> 00:06:58,708
所以在实践中 人们一般这么定z的导数
So in practice this is what people implement for the derivative of z 

105
00:06:58,761 --> 00:07:02,200
最后如果你在训练自己的网络时
and finally if you are training on your own network with

106
00:07:02,200 --> 00:07:04,150
带泄漏的ReLU激活函数的网络
the leaky ReLU activation function 

107
00:07:04,224 --> 00:07:12,562
那么g(z)就是max(0.01z,z)
then g(z) is going to be max of say 0.01 z comma z 

108
00:07:12,638 --> 00:07:21,462
所以z小于0时 g'(z)就等于0.01
and so g prime of z is equal to 0.01 if z is less than 0

109
00:07:21,537 --> 00:07:26,387
z>0 g'(z)就等于1
and 1, if z is greater than 0

110
00:07:26,461 --> 00:07:30,621
再次 z精确为0时的梯度技术上是没定义的
and once again the gradient is technically not defined when z is exactly equal to 0 

111
00:07:30,699 --> 00:07:34,739
但你可以写一段代码去定义这个梯度
but some maybe implement a piece of code that sets the derivative 

112
00:07:34,808 --> 00:07:38,168
在z=0处令g'(z)为0.01或1
or the sets g prime z either a 0.01 or to 1 

113
00:07:38,231 --> 00:07:41,347
用哪个值其实无关紧要
either way it doesn't really matter when z is exactly 0 

114
00:07:41,412 --> 00:07:42,489
你的程序也是能工作的 
your code would work just fine

115
00:07:42,561 --> 00:07:44,197
掌握了这些式子
So arm with of these formulas

116
00:07:44,269 --> 00:07:48,615
你应该计算这些激活函数的斜率或导数
you should either compute the slopes or the derivatives of your activation functions

117
00:07:49,659 --> 00:07:51,384
现在我们有了这个基础工具
now we have this building blocks 

118
00:07:51,451 --> 00:07:54,984
你就已经准备好如何在你的神经网络上实现梯度下降算法了
you're ready to see how to implement gradient descent for your neural network 

119
00:07:55,040 --> 00:07:57,047
让我们来看下一个视频
let's go onto the next video to see that

