1
00:00:00,030 --> 00:00:01,329
在上一期的视频中我们已经见过
In the last video you saw

2
00:00:01,392 --> 00:00:04,511
单隐层神经网络长什么样
what a single hidden layer neural network looks like

3
00:00:04,557 --> 00:00:07,566
在这期的视频中让我们了解
in this video let's go through the details of exactly

4
00:00:07,603 --> 00:00:10,001
神经网络的输出 究竟是如何计算出来的
how this neural network computers outputs

5
00:00:10,048 --> 00:00:13,414
你所看到的是像Logistic那样的运算过程
what you see is that is like logistic regression

6
00:00:13,486 --> 00:00:15,301
但整个运算过程会重复很多遍
but repeat of all the times

7
00:00:15,353 --> 00:00:19,382
看一下 这是一个两层的神经网络
let's take a look so this is what's a two layer neural network

8
00:00:19,445 --> 00:00:23,868
让我们更深入地了解神经网络到底在计算什么
let's go more deeply into exactly what this neural network compute

9
00:00:23,952 --> 00:00:26,796
我们之前说过 Logistic回归
now we've said before that logistic regression 

10
00:00:26,860 --> 00:00:31,351
这里的圆圈代表了回归计算的两个步骤
the circle images the regression really represents two steps of computation

11
00:00:31,422 --> 00:00:33,168
首先你按步骤计算出z
first you compute z as follows

12
00:00:33,209 --> 00:00:35,418
然后在第二步计算激活函数
and in second you compute the activation 

13
00:00:35,493 --> 00:00:37,359
就是函数sigmoid(z)
as a sigmoid function of z

14
00:00:37,408 --> 00:00:40,597
所以神经网络只不过重复计算这些步骤很多次
so a neural network just does this a lot more times

15
00:00:40,651 --> 00:00:42,661
我们先来看
let's start by focusing on just 

16
00:00:42,703 --> 00:00:44,657
隐层的其中一个节点
one of the nodes in the hidden layer

17
00:00:44,715 --> 00:00:46,395
看看这个隐层的第一个节点
and this look at the first node in the hidden layer

18
00:00:46,451 --> 00:00:48,199
我暂时先隐去其他的节点
so I've grayed out the other nodes for now

19
00:00:48,252 --> 00:00:50,836
左边看上去和Logistic回归很相似
so similar to logistic regression on the left

20
00:00:50,889 --> 00:00:54,071
隐层的这个节点进行两步计算
this node in a hidden layer does two steps of computation

21
00:00:54,112 --> 00:00:57,904
第一步 我们可以看成是节点的左边
right the first step we think it's as the left half of this node

22
00:00:57,956 --> 00:01:02,668
计算z = w^T x + b
it computes Z equals W transpose X plus B

23
00:01:02,725 --> 00:01:04,710
这些我们会用到的标记
and the notation we'll use is um

24
00:01:04,748 --> 00:01:08,117
这些都是和第一隐层有关的量
these are all quantities associated with the first hidden layer

25
00:01:08,169 --> 00:01:10,550
所以才用了那么多[1]上标
so that's why we have a bunch of square brackets there

26
00:01:10,590 --> 00:01:13,486
这是隐层的第一个节点
and this is the first node in the hidden layer

27
00:01:13,562 --> 00:01:16,543
所以我们有个下标1
so that's why we have the subscript one over there

28
00:01:16,601 --> 00:01:17,860
第一步就是这样
so first it does that

29
00:01:17,928 --> 00:01:19,983
然后第二步是计算
and then a second step is it computes

30
00:01:20,031 --> 00:01:24,750
a[1]1 = sigmoid(Z^[1]1) 就像这样
a11 equals sigmoid of z11 like so

31
00:01:24,796 --> 00:01:27,965
所以对于z和a 按符号约定写成
so for both z and a the notational convention is that

32
00:01:28,016 --> 00:01:32,154
写成a^[l]_i
a Li the L here in superscript square brackets

33
00:01:32,207 --> 00:01:33,615
这里上标方括号表示层数
refers to layer number

34
00:01:33,677 --> 00:01:37,704
而下标i则表示层中的第几个节点
and the i subscript here refers to the nodes in that layer

35
00:01:37,758 --> 00:01:41,855
我们看的是第一隐层的第一个节点
so the node we will be looking at is layer 1 that is a hidden layer node 1

36
00:01:41,855 --> 00:01:46,068
所以有上标 和下标都是1 1
 so that's why the superscript and subscript were on both 1 1

37
00:01:46,126 --> 00:01:49,397
所以这个小圆圈 即神经网络的第一个节点
so that little circle that first node in neural network

38
00:01:49,440 --> 00:01:52,549
表示执行这两步计算
represents carrying out these two steps of computation

39
00:01:52,591 --> 00:01:55,104
现在让我们看看神经网络的第二个节点
now let's look at the second node in neural network

40
00:01:55,151 --> 00:01:57,831
即神经网络中隐层的第二个节点
the second node in the hidden layer of in neural network

41
00:01:58,371 --> 00:02:01,042
与左边的Logistic回归单元类似
similar to the logistic regression unit on the left

42
00:02:01,105 --> 00:02:04,629
这个小圆圈代表了计算的两个步骤
this little circle represents two steps of computation

43
00:02:04,697 --> 00:02:07,179
第一步是计算z
the first step is compute z

44
00:02:07,212 --> 00:02:09,911
这还是在第一层 但变成第二个节点了
this is still layer 1 but now the second node

45
00:02:09,953 --> 00:02:14,156
等于w^T x + b^[1]_2
equals W transpose x plus b^[1]_2

46
00:02:14,156 --> 00:02:18,869
然后a[1]2 = sigmoid(Z^[1]2)
and then a 12 equals Sigma z12

47
00:02:18,927 --> 00:02:21,412
再次 需要的话 可以暂停视频仔细看看
and again feel free to pause the video if you want

48
00:02:21,450 --> 00:02:22,551
这样你就可以再次查看
but you can double check that 

49
00:02:22,614 --> 00:02:24,836
标记的上标和下标
the superscript and subscript notation

50
00:02:24,874 --> 00:02:28,444
和我们上面所写的是保持一致的
is consistent with what we have written here above in purple

51
00:02:28,481 --> 00:02:32,547
所以我们已经讨论了神经网络的前两个隐层单元
so we've talk through the first two hidden units in the neural network

52
00:02:32,547 --> 00:02:34,477
第三四个隐藏单元
on hidden units three and four

53
00:02:34,509 --> 00:02:36,579
也表示同样的计算
also represents some computations

54
00:02:37,097 --> 00:02:39,906
现在让我们把这对等式
so now let me take this pair of equations

55
00:02:39,957 --> 00:02:42,141
还有这对等式
and this pair of equations

56
00:02:42,181 --> 00:02:44,125
把它们复制到下一个幻灯片中
and let's copy them to the next slide

57
00:02:44,162 --> 00:02:45,292
这是我们的神经网络
so here's our network

58
00:02:45,361 --> 00:02:48,935
这是第一个等式 这是第二个等式
and here's the first and there's a second equations

59
00:02:48,976 --> 00:02:50,943
它们之前已经在隐层的
they were worked on previously for 

60
00:02:50,977 --> 00:02:54,061
第一二个节点中用过了
the first and the second hidden units

61
00:02:54,107 --> 00:02:57,364
如果你接下去看并且写出相应的等式
if you then go through and write out the corresponding equations

62
00:02:57,411 --> 00:02:59,736
对应于第三 第四个隐层单元
for the third and fourth hidden units

63
00:02:59,795 --> 00:03:01,089
你就会得到下面的这些等式
you get the following

64
00:03:01,158 --> 00:03:03,488
我确认一下你弄懂了这些符号
and let's make sure this notation is clear

65
00:03:03,535 --> 00:03:08,904
这是向量w^[1]_1 这是向量的转置乘以 x
this is the vector W^[1]_1 this is a vector transpose times x ok

66
00:03:08,978 --> 00:03:11,216
那个上标T
so that's what the superscript T there

67
00:03:11,253 --> 00:03:13,340
表示向量转置
represents this is a vector transpose

68
00:03:13,415 --> 00:03:14,860
现在就像你可能所猜想的那样
now as you might have guessed

69
00:03:14,912 --> 00:03:17,771
如果你确实在神经网络中执行
if you're actually implementing in neural network doing this

70
00:03:17,823 --> 00:03:20,150
用for循环来做这些看起来真的很低效
with a for loop seems really inefficient

71
00:03:20,203 --> 00:03:21,750
所以接下来我们要做的就是
so what we're going to do is

72
00:03:21,816 --> 00:03:25,162
把这四个等式向量化
take these four equations and vectorize

73
00:03:25,236 --> 00:03:28,636
我将展示如何把z看做向量计算
so I'm going to start by showing how to compute z as a vector

74
00:03:28,688 --> 00:03:30,712
结果显示 你可以这么做
it turns out you could do it as follows

75
00:03:30,765 --> 00:03:34,918
让我们把这些w堆起来 构成一个矩阵
let me take these WS and stack them into a matrix

76
00:03:34,950 --> 00:03:38,144
然后你就有W^[1]1转置
then you have W 1 1 transpose

77
00:03:38,181 --> 00:03:40,602
所以这是这个行向量 是一个列向量的转置
so that say a row vector oh that's a column vector transpose

78
00:03:40,661 --> 00:03:42,224
变为一个行向量
gives you a row vector

79
00:03:42,292 --> 00:03:48,707
然后 W^[1]2转置 W^[1]3转置以及W^[1]4的转置
then W 1 2 transpose W 1 3 transpose and W 1 4 transpose

80
00:03:48,760 --> 00:03:52,921
把这四个w向量堆叠在一起
and so this by stacking those four W vectors together

81
00:03:53,039 --> 00:03:54,457
你会得出一个矩阵
you end up with a matrix

82
00:03:54,509 --> 00:03:56,065
另一个看待这个的方法是
so another way to think of this is that

83
00:03:56,107 --> 00:03:58,661
我们有四个Logistic回归单元
we have for logistic regression unions there

84
00:03:58,714 --> 00:04:00,803
而每一个Logistic回归单元
and each of the logistic regression unions

85
00:04:00,850 --> 00:04:03,754
都有对应的参数 向量w
have a corresponding parameter vector w

86
00:04:03,790 --> 00:04:05,975
把这四个向量堆叠在一起
and by stacking those four vectors together

87
00:04:06,019 --> 00:04:09,111
你会得出这个4 × 3 的矩阵
you end up with this four by three matrix

88
00:04:09,145 --> 00:04:12,008
然后如果你把这个矩阵
so if you then take this matrix and multiply it

89
00:04:12,042 --> 00:04:16,091
乘以你的输入特征 x1 x2 x3 你会得出
by your input features x1 x2 x3 you end up with

90
00:04:16,129 --> 00:04:19,247
通过矩阵乘法你可以得出
by our matrix multiplication works you end up with

91
00:04:19,290 --> 00:04:28,413
w^[1]_1转置x w^[1]_2转置x w^[1]_3转置x w^[1]_4转置x
w^[1]_1 transpose x w^[1]_2 transpose X of w^[1]_3 transpose x w^[1]_4 transpose x

92
00:04:28,455 --> 00:04:30,908
然后别忘记了b
and then let's not forget the bs

93
00:04:30,966 --> 00:04:33,256
让我们现在加上一个向量
so we now add to this a vector

94
00:04:33,297 --> 00:04:40,696
b^[1]1 b^[1]2 b^[1]3 b^[1]4 所以它们看起来这样
b[1]1 b[1]2 b[1]3 b[1]4 so that they see this

95
00:04:40,736 --> 00:04:46,265
然后 b^[1]1 b^[1]2 b^[1]3 b^[1]4
then this is b[1]1 b[1]2 b[1]3 b[1]4

96
00:04:46,299 --> 00:04:49,535
然后你会看到这四行的结果
and so you see that each of the four rows of this outcome

97
00:04:49,588 --> 00:04:52,886
恰好对应于这四行
correspond exactly to each of these four rows

98
00:04:52,923 --> 00:04:55,294
对应于上面的这四个等式
of each these four quantities that we had above

99
00:04:55,333 --> 00:04:57,591
换句话说 我们刚刚展示了
so in other words we've just shown that

100
00:04:57,645 --> 00:05:04,705
这个东西是等于Z^[1]1 Z^[1]2 Z^[1]3 Z^[1]4
this thing is therefore equal to Z11 Z12 Z13 Z14

101
00:05:04,752 --> 00:05:05,731
就如之前在这定义的
right as defined here

102
00:05:05,789 --> 00:05:07,435
这可能并不奇怪 我们将
and maybe not surprisingly we're going to

103
00:05:07,478 --> 00:05:09,786
把这整个东西称作向量Z^[1]
call this whole thing the vector Z1

104
00:05:09,839 --> 00:05:15,013
我们是把单独的z堆叠起来构成一个列向量Z^[1]的
which is taken by stacking up these um individuals of z into a column vector

105
00:05:15,076 --> 00:05:18,063
当我们向量化时一条经验法则
when we're vectorizing one of the rules of thumb

106
00:05:18,101 --> 00:05:20,362
可能帮助你找到方向
that might help you navigate this 

107
00:05:20,398 --> 00:05:22,514
就是当我们在一层中有不同的节点
is that when we have different nodes in a layer

108
00:05:22,567 --> 00:05:23,982
那就纵向地堆叠起来
we stack them vertically

109
00:05:24,049 --> 00:05:27,199
所以这里有z^[1]1~Z^[1]4
so that's why when you have z^[1]1 to z^[1]4

110
00:05:27,250 --> 00:05:30,375
对应隐层4个不同的节点
those correspond to four different nodes in the hidden layer

111
00:05:30,433 --> 00:05:33,162
我们把这四个数竖向堆叠起来
and so we stack these four numbers vertically 

112
00:05:33,204 --> 00:05:34,908
得到向量Z^[1]
to form the vectors Z1

113
00:05:34,982 --> 00:05:37,121
如果用另一种符号惯例来表示
and to use one more piece of notation

114
00:05:37,172 --> 00:05:39,145
这个4×3的矩阵是我们通过
this 4 by 3 matrix here

115
00:05:39,193 --> 00:05:44,676
堆叠 W^[1]1 W^[1]2 等等 形成的
which we obtained by stacking the lower case you know W11 W12 and so on

116
00:05:44,729 --> 00:05:48,091
我们将这个矩阵称为大写W^[1]
we're going to call this matrix W capital 1

117
00:05:48,144 --> 00:05:49,527
类似的这个矩阵
and similarly this vector 

118
00:05:49,595 --> 00:05:52,631
我们称为b^[1]
we going to call b superscript 1 square bracket

119
00:05:52,679 --> 00:05:54,563
所以这是个4×1的向量
and so this is a 4 by 1 vector

120
00:05:54,622 --> 00:05:59,338
所以现在我们使用矩阵表示来计算Z
so now we've computed Z using this vector matrix notation

121
00:05:59,379 --> 00:06:02,930
最后一件需要做的事是计算这些a的值
the last thing we need to do is also compute these values of a

122
00:06:02,974 --> 00:06:06,257
所以你应该不会惊讶 
and so probably won't surprise you to see 

123
00:06:06,304 --> 00:06:07,962
我们要把a[1]定义为
that we're going to define a1

124
00:06:08,003 --> 00:06:13,076
a[1]1~a[1]4这些激活值的堆叠
as just stacking together those activation values a11 to a14

125
00:06:13,110 --> 00:06:15,514
所以把这四个值堆叠起来
so just take these 4 values and stack them together 

126
00:06:15,588 --> 00:06:17,577
称为一个向量a^[1]
in a vector called a^[1]

127
00:06:17,654 --> 00:06:20,519
这里就会有sigmoid(Z^[1])
and this is going to be sigmoid of z1

128
00:06:20,566 --> 00:06:24,270
这里面 它应用
where there's been implementation of the sigmoid function

129
00:06:24,318 --> 00:06:27,023
sigmoid函数作用于Z的四个元素
that takes in the four elements of Z

130
00:06:27,086 --> 00:06:30,284
也就相当于把sigmoid函数作用到Z的每个元素
and applies the sigmoid function element wise to it

131
00:06:30,321 --> 00:06:33,217
概括一下 我们发现
so just a recap we figured out that

132
00:06:33,266 --> 00:06:38,746
Z^[1] 等于 W^[1] × X + b^[1]
z1 is equal to W 1 times the vector X plus the vector B1

133
00:06:38,794 --> 00:06:42,126
而a[1] = sigmoid(Z^[1])
and a^[1] a 1 is sigmoid of z1


134
00:06:42,179 --> 00:06:45,287
让我们把这些复制到下一个幻灯片 可以看到
let's just copy this to the next slide and what we see is that

135
00:06:45,326 --> 00:06:47,956
对于神经网络的第一层 给予一个输入X
for the first layer of the neural network given an input X

136
00:06:48,020 --> 00:06:52,246
我们得出z^[1] = W^[1]·x + b^[1]
we have that z^[1] = W^[1]·x + b^[1]

137
00:06:52,270 --> 00:06:58,062
而a[1] = sigmoid(Z^[1]) 而它的维度是4×1
and a 1is sigmoid of Z^[1] and the dimensions of this are 4 by 1

138
00:06:58,116 --> 00:07:02,676
等于 这是一个4×3的矩阵乘以1一个3×1的向量
equals this is a 4 by 3 matrix times a 3 by 1 vector

139
00:07:02,737 --> 00:07:07,742
加上一个4×1的向量b  这个同样是4×1的维度
plus a 4by 1 vector B and this is 4 by 1 same dimensions

140
00:07:07,779 --> 00:07:12,515
记得我们说过 x等于a[0]
and remember that we said x is equal to a 0

141
00:07:12,557 --> 00:07:16,307
就像y帽等于a[2]一样
right just like y hat is also equal to a 2

142
00:07:16,362 --> 00:07:18,620
如果你确实想把x
so if you want you can actually take this X 

143
00:07:18,674 --> 00:07:20,817
用a[0]代替
and replace it with a 0

144
00:07:20,870 --> 00:07:25,410
因为a^[0]可以作为输入特征x 这个向量的别名
since a^[0] is if you want as an alias for the vector of input feature x

145
00:07:25,474 --> 00:07:28,150
用同样的方法推导
now through a similar derivation you can figure out

146
00:07:28,199 --> 00:07:30,837
下一层的表示
that the representation for the next layer 

147
00:07:30,889 --> 00:07:33,697
可以写成类似的形式
can also be written similarly

148
00:07:33,748 --> 00:07:36,378
而输出层的作用是 
well what the output layer does is

149
00:07:36,379 --> 00:07:40,854
它带参数W^[2] b^[2]
 it has associated with it so the parameters W^[2] and b^[2]

150
00:07:40,907 --> 00:07:44,577
这里的W^[2]就是一个1×4的矩阵
so W 2 in this case is going to be a 1 by 4 matrix

151
00:07:44,632 --> 00:07:47,250
而b^[2]就是一个实数 即1×1矩阵
and B 2 is just a real number as 1 by 1 and

152
00:07:47,290 --> 00:07:51,874
所以Z^[2]是一个实数 即一个1×1的矩阵
so Z^[2] is going to be a real numbers right as a 1 by 1 matrix

153
00:07:51,937 --> 00:07:57,715
这里就是一个 1×4的矩阵乘以 a 4×1向量 加上b^[2] 1×1
is going to be a 1 by 4 thing times a was 4 by 1 plus B2 is 1 by 1

154
00:07:57,764 --> 00:07:59,626
这最后得出了一个实数
and so this gives you just a real number

155
00:07:59,679 --> 00:08:01,990
如果你把这最后的输出单元
and if you think of this last output unit

156
00:08:02,027 --> 00:08:04,613
看作是Logistic回归的类似物
as just being analogous to logistic regression

157
00:08:04,652 --> 00:08:06,525
它有着参数W和b
which had parameters W and b

158
00:08:06,570 --> 00:08:12,249
W实际上是类似于W^[2]转置
on W really plays analogous role to W^[2] transpose

159
00:08:12,305 --> 00:08:16,349
W^[2]其实是W转置就是W b则等于b^[2]
or W^[2] is really W transpose and b is equal to b^[2]

160
00:08:16,397 --> 00:08:17,811
就像你所知道的
right similar to you know

161
00:08:17,864 --> 00:08:21,696
把网络左边部分盖住 先忽略这些
cover up the left of this network and ignore all that for now

162
00:08:21,757 --> 00:08:24,177
那么这最后的输出单元
then this is just this last output unit 

163
00:08:24,219 --> 00:08:25,789
就像Logistic回归一样
there's a lot like logistic regression

164
00:08:25,825 --> 00:08:29,125
不过我们不再把参数写成W和b
except that instead of writing the parameters as W and b

165
00:08:29,173 --> 00:08:32,642
而是写成W^[2] 和 b^[2] 
we're writing them as W^[2] and b^[2]

166
00:08:32,710 --> 00:08:36,174
其维度分别为1×4和1×1
with dimensions one by four and one by one so

167
00:08:36,186 --> 00:08:38,481
归纳一下 对于Logistic回归
just a recap for logistic regression

168
00:08:38,515 --> 00:08:41,547
为了计算输出或者说预测
to implement the output or implement prediction

169
00:08:41,585 --> 00:08:44,949
你要计算z = w^T x + b
you compute z = w^T x + b

170
00:08:45,014 --> 00:08:50,549
和 y帽 = a = sigmoid(z)
and a y hat equals a equals sigmoid of z

171
00:08:51,477 --> 00:08:54,238
当你有一个单隐层神经网络
when you have a neural network who have one hidden layer

172
00:08:54,296 --> 00:08:56,462
你需要去在代码中实现的是
what you need to implement to computers output 

173
00:08:56,510 --> 00:08:58,728
计算这四个等式
is just the four equations

174
00:08:59,208 --> 00:09:00,387
且你可以把这看成是
and you can think of this as

175
00:09:00,437 --> 00:09:05,008
一个向量化的计算过程 计算出这四个
a vectorized implementation of computing the output of

176
00:09:05,062 --> 00:09:08,060
四个隐层中的Logistic回归单元
first these four logistical regression units in a hidden layer

177
00:09:08,110 --> 00:09:09,127
这就是这两个等式做的
that's what this does

178
00:09:09,190 --> 00:09:12,203
而这个输出层的logistic回归
and then this logistic regression in the output layer

179
00:09:12,242 --> 00:09:13,463
就是用这两个等式算的
which is what this does

180
00:09:13,517 --> 00:09:15,601
我希望这些描述易于理解
I hope this description made sense

181
00:09:15,644 --> 00:09:19,075
但总的说来要想计算神经网络的输出
but takeaway is to compute the output of this neural network

182
00:09:19,128 --> 00:09:21,478
你所需要的只是这四行代码
all you need is those four lines of code

183
00:09:22,048 --> 00:09:26,294
现在 你知道如何输入单个特征向量x
so now you've seen how given a single input feature vector x

184
00:09:26,334 --> 00:09:29,992
你可以运用四行代码计算出 这个神经网络的输出
you can with four lines of code compute the outputs of this neural Network

185
00:09:30,071 --> 00:09:32,484
和当时我们处理Logistic回归时的做法类似
um similar to what we did for logistic regression 

186
00:09:32,554 --> 00:09:36,035
我们也想把整个训练样本都向量化
We will also want to vectorize across multiple training examples

187
00:09:36,088 --> 00:09:37,750
我们会发现
and we'll see that 

188
00:09:37,792 --> 00:09:41,391
通过把不同训练样本堆叠起来构成矩阵
by stacking up training examples in different column in the matrix

189
00:09:41,438 --> 00:09:43,556
只需稍微修改这些公式
or just slight modification to this

190
00:09:43,630 --> 00:09:46,300
你可以得到类似之前Logistic回归的结果
you also similar to what you saw in which is regression

191
00:09:46,358 --> 00:09:52,082
能够同时计算出 不止一个样本的神经网络输出
be able to compute the output of this neural network not just on one example at a time

192
00:09:52,130 --> 00:09:54,965
而是能一次性计算你的整个训练集
but to your say your entire training set at a time

193
00:09:55,021 --> 00:09:57,558
让我们在下一期中了解这些细节
so let's see the details of that in the next video

