1
00:00:00,000 --> 00:00:03,615
在以前的视频中 我们看到如何将训练样本
In the previous video we saw how with your training examples 

2
00:00:03,672 --> 00:00:06,745
横向堆叠起来构成矩阵X
stacked up horizontally in the matrix X 

3
00:00:06,802 --> 00:00:09,945
你就可以导出一个在网络中正向传播算法的
You can derive a vectorized implementation of 

4
00:00:10,007 --> 00:00:11,737
向量化实现
forward propagation through your network 

5
00:00:11,813 --> 00:00:13,709
这里我们讲一下更多的理由 说明
Let's give a bit more justification for 

6
00:00:13,741 --> 00:00:15,015
为什么我们写下的方程
Why the equations we wrote down 

7
00:00:15,070 --> 00:00:19,396
 向量化多个例子的正确实现
is a correct implementation of vectorizing across multiple examples

8
00:00:19,449 --> 00:00:25,129
我们对几个例子手动算算正向传播
So let's go through part of the forward propagation calculation for a few examples 

9
00:00:25,190 --> 00:00:27,415
我们看第一个训练样本
Let's say that for the first training example 

10
00:00:27,513 --> 00:00:36,506
你最后计算出这个W^[1] x^(1)+b^[1]
You end up computing this W^[1] x^(1) plus b1^[1]

11
00:00:36,506 --> 00:00:38,847
然后是第二个训练样本
And then for the second training example 

12
00:00:38,907 --> 00:00:46,929
你最后计算出这个.. x^(2)+b^[1]
You end up computing this .. x^(2) plus b^[1]

13
00:00:48,592 --> 00:00:50,885
然后是第三个训练样本
And then for the third training example 

14
00:00:50,969 --> 00:00:56,739
你最后计算的是这个.. x^(3)+b^[1]
You end up computing this 3 plus b^[1]

15
00:00:56,739 --> 00:00:59,923
所以为了简化幻灯片上的描述
So just to simplify the explanation on this slide 

16
00:00:59,968 --> 00:01:00,961
我要忽略b
I'm going to ignore b

17
00:01:01,009 --> 00:01:05,346
我们看看 比如说 为了简化这个推导一点点
So let's just say you know for the to simplify this justification a little bit 

18
00:01:05,391 --> 00:01:10,125
令b=0 所以参数只需要变化一点点
that B is equal to 0, so the argument going to layout 

19
00:01:10,191 --> 00:01:14,326
就可以处理b非零的情况
will work with just a little bit of a change even when B is nonzero 

20
00:01:14,407 --> 00:01:16,816
它只是简化了这张幻灯片的描述 
It does just simplify the description on this slide of it 

21
00:01:17,702 --> 00:01:21,251
现在W^[1]现在是个矩阵 
Now w1 is going to be some matrix right 

22
00:01:21,321 --> 00:01:24,872
这个矩阵里有一定数目的行
So I have some number of rows in this matrix 

23
00:01:24,962 --> 00:01:28,194
所以你看这个x^(1)的计算
So if you look at this calculation x^(1) 

24
00:01:29,476 --> 00:01:39,365
你这里得到的是W^[1]乘以x^(1) 得到一些列向量
What you have is that W^[1] times x^(1) gives you some column vector 

25
00:01:39,415 --> 00:01:42,388
我这里用这样的小点表示
which you must draw a light ball like this 

26
00:01:43,639 --> 00:01:47,434
同样 你观察一下向量x^(2)
And similarly if you look at this vector x^(2)

27
00:01:47,434 --> 00:02:01,098
这里有W^[1]乘以x^(2)得到其他一些列向量 对吧
You have that W^[1] times x^(2) gives some other column vector, right

28
00:02:01,098 --> 00:02:03,062
然后我给你这个 我想是z^[1](2)
And that's what gives you this,  I guess z^[1](2) 

29
00:02:03,121 --> 00:02:06,340
最后你看x^(3)
and finally if you look at x^(3)

30
00:02:06,390 --> 00:02:18,762
你有W^[1]乘x^(3)得到第三个列向量 就是z^[1](3)
You have W^[1] times x^(3) gives you some third column vector, that's this z^[1](3)

31
00:02:19,395 --> 00:02:25,588
现在如果你考虑训练集X
So now if you consider the training set capital X 

32
00:02:25,645 --> 00:02:30,719
我们将所有训练样本堆叠起来得到的
which we form by stacking together all of our training examples 

33
00:02:31,339 --> 00:02:36,130
所以矩阵大写X是把向量x^(1)拿过来
So the matrix capital X is formed by taking the vector x^(1)

34
00:02:36,220 --> 00:02:43,633
横向叠上x^(2) 然后用x^(3)
and stacking it vertically with x^(2) and then also x^(3) 

35
00:02:43,658 --> 00:02:46,053
就是我们只有三个训练样本的情况
This is a we have only three training examples 

36
00:02:46,119 --> 00:02:49,847
如果有更多的样本 你只要继续横向叠上去
If you have more you know they'll be a little keep stacking horizontally like that 

37
00:02:49,907 --> 00:02:55,143
但如果你现在取这个矩阵X 然后让它乘以W
but if you now take this matrix X and multiply it by W

38
00:02:55,195 --> 00:02:57,705
最后你会得到
then you end up with 

39
00:02:57,705 --> 00:03:00,089
如果你想想矩阵乘法是怎么做的话
If you think about how matrix multiplication works 

40
00:03:00,143 --> 00:03:03,931
你的第一列还是这些一样的值
you end up with the first column being these same values 

41
00:03:03,998 --> 00:03:05,991
这些用紫色画出来的
that had drawn up there in purple 

42
00:03:06,057 --> 00:03:10,366
第二列就是那同样的四个值
The second column will be those same four values 

43
00:03:10,429 --> 00:03:19,345
第三列是这些橙色的值
and the third column will be those are orange values what they turn out to be

44
00:03:19,345 --> 00:03:28,478
但当然了 这就等于将z^[1](1)写成列向量
but of course this is just equal to z^[1](1) expressed as a column vector 

45
00:03:29,671 --> 00:03:34,668
然后是列向量表示的z^[1](2)
followed by z^[1](2) express as a column vector 

46
00:03:34,745 --> 00:03:39,108
然后是列向量表示的z^[1](3)
followed by z^[1](3) also express as a column vector 

47
00:03:39,163 --> 00:03:41,987
这些是特征样本 如果你有更多样本
and this is featuring examples if you have more examples 

48
00:03:42,066 --> 00:03:43,352
那么列数会更多
and they'll be more columns 

49
00:03:43,420 --> 00:03:50,101
所以这就是我们的矩阵大写Z^[1]
and so this is just our matrix capital Z^[1] 

50
00:03:51,155 --> 00:03:56,325
我希望能让你们弄清楚 为什么我们之前要写成
So I hope this gives a justification to why when we had previously 

51
00:03:56,325 --> 00:04:05,488
W^[1]乘x^(i)等于z^[1](i)这个形式
W^[1] times x^(i) equals z^[1][i] 

52
00:04:05,587 --> 00:04:08,004
那是针对单个训练样本的公式
when we're looking at single training example at a time

53
00:04:08,127 --> 00:04:10,291
当你处理不同训练样本时
when you took the different training examples 

54
00:04:10,363 --> 00:04:12,161
就将它们堆到各列中
and stack them up in different columns 

55
00:04:12,228 --> 00:04:14,719
那么对应的结果应该是这样的
Then the corresponding result is that 

56
00:04:14,789 --> 00:04:18,268
你最后会得到这些z叠起来 放在不同的列里
you end up with the z-s stacked as different columns

57
00:04:18,268 --> 00:04:21,750
我不会写出具体形式 但你可以自己验证
and I won't show but you can convince yourself

58
00:04:21,750 --> 00:04:24,517
如果你想用Python广播做矩阵和向量的加法
if you want stats with Python broadcasting

59
00:04:24,517 --> 00:04:27,668
如果你把这些b值加回来
if you add back in these values of b

60
00:04:27,745 --> 00:04:32,155
这些值还是对 但最后结果是
The values are still correct and what actually ends up happening is 

61
00:04:32,221 --> 00:04:34,448
你最后用到Python广播
You end up with Python broadcasting 

62
00:04:34,549 --> 00:04:40,934
你最后将b^[i]单独加到矩阵各列
You end up having b^[i] individually to each of the columns of this matrix 

63
00:04:40,995 --> 00:04:44,379
所以在这张幻灯片中 我只说明了
So on this slide I've only justified that 

64
00:04:44,452 --> 00:04:51,426
为什么Z^[1]等于W^[1] X加b^[1]
Z^[1] equals W^[1] X plus b^[1]

65
00:04:51,517 --> 00:04:56,039
这是四步中第一步的正确向量化实现
That's a correct vectorization of the first step of the four steps 

66
00:04:56,103 --> 00:04:56,998
就是上一张幻灯片那四步
We have in the previous slide 

67
00:04:57,069 --> 00:04:59,351
但事实证明 类似的分析
but it turns out that the similar analysis

68
00:04:59,466 --> 00:05:02,305
让你发现其他步骤
allows you to show that the other steps also work on 

69
00:05:02,378 --> 00:05:06,534
也可以使用非常相似的逻辑 如果将输入成列向量堆叠
using a very similar logic where if you stack the inputs in columns 

70
00:05:06,612 --> 00:05:10,769
那么在方程运算之后 你也能得到成列堆叠的输出
Then after the equation you get the corresponding outputs also stacked up in columns 

71
00:05:10,848 --> 00:05:14,320
最后我们回顾一下这段视频的内容
Finally let's just recap everything we talked about in this video 

72
00:05:15,158 --> 00:05:16,373
这是你的神经网络
This is your neural network 

73
00:05:16,437 --> 00:05:19,673
我说这就是如果你需要
We said that this is what you need to do if you were to implement 

74
00:05:19,744 --> 00:05:23,213
在单个训练样本中实现正向传播算法的话 就要这么做
forward propagation one training example at a time 

75
00:05:23,280 --> 00:05:25,486
就是从i从1到m遍历
going from i equals 1 through m 

76
00:05:26,716 --> 00:05:30,666
然后我说把这些训练样本以列向量堆叠起来
And we said let's stack up the training examples in columns like so 

77
00:05:30,733 --> 00:05:35,499
所以这里面每一个值 z^[1] a^[1] z^[2] a^[2]
And so each of these values z^[1] a^[1] z^[2] a^[2]

78
00:05:35,499 --> 00:05:38,214
对应各列堆叠起来是这样的
The stack of the corresponding columns as follows 

79
00:05:38,267 --> 00:05:46,005
这对A^[1]成立 对Z^[1] A^[1] Z^[2]和A^[2]都成立
So this example for A^[1] but this is true for Z^[1] A^[1] Z^[2] and A^[2]

80
00:05:47,823 --> 00:05:50,713
现在我们上一张幻灯片中展示的是
Then what we showed on the previous slide was that 

81
00:05:50,765 --> 00:05:58,229
这一行能让你对所有m个例子同时向量化
This line allows you to vectorize this across all m examples at the same time 

82
00:05:58,307 --> 00:06:00,565
事实证明 使用类似的推导
And it turns out with the similar reasoning 

83
00:06:00,628 --> 00:06:02,820
你可以证明所有其他行
you can show that all of the other lines 

84
00:06:02,899 --> 00:06:08,003
都是这四行代码的正确向量化形式
are correct vectorization of all four of these lines of code 

85
00:06:09,201 --> 00:06:16,188
这里提醒一下 因为X也等于A^[0]
And just as a reminder, because X is also equal to A^[0]

86
00:06:16,188 --> 00:06:20,767
因为你还记得输入的特征向量x
Because you remember that the input feature vector x

87
00:06:20,767 --> 00:06:27,164
是等于a^[0]的 所以x^(i)等于a^[0](i)
was equal to a^[0], so x^(i) equals a^[0](i)

88
00:06:27,164 --> 00:06:31,753
其实这些方程有一定对称性
I then there's actually a certain symmetry to these equations 

89
00:06:31,821 --> 00:06:41,244
其中第一个方程也可以写成Z^[1]等于W^[1] A^[0]加b^[1]
where this first equation can also be written Z^[1] equals W^[1] A^[0] plus b^[1]

90
00:06:41,312 --> 00:06:45,300
你看这对方程
And so you see that this pair of equations 

91
00:06:45,355 --> 00:06:47,608
还有这对方程形式其实很类似
and this pair of equations actually look very similar 

92
00:06:47,670 --> 00:06:50,131
只不过这里所有指标加了1
but just of all that the indices advance by one 

93
00:06:51,172 --> 00:06:55,225
所以这样就显示出神经网络的不同层次
So this kind of shows that the different layers of a neural network 

94
00:06:55,290 --> 00:06:57,575
你知道大概每一步做的都是一样的
are you know roughly doing the same thing 

95
00:06:57,660 --> 00:07:00,067
或者只不过同样的计算不断重复而已
or just doing the same computation over and over 

96
00:07:00,129 --> 00:07:02,533
这里我们有一个双层神经网络
and here we have a two layer neural network 

97
00:07:02,576 --> 00:07:07,977
我们在下周视频里会讲深得多的神经网络
where we go to a much deeper neural network in next week's videos 

98
00:07:08,055 --> 00:07:10,750
你看到随着网络的深度变大
you see that even deeper in your networks 

99
00:07:10,800 --> 00:07:12,669
基本上也还是重复这两步运算
are basically taking these two steps 

100
00:07:12,741 --> 00:07:15,340
只不过重复次数更多 而这里你看到的是
and just doing them even more times than you're seeing here 

101
00:07:16,184 --> 00:07:20,339
所以这就是对不同训练样本向量化的神经网络
So that's how you can vectorize your neural network across multiple training examples 

102
00:07:20,417 --> 00:07:25,117
接下来 到目前为止 我们一直用的是σ函数
Next, we've so far been using the sigmoid function throughout that neural network 

103
00:07:25,185 --> 00:07:27,468
事实证明 这不是最好的选择
turns out that's actually not the best choice 

104
00:07:27,525 --> 00:07:30,706
在下一个视频中 我们进一步深入研究
On the next video let's delve a little bit further into 

105
00:07:30,757 --> 00:07:33,709
如何使用不同种类的激活函数
how you can use different what's called activation functions 

106
00:07:33,756 --> 00:07:36,769
其中σ函数只是其中一个可能选择
of which the sigmoid function is just one possible choice

