1
00:00:00,000 --> 00:00:01,230
在上一个视频里
In the last video,

2
00:00:01,230 --> 00:00:03,720
你们学到了反向传播的式子
you saw the equations for back propagation.

3
00:00:03,720 --> 00:00:06,900
在这个视频中 我们看看它们的来源
In this video, let's go over some intuition using

4
00:00:06,900 --> 00:00:10,515
这些式子是如何通过流程图推导出来的
the computation graph for how those equations were derived.

5
00:00:10,515 --> 00:00:12,385
这个视频可以不看
This video is completely optional.

6
00:00:12,385 --> 00:00:14,106
所以想看就看 不看也可以忽略
So, feel free to watch or not.

7
00:00:14,106 --> 00:00:16,360
不看你也应该能够把作业完成
you should be able to do the whole work either way.

8
00:00:16,360 --> 00:00:19,410
所以回想当时我们讨论logistic回归的时候
So, recall that when we talk about logistic regression,

9
00:00:19,410 --> 00:00:23,685
我们有这个正向传播步骤 其中我们计算z
we had this forward pass where we compute z,

10
00:00:23,685 --> 00:00:26,145
然后a 然后损失
then a and then the loss.

11
00:00:26,145 --> 00:00:27,445
然后求导数
And then to take the derivatives,

12
00:00:27,445 --> 00:00:32,520
我们有这个反向步骤 我们可以首先计算da
we had this backward pass where we could first compute da,

13
00:00:32,520 --> 00:00:35,400
然后计算dz
and then go on to compute dz,

14
00:00:35,400 --> 00:00:40,720
然后计算dW和db
and then go on to compute dW and db.

15
00:00:40,720 --> 00:00:47,269
所以损失函数的定义是L(a,y)
So, the definition for the loss was L(a,y)

16
00:00:47,270 --> 00:00:56,126
等于 - y log a - (1-y)log(1-a)
equals negative y log a - (1-y)log(1-a)

17
00:00:56,890 --> 00:01:00,283
所以如果你对微积分很熟悉
So, if you are familiar with calculus

18
00:01:00,284 --> 00:01:03,600
那么你求一下这个对a的导数
and you take the derivative of this with respect to a,

19
00:01:03,600 --> 00:01:06,156
那就可以得到da的式子
that would give you the formula for da.

20
00:01:06,156 --> 00:01:09,060
所以da等于那个
So, da is equal to that.

21
00:01:09,060 --> 00:01:12,750
如果我们进行具体的微积分运算 就得到
And if we actually figure out the calculus you could show that this is

22
00:01:12,750 --> 00:01:18,808
这个是-y/a + (1-y)/(1-a)
negative y/a plus (1-y)/(1-a)

23
00:01:18,808 --> 00:01:22,537
直接用微积分对那个式子求导就能得到
you just kind of derive that from calculus by taking derivatives of this.

24
00:01:22,603 --> 00:01:26,680
事实上 当你再往反向走一步 计算dz时
It turns out when you take another step backwards to compute dz,

25
00:01:26,680 --> 00:01:32,430
我们确实算出dz = a - y  我之前解释过
we did work out that dz is equal to a-y. I did explain why previously,

26
00:01:32,430 --> 00:01:35,798
但事实上 使用微积分的链式法则
but it turns out that from the chamber of calculus 

27
00:01:35,868 --> 00:01:45,425
dz等于da g'(z)
dz is equal to da times g'(z).

28
00:01:45,425 --> 00:01:50,535
其中g(z)等于z的sigmoid函数
Where here g(z) equals sigmoid of z

29
00:01:50,535 --> 00:01:56,245
就是logistic回归中输出单元的激活函数
is our activation function for this output unit in logistic regression, right?

30
00:01:56,245 --> 00:02:01,422
所以要记住 这还是logistic回归 这里我们有x1 x2 x3
So, just remember this is still logistic regression where we have x1, x2, x3

31
00:02:01,422 --> 00:02:07,400
这里只有一个sigmoid单元 可以得到y帽
and then just one sigmoid unit and that gives us a, will gives us y hat.

32
00:02:07,400 --> 00:02:11,400
所以这里的激活函数时个sigmoid函数
So, here are the activation function was a sigmoid function.

33
00:02:11,400 --> 00:02:12,960
另外插一句
And as an aside,

34
00:02:12,960 --> 00:02:17,205
对于那些熟悉微积分链式法则的人来说
only for those of you familiar with the chaine rule of calculus

35
00:02:17,205 --> 00:02:22,520
得到这种形式的原因是 a = sigmoid(z)
the reason for this is because a is equal to sigmoid of z.

36
00:02:22,520 --> 00:02:27,908
所以 L对z的偏导
And so, partial of L with respect to z is equal to

37
00:02:27,909 --> 00:02:36,800
就等于L对a的偏导 乘以da/dz
partial of L with respect to a times da/dz.

38
00:02:36,800 --> 00:02:39,327
这a等于sigmoid(z)
This is a is equal to sigmoid of z,

39
00:02:39,327 --> 00:02:49,080
这等于d/dz g(z) 就等于g'(z)
this is equal to d/dz, g(z), which is equal to g'(z).

40
00:02:49,080 --> 00:02:53,293
所以在我们的代码中 dz的式子就是这样的
So, that's why this expression which is dz in our code 

41
00:02:53,294 --> 00:02:59,484
就等于这个式子 在我们的代码中da乘以g'(z)
is equal to this expression which is da in our code times g'(z).

42
00:02:59,484 --> 00:03:05,860
就是这样
And so this is just that.

43
00:03:05,860 --> 00:03:09,172
要弄懂上面的推导
So, that last derivation would made sense only if

44
00:03:09,172 --> 00:03:13,510
你必须熟悉微积分 特别是链式法则
you're familiar with calculus and specifically the chamber from calculus.

45
00:03:13,510 --> 00:03:15,325
但也不用太担心
But if not don't worry about it.

46
00:03:15,325 --> 00:03:18,853
我会尽量用直觉的方式去解释
I'll try to explain the intuition wherever it's needed.

47
00:03:18,853 --> 00:03:22,315
最后计算出这个回归的dz
And then finally having computed dz for this regression,

48
00:03:22,315 --> 00:03:26,335
然后我们计算dW 这结果是
we will compute dw which turns out was

49
00:03:26,335 --> 00:03:31,470
dz·x和db 这就是dz 当你只有一个训练样本的时候
dz times x and db which is just dz when you have a single training example.

50
00:03:31,470 --> 00:03:33,822
这就是logistic回归
So, that was logistic regression.

51
00:03:33,822 --> 00:03:38,504
所以 当你计算神经网络的反向传播时
So, what we're going to do when computing back propagation for a neural network

52
00:03:38,505 --> 00:03:40,418
你做的计算很像这些
is a calculation a lot like this

53
00:03:40,419 --> 00:03:46,995
我们这里会算了两次 现在不是x直接连着输出单元
but only we'll do it twice because now we have not x going to an output unit,

54
00:03:46,995 --> 00:03:50,930
x先进入隐层 然后才连到输出单元
but x going to a hidden layer and then going to an output unit.

55
00:03:50,930 --> 00:03:57,996
所以和我们这里的一步计算不同
And so instead of this computation being sort of one step as we have here,

56
00:03:58,060 --> 00:04:03,778
我们这里有两步 这就像是双层神经网络
we'll have you two steps here in this kind of a neural network with two layers.

57
00:04:03,847 --> 00:04:08,547
所以在这双层神经网络中 我们有一个输入层
So, in this two layer neural network that is we have the input layer,

58
00:04:08,606 --> 00:04:10,021
隐层 还有一个输出层
a hidden layer and then output layer.

59
00:04:10,085 --> 00:04:11,884
回忆一下计算步骤
Remember the steps of a computation.

60
00:04:11,957 --> 00:04:16,794
首先用这个式子计算z^[1]
First you compute z^[1] using this equation,

61
00:04:17,428 --> 00:04:22,177
然后计算a^[1] 然后计算z^[2]
and then compute a^[1] and then you compute z^[2].

62
00:04:22,177 --> 00:04:25,505
并注意到z^[2]也取决于参数W^[2]和b^[2]
And notice z^[2] also depends on the parameters W^[2] and b^[2].

63
00:04:25,505 --> 00:04:27,530
然后从z^[2]出发
And then based on z^[2],

64
00:04:27,530 --> 00:04:32,815
计算a^[2] 最后得到损失函数
compute a^[2] and then finally that gives you the loss.

65
00:04:32,815 --> 00:04:42,399
反向传播的做法是向后推算出da^[2] 然后是dz^[2]
What backpropagation does is it will go backward to compute da^[2] and then dz^[2],

66
00:04:42,399 --> 00:04:48,805
然后你回去计算dW^[2]和db^[2]
and then you go back to compute dW^[2] and dP2,

67
00:04:48,805 --> 00:04:53,232
然后反向计算da^[1]
go backwards to compute da^[1],

68
00:04:53,232 --> 00:04:57,278
dz^[1]等等
dz^[1] and so on.

69
00:04:57,278 --> 00:05:00,948
我们不需要对输入x求导
We don't need to take the riveter as respect to the input x

70
00:05:00,949 --> 00:05:03,745
因为监督学习的输入x是固定的
since the input x for supervised learning is fix 

71
00:05:03,745 --> 00:05:07,845
我们不是想优化x 所以我们就不求导了
We're not trying to optimize x so we won't bother to take derivatives

72
00:05:07,845 --> 00:05:10,431
至少 对于监督学习 不会对x求导
At least, for supervised learning, with respect to x.

73
00:05:10,486 --> 00:05:16,075
我们要跳过显式计算da^[2]
I'm going to skip explicitly computing da^[2].

74
00:05:16,075 --> 00:05:18,783
如果你想的话 可以自己动笔算算da^[2]
If you want, you can actually compute da^[2]

75
00:05:18,783 --> 00:05:21,196
然后用它来计算dz^[2] 但实际上
and then use that to compute dz^[2] but, in practice,

76
00:05:21,196 --> 00:05:25,143
你可以将这两步合并成一步
you could collapse both of these steps into one step 

77
00:05:25,143 --> 00:05:31,715
最后你会得到dz^[2] = a^[2] -y 和以前一样
so you end up at dz^[2]= a^[2]-y, same as before.

78
00:05:31,715 --> 00:05:33,620
而且 你还有..
And, you have also,

79
00:05:33,620 --> 00:05:38,615
我会在下面写出dW^[2]和db^[2]的式子
I'm going to write dW^[2] and db^[2] down here below.

80
00:05:38,615 --> 00:05:46,700
你得到dW^[2] = dz^[2] * a^[1]
you have that dW^[2]=dz^[2]*a^[1],

81
00:05:46,700 --> 00:05:52,040
转置 然后db^[2] = dz^[2]
transpose, and db^[2]=dz^[2].

82
00:05:52,040 --> 00:05:55,990
这一步与logistic回归是非常相似的
This step is quite similar for logistic regression where we had

83
00:05:55,990 --> 00:06:03,550
那个dw = dz·x 不过现在
that dw=dz·x except that now,

84
00:06:03,550 --> 00:06:07,877
a^[1]扮演了x的角色 那有一个额外的转置运算
a^[1] plays the role of x and there's an extra transpose there 

85
00:06:07,878 --> 00:06:14,125
因为大写矩阵W和我们单个参数w的关系是
because the relationship between the capital matrix W and our individual parameters w,

86
00:06:14,125 --> 00:06:16,660
这里有个转置 对吧
there's a transpose there, right?

87
00:06:16,660 --> 00:06:24,223
因为W是一个行向量 在单一输出的logistic回归时是这样
Because W is equal a row vector, in the case of the logistic regression with a single output.

88
00:06:25,151 --> 00:06:26,980
dW^[2]就是这样 然而
dW^[2] is like that, whereas,

89
00:06:26,980 --> 00:06:32,805
W这里是一个列向量 所以a^[1]需要转置一次
W here was a column vector so that's why it has an extra transpose for a^[1],

90
00:06:32,868 --> 00:06:35,945
而这里 对于logistic回归 x不需要转置
whereas, we didn't for x here for logistic regression.

91
00:06:36,730 --> 00:06:39,935
这完成了反向传播的一半
This completes half of backpropagation.

92
00:06:39,993 --> 00:06:44,065
那么 再次 如果你愿意 你可以计算da^[1]
Then, again, you can compute da^[1] if you wish.

93
00:06:44,132 --> 00:06:50,055
虽然在实践中 da^[1]和dz^[1]的计算
Although, in practice, the computation for da^[1] and the dz^[1]

94
00:06:50,056 --> 00:06:52,005
通常合并成一步
are usually collapsed into one step 

95
00:06:52,068 --> 00:06:57,572
所以你实际编程时用的是dz^[1] = W^[2]
and so what you'll actually implement is that dz^[1]=W^[2],

96
00:06:57,572 --> 00:07:00,614
转置* dz^[2]
transpose *dz^[2], 

97
00:07:00,615 --> 00:07:10,383
然后 *g [1]'(z^[1]) 逐个元素乘积
and then times an element-wise product of g[1]'(z^[1]).

98
00:07:10,383 --> 00:07:13,960
我们这里检查一下维度
And, just to do a check on the dimensions, right?

99
00:07:13,960 --> 00:07:19,510
如果你有这样一个新网络
If you have a new network that looks like this,

100
00:07:19,510 --> 00:07:23,000
这么输出y
output y if so.

101
00:07:23,000 --> 00:07:28,265
如果你有n^[0], n_x = n^[0]输入特征
If you have n^[0], n_x = n^[0] input features,

102
00:07:28,265 --> 00:07:30,230
n^[1]个隐藏单位
n^[1] hidden units,

103
00:07:30,230 --> 00:07:34,275
还有n^[2]
and n^[2] so far.

104
00:07:34,275 --> 00:07:38,565
还有n^[2] 在我们的例子中只有一个输出单元
and n^[2], in our case, just one output unit,

105
00:07:38,565 --> 00:07:48,795
那么矩阵W^[2]是(n^[2],n^[1])维
then the matrix W^[2] is (n^[2],n^[1]) dimensional,

106
00:07:48,795 --> 00:07:57,490
z^[2]还有dz^[2]就是是(n^[2],1)维 
z^[2] and therefore dz^[2] are going to be (n^[2],n^[1]) by one dimensional.

107
00:07:57,490 --> 00:08:02,000
当我们做二元分类时 就是1×1维度
This really is going to be a one by one when we are doing binary classification,

108
00:08:02,000 --> 00:08:10,045
然后z^[1] 和dz^[1]一样都是(n^[1],1)维 对吧?
and z^[1] and therefore also dz^[1] are going to be n^[1] by one dimensional, right?

109
00:08:10,045 --> 00:08:16,115
要注意 对于任意变量foo和d foo 它们的维度都是一样的
Note that for any variable foo and d foo always have the same dimension.

110
00:08:16,115 --> 00:08:20,850
所以W和dW也有相同的维度 类似地
That's why W and dW always have the same dimension and similarly,

111
00:08:20,850 --> 00:08:23,680
对于b和db z和dz等等也一样
for b and db and z and dz and so on.

112
00:08:23,680 --> 00:08:26,895
为了确保一切的维度互相匹配
To make sure that the dimensions of this all match up,

113
00:08:26,895 --> 00:08:35,430
我们有dz^[1] = W^[2]转置乘以dz^[2]
we have that dz^[1]=W^[2] transpose times dz^[2]

114
00:08:35,430 --> 00:08:44,490
这是逐元素乘积 * g[1]'(z^[1])
and then this is an element y's product times g[1]' of z^[1].

115
00:08:44,490 --> 00:08:47,040
和上面维度匹配
Matching the dimensions from above,

116
00:08:47,040 --> 00:08:52,575
这是n^[1],1 = W^[2]转置
this is going to be n^[1] by one=W^[2] transpose,

117
00:08:52,575 --> 00:08:57,945
转置之后 这就是(n^[1],n^[2])维
we transpose of this so there's going to be n^[1] by n^[2] dimensional.

118
00:08:57,945 --> 00:09:05,790
dz^[2]就是(n^[2],1)维 然后这个
dz^[2] is going to be n^[2] by one dimensional and then this,

119
00:09:05,790 --> 00:09:07,230
维度和z^[1]相同
this is the same dimension as z^[1].

120
00:09:07,230 --> 00:09:12,606
这也是(n^[1],1)维 所以逐元素y乘积
This is also n^[1] by one dimensional so element y's product.

121
00:09:12,606 --> 00:09:14,350
这个维度有道理吧
The dimensions do make sense, right?

122
00:09:14,350 --> 00:09:18,330
(n^[1],1)维向量可以通过
n^[1] by one dimensional vector can be obtained by

123
00:09:18,330 --> 00:09:23,520
(n^[1],n^[2])维矩阵乘以(n^[2],n^[1])得到.. 因为两个矩阵的乘积
n^[1] by n^[2] dimensional matrix times n^[2] by n^[1] because the product of

124
00:09:23,520 --> 00:09:27,956
可以得到一个(n^[1],1)维矩阵 
these two things gives you an n^[1] by one dimensional matrix 

125
00:09:27,957 --> 00:09:34,618
这就变成 两个(n^[1],1)维向量的逐元素乘积
and so this becomes the element y's product of two n^[1] by one dimensional vectors,

126
00:09:34,618 --> 00:09:36,060
所以维度是匹配的
and so the dimensions do match.

127
00:09:36,060 --> 00:09:40,620
实现后向传播算法有个技巧
One tip when implementing a back prop.

128
00:09:40,620 --> 00:09:44,790
你必须确保矩阵的维度互相匹配
If you just make sure that the dimensions of your matrices match up,

129
00:09:44,790 --> 00:09:47,190
你可以想想不同矩阵的维度都是怎样的
so you think through what are the dimensions of

130
00:09:47,190 --> 00:09:50,430
包括W^[1] W^[2] z^[1]
the various matrices including W^[1], W^[2], z^[1],

131
00:09:50,430 --> 00:09:54,180
z^[2] a^[1] a^[2]等等 只要确定
z^[2], a^[1], a^[2] and so on and just make sure

132
00:09:54,180 --> 00:09:58,642
这些矩阵运算的维度互相匹配
that the dimensions of these matrix operations match up,

133
00:09:58,642 --> 00:10:03,390
有时候 这已经可以消除后向传播实现中的很多bug了
sometimes that will already eliminate quite a lot of bugs in back prop.

134
00:10:03,390 --> 00:10:06,960
好 这就得到dz^[1] 最后
All right. This gives us dz^[1] and then finally,

135
00:10:06,960 --> 00:10:12,160
把dW^[1]和db^[1]写出
just to wrap up dW^[1] and db^[1],

136
00:10:12,160 --> 00:10:13,965
我们应该把它们写在这里
we should write them here I guess,

137
00:10:13,965 --> 00:10:17,200
但右边空间不够了
but since I'm running of the space right on the right of the slight,

138
00:10:17,200 --> 00:10:21,965
dW^[1]和dB^[1]由下式给出
dW^[1] and dB^[1] are given by the following formulas.

139
00:10:21,965 --> 00:10:25,950
这等于dz^[1]乘以x转置
This is going to be equal to the dz^[1] times x transpose

140
00:10:25,950 --> 00:10:28,905
这就等于dz
and this is going to be equal to dz.

141
00:10:28,905 --> 00:10:34,045
你可能注意到这些式子和这些式子的相似性
you might notice a similarity between these equations and these equations,

142
00:10:34,045 --> 00:10:35,466
这真的不是巧合 
which is really no coincidence 

143
00:10:35,552 --> 00:10:41,660
因为x扮演了a^[0]的角色 所以x转置就是a^[0]转置
because x plays the role of a^[0] so x transpose is a^[0] transpose.

144
00:10:41,660 --> 00:10:45,484
那些方程式其实非常相似
Those equations are actually very similar.

145
00:10:45,484 --> 00:10:50,260
这样你们就理解反向传播是怎么推导的了
That gives a sense for how backpropagation is derived.

146
00:10:50,260 --> 00:10:54,530
对于dz^[2] dW^[2] 我们有六个关键方程
We have six key equations here for dz^[2], dW^[2],

147
00:10:54,530 --> 00:11:00,190
db^[2] dz^[1] dW^[1]和db^[1]
db^[2], dz^[1],dW^[1] and db^[1].

148
00:11:00,190 --> 00:11:05,767
我们就把这两个方程拿过来 放到下一页 就在这里
Let me just take these six equations and copy them over to the next slide. Here they are.

149
00:11:05,767 --> 00:11:08,950
到目前为止 我们必须写出反向传播
So far, we have to write backpropagation,

150
00:11:08,950 --> 00:11:13,959
如果你每次训练单个训练样本的话
for if you are training on a single training example at the time,

151
00:11:13,959 --> 00:11:21,530
但你应该不会意外 我们实际不会一个个样本算
but it should come as no surprise that rather than working on a single example at a time,

152
00:11:21,530 --> 00:11:27,810
我们要把所有训练样本向量化
we would like to vectorize across different training examples.

153
00:11:27,810 --> 00:11:30,971
我们记得正向传播的时候
We remember that for propagation,

154
00:11:30,971 --> 00:11:33,545
我们一次处理一个样本
when we're operating on one example at a time,

155
00:11:33,545 --> 00:11:41,665
我们有这样的方程 比如a^[1] = g^[1](z^[1])
we had equations like this as was say a^[1]=G1 of z^[1].

156
00:11:41,665 --> 00:11:43,655
为了向量化
In order to vectorize,

157
00:11:43,655 --> 00:11:54,318
我们把这些z堆叠起来 写成这样的列向量
we took say the zs and stacked them up in columns like this

158
00:11:54,319 --> 00:12:00,775
一直到z^[1](m) 并把这个叫Z
onto z^[1](m) and call this capital Z.

159
00:12:00,775 --> 00:12:04,960
我们发现将所有样本以列向量堆叠起来
Then we found that by stacking things up in columns

160
00:12:04,960 --> 00:12:10,240
然后定义这个的大写版本
and defining the capital uppercase version of this,

161
00:12:10,240 --> 00:12:17,093
我们就得到Z^[1] = W^[1] X + b
we then just had Z^[1]=W^[1] x + B

162
00:12:17,093 --> 00:12:24,700
还有A^[1] = g^[1](Z^[1]) 对吧?
and A^[1]=g^[1](z^[1]), right?

163
00:12:24,700 --> 00:12:28,645
在本课中我们很注意符号约定 
We define the notation very carefully in this course to make sure that

164
00:12:28,645 --> 00:12:35,550
确保顺利将样本堆叠到矩阵里的各列 然后满足这种形式
stacking examples into different columns of a matrix makes all this work out.

165
00:12:35,550 --> 00:12:40,105
事实证明 如果你仔细推算这里的数学步骤
It turns out that if you go through the math carefully,

166
00:12:40,105 --> 00:12:46,645
反向传播用的也是一样的技巧 所以向量化方程是这样的
the same trick also works for backpropagation so the vectorize equations are as follows.

167
00:12:46,645 --> 00:12:51,486
首先 如果这些dz代表不同的训练样本
First, if you take these dzs for different training examples 

168
00:12:51,486 --> 00:12:55,487
然后堆叠起来 把它们作为矩阵的列向量堆叠起来 
and stack them as the different columns of a matrix 

169
00:12:55,562 --> 00:12:58,339
这两个也一样
and the same for this and the same for this,

170
00:12:58,339 --> 00:13:03,070
这就是向量化的实现 然后这就是定义
then this is the vectorize implementation and then here's the definition for,

171
00:13:03,070 --> 00:13:05,569
如何计算dW^[2]的定义
or here's how you can compute dW^[2].

172
00:13:05,569 --> 00:13:11,130
这里有个额外的1/m 因为成本函数J是
There is this extra 1/M because the cost function J is

173
00:13:11,130 --> 00:13:18,410
这个1/m 从y=1到m 对损失求和
this 1/M of sum for y = one through M of the losses.

174
00:13:18,410 --> 00:13:20,615
计算导数时
When computing derivatives,

175
00:13:20,615 --> 00:13:23,081
我们有这个额外的1/m项 
we have that extra 1/M term just as we did 

176
00:13:23,082 --> 00:13:27,982
当我们计算Logistic回归的更新
when we were computing the [inaudible] updates for the logistic regression.

177
00:13:27,982 --> 00:13:31,790
那是对db^[2]的更新
That's the update you get for db^[2].

178
00:13:31,790 --> 00:13:40,640
再次 sum(dZ^[2]).. 还有1/m  然后dZ^[1]是这样算的
Again, sum of the dZ and then with a 1/m and then dZ^[1] is computed as follows.

179
00:13:40,640 --> 00:13:49,109
再次 这是逐元素乘积 而之前
Once again, this is an element-wise product only whereas previously,

180
00:13:49,109 --> 00:13:56,595
在上一张幻灯片里看到 这是(n^[1],1)维向量
we saw on the previous slide that this was an n^[1] by one dimensional vector.

181
00:13:56,595 --> 00:14:03,185
现在 这是n^[1],m维矩阵
Now, this is a n^[1] by m dimensional matrix.

182
00:14:03,185 --> 00:14:09,045
这两者也是(n^[1],m)维
Both of these are also n^[1] by m dimensional.

183
00:14:09,045 --> 00:14:19,310
所以这个星号就表示逐元素乘积 然后最后
That's why that asterisk is element y's product and then finally,

184
00:14:19,310 --> 00:14:21,454
剩下的两个更新
the remaining two updates.

185
00:14:21,454 --> 00:14:25,836
应该不会很意外了
Perhaps it shouldn't look too surprising.

186
00:14:25,836 --> 00:14:29,880
我希望本视频能让你们知道这些后向传播算法是怎么推导的
I hope that gives you some intuition for how the backpropagation algorithm is derived.

187
00:14:29,880 --> 00:14:32,205
在所有机器学习领域中
In all of machine learning,

188
00:14:32,205 --> 00:14:34,820
我认为反向传播算法的推导 
I think the derivation of the backpropagation algorithm

189
00:14:34,820 --> 00:14:38,465
实际上是我看过的最复杂的数学之一
is actually one of the most complicated pieces of math I've seen,

190
00:14:38,465 --> 00:14:42,470
它需要知道线性代数以及 
and it requires knowing both linear algebra as well as

191
00:14:42,470 --> 00:14:46,830
矩阵的导数 要用链式法则推导出来
the derivative of matrices to re-derive it from scratch from first principles.

192
00:14:46,830 --> 00:14:50,165
如果你不是矩阵微积分的专家
If you aren't an expert in matrix calculus,

193
00:14:50,165 --> 00:14:54,255
使用这个步骤 你可以自己证明求导算法
using this process, you might prove the derivative algorithm yourself,

194
00:14:54,255 --> 00:14:57,500
但我认为实际上有很多深度学习实践者
but I think there are actually plenty of deep learning practitioners

195
00:14:57,500 --> 00:15:02,238
看过的推导过程水平和本视频差不多
that have seen the derivation at about the level you've seen in this video

196
00:15:02,239 --> 00:15:05,395
他们就已经掌握了这种直觉
and are already able to have all the very intuitions

197
00:15:05,396 --> 00:15:08,580
并能够非常有效地实现该算法
and be able to implement this algorithm very effectively.

198
00:15:08,580 --> 00:15:10,566
如果你是微积分的专家
If you are an expert in calculus,

199
00:15:10,566 --> 00:15:13,395
你可以看看 是否可以从头开始推导全部公式
do see if you can derive the whole thing from scratch.

200
00:15:13,395 --> 00:15:15,665
这是最难的一部分数学
It is one of the very hardest pieces of math.

201
00:15:15,665 --> 00:15:20,010
这是我在机器学习领域中看到的最难的推导之一
One of the very hardest derivations that I've seen in all of machine learning.

202
00:15:20,010 --> 00:15:22,861
无论如何 只要你实现了这些方程
Either way, if you implement this,

203
00:15:22,861 --> 00:15:27,260
这就能用了 我想你也会有足够的直觉来调整并使其工作
this will work and I think you have enough intuitions to tune and get it to work.

204
00:15:27,260 --> 00:15:31,377
最后我还有一个细节想给大家分享
There's just one last detail I want to share with you

205
00:15:31,445 --> 00:15:34,190
在你实现神经网络之前
before you implement your neural network,

206
00:15:34,190 --> 00:15:37,334
如何初始化你的神经网络的权重
which is how to initialize the weights of your neural network.

207
00:15:37,389 --> 00:15:40,600
事实证明 初始化你的参数
It turns out that initializing your parameters,

208
00:15:40,600 --> 00:15:42,560
不要全零 而是随机初始化
not to zero but randomly,

209
00:15:42,560 --> 00:15:45,515
对于训练你的神经网络而言 这一点非常重要
turns out to be very important for training your neural network.

210
00:15:45,515 --> 00:15:48,000
在下一个视频中 你将会看到原因
In the next video, you'll see why.

