1
00:00:00,030 --> 00:00:02,139
欢迎回来 通过本周的视频课程
Welcome back in this week's videos

2
00:00:02,192 --> 00:00:04,267
你会学到 如何实现一个神经网络
you learn to implement a neural network.

3
00:00:04,304 --> 00:00:06,732
在我们深入学习技术细节之前
Before diving into the technical details

4
00:00:06,774 --> 00:00:09,324
通过本视频 我想带你快速地了解一下
I wanted in this video to give you a quick overview

5
00:00:09,370 --> 00:00:11,506
本周课程中 你会学习到哪些内容
of what you'll be seeing in this week's videos.

6
00:00:11,554 --> 00:00:14,664
所以 如果本视频的某些内容你不甚理解
So if you don't follow all the details in this video,

7
00:00:14,710 --> 00:00:15,780
不用太担心
don't worry about it

8
00:00:15,843 --> 00:00:18,683
之后的视频课程里 还会深入其中的技术细节
we'll delve in the technical details in the next few videos

9
00:00:18,720 --> 00:00:20,619
但现在 我们来快速过一遍
But for now, let's give a quick overview

10
00:00:20,683 --> 00:00:23,302
如何实现神经网络
of how you implement in your network.

11
00:00:23,881 --> 00:00:25,984
上周 我们讨论了logistic回归
Last week we had talked about logistic regression

12
00:00:26,058 --> 00:00:29,720
一起了解了 这个模型
and we saw how this model corresponds to 

13
00:00:29,768 --> 00:00:32,050
和下面这个流程图的联系
the following computation graph

14
00:00:32,119 --> 00:00:36,662
这里面 你需要输入特征x、参数w和b
where you need to put the features X and parameters w and b

15
00:00:36,693 --> 00:00:38,321
用那些计算z
that allows you to compute z

16
00:00:38,351 --> 00:00:39,936
然后用z计算出a
which is then used to compute a

17
00:00:40,006 --> 00:00:45,234
我们用a同时表示输出y帽
And we were using a interchangeably with this output Y hat

18
00:00:45,297 --> 00:00:48,894
接下你就可以计算损失函数L
and then you can compute the loss function L.

19
00:00:48,947 --> 00:00:51,224
神经网络就是这个样子
A neural network looks like this

20
00:00:51,271 --> 00:00:53,286
我之前已经提到过了
and as I'd already previously alluded

21
00:00:53,338 --> 00:00:58,268
你可以把很多sigmoid单元堆叠起来构成一个神经网络
you can form a neural network by stacking together a lot of little sigmoid units

22
00:00:58,353 --> 00:01:03,613
而之前 这个节点对应两个计算步骤
whereas previously this node corresponds to two steps of calculations

23
00:01:03,671 --> 00:01:05,811
首先 计算出z值
The first three compute the z value.

24
00:01:05,864 --> 00:01:08,201
然后计算a值
Second is it computes this a value

25
00:01:08,233 --> 00:01:12,018
这个神经网络中 这堆节点
in this neural network this stack of nodes

26
00:01:12,090 --> 00:01:17,472
对应像z这样的计算
will correspond to a z like calculation like this

27
00:01:17,473 --> 00:01:19,954
然后那个节点 接着是这种类似a的计算
as well as an a like calculation like that

28
00:01:19,985 --> 00:01:23,606
然后这个节点
and then that node will 

29
00:01:23,607 --> 00:01:25,909
就对应了另一个类似z和a的计算
correspond to another z, and another a like calculation

30
00:01:25,990 --> 00:01:30,003
因此 我们稍后会使用下面这些记号
so the notation which we should use later will look like this

31
00:01:30,063 --> 00:01:33,133
首先 我们用x表示输入特征
First, with inputs the features X 

32
00:01:33,190 --> 00:01:36,509
还有参数W和b
together with some parameters W and b

33
00:01:36,567 --> 00:01:39,582
这样你就可以算出z^[1]
and this will allow you to compute z^[1] 

34
00:01:39,624 --> 00:01:43,065
我们会使用新的符号
so new notation that one should use is that

35
00:01:43,117 --> 00:01:45,819
上标 方括号 1
we'll use a superscript square bracket 1

36
00:01:45,872 --> 00:01:49,827
表示与这些节点相关的量
to refer to quantities associated with this stack of nodes

37
00:01:49,878 --> 00:01:51,180
所谓的“层”
called a layer

38
00:01:51,218 --> 00:01:54,190
我们用上标 方括号 2
and then later we'll use superscript square bracket 2 

39
00:01:54,747 --> 00:01:57,678
表示和这个东西相关的量
to refer to quantities associated with that

40
00:01:57,751 --> 00:02:01,360
这是神经网络的另一层
really that's called another layer of the neural network

41
00:02:01,405 --> 00:02:04,243
这里使用这样的上标方括号 目的是
and the superscript square brackets like we have here

42
00:02:04,244 --> 00:02:09,238
区分用来表示单个训练样本的圆括号
are not to be confused with the superscript round brackets

43
00:02:09,288 --> 00:02:12,901
圆括号是用来表示单个训练样本的
which we used to refer to individual training examples

44
00:02:12,962 --> 00:02:15,888
x上标(i)表示
so whereas x superscript round bracket i

45
00:02:15,931 --> 00:02:17,658
第i个训练样本
referred to the Ith trained example

46
00:02:17,700 --> 00:02:21,357
上标方括号1 2
superscript square bracket 1 and 2 refers to

47
00:02:21,398 --> 00:02:27,439
表示不同的层 这是网络的第一层 这是第二层
these different layers layer 1 and layer 2 in this network

48
00:02:27,498 --> 00:02:33,734
然后使用类似logistic回归去计算了z^[1]之后
but they're going on after computing z^[1] similar to logistic regression

49
00:02:33,797 --> 00:02:40,701
需要使用sigmoid(z^[1]) 计算a^[1]
there will be a computation to compute a1 and that's just somesigmoid of z^[1]

50
00:02:40,753 --> 00:02:48,618
接下来你用另外一个线性方程计算 z^[2]
and then you compute z^[2] using another linear equation

51
00:02:48,670 --> 00:02:50,943
接着计算a^[2]
and then compute a^[2]

52
00:02:51,001 --> 00:02:56,376
a^[2]就是整个神经网络的最终输出
and a^[2] is the final output of the neural network

53
00:02:56,459 --> 00:02:59,240
同时我也用y帽表示网络的输出
and will also be used interchangeably with y hat

54
00:02:59,298 --> 00:03:00,974
我知道其中有很多细节
so I know there was a lot of details

55
00:03:01,022 --> 00:03:04,149
但关键你要学到这种直觉
but the key intuition to take away is that

56
00:03:04,215 --> 00:03:09,037
logistic回归中 得到z后 直接计算a
whereas for logistic regression we had this z followed by a calculation

57
00:03:09,100 --> 00:03:12,665
而这个神经网络中我们要做多次计算
and this neural network here we just do it multiple times

58
00:03:12,740 --> 00:03:14,907
反复计算z和a
a z followed by a calculation

59
00:03:14,975 --> 00:03:17,291
反复计算a和z
and a z followed by a calculation

60
00:03:17,340 --> 00:03:21,159
最后计算损失函数
and then you finally compute the loss at the end

61
00:03:21,211 --> 00:03:24,150
应该还记得 在logistic回归中
and you remember that for the logistic regression

62
00:03:24,203 --> 00:03:26,753
会有这种反向计算
we had in some backward calculation

63
00:03:26,819 --> 00:03:33,285
用来计算导数da dz这些 
in order to compute derivatives they computing da dz and so on

64
00:03:33,331 --> 00:03:35,771
同样在神经网络中
so in the same way in a neural network

65
00:03:35,853 --> 00:03:37,915
也有类似的反向计算
we'll end up doing a backward calculation

66
00:03:37,976 --> 00:03:39,437
像这样
that looks like this

67
00:03:39,505 --> 00:03:47,851
最后会计算da^[2] 还有dz^[2]
and you end up computing da^[2] dz^[2]

68
00:03:47,911 --> 00:03:55,539
然后让你计算出dW^[2] db^[2]等等
that allows you to compute so dW^[2] db^[2] and so on

69
00:03:56,507 --> 00:04:00,307
就是这样从右到左反向计算
in this order the right to left backward calculation

70
00:04:00,374 --> 00:04:03,223
用红色箭头表示的方向
that is denoting with the red arrows

71
00:04:03,899 --> 00:04:08,745
刚才带你大概了解了一下神经网络长什么样
So that's quick overview of what a neural network looks like

72
00:04:08,806 --> 00:04:10,231
基本上 我们把logistic回归
but we basically take the logistic regression

73
00:04:10,284 --> 00:04:11,943
重复了两次
and repeating it twice

74
00:04:11,990 --> 00:04:15,596
这视频讲了很多新符号和细节
I know there was a lot of new notation lot of new details

75
00:04:15,628 --> 00:04:17,678
如果你没有理解 不用担心 
don't worry about to get and follow everything

76
00:04:17,711 --> 00:04:21,115
在接下来的视频中 我们会慢慢讲解这些细节
we'll go into the details most slowly in the next few videos

77
00:04:21,176 --> 00:04:22,863
继续看下一个视频吧
so let's go on to the next video

78
00:04:22,905 --> 00:04:26,099
我们将会开始讨论 神经网络的表示
we'll stop to talk about the neural network representation

