1
00:00:00,000 --> 00:00:03,846
为什么神经网络需要非线性激活函数?
Why does your neural network need a nonlinear activation function 

2
00:00:03,900 --> 00:00:07,281
事实证明 要让你的神经网络能够计算出有趣的函数
It turns out that for your neural network to compute interesting functions 

3
00:00:07,347 --> 00:00:11,116
你必须使用非线性激活函数 除非你想..
you do need to take a nonlinear activation function  unless you want

4
00:00:11,116 --> 00:00:15,005
这是神经网络正向传播的方程
so here is the forprop equations for the neural network

5
00:00:15,065 --> 00:00:17,386
为什么我们不能直接去掉这个?
why don't we just get rid of this 

6
00:00:17,453 --> 00:00:22,114
去掉函数g 然后令a^[1]等于z^[1]
get rid of the function g and set a^[1] equals z^[1] 

7
00:00:22,185 --> 00:00:27,804
或者你可以令g(z)等于z 对吧
or alternatively you could say that g(z) is equal to z, right 

8
00:00:27,884 --> 00:00:31,579
这有时叫线性激活函数 
Sometimes this is called the linear activation function 

9
00:00:31,652 --> 00:00:34,956
更学术一点的名字是 恒等激活函数
maybe a better name for it would be the identity activation function 

10
00:00:35,005 --> 00:00:37,703
因为它们就直接把输入值输出了
because they're just outputs whatever was input 

11
00:00:37,704 --> 00:00:43,106
为了说明问题 我们看看a^[2]等于z^[2]会怎样
for the purpose of this  what if a^[2] was just equal to z^[2] 

12
00:00:43,180 --> 00:00:45,217
事实证明 如果你这样做
it turns out if you do this 

13
00:00:45,304 --> 00:00:53,210
那么这个模型的输出y或y帽不过是你输入特征x的线性组合
then this model is just computing y or y hat as a linear function of your input features x

14
00:00:53,210 --> 00:00:56,931
我们看前两个式子 如果你令
take the first two equations if you have that 

15
00:00:57,016 --> 00:01:07,488
a^[1]等于z^[1 ]等于W^[1] x+b
a^[1] is equal to z^[1] is equal to W^[1] x plus b 

16
00:01:07,565 --> 00:01:20,603
然后a^[2]等于z^[2]等于W^[2] a^[1]加上b^[2]
and if then a^[2] is equal to z^[2] is equal to W^[2] a^[1] plus b^[2]

17
00:01:20,686 --> 00:01:23,535
如果你代入a^[1]的定义
then if you take the definition of a^[1] 

18
00:01:23,611 --> 00:01:26,348
代进去 就发现
and plug it in there you find that 

19
00:01:26,399 --> 00:01:36,739
a^[2]等于W^[2]乘以W^[1] x+b^[1] **
a^[2] is equal to W^[2] times W^[1] x plus b^[1], a bit 

20
00:01:37,718 --> 00:01:43,326
好 如果这是 a^[1]加b^[2]
all right so this is um a^[1] plus b^[2] 

21
00:01:43,421 --> 00:01:56,695
因为这化简成 W^[2] W^[1] x +W^[2] b^[1] +b^[2]
and so this simplifies to W^[2] W^[1] x plus W^[2] b^[1] plus b^[2] 

22
00:01:57,984 --> 00:02:06,776
所以我们可以写成W' b'
so this it's just let's call this w prime b prime 

23
00:02:06,844 --> 00:02:10,656
这其实就等于W'x+b'
so it is just equal to w prime x plus b Prime 

24
00:02:10,709 --> 00:02:13,407
如果你要用线性激活函数
If you were to use linear activation functions 

25
00:02:13,464 --> 00:02:16,635
或者叫恒等激活函数
or we go to call them identity activation functions 

26
00:02:16,704 --> 00:02:22,419
那么神经网络只是把输入线性组合再输出
then the neural network is just outputting a linear function of the input

27
00:02:22,484 --> 00:02:26,005
我们稍后会谈到深度网络 
and we'll talk about deep networks later 

28
00:02:26,084 --> 00:02:29,191
有很多层的神经网络 很多隐藏层
neural networks with many many layers, many many hidden layers 

29
00:02:29,248 --> 00:02:33,193
事实证明 如果你使用线性激活函数
and it turns out that if you use a linear activation function 

30
00:02:33,262 --> 00:02:36,089
或者如果没有激活函数 
or alternatively if you don't have an activation function 

31
00:02:36,144 --> 00:02:39,084
那么无论你的神经网络有多少层 
then no matter how many layers your neural network has 

32
00:02:39,143 --> 00:02:42,519
一直在做的只是计算线性激活函数 
always doing is just computing a linear activation function 

33
00:02:42,569 --> 00:02:45,166
所以不如直接去掉全部隐藏层
so you might as well not have any hidden layers 

34
00:02:46,092 --> 00:02:49,146
在我们简要提到的案例中
some of the cases that briefly mentioned 

35
00:02:49,195 --> 00:02:52,986
事实证明 如果你在这里用线性激活函数
it turns out that if you have a linear activation function here 

36
00:02:53,035 --> 00:02:54,942
在这里用Sigmoid函数
and a sigmoid function here 

37
00:02:55,068 --> 00:02:57,786
那这个模型的复杂度
then this model is no more expressive 

38
00:02:57,861 --> 00:03:02,367
和没有任何隐藏层的标准逻辑Logistic回归是一样的
than standard logistic regression without any hidden layer 

39
00:03:02,427 --> 00:03:03,847
我懒得证明
so I won't bother to prove that 

40
00:03:03,904 --> 00:03:05,658
但如果你愿意 可以自己证明一下
but you could try to do so if you want 

41
00:03:05,713 --> 00:03:11,296
但要点在于 线性隐层一点用都没有
but the take-home is that a linear hidden layer is more or less useless 

42
00:03:11,364 --> 00:03:16,196
因为两个线性函数的组合本身就是线性函数
because the composition of two linear functions is itself a linear function

43
00:03:16,263 --> 00:03:19,765
所以除非你引入非线性
so unless you throw a non-linearity in there 

44
00:03:19,828 --> 00:03:22,348
那么你无法计算更有趣的函数
then you're not computing more interesting functions 

45
00:03:22,426 --> 00:03:24,902
网络层数再多也不行
even as you go deeper in the network 

46
00:03:25,000 --> 00:03:29,514
只有一个地方可以使用线性激活函数
there is just one place where you might use a linear activation function 

47
00:03:29,573 --> 00:03:36,917
g(z)=z 就是如果你要机器学习的是回归问题
g(z) equals z and that's if you are doing machine learning on a regression problem 

48
00:03:36,987 --> 00:03:42,475
所以y是一个实数 比如说 你想预测房地产价格
so y is a real number, so for example if you're trying to predict housing prices 

49
00:03:42,545 --> 00:03:46,675
所以y是一个.. 不是0和1 而是一个实数
so y is a, it's not 0, 1, but it's a real number 

50
00:03:46,743 --> 00:03:50,949
你知道房价是0美元 一直到
you know anywhere from zero dollars is a price of house 

51
00:03:51,034 --> 00:03:55,336
能多贵就多贵
up to however expensive right house is gonna get

52
00:03:55,336 --> 00:03:58,953
我也不知道能到多少 也许几百万美元
I guess maybe however can be, you know, potentially millions of dollars 

53
00:03:59,015 --> 00:04:04,590
但不管你的数据集里房价是多少
so however however much houses cost in your data set 

54
00:04:04,644 --> 00:04:09,327
y都是一个实值
but y takes on these real values 

55
00:04:09,327 --> 00:04:13,889
那么用线性激活函数也许可行
then it might be OK to have a linear activation function here 

56
00:04:13,953 --> 00:04:19,827
所以你的输出y也是一个实数
so that your output y hat is also a real number 

57
00:04:19,897 --> 00:04:22,606
从负无穷到正无穷
going anywhere from minus infinity to plus infinity 

58
00:04:23,786 --> 00:04:28,529
但这些隐藏单元不能用线性激活函数
but then the hidden units should not use the linear activation functions 

59
00:04:28,588 --> 00:04:33,865
它们可以用ReLU或者tanh或者带泄漏的ReLU或者别的东西
they could use ReLU or tanh or leaky ReLU or maybe something else 

60
00:04:33,865 --> 00:04:37,026
所以唯一可以用线性激活函数的地方
so the one place you might use as linear activation function 

61
00:04:37,116 --> 00:04:39,530
通常就是输出层
others usually in the output layer 

62
00:04:39,597 --> 00:04:46,678
除了这种情况 会在隐层用线性激活函数的
but other than that using a linear activation function in a hidden layer 

63
00:04:46,743 --> 00:04:51,668
可能除了与压缩有关的一些非常特殊的情况
except for some very special circumstances relating to compression 

64
00:04:51,734 --> 00:04:53,000
那方面我不想深入讨论
that we won't want to talk about 

65
00:04:53,081 --> 00:04:55,803
在那之外 使用线性激活函数非常少见
Using a linear activation function is extremely rare 

66
00:04:55,872 --> 00:05:00,138
哦 当然实际上预测住房价格就像你在第一周的视频中看到的
oh and of course actually predicting housing prices as you saw on the week 1 video 

67
00:05:00,203 --> 00:05:02,405
因为房价都是非负数
because housing prices are all non-negative 

68
00:05:02,466 --> 00:05:06,220
也许甚至可以使用ReLU激活函数
perhaps even then you can use a ReLU activation function 

69
00:05:06,292 --> 00:05:10,836
这样你的所有y帽都大于等于0
so that your outputs y hat are all greater than or equal to 0 

70
00:05:10,884 --> 00:05:15,878
我希望这样你就知道 为什么使用非线性激活函数
so I hope that gives you a sense of why having a nonlinear activation function 

71
00:05:15,959 --> 00:05:18,577
对神经网络来说很关键
is a critical part of neural networks 

72
00:05:18,645 --> 00:05:22,591
接下来 我们将开始谈论梯度下降
next we're going to start to talk about gradient descent 

73
00:05:22,691 --> 00:05:27,275
并在下一个视频中开始讨论梯度下降的基础
and to do that to set up for discussion for gradient descent in the next video 

74
00:05:27,360 --> 00:05:29,902
我想告诉你如何估计 如何计算
I want to show you how to estimate how to compute 

75
00:05:29,986 --> 00:05:33,699
单个激活函数的导数 斜率
the slope of the derivative of individual activation functions 

76
00:05:33,769 --> 00:05:35,633
我们下一个视频继续
so let's go on to the next video

