1
00:00:00,874 --> 00:00:02,142
要搭建一个神经网络
When you build a neural network 

2
00:00:02,200 --> 00:00:04,272
你可以选择的是
one of the choices you get to make is 

3
00:00:04,325 --> 00:00:07,551
选择隐层里用那一个激活函数
what activation functions use in the hidden layers 

4
00:00:07,551 --> 00:00:10,427
还有神经网络的输出单元用什么激活函数
as well as at the output unit of your neural network 

5
00:00:10,488 --> 00:00:14,329
到目前为止 我们一直用的是σ激活函数
So far we've just been using the sigmoid activation function 

6
00:00:14,329 --> 00:00:17,293
但有时其他函数效果要好得多
but sometimes other choices can work much better 

7
00:00:17,351 --> 00:00:19,700
我们看看一些可供选择的函数
let's take a look at some of the options 

8
00:00:19,765 --> 00:00:23,342
在神经网络的正向传播步骤中 
in the forward propagation steps for the neural network 

9
00:00:23,398 --> 00:00:27,652
我们有这两步 用的是σ函数
we have these two steps where we use the sigmoid function here 

10
00:00:27,719 --> 00:00:30,868
这个σ就是所谓的激活函数
so that sigmoid is called an activation function 

11
00:00:30,917 --> 00:00:35,810
这是大家很熟悉的σ函数
and here is the familiar sigmoid function 

12
00:00:35,868 --> 00:00:39,802
就是a = 1/(1+e^-z)
a equals 1 over 1 plus e to negative z

13
00:00:39,802 --> 00:00:47,662
所以在更一般的情况下 我们可以使用不同的函数g(z)
So in the more general case we can have a different function g of z 

14
00:00:47,726 --> 00:00:50,152
我会在这里写出来
which I'm gonna write here

15
00:00:50,152 --> 00:00:56,561
其中g可以是非线性函数 不一定是σ函数
where g could be a nonlinear function that may not be the sigmoid function 

16
00:00:56,640 --> 00:01:01,521
比如说 σ函数介于0和1之间
so for example the sigmoid function goes between 0 and 1 

17
00:01:01,581 --> 00:01:07,322
有个激活函数几乎总比σ表现更好
an activation function that almost always works better than the sigmoid function is 

18
00:01:07,396 --> 00:01:11,411
就是tanh函数 或者叫双曲正切函数
the tanh function or the hyperbolic tangent function 

19
00:01:11,485 --> 00:01:19,522
所以这是z 这是a 这是a=tanh(z)
so this is z, this is a, this is a equals tanh of z

20
00:01:19,620 --> 00:01:24,351
这函数介于-1和1之间
and this goes between plus 1 and minus 1 

21
00:01:24,419 --> 00:01:36,164
tanh函数的公式是 e^z-e^(-z) 再除以它们之和
the formula for the tanh function is e to the z minus e to negative z over their sum

22
00:01:36,243 --> 00:01:42,263
数学上这实际上是σ函数平移后的版本
and it's actually mathematically a shifted version of the sigmoid function

23
00:01:42,316 --> 00:01:46,408
所以你知道σ函数是这样的
so as a you know sigmoid function just like that 

24
00:01:46,477 --> 00:01:51,758
但把它移动一下 让它穿过零点 然后重新标度
but shift it so that it now crosses a zero zero point and rescale 

25
00:01:51,830 --> 00:01:53,471
让它介于-1和1之间
so it goes from minus one to plus one 

26
00:01:53,534 --> 00:01:56,534
事实证明 对于隐藏单元
and it turns out that for hidden units 

27
00:01:56,615 --> 00:02:07,201
如果你让函数g(z)等于tanh(z)
if you let the function g(z) be equal to tanh(z)

28
00:02:08,239 --> 00:02:11,909
这几乎总比σ函数效果更好
this almost always works better than the sigmoid function

29
00:02:11,988 --> 00:02:14,221
因为现在函数输出介于-1和1之间
because with values between plus one and minus one 

30
00:02:14,327 --> 00:02:18,031
激活函数的平均值
the mean of the activations that come out of your head in there 

31
00:02:18,092 --> 00:02:20,467
就更接近0
are closer to having a zero mean 

32
00:02:23,502 --> 00:02:23,584
就像有时在你训练学习算法时
and so just as sometimes when you train a learning algorithm 

33
00:02:23,584 --> 00:02:27,578
你可能需要平移所有数据 让数据平均值为0
you might Center the data and have your data have zero mean 

34
00:02:27,650 --> 00:02:34,305
使用tanh而不是σ函数也有类似数据中心化的效果
using a tanh instead of a sigmoid function kind of has the effect of centering your data 

35
00:02:34,402 --> 00:02:37,348
使得数据的平均值接近0
so that the mean of the data is close to the zero 

36
00:02:37,394 --> 00:02:39,263
而不是0.5 
rather than maybe a 0.5 

37
00:02:39,314 --> 00:02:42,731
这实际上让下一层的学习更方便一点
and this actually makes learning for the next layer a little bit easier 

38
00:02:42,779 --> 00:02:45,457
我会在第二门课程里详细讨论这点
we'll say more about this in the second course 

39
00:02:45,523 --> 00:02:47,668
那时我们也会介绍算法优化
when we talk about optimization algorithms as well

40
00:02:47,723 --> 00:02:54,334
但这里要记住一点 我几乎不用σ激活函数了
but one takeaway is that I pretty much never use the sigmoid activation function anymore 

41
00:02:54,391 --> 00:02:58,470
tanh函数几乎在所有场合都更优越
the tanh function is almost always strictly superior 

42
00:02:58,470 --> 00:03:01,240
一个例外是输出层 
the one exception is for the output layer 

43
00:03:01,303 --> 00:03:05,251
因为如果y是0或1
because if y is either 0 or 1 

44
00:03:05,299 --> 00:03:13,551
那么你希望y_帽介于0到1之间更合理
then it makes sense for y hat to be a number that you want to output just between 0 and 1 

45
00:03:13,607 --> 00:03:15,781
而不是-1和1之间
rather than between minus 1 and 1 

46
00:03:15,869 --> 00:03:20,971
我会用σ激活函数的一个例外场合是
so the one exception where I would use the sigmoid activation function is 

47
00:03:21,019 --> 00:03:22,747
使用二元分类的时候
when you're using binary classification 

48
00:03:22,800 --> 00:03:28,690
在这种情况下 你可以用σ激活函数作为输出层
in which case you might use the sigmoid activation function for the output layer 

49
00:03:28,747 --> 00:03:34,752
所以g(z^[2])等于σ(z^[2])
so g(z^[2]) here is equal to Sigma(z^[2])

50
00:03:34,821 --> 00:03:37,150
所以在这个例子中你可以
and so what you see in this example is 

51
00:03:37,195 --> 00:03:42,484
在隐层里用tanh激活函数
where you might have a tanh activation function for the hidden layer 

52
00:03:42,559 --> 00:03:47,206
输出层用σ函数
and sigmoid for the output layer 

53
00:03:47,252 --> 00:03:50,216
所以不同层的激活函数可以不一样
so the activation functions can be different for different layers 

54
00:03:50,269 --> 00:03:55,011
有时候为了表示不同层的不同激活函数
and sometimes to denote that the different activation functions are different for different layers 

55
00:03:55,011 --> 00:03:58,969
我们可能会用这些方括号上标
we might use these square brackets super scripts as well 

56
00:03:59,030 --> 00:04:05,269
来表示g^[1]可能和g^[2]不同
to indicate that g of square bracket 1 may be different than g square bracket 2 

57
00:04:05,330 --> 00:04:09,281
上标方括号1表示这一层
to indicate, square bracket 1 superscript refers to this layer 

58
00:04:09,361 --> 00:04:12,391
上标方括号2表示输出层
and superscript square bracket 2 refers to the output layer 

59
00:04:13,216 --> 00:04:18,342
现在σ函数和tanh函数都有的一个缺点 就是
now one of the downsides of both the sigmoid function and the tanh function is 

60
00:04:18,402 --> 00:04:21,521
如果z非常大或非常小
that if z is either very large or very small 

61
00:04:21,521 --> 00:04:26,291
那么导数的梯度 或者说这个函数的斜率可能就很小
then the gradient of the derivative or the slope of this function becomes very small 

62
00:04:26,353 --> 00:04:29,103
所以z很大或很小的时候
so z is very large or z is very small 

63
00:04:29,171 --> 00:04:33,586
函数的斜率很接近0
the slope of the function you know ends up being close to zero 

64
00:04:33,646 --> 00:04:35,804
这样会拖慢梯度下降算法
and so this can slow down gradient descent 

65
00:04:35,885 --> 00:04:41,289
在机器学习里 最受欢迎的一个玩具是
so one of the toys that is very popular in machine learning is 

66
00:04:41,361 --> 00:04:43,921
所谓的修正线性单元(ReLU)
what's called the rectified linear unit 

67
00:04:44,032 --> 00:04:47,962
所以一个ReLU函数长这样
so the ReLU function looks like this 

68
00:04:49,725 --> 00:04:56,501
公式就是 a=max(0,z)
and the formula is a equals max of 0 comma z 

69
00:04:56,501 --> 00:05:01,197
只要z为正 导数就是1
so the derivative is 1 so long as z is positive 

70
00:05:01,255 --> 00:05:05,441
当z为负时 斜率为0
and derivative or the slope is 0 when z is negative 

71
00:05:05,493 --> 00:05:07,457
如果你实际使用这个函数
if you're implementing this technically 

72
00:05:07,520 --> 00:05:10,791
z刚好为0时 导数是没有定义的
the derivative when z is exactly 0 is not well-defined 

73
00:05:10,840 --> 00:05:13,310
但如果你编程实现
but when you implement is in the computer the 

74
00:05:13,377 --> 00:05:20,608
那么你得到z刚好等于0 0 0 0 0 0的概率很低
odds that you get exactly z equals 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0  is very small

75
00:05:20,608 --> 00:05:22,645
所以实践中不用担心这点
so you don't need to worry about it in practice

76
00:05:22,699 --> 00:05:25,983
你可以在z=0时 给导数赋值
you could pretend a derivative when z is equal to 0 

77
00:05:26,064 --> 00:05:31,657
你可以赋值成1或0 那样也是可以的
you can pretend is either 1 or 0 and you can work just fine 

78
00:05:31,657 --> 00:05:34,010
尽管事实上这个函数不可微
so the fact that is not differentiable  the fact that

79
00:05:35,061 --> 00:05:38,726
在选择激活函数时有一些经验法则
so here are some rules of thumb for choosing activation functions

80
00:05:38,821 --> 00:05:42,593
如果你的输出值是0和1
if your output is 0 1 value 

81
00:05:42,707 --> 00:05:44,467
如果你在做二元分类
if you're I'm using binary classification 

82
00:05:44,554 --> 00:05:48,513
那么σ函数很适合作为输出层的激活函数
then the sigmoid activation function is very natural for the output layer 

83
00:05:48,600 --> 00:05:53,485
然后其他所有单元都用ReLU
and then for all other units on ReLU

84
00:05:53,485 --> 00:06:00,043
所谓的修正线性单元
or the rectified linear unit 

85
00:06:01,617 --> 00:06:05,847
现在已经变成激活函数的默认选择了
is increasingly the default choice of activation function

86
00:06:05,909 --> 00:06:10,839
如果你不确定隐层应该用哪个
so if you're not sure what to use for your hidden layer

87
00:06:10,944 --> 00:06:14,204
我就用ReLU作为激活函数
I would just use the ReLU activation function

88
00:06:14,263 --> 00:06:16,172
这是今天大多数人都在用的
that's what you see most people using these days

89
00:06:16,249 --> 00:06:18,667
虽然人们有时候也会用
although sometimes people also use 

90
00:06:18,748 --> 00:06:20,753
tanh激活函数 
the tanh activation function 

91
00:06:21,601 --> 00:06:23,143
而ReLU的一个缺点是
one disadvantage of the ReLU is that 

92
00:06:23,143 --> 00:06:27,077
当z为负时 导数等于零
the derivative is equal to zero when z is negative 

93
00:06:27,142 --> 00:06:28,945
在实践中这没什么问题
in practice this works just fine 

94
00:06:28,997 --> 00:06:33,131
但ReLU还有另一个版本 叫做带泄漏的ReLU
but there is another version of the ReLU called the leaky ReLU

95
00:06:33,206 --> 00:06:35,356
我们会在下一页给出公式
we will give you the formula on the next slide 

96
00:06:35,417 --> 00:06:39,390
当z为负时 函数不再为0
but instead of it being zero when z is negative 

97
00:06:39,390 --> 00:06:41,391
它有一个很平缓的斜率
it just takes a slight slope like so 

98
00:06:41,467 --> 00:06:44,128
这就是所谓的带泄漏 ReLU
so this is called the Leaky ReLU 

99
00:06:45,970 --> 00:06:49,583
这通常比ReLU激活函数更好 
this usually works better than the ReLU activation function 

100
00:06:49,634 --> 00:06:52,786
不过实际中使用的频率没那么高
although it's just not used as much in practice 

101
00:06:52,843 --> 00:06:56,299
这些选一个就好了 如果你一定要选一个
either one should be fine although if you had to pick one 

102
00:06:57,236 --> 00:06:58,859
我通常只用ReLU
I usually just use the ReLU

103
00:06:58,859 --> 00:07:02,390
ReLU和带泄漏的ReLU好处在于
and the advantage of both the ReLU and the leaky ReLU is that

104
00:07:02,390 --> 00:07:04,928
对于很多z空间
for a lot of the space of z

105
00:07:04,988 --> 00:07:07,261
激活函数的导数
the derivative of the activation function 

106
00:07:07,310 --> 00:07:11,661
激活函数的斜率和0差很远
the slope of the activation function is very different from zero 

107
00:07:11,718 --> 00:07:15,410
所以在实践中使用ReLU激活函数
and so in practice using the ReLU activation function 

108
00:07:15,410 --> 00:07:18,002
你的神经网络的学习速度通常会快得多
your neural network will often learn much faster 

109
00:07:18,002 --> 00:07:21,549
比使用tanh或σ激活函数快得多
than using the tanh or the sigmoid activation function 

110
00:07:21,604 --> 00:07:23,717
主要原因在于 
and the main reason is that 

111
00:07:23,754 --> 00:07:28,059
ReLu没有这种函数斜率接近0时
there is less of this effect of the slope of the function going to zero 

112
00:07:28,123 --> 00:07:29,498
减慢学习速度的效应
which slows down learning 

113
00:07:29,559 --> 00:07:32,577
我知道 对于z的一半范围来说
and I know that for half of the range of z 

114
00:07:32,636 --> 00:07:35,500
ReLU的斜率为零 但在实践中
the slope of ReLU is zero but in practice 

115
00:07:35,580 --> 00:07:39,471
有足够多的隐藏单元 令z大于0
enough of your hidden units will have z greater than zero 

116
00:07:39,471 --> 00:07:42,401
所以对大多数训练样本来说还是很快的
so learning can still be quite mask for most training examples 

117
00:07:42,470 --> 00:07:44,513
我们快速回顾一下
so let's just quickly recap 

118
00:07:44,561 --> 00:07:46,949
不同激活函数的利弊
there are pros and cons of different activation functions 

119
00:07:47,018 --> 00:07:49,076
这里是σ激活函数
here's the sigmoid activation function 

120
00:07:49,126 --> 00:07:55,088
除非用在二元分类的输出层 不然绝对不要用
I would say never use this except for the output layer if you are doing binary classification

121
00:07:55,141 --> 00:07:56,769
或者几乎从来不会用
or maybe almost never use this 

122
00:07:56,821 --> 00:08:00,517
我几乎从来没用过 原因在于
and the reason I almost never use this is because 

123
00:08:00,576 --> 00:08:03,695
tanh几乎在所有场合都更优越
the tanh is pretty much strictly superior 

124
00:08:03,747 --> 00:08:09,919
所以tanh函数是这样的
so the tanh activation function is this

125
00:08:10,219 --> 00:08:15,629
还有最常用的默认激活函数是ReLU
and then the default the most commonly used activation function is the ReLU

126
00:08:15,689 --> 00:08:17,619
就是这个
which is this

127
00:08:17,672 --> 00:08:20,385
如果你不确定要用哪个 就用这个
so you're not sure what else to use, use this one

128
00:08:20,445 --> 00:08:27,044
或者你想用的话 也可以试试带泄漏的ReLU
and maybe you know feel free also to try the leaky ReLU

129
00:08:27,103 --> 00:08:34,693
公式可能是max(0.01z,z) 对吧
where um might be (0.01z,z) right

130
00:08:34,693 --> 00:08:39,753
所以a是0.01*z和z两者的最大值
so a is the max of 0.01 times z and z 

131
00:08:39,854 --> 00:08:42,874
这样函数会这样拐一下
so that gives you this some Bend in the function 

132
00:08:42,874 --> 00:08:47,556
你可能会问 为什么那个常数是0.01?
and you might say you know why is that constant 0.01 

133
00:08:47,620 --> 00:08:53,327
你也可以把它设成学习函数的另一个参数
well you can also make that another parameter of the learning algorithm 

134
00:08:53,375 --> 00:08:55,011
有人说这样效果更好
and some people say that works even better 

135
00:08:55,067 --> 00:08:57,257
但我很少见到有人这么做 所以
but I hardly see people do that so 

136
00:08:57,257 --> 00:09:00,162
如果你想在你的应用里试试
but if you feel like trying it in your application

137
00:09:00,218 --> 00:09:02,162
自己喜欢就好
you know please feel free to do so and 

138
00:09:02,225 --> 00:09:05,100
你可以看看效果如何 有多好
and you can just see how it works and how well it works 

139
00:09:05,101 --> 00:09:07,067
如果结果很好 那么就一直用它
and stick with it if it gives you good result 

140
00:09:07,118 --> 00:09:09,497
我希望这样你就对
so I hope that gives you a sense of 

141
00:09:09,567 --> 00:09:12,740
如何在你的网络里选择激活函数有概念
some of the choices of activation functions you can use in your network 

142
00:09:12,793 --> 00:09:15,619
深度学习其中一个特点是
one of the themes we'll see in deep learning is that 

143
00:09:15,679 --> 00:09:19,726
在建立神经网络时经常有很多不同的选择
you often have a lot of different choices in how you build your neural network 

144
00:09:19,780 --> 00:09:21,650
比如隐藏单元数
ranging from number of hidden units 

145
00:09:21,706 --> 00:09:23,447
激活函数
to the choice of activation function 

146
00:09:23,510 --> 00:09:26,287
还有如何初始化权重 这个我们接下来会讲
to how you initialize the weights which we'll see later 

147
00:09:26,353 --> 00:09:30,696
有很多这样的选择 有时真的很难
a lot of choices like that and it turns out that is sometimes difficult 

148
00:09:30,744 --> 00:09:34,832
去定下一个准则 来确定什么参数最适合你的问题
to get good guidelines for exactly what will work best for your problem 

149
00:09:34,891 --> 00:09:36,559
所以在这三门课程中
so throughout all these three courses

150
00:09:36,559 --> 00:09:39,582
我会让你大概了解我在行业里见到的
I'll keep on giving you a sense of what I see in the industry

151
00:09:39,643 --> 00:09:41,412
热门选择 或者冷门选择
in terms of what's more or less popular 

152
00:09:41,473 --> 00:09:45,273
但是对于你的应用 你的应用的特质
but for your application with your applications idiosyncrasy

153
00:09:45,273 --> 00:09:48,928
事实上很难预先准确地知道什么参数最有效
it's actually very difficult to know in advance exactly what will work best 

154
00:09:48,980 --> 00:09:50,982
所以一个建议是 
so a piece of advice would be 

155
00:09:51,029 --> 00:09:53,681
如果你不确定哪种激活函数最有效
if you're not sure which one of these activation functions work best 

156
00:09:53,782 --> 00:09:58,629
你可以先试试 在你的保留交叉验证数据集上跑跑
you know try them all and then evaluate on like a holdout validation set 

157
00:09:58,717 --> 00:10:01,456
或者在开发集上跑跑
or like a development set which we'll talk about later 

158
00:10:01,502 --> 00:10:04,762
看看哪个参数效果更好 就用那个
and see which one works better  and then go with that

159
00:10:04,822 --> 00:10:10,123
我想通过在你的应用中测试这些不同的选择
and I think that by testing these different choices for your application 

160
00:10:10,184 --> 00:10:14,625
你可以搭建具有前瞻性的神经网络架构
you'd be better at future proofing your neural network architecture 

161
00:10:14,686 --> 00:10:17,945
可以对你问题的特质更有针对性
against the the idiosyncrasy in our problem 

162
00:10:17,945 --> 00:10:19,654
让你的算法迭代更流畅
as well evolutions of the algorithms 

163
00:10:19,708 --> 00:10:24,616
我这里不会告诉你一定要用ReLU激活函数
rather than you know if I were to tell you always use a ReLUactivation 

164
00:10:24,665 --> 00:10:27,010
而不用其他的.. 
and don't use anything else that that just 

165
00:10:27,055 --> 00:10:30,070
那对你现在或者未来要处理的问题而言 
may or may not apply for whatever problem you end up working on 

166
00:10:30,115 --> 00:10:32,707
可能管用 也可能不管用
you know either either in the near future on the distant future 

167
00:10:33,841 --> 00:10:37,374
好 这就是激活函数的选择
all right so that was a choice of activation functions

168
00:10:37,374 --> 00:10:39,243
你们看到了最热门的激活函数
you've seen the most popular activation functions 

169
00:10:39,307 --> 00:10:43,493
还有另一个问题 经常有人会问
there's one other question that sometimes is ask which is 

170
00:10:43,542 --> 00:10:46,693
为什么你需要激活函数呢?
why do you even need to use an activation function at all 

171
00:10:46,693 --> 00:10:47,909
为什么不直接去掉
why not just do away with that 

172
00:10:47,959 --> 00:10:50,748
在下一个视频我们会谈到为什么
so let's talk about that in the next video 

173
00:10:50,814 --> 00:10:53,630
神经网络确实需要
and where you will see why neural network 

174
00:10:53,630 --> 00:10:56,197
某种非线性激活函数
do need some sort of nonlinear activation function

