1
00:00:00,000 --> 00:00:01,256
当你训练神经网络时 
When you train your neural network 

2
00:00:01,315 --> 00:00:03,655
随机初始化权重非常重要
It is important to initialize the weights randomly 

3
00:00:03,718 --> 00:00:07,569
对于logistic回归 可以将权重初始化为零
for logistic regression it was okay to initialize the weights to zero 

4
00:00:07,630 --> 00:00:11,737
但如果将神经网络的各参数数组全部初始化为0
but for a neural network of initialize the arrays of parameters to all zero 

5
00:00:11,805 --> 00:00:14,352
再使用梯度下降算法 那会完全无效
and apply gradient descent it won't work 

6
00:00:14,416 --> 00:00:15,548
我们来看看为什么 
let's see why 

7
00:00:16,114 --> 00:00:20,269
所以你有两个输入特征
so you have here two input features

8
00:00:20,332 --> 00:00:24,230
所以n^[0]等于2 然后有两个隐藏单元
so n^[0] is equal to two and two hidden units 

9
00:00:24,301 --> 00:00:26,273
所以n^[1]=2
so n^[1] is equal to two 

10
00:00:26,331 --> 00:00:32,259
所以和隐层相关的矩阵W^[1]
and so the matrix associated with a hidden layer or W^[1] 

11
00:00:32,318 --> 00:00:34,242
是2×2的
it is going to be 2x2 

12
00:00:34,570 --> 00:00:41,099
假设你把它全部初始化成0, 0 0 0 0, 2×2矩阵
let's say that you initialize it to all zeros 0 0 0 0, 2 by 2 matrix 

13
00:00:41,160 --> 00:00:45,296
我们也令b^[1]等于0 0
and let's say b^[1] is also equal to 0 0 

14
00:00:45,802 --> 00:00:50,244
将偏置项b初始化为0实际上是可行的
turns out initializing the bias terms b to 0 is actually okay 

15
00:00:50,301 --> 00:00:53,472
但把W初始化成全零就成问题了
but the initializing W to all zeros is a problem 

16
00:00:54,651 --> 00:00:56,888
这种初始化形式的问题在于
so the problem with this form of initialization is that 

17
00:00:56,975 --> 00:01:08,734
你给网络输入任何样本 你的a^[1]_1和a^[1]_2是一样的
for any example you give it you have that a^[1]_1 and a^[1]_2 will be equal 

18
00:01:08,795 --> 00:01:12,923
所以这两个激活函数完全一样
all right so this activation and this activation would be same 

19
00:01:12,981 --> 00:01:16,294
因为两个隐藏单元都在做完全一样的计算
because both of these hidden units are computing exactly the same function 

20
00:01:16,355 --> 00:01:19,550
当你计算反向传播时
and then when you compute back propagation 

21
00:01:19,616 --> 00:01:30,479
事实证明 出于对称性 dz^[1] _1和dz^[1] _2也是相同的
it turns out that d z^[1]_1 and d z^[1]_2 will also be the same kind of by symmetry right 

22
00:01:30,547 --> 00:01:32,626
这两个隐藏单元会以同样方式初始化
both of these hidden units will initialize the same way 

23
00:01:33,705 --> 00:01:39,194
技术上 我说的就是 假设输出的权重也是一样的
technically for what I'm saying I'm assuming that the outgoing weights are also identical 

24
00:01:39,298 --> 00:01:44,236
所以W^[2]就等于0
so that W^[2] is equal to 0 0 

25
00:01:44,290 --> 00:01:48,952
但如果你以这种方式初始化神经网络
but if you initialize the neural network this way 

26
00:01:49,025 --> 00:01:54,058
那么这个隐藏单元和这个隐藏单元就完全一样了
then this hidden unit and this hidden unit are completely identical 

27
00:01:54,121 --> 00:01:57,168
所以这就是所谓的完全对称
so they're completely sometimes you say they're completely symmetric 

28
00:01:57,248 --> 00:02:00,216
意味着节点计算完全一样的函数
which just means that the computing exactly the same function 

29
00:02:00,284 --> 00:02:03,215
我们可以通过归纳法证明
and by kind of a proof by induction 

30
00:02:03,282 --> 00:02:07,585
每次训练迭代之后
it turns out that after every single iteration of training 

31
00:02:07,642 --> 00:02:11,180
两个隐藏单元仍然在计算完全相同的函数
your two hidden units are still computing exactly the same function 

32
00:02:11,238 --> 00:02:16,687
因为很大一部分网络记忆dW是这样的一个矩阵
since part of the show that dW will be a matrix that looks like this 

33
00:02:17,344 --> 00:02:20,465
其中每行的数值都一样
where every row takes on the same value 

34
00:02:20,525 --> 00:02:23,644
然后我们执行一次权重更新 所以你计算
so we perform a weight update so you perform 

35
00:02:23,702 --> 00:02:30,048
所以你计算一次权重更新 W^[1]更新为W^[1]-α·dW
when you perform a weight update W^[1] gets updated as W^[1] minus alpha times dW

36
00:02:30,110 --> 00:02:33,878
你会发现每次迭代后W^[1]的形式都是
you find that W^[1] after every iteration will have 

37
00:02:33,950 --> 00:02:37,788
第一行和第二行完全一样
you know the first row equal to the second row 

38
00:02:37,851 --> 00:02:41,051
所以是可以通过归纳法证明
so it's possible to construct a proof by induction that 

39
00:02:41,107 --> 00:02:44,560
如果你将W所有值初始化为0
if you initialize all the ways all the values of W to 0 

40
00:02:44,628 --> 00:02:49,413
那么因为两个隐藏单元一开始就在做同样的计算
then because both hidden units start off computing the same function 

41
00:02:49,482 --> 00:02:53,740
两个隐藏单元对输出单元的影响也一样大
and both hidden units have the same influence on the output unit 

42
00:02:53,797 --> 00:02:58,226
那么在一次迭代之后 同样的对称性依然存在
then after one iteration that same statement is still true 

43
00:02:58,288 --> 00:03:00,291
两个隐藏单位仍然是对称的
the two hidden units are still symmetric 

44
00:03:00,291 --> 00:03:03,947
所以通过归纳两到三次迭代就可以证明
and therefore by induction after two iterations three iterations and so on 

45
00:03:04,013 --> 00:03:06,120
无论你训练神经网络多长时间 
No matter how long you train your neural network 

46
00:03:06,186 --> 00:03:10,188
两个隐藏单元仍然在计算完全一样的函数
both hidden units are still computing exactly the same function 

47
00:03:10,270 --> 00:03:15,152
所以在这种情况下 多个隐藏单元真的没有意义
and so in this case there's really no point to having more than one hidden unit 

48
00:03:15,214 --> 00:03:16,724
因为它们计算的都是同样的东西
because they're all computing the same thing 

49
00:03:16,782 --> 00:03:21,315
当然 对于更大的神经网络 或者输入有三个特征
and of course for larger neural networks let's see if you have three features 

50
00:03:21,378 --> 00:03:24,438
或者隐藏单元的数目非常多
and maybe a very large number of hidden units 

51
00:03:24,499 --> 00:03:29,425
那么用类似的方法可以证明 这样的神经网络
a similar argument works to show that what with a neural network like this 

52
00:03:31,076 --> 00:03:34,433
如果你把所有权重都初始化成0 我就不把所有连线画出来了
because I won't drawn all the edges if you initialize the weight to zero 

53
00:03:34,492 --> 00:03:37,074
那么所有隐藏单元都是对称的
then all of your hidden units are symmetric 

54
00:03:37,074 --> 00:03:39,601
不管你跑多久梯度下降
and no matter how long you run gradient descent 

55
00:03:39,659 --> 00:03:43,106
它们都在计算完全一样的函数
they'll all continue to compute exactly the same function 

56
00:03:43,173 --> 00:03:45,152
所以没有一点用处
so that's not helpful 

57
00:03:45,215 --> 00:03:49,157
因为你需要两个不同的隐藏单元 去计算不同的函数
because you want two different hidden units to compute different functions

58
00:03:49,232 --> 00:03:53,195
这个问题的解决方案是随机初始化所有参数
the solution to this is to initialize your parameters randomly 

59
00:03:53,852 --> 00:03:54,847
你应该这么做
so here's what you do 

60
00:03:55,499 --> 00:04:03,471
你可以令W^[1] = np.random.randn
you can set W^[1] = np.random.randn

61
00:04:03,471 --> 00:04:07,296
这可以产生参数为(2,2)的高斯分布随机变量
this generates on Gaussian random variable (2,2)

62
00:04:07,356 --> 00:04:12,598
然后你再乘以一个很小的数字 比如0.01
and then usually you multiply this by a very small number such as 0.01 

63
00:04:12,664 --> 00:04:15,190
所以你将权重初始化成很小的随机数
so you initialize it to very small random values 

64
00:04:15,257 --> 00:04:22,276
然后b .. 其实b完全没有这个对称性问题
and then b um it turns out that b does not have this symmetry problem 

65
00:04:22,345 --> 00:04:24,110
所谓的破坏对称性问题
what's called a symmetry breaking problem 

66
00:04:24,171 --> 00:04:30,221
把b初始化成0是可以的 因为
so is okay to initialize b to just zeros because 

67
00:04:30,279 --> 00:04:32,439
只要W随机初始化
so long as W is initialized randomly 

68
00:04:32,495 --> 00:04:36,169
你一开始还是用不同的隐藏单元计算不同的函数
you start off with a different hidden units computing different things 

69
00:04:36,169 --> 00:04:39,651
这里并不需要破坏对称性
and so you no longer have this um symmetry breaking problem 

70
00:04:39,718 --> 00:04:42,271
然后类似地对于W^[2]
and then similarly for W^[2] 

71
00:04:42,331 --> 00:04:45,016
你也可以随机初始化 
you can initialize that randomly

72
00:04:45,017 --> 00:04:50,149
还有b2 你可以初始化成0
 and b2 you can initialize that to zero

73
00:04:50,204 --> 00:04:51,766
你可能会奇怪
so you might be wondering 

74
00:04:51,847 --> 00:04:53,719
这个常数是什么地方来的
you know where did this constant come from 

75
00:04:53,818 --> 00:04:58,742
为什么是0.01 为什么不用100或1000之类的数字
and why is it 0.01 why not put the number 100 or 1000 

76
00:04:58,795 --> 00:05:02,595
实际上 我们通常喜欢把权重矩阵
turns out that we usually prefer to initialize the ways to 

77
00:05:02,647 --> 00:05:04,469
初始化成非常非常小的随机值
very very small random values 

78
00:05:05,399 --> 00:05:10,836
因为 如果你用的是tanh或者sigmoid激活函数
because um if you're using a say tanh or sigmoid activation function 

79
00:05:10,895 --> 00:05:13,502
或者你在输出层有一个sigmoid函数
or if you have a sigmoid even just at the output layer 

80
00:05:13,568 --> 00:05:19,572
那如果权重太大 当你计算激活函数值时
if the weights are too large then when you compute the activation values 

81
00:05:19,638 --> 00:05:27,793
要记住z^[1]=W^[1] x+b^[1]
remember that z^[1] is equal to W^[1] x plus b^[1]

82
00:05:28,746 --> 00:05:35,168
然后a^[1]是应用于z^[1]的激活函数
and then a^[1] is the activation function applied to z^[1]

83
00:05:35,168 --> 00:05:38,702
所以如果W很大 z就会很大
so if W is very big, z will be very big 

84
00:05:38,702 --> 00:05:43,734
或者这些z值会很大或者很小
or these some values of z will be either very large or very small 

85
00:05:43,734 --> 00:05:47,428
所以在这种情况下 你最后可能落在
and so in that case you're more likely to end up at 

86
00:05:47,479 --> 00:05:52,133
这些tanh函数或者sigmoid函数的平缓部分
these flat parts of the tanh function or the sigmoid function 

87
00:05:52,200 --> 00:05:55,537
梯度的斜率非常小 
where the slope of the gradient is very small 

88
00:05:55,604 --> 00:05:58,584
意味着梯度下降法会非常慢
meaning that gradient descent would be very slow 

89
00:05:58,649 --> 00:06:00,048
所以学习会很慢 
and so learning would be very slow 

90
00:06:00,691 --> 00:06:01,912
所以回顾一下
so just a recap 

91
00:06:01,993 --> 00:06:05,126
如果W太大 那么你就很可能
if W is too large you're more likely to end up

92
00:06:05,216 --> 00:06:08,282
在一开始训练时就落在z很大的区域
even at the very start of training with very large values of z

93
00:06:08,359 --> 00:06:12,881
导致你的tanh或Sigmoid激活函数接近饱和
which causes your tanh or a sigmoid activation function  to be saturated

94
00:06:12,881 --> 00:06:15,161
从而减慢学习速度 
thus slowing down learning

95
00:06:15,237 --> 00:06:19,766
如果你的神经网络中没有任何sigmoid或者tanh激活函数
if you don't have any sigmoid or tanh activation functions throughout your neural network 

96
00:06:19,766 --> 00:06:23,678
那问题可能没那么大 但如果你在做二元分类
this is less of an issue but if you're doing binary classification 

97
00:06:23,752 --> 00:06:26,039
你的输出单元是Sigmoid函数
and your output unit is a sigmoid function 

98
00:06:26,107 --> 00:06:30,035
那么你就不希望初始参数太大
then you know you just don't want the initial parameters to be too large 

99
00:06:30,101 --> 00:06:35,480
所以用0.01是比较合理的
so that's why multiplying by 0.01 would be something reasonable to try 

100
00:06:35,550 --> 00:06:38,712
或者任意其他小数字 初始化W^[2]也一样
or any other small number and same for W^[2] 

101
00:06:38,802 --> 00:06:42,777
可能用命令np.random.randn
this can be a np.random.randn

102
00:06:42,857 --> 00:06:51,255
我想这个例子中就是1×2 这个例子里乘以0.01 这里漏了s
I guess this would be 1 by 2 in this example times 0.01, missing an s there

103
00:06:51,324 --> 00:07:00,121
所以实际上 有时有比0.01更好用的常数
so finally it turns out that sometimes there can be better constants than 0.01 

104
00:07:00,185 --> 00:07:04,919
但当你训练一个单隐层神经网络时
when you're training a neural network with just one hidden layer 

105
00:07:04,996 --> 00:07:09,009
这是一个相对较浅的神经网络 没有太多的隐藏层
this is a relatively shallow neural network without too many hidden layers 

106
00:07:09,086 --> 00:07:12,214
设为0.01应该还可以
setting to 0.01 will probably work ok 

107
00:07:12,286 --> 00:07:15,208
但是当你训练一个很深的神经网络的时候 
but when you're training a very very deep neural network 

108
00:07:15,288 --> 00:07:19,282
你可能要试试0.01以外的常数
then you might want to pick a different constant as 0.01 

109
00:07:19,344 --> 00:07:23,028
在下周的材料中会谈一点 
and in next week's material will talk a little bit about 

110
00:07:23,028 --> 00:07:27,219
什么时候应该选用0.01以外的常数
how and when you might want to choose a different constant than 0.01 

111
00:07:27,284 --> 00:07:31,791
但不管怎样 初始化参数一般都很小
but either way it will usually end up being a relatively small number 

112
00:07:31,871 --> 00:07:38,611
所以在这周的视频里 你知道如何设立单隐层神经网络
so that's it so this week videos you now know how to set up a neural network of a hidden layer 

113
00:07:38,668 --> 00:07:41,958
初始化参数 并用正向传播计算预测值
initialize the parameters make predictions using forward prop 

114
00:07:42,028 --> 00:07:45,731
还有计算导数 然后使用梯度下降 反向传播
as well as compute derivatives and apply gradient descent using back prop 

115
00:07:45,731 --> 00:07:48,948
你们应该能够完成小测
so that you should be able to do the quizzes 

116
00:07:49,027 --> 00:07:50,932
以及本周的编程练习 
as well as this week's programming exercises 

117
00:07:50,994 --> 00:07:52,744
祝你们好运
best of luck with that 

118
00:07:52,799 --> 00:07:54,715
我希望你做练习时玩得开心 
I hope you have fun with the exercise 

119
00:07:54,783 --> 00:07:57,571
并期待在第4周的材料中见到你
and look forward to seeing you in week 4 materials

