1
00:00:02,550 --> 00:00:05,830
Hi, Ian. Thanks a lot for joining us today.
嗨 Ian 感谢你今天接受采访

2
00:00:05,830 --> 00:00:06,860
Thank you for inviting me,
谢谢你邀请我

3
00:00:06,860 --> 00:00:08,775
Andrew. I am glad to be here.
Andrew 我很高兴来到这里

4
00:00:08,775 --> 00:00:11,920
Today, you are one of the world's most visible deep learning researchers.
今天 你也许是世界上最知名的深度学习研究员之一

5
00:00:11,920 --> 00:00:14,450
Let us share a bit about your personal story.
让我们来听听你的心路历程吧

6
00:00:14,450 --> 00:00:16,810
So, how do you end up doing this work that you now do?
你是怎样一步步进入这行的呢?

7
00:00:16,810 --> 00:00:19,150
Yeah. That sounds great.
好 是个好想法

8
00:00:19,150 --> 00:00:24,287
I guess I first became interested in machine learning right before I met you, actually.
我想我是在遇到你之后才开始对机器学习感兴趣的

9
00:00:24,287 --> 00:00:29,705
I had been working on neuroscience and my undergraduate advisor,
我一直从事神经科学研究 我的本科时代导师

10
00:00:29,705 --> 00:00:34,600
Jerry Cain, at Stanford encouraged me to take your Intro to AI class.
斯坦福大学的Jerry Cain鼓励我去上你的AI课

11
00:00:34,600 --> 00:00:35,790
Oh, I didn't know that. Okay.
啊 这我不知道呢 好

12
00:00:35,790 --> 00:00:39,885
So I had always thought that AI was a good idea,
所以我一直觉得AI是个好想法

13
00:00:39,885 --> 00:00:42,590
but that in practice, the main, I think,
但在实践中 主要的 我想

14
00:00:42,590 --> 00:00:44,483
idea that was happening was like game AI,
主要达到实用的是一些比如游戏AI

15
00:00:44,483 --> 00:00:47,375
where people have a lot of hard-coded rules for
有很多人工编码的规则

16
00:00:47,375 --> 00:00:48,888
non-player characters in games
让游戏中的非玩家角色

17
00:00:48,952 --> 00:00:52,085
to say different scripted lines at different points in time.
在不同的时间点说出不同的脚本对话

18
00:00:52,085 --> 00:00:56,750
And then, when I took your Intro to AI class and you covered topics like
然后 当我在上你的AI入门课程时 你讲到的话题

19
00:00:56,750 --> 00:01:02,815
linear regression and the bias and variance decomposition of the error of linear regression,
线性回归和线性回归 误差的偏差和方差分解

20
00:01:02,815 --> 00:01:06,665
I started to realize that this is a real science and I could actually
我开始意识到这可以是真正的科学 我实际上可以

21
00:01:06,665 --> 00:01:10,970
have a scientific career in AI rather than neuroscience.
在AI领域从事科学研究 而不是神经科学

22
00:01:10,970 --> 00:01:12,730
I see. Great. And then what happened?
我知道了 很好 那接下来呢?

23
00:01:12,730 --> 00:01:15,290
Well, I came back and I'd TA to your course later.
然后我就回来当你的课程助教了呀

24
00:01:15,290 --> 00:01:17,815
Oh, I see. Right. Like a TA.
原来如此 当我的助教

25
00:01:17,815 --> 00:01:22,595
So a really big turning point for me was while I was TA-ing that course,
其实我人生的一大转折点 就是在当那门课助教的时候

26
00:01:22,595 --> 00:01:25,310
one of the students, my friend Ethan Dreifuss,
其中一名学生 我的朋友Ethan Dreifuss

27
00:01:25,310 --> 00:01:28,689
got interested in Geoff Hinton's deep belief net paper.
对Geoff Hinton的深度信念网络论文很感兴趣

28
00:01:28,689 --> 00:01:29,022
I see.
我知道了..

29
00:01:29,022 --> 00:01:30,703
And the two of us ended up building 
是我们两个最后一起

30
00:01:31,145 --> 00:01:36,134
one of the first GPU CUDA-based machines at Stanford
在斯坦福大学搭建了世界第一台GPU CUDA机器

31
00:01:36,134 --> 00:01:41,480
in order to run Boltzmann machines in our spare time over winter break.
专门用来跑玻尔兹曼机 就在那年寒假的业余时间里

32
00:01:41,534 --> 00:01:42,459
I see.
我知道了..

33
00:01:42,514 --> 00:01:46,295
And at that point, I started to have
在那时候 我开始有

34
00:01:46,295 --> 00:01:50,720
a very strong intuition that deep learning was the way to go in the future,
一个非常强烈的直觉 深度学习才是未来

35
00:01:50,720 --> 00:01:53,660
that a lot of the other algorithms that I was working with,
那时我们接触了很多其他算法

36
00:01:53,660 --> 00:01:56,285
like support vector machines,
比如支持向量机

37
00:01:56,285 --> 00:01:58,845
didn't seem to have the right asymptotics,
它们的渐近线不太靠谱

38
00:01:58,845 --> 00:02:01,400
that you add more training data and they get slower,
当你输入更多训练数据时 它们却在变慢

39
00:02:01,400 --> 00:02:03,476
or for the same amount of training data,
或者对于相同数量的训练数据

40
00:02:03,476 --> 00:02:08,240
it's hard to make them perform a lot better by changing other settings.
改变其他设定并没有改善它们的表现

41
00:02:08,240 --> 00:02:13,065
At that point, I started to focus on deep learning as much as possible.
从那开始 我就专注于深度学习了

42
00:02:13,065 --> 00:02:18,595
And I remember Richard Reyna's very old GPU paper
我记得Richard Reyna有一篇很老的GPU文章

43
00:02:18,595 --> 00:02:21,585
acknowledges you for having done a lot of early work.
提到你做了很多早期的工作

44
00:02:21,585 --> 00:02:25,850
Yeah. Yeah. That was written using some of the machines that we built.
是的 是的 那篇文章用的就是我们搭建的一些机器

45
00:02:25,850 --> 00:02:26,656
Yeah.
是的

46
00:02:26,656 --> 00:02:30,755
The first machine I built was just something that Ethan and I built at
我建造的第一台机器就是 Ethan和我建立的机器

47
00:02:30,755 --> 00:02:35,120
Ethan's mom's house with our own money,
用我们自己的钱在Ethan妈妈的房子里搭的

48
00:02:35,120 --> 00:02:39,835
and then later, we used lab money to build the first two or three for the Stanford lab.
之后 我们用实验室经费在斯坦福实验室搭了两三台

49
00:02:39,835 --> 00:02:42,965
Wow that's great. I never knew that story. That's great.
哇 太神奇了 我还不知道这事 太好了

50
00:02:42,965 --> 00:02:48,365
And then, today, one of the things that's really taken
那么 今天 真正以风暴席卷深度学习世界的

51
00:02:48,365 --> 00:02:51,645
the deep learning world by storm is your invention of GANs.
是你发明的生成式对抗网络(GAN)

52
00:02:51,645 --> 00:02:54,085
So how did you come up with that?
那么你怎么想出来的呢?

53
00:02:54,085 --> 00:02:56,885
I've been studying generative models for a long time,
我一直在研究生成模型很久

54
00:02:56,885 --> 00:02:59,000
so GANs are a way of doing
所以GAN是其中一种

55
00:02:59,000 --> 00:03:02,570
generative modeling where you have a lot of training data and you'd like
生成模型 你有很多训练数据 你希望

56
00:03:02,570 --> 00:03:06,908
to learn to produce more examples that resemble the training data,
学会制造更多类似它们的数据

57
00:03:06,909 --> 00:03:08,420
but they're imaginary.
但它们都是虚构的

58
00:03:08,420 --> 00:03:13,265
They've never been seen exactly in that form before.
网络还没见过这种形式的虚构数据

59
00:03:13,265 --> 00:03:15,629
There were several other ways of doing generative models
还有几种办法可以做生成模型

60
00:03:15,630 --> 00:03:19,780
that had been popular for several years before I had the idea for GANs.
在我们想出GAN之前还流行了几年

61
00:03:19,780 --> 00:03:24,860
And after I'd been working on all those other methods throughout most of my Ph.D.,
在我读博的时候 我一直在研究其他各种方法

62
00:03:24,860 --> 00:03:29,000
I knew a lot about the advantages and disadvantages of all the other frameworks like
我非常了解所有其他框架的优缺点 

63
00:03:29,000 --> 00:03:32,630
Boltzmann machines and sparse coding
玻尔兹曼机器和稀疏编码 

64
00:03:32,630 --> 00:03:35,955
and all the other approaches that have been really popular for years.
还有其他多年来一直很受欢迎的方法

65
00:03:35,955 --> 00:03:40,265
I was looking for something that avoid all these disadvantages at the same time.
我那时正在寻找某个可以同时避免所有方法缺点的东西

66
00:03:40,265 --> 00:03:44,110
And then finally, when I was arguing about generative models with my friends in a bar,
最后 当我在一个酒吧里和朋友争论生成模型的时候

67
00:03:44,110 --> 00:03:45,845
something clicked into place,
灵感来了

68
00:03:45,845 --> 00:03:47,540
and I started telling them, You need to do,
我开始告诉他们 你需要这么做

69
00:03:47,540 --> 00:03:49,510
this, this, and this and I swear it will work.
这么做 这么做 我保证管用

70
00:03:49,510 --> 00:03:52,890
And my friends didn't believe me that it would work.
我的朋友不相信会管用

71
00:03:52,890 --> 00:03:55,410
I was supposed to be writing the deep learning textbook at the time,
我本来还在写一本深度学习的教科书

72
00:03:55,410 --> 00:03:55,790
I see.
我知道了..

73
00:03:55,790 --> 00:03:57,620
But I believed strongly enough that it would work that I
但是我强烈相信 这个想法是靠谱的

74
00:03:57,620 --> 00:03:59,870
went home and coded it up the same night and it worked.
我马上回家 当天晚上就调试成功了

75
00:03:59,870 --> 00:04:02,920
So it take you one evening to implement the first version of GANs?
所以只花了一晚上就调试成功第一个GAN了?

76
00:04:02,920 --> 00:04:06,050
I implemented it around midnight
我大概在午夜做完的

77
00:04:06,050 --> 00:04:09,530
after going home from the bar where my friend had his going-away party.
就从我朋友在酒吧的离职派对离开回到家之后

78
00:04:09,530 --> 00:04:10,086
I see.
我知道了..

79
00:04:10,086 --> 00:04:11,784
And the first version of it worked,
而它的第一个版本是有效的

80
00:04:11,784 --> 00:04:13,275
which is very, very fortunate.
这是非常非常幸运的

81
00:04:13,275 --> 00:04:15,825
I didn't have to search for hyperparameters or anything.
我没有搜索超参数或任何东西

82
00:04:15,825 --> 00:04:17,840
There was a story, I read it somewhere,
我在某个地方读过一个故事

83
00:04:17,840 --> 00:04:22,977
where you had a near-death experience and that reaffirmed your commitment to AI.
在那里你有一次涉死体验 让你对AI的信仰更坚定了

84
00:04:22,977 --> 00:04:24,160
Tell me that one.
给我讲讲那个故事

85
00:04:24,160 --> 00:04:30,215
So, yeah. I wasn't actually near death but I briefly thought that I was.
我其实没有涉死啦 但有那么一瞬间我觉得要死了

86
00:04:30,215 --> 00:04:32,588
I had a very bad headache and 
我头很痛很痛

87
00:04:32,628 --> 00:04:37,571
some of the doctors thought that I might have a brain hemorrhage.
一些医生认为我可能有脑出血

88
00:04:37,571 --> 00:04:40,850
And during the time that I was waiting for my MRI results
在我等待我的MRI结果

89
00:04:40,850 --> 00:04:43,180
to find out whether I had a brain hemorrhage or not,
看看有没有脑出血时

90
00:04:43,180 --> 00:04:46,356
I realized that most of the thoughts I was having 
我意识到 我的大部分想法都是

91
00:04:46,424 --> 00:04:49,894
were about making sure that other people would eventually
要确定有其他人

92
00:04:49,958 --> 00:04:52,750
try out the research ideas that I had at the time.
继续尝试我当时的研究思路

93
00:04:52,750 --> 00:04:53,224
I see. I see.
我懂了 我懂了

94
00:04:53,224 --> 00:04:55,820
In retrospect, they're all pretty silly research ideas.
回想起来 那些都是非常愚蠢的研究思路

95
00:04:55,820 --> 00:04:56,553
I see.
我懂了..

96
00:04:56,553 --> 00:04:58,700
But at that point,
但在这一点上

97
00:04:58,700 --> 00:05:02,325
I realized that this was actually one of my highest priorities in life,
我意识到这实际上是我生活中优先级最高的事

98
00:05:02,325 --> 00:05:05,780
was carrying out my machine learning research work.
就是做机器学习研究工作

99
00:05:05,780 --> 00:05:07,910
I see. Yeah. That's great,
我懂了 是啊 那很棒

100
00:05:07,910 --> 00:05:10,055
that when you thought you might be dying soon,
当你以为你快要死的时候

101
00:05:10,055 --> 00:05:12,265
you're just thinking how to get the research done.
你还是想如何完成研究

102
00:05:12,265 --> 00:05:12,649
Yeah.
是的

103
00:05:12,649 --> 00:05:15,690
Yeah. That's commitment.
是 这真的是信仰

104
00:05:15,690 --> 00:05:17,850
Yeah.
是的

105
00:05:17,850 --> 00:05:21,808
Yeah. Yeah. So today, you're still at the center of a lot of the activities with GANs,
是啊 是啊 所以今天你仍然处于GAN研究的风暴中心

106
00:05:21,808 --> 00:05:24,560
with Generative Adversarial Networks.
就是这个生成性对抗网络

107
00:05:24,560 --> 00:05:27,710
So tell me how you see the future of GANs.
可以告诉我怎么看GAN的未来吗

108
00:05:27,710 --> 00:05:32,930
Right now, GANs are used for a lot of different things, like semi-supervised learning,
现在GANs应用在很多场合里 比如半监督学习

109
00:05:32,930 --> 00:05:39,185
generating training data for other models and even simulating scientific experiments.
生成其他模型的训练数据 甚至模拟科学实验

110
00:05:39,185 --> 00:05:43,850
In principle, all of these things could be done by other kinds of generative models.
原则上 这些东西都可以用其他生成模型来做

111
00:05:43,850 --> 00:05:47,695
So I think that GANs are at an important crossroads right now.
所以我认为GAN现在在一个重要的十字路口

112
00:05:47,695 --> 00:05:50,210
Right now, they work well some of the time,
现在 它们有时候效果很好

113
00:05:50,210 --> 00:05:55,890
but it can be more of an art than a science to really bring that performance out of them.
但要把它们的潜力真正发挥出来 更像是艺术 而不是科学

114
00:05:55,890 --> 00:05:59,870
It's more or less how people felt about deep learning in general 10 years ago.
10年前 人们对深度学习的感觉或多或少也是如此

115
00:05:59,870 --> 00:06:01,430
And back then, we were using
当时我们正在使用 

116
00:06:01,430 --> 00:06:05,330
deep belief networks with Boltzmann machines as the building blocks,
以波尔兹曼机器为基础的深层信念网络

117
00:06:05,330 --> 00:06:07,420
and they were very, very finicky.
它们他们非常非常挑剔

118
00:06:07,420 --> 00:06:11,945
Over time, we switched to things like rectified linear units and batch normalization,
随着时间的推移 我们切换到修正线性单元和批量归一化

119
00:06:11,945 --> 00:06:14,635
and deep learning became a lot more reliable.
深入学习变得更加可靠

120
00:06:14,635 --> 00:06:18,470
If we can make GANs become as reliable as deep learning has become,
如果我们可以把GAN变得像深度学习一样可靠

121
00:06:18,470 --> 00:06:20,840
then I think we'll keep seeing GANs used in
那么我想我们会继续看到GAN

122
00:06:20,840 --> 00:06:24,110
all the places they're used today with much greater success.
在今天它们的应用领域里获得更大的成功

123
00:06:24,110 --> 00:06:29,060
If we aren't able to figure out how to stabilize GANs,
如果我们弄不清楚如何稳定GAN

124
00:06:29,060 --> 00:06:32,960
then I think their main contribution to the history of deep learning is
那么我想它对深度学习历史的贡献

125
00:06:32,960 --> 00:06:35,060
that they will have shown people how to
就是它向人们展示了

126
00:06:35,060 --> 00:06:37,590
do all these tasks that involve generative modeling,
如何完成这些涉及到生成模型的全部任务

127
00:06:37,590 --> 00:06:41,505
and eventually, we'll replace them with other forms of generative models.
最终 我们将用其他形式的生成模型来代替它们

128
00:06:41,505 --> 00:06:45,916
So I spend maybe about 40 percent of my time right now working on stabilizing GANs.
所以我花了大约40%的时间试图稳定GAN

129
00:06:45,916 --> 00:06:50,780
I see. Cool. Okay. Oh, and so just as a lot of people
我懂了 很酷 我想就像很多人

130
00:06:50,780 --> 00:06:53,765
that joined deep learning about 10 years ago, such as yourself,
大约10年前进入深度学校领域一样 比如你自己

131
00:06:53,765 --> 00:06:54,963
wound up being pioneers,
最后变成了领域的先驱者

132
00:06:54,963 --> 00:06:57,360
maybe the people that join GANs today,
也许今天加入GAN的人

133
00:06:57,360 --> 00:07:00,120
if it works out, could end up the early pioneers.
如果它确实管用 那么最后可能也会成为先驱

134
00:07:00,120 --> 00:07:04,220
Yeah. A lot of people already are early pioneers of GANs,
是啊 很多人已经是GAN的早期先驱

135
00:07:04,220 --> 00:07:09,105
and I think if you wanted to give any kind of history of GANs so far,
如果你想描述GAN的历史

136
00:07:09,105 --> 00:07:12,740
you'd really need to mention other groups like Indico
你真的需要提到 比如Indico等其他组织

137
00:07:12,740 --> 00:07:17,280
and Facebook and Berkeley for all the different things that they've done.
还有Facebook和伯克利 那些小组完成的各种工作

138
00:07:17,280 --> 00:07:19,735
So in addition to all your research,
所以除了你的研究

139
00:07:19,735 --> 00:07:24,300
you also coauthored a book on deep learning. How is that going?
你还合著了一本关于深度学习的书 可以说说吗?

140
00:07:24,300 --> 00:07:26,897
That's right, with Yoshua Bengio and Aaron Courville,
没错 我和Yoshua Bengio和Aaron Courville合著的

141
00:07:26,897 --> 00:07:29,900
who are my Ph.D. co-advisers.
他们是我的博士导师

142
00:07:29,900 --> 00:07:35,465
We wrote the first textbook on the modern version of deep learning,
我们写了一本现代版深度学习教科书

143
00:07:35,465 --> 00:07:38,615
and that has been very popular,
一直很受欢迎

144
00:07:38,615 --> 00:07:42,920
both in the English edition and the Chinese edition.
英文版和中文版都很受欢迎

145
00:07:42,920 --> 00:07:48,915
We've sold about, I think around 70,000 copies total between those two languages.
我们已经售出了 我想两种语言加起来有70000本吧

146
00:07:48,915 --> 00:07:54,730
And I've had a lot of feedback from students who said that they've learned a lot from it.
而且我从学生那里得到了很多反馈 他们说获益良多

147
00:07:54,730 --> 00:07:58,940
One thing that we did a little bit differently than some other books is we start with
我们有件事做得和其他教材不同 

148
00:07:58,940 --> 00:08:03,905
a very focused introduction to the kind of math that you need to do in deep learning.
我们一开始就介绍深度学习需要用到的数学知识

149
00:08:03,905 --> 00:08:07,670
I think one thing that I got from your courses at Stanford is
我从斯坦福大学课程中得到的一件事是

150
00:08:07,670 --> 00:08:11,570
that linear algebra and probability are very important,
线性代数和概率论非常重要

151
00:08:11,570 --> 00:08:15,230
that people get excited about the machine learning algorithms,
人们对机器学习算法感到兴奋

152
00:08:15,230 --> 00:08:18,500
but if you want to be a really excellent practitioner,
但如果你想成为一名非常优秀的从业者

153
00:08:18,500 --> 00:08:26,055
you've got to master the basic math that underlies the whole approach in the first place.
你必须掌握基本数学 这是整个算法的基础

154
00:08:26,055 --> 00:08:27,290
So we make sure to give
所以我们确保一开始

155
00:08:27,290 --> 00:08:31,345
a very focused presentation of the math basics at the start of the book.
集中讨论需要的数学基础

156
00:08:31,345 --> 00:08:34,153
That way, you don't need to go ahead and learn all that linear algebra,
这样 你就不需要重头开始学习线性代数

157
00:08:34,153 --> 00:08:37,770
that you can get a very quick crash course in the pieces of
你可以得到一个短期训练课程

158
00:08:37,770 --> 00:08:40,540
linear algebra that are the most useful for deep learning.
了解对深度学习最有用的线性代数

159
00:08:40,540 --> 00:08:44,660
So even someone whose math is a little shaky or haven't seen the math for
所以即使有些学生数学基础不好 或者有几年没接触过数学

160
00:08:44,660 --> 00:08:47,000
a few years will be able to start from the beginning of your book and
你就可以从教材的开始

161
00:08:47,000 --> 00:08:49,790
get that background and get into deep learning?
学到进入深度学习的所有背景知识

162
00:08:49,790 --> 00:08:52,175
All of the facts that you would need to know are there.
你需要知道的所有事实都在那里

163
00:08:52,175 --> 00:08:57,307
It would definitely take some focused effort to practice making use of them.
当然 你肯定需要集中精神去掌握其中一些概念

164
00:08:57,839 --> 00:08:59,217
Yeah. Yeah. Great.
是的 是的 很好

165
00:08:59,684 --> 00:09:01,370
If someone's really afraid of math,
如果有人真的害怕数学

166
00:09:01,370 --> 00:09:03,700
it might be a bit of a painful experience.
这经历可能还会有点痛苦

167
00:09:03,700 --> 00:09:08,323
But if you're ready for the learning experience and you believe you can master it,
但如果你准备好去学习的话 我相信你一定可以掌握的

168
00:09:08,323 --> 00:09:11,360
I think all the tools that you need are there.
你们需要的所有工具都在哪了

169
00:09:11,360 --> 00:09:15,470
As someone that worked in deep learning for a long time,
作为在深度学习领域工作了很长时间的研究员

170
00:09:15,470 --> 00:09:18,710
I'd be curious, if you look back over the years.
我很好奇 如果你回头看看这几年

171
00:09:18,710 --> 00:09:21,050
Tell me a bit about how you're thinking
可以告诉我你的一些想法吗

172
00:09:21,050 --> 00:09:24,650
of AI and deep learning has evolved over the years.
AI和深度学习在这些年是如何逐渐演变的

173
00:09:24,650 --> 00:09:28,595
Ten years ago, I felt like, as a community,
十年前 我觉得 作为一个社区

174
00:09:28,595 --> 00:09:31,358
the biggest challenge in machine learning was just
机器学习中最大的挑战就是这样 

175
00:09:31,359 --> 00:09:34,715
how to get it working for AI-related tasks at all.
如何让它可以处理AI相关的任务

176
00:09:34,715 --> 00:09:39,440
We had really good tools that we could use for simpler tasks,
对于更简单的任务 我们那时有很好的工具

177
00:09:39,440 --> 00:09:44,555
where we wanted to recognize patterns in how to extract features,
比如我们想要提取特征 识别规律 

178
00:09:44,555 --> 00:09:47,000
where a human designer could do a lot of
人类设计师可以做很多事情 

179
00:09:47,000 --> 00:09:51,965
the work by creating those features and then hand it off to the computer.
他们设计出这些功能 然后交给计算机去做

180
00:09:51,965 --> 00:09:54,170
Now, that was really good for different things
这种做法对很多任务效果都很好

181
00:09:54,170 --> 00:09:57,052
like predicting which ads a user would click on
比如预测用户会不会点开广告

182
00:09:57,053 --> 00:10:01,895
or different kinds of basic scientific analysis.
或者不同的基本科学分析

183
00:10:01,895 --> 00:10:07,505
But we really struggled to do anything involving millions of pixels in an image or
但当我们要处理几百万像素的图片时 就很困难了

184
00:10:07,505 --> 00:10:10,150
a raw audio wave form where
或者处理音频波形 其中..

185
00:10:10,150 --> 00:10:13,950
the system had to build all of its understanding from scratch.
系统必须从零开始学到所有知识

186
00:10:13,950 --> 00:10:18,880
We finally got over the hurdle really thoroughly maybe five years ago.
五年前我们开始跨越了这个障碍

187
00:10:18,880 --> 00:10:22,180
And now, we're at a point where there are
现在我们来到了一个时代

188
00:10:22,180 --> 00:10:26,268
so many different paths open that someone who wants to get involved in AI,
如果你想从事AI事业 有太多不同的道路可以走 

189
00:10:26,268 --> 00:10:31,060
maybe the hardest problem they face is choosing which path they want to go down.
也许他们面临的最难的问题是应该选择哪条路走下去

190
00:10:31,060 --> 00:10:35,500
Do you want to make reinforcement learning work as well as supervised learning works?
你希望让加强学习效果和监督学习一样好吗?

191
00:10:35,500 --> 00:10:40,410
Do you want to make unsupervised learning work as well as supervised learning works?
你希望让无监督学习效果和监督学习一样好吗?

192
00:10:40,410 --> 00:10:44,333
Do you want to make sure that machine learning algorithms are fair
你希望机器学习算法是不偏不倚

193
00:10:44,333 --> 00:10:48,460
and don't reflect biases that we'd prefer to avoid?
不会带上我们的偏见 要尽量避免这些偏见

194
00:10:48,460 --> 00:10:54,565
Do you want to make sure that the societal issues surrounding AI work out well,
如果你想确保和AI有关的社会问题得到妥善解决

195
00:10:54,565 --> 00:10:58,535
that we're able to make sure that AI benefits everyone
确保AI可以让所有人获益

196
00:10:58,535 --> 00:11:03,440
rather than causing social upheaval and trouble with loss of jobs?
而不是造成社会动荡和大规模失业?

197
00:11:03,440 --> 00:11:04,600
I think right now,
我想现在

198
00:11:04,600 --> 00:11:08,025
there's just really an amazing amount of different things that can be done,
真的可以做到很多不同的东西

199
00:11:08,025 --> 00:11:11,380
both to prevent downsides from AI but also to make sure
可以避开AI的所有缺点

200
00:11:11,380 --> 00:11:14,965
that we leverage all of the upsides that it offers us.
同时利用它能提供的所有优点

201
00:11:14,965 --> 00:11:19,800
And so today, there are a lot of people wanting to get into AI.
今天有很多人想进入AI领域

202
00:11:19,800 --> 00:11:23,285
So, what advice would you have for someone like that?
你对这些人有什么建议?

203
00:11:23,285 --> 00:11:26,950
I think a lot of people that want to get into AI start thinking that
我想很多想进入AI领域的人 一开始想

204
00:11:26,950 --> 00:11:32,200
they absolutely need to get a Ph.D. or some other kind of credential like that.
他们绝对需要获得博士学位 或者这样那样的证书

205
00:11:32,200 --> 00:11:35,155
I don't think that's actually a requirement anymore.
我觉得实际上这已经不是必要条件了

206
00:11:35,155 --> 00:11:40,285
One way that you could get a lot of attention is to write good code and put it on GitHub.
其中一种获得注意的方式是 在GitHub上写很好的代码

207
00:11:40,285 --> 00:11:42,909
If you have an interesting project that
如果你有一个很好玩的项目

208
00:11:42,910 --> 00:11:45,168
solves a problem that someone working at the top level wanted to solve,
解决了某人在前沿希望解决的问题

209
00:11:47,320 --> 00:11:49,840
once they find your GitHub repository,
一旦他们找到了你的GitHub代码

210
00:11:49,840 --> 00:11:53,450
they'll come find you and ask you to come work there.
他们会直接找到你 让你到他们那工作

211
00:11:53,450 --> 00:11:56,140
A lot of the people that I've hired or
我雇的很多人

212
00:11:56,140 --> 00:12:00,010
recruited at OpenAI last year or at Google this year,
去年在OpenAI或今年在谷歌招聘的人

213
00:12:00,010 --> 00:12:02,755
I first became interested in working with them because of
我一开始想很他们合作 是因为

214
00:12:02,755 --> 00:12:06,895
something that I saw that they released in an open-source forum on the Internet.
我见到他们在互联网开源论坛上发表的一些代码段

215
00:12:06,895 --> 00:12:11,275
Writing papers and putting them on arXiv can also be good.
写文章并发表到arXiv上也是可以的

216
00:12:11,275 --> 00:12:12,745
A lot of the time,
很多时候

217
00:12:12,745 --> 00:12:16,750
it's harder to reach the point where you have something polished enough to really be
要将一个东西打磨完美

218
00:12:16,750 --> 00:12:20,860
a new academic contribution to the scientific literature,
成为对科学文献的新贡献是很难的

219
00:12:20,860 --> 00:12:27,885
but you can often get to the point of having a useful software product much earlier.
但在这之前你可能已经能开发出一个有用的软件产品了

220
00:12:27,885 --> 00:12:30,022
So read your book,
所以读读你的教材

221
00:12:30,022 --> 00:12:33,930
practice the materials and post on GitHub and maybe on arXiv.
在各种材料上练习 然后把代码发布到GitHub 或者arXiv上

222
00:12:33,930 --> 00:12:36,100
I think if you learned by reading the book,
如果你要用那本教材学习

223
00:12:36,100 --> 00:12:39,454
it's really important to also work on a project at the same time,
那么同时开始做一个项目是很重要的

224
00:12:39,454 --> 00:12:42,730
to either choose some way of
总之要选择某种方式

225
00:12:42,730 --> 00:12:46,555
applying machine learning to an area that you are already interested in.
将机器学习应用到你兴趣的领域

226
00:12:46,555 --> 00:12:50,500
Like if you're a field biologist and you want to get into deep learning,
比如 如果你是一名田野生物学家 你想利用深度学习

227
00:12:50,500 --> 00:12:53,255
maybe you could use it to identify birds,
也许你可以用它来识别鸟类

228
00:12:53,255 --> 00:12:56,905
or if you don't have an idea for how you'd like to use machine learning in your own life,
或者如果你不知道想用机器学习做什么

229
00:12:56,905 --> 00:13:01,600
you could pick something like making a Street View house numbers classifier,
你可以去做 比如街景门牌号码分类器

230
00:13:01,600 --> 00:13:05,580
where all the data sets are set up to make it very straightforward for you.
这里所有数据集都设立好了 你直接可以用

231
00:13:05,580 --> 00:13:07,330
And that way, you get to exercise all of
这样你就可以练习一下

232
00:13:07,330 --> 00:13:09,235
the basic skills while you read the book 
教材介绍到的所有基本技能

233
00:13:09,236 --> 00:13:14,105
or while you watch Coursera videos that explain the concepts to you.
或者当你看给你解释概念的Coursera视频时 直接去练习

234
00:13:14,105 --> 00:13:15,670
So over the last couple of years,
所以在过去的几年里 

235
00:13:15,670 --> 00:13:20,045
I've also seen you do one more work on adversarial examples.
我看到你做的一些对抗性样本的工作

236
00:13:20,045 --> 00:13:21,535
Tell us a bit about that.
告诉我们一下

237
00:13:21,535 --> 00:13:24,490
Yeah. I think adversarial examples are
是 我想对抗性样本就是

238
00:13:24,490 --> 00:13:29,835
the beginning of a new field that I call machine learning security.
我称为机器学习安全的新领域

239
00:13:29,835 --> 00:13:33,250
In the past, we've seen computer security issues
过去 我们看到计算机安全问题

240
00:13:33,250 --> 00:13:38,275
where attackers could fool a computer into running the wrong code.
攻击者可能会骗计算机跑错误的代码

241
00:13:38,275 --> 00:13:40,890
That's called application-level security.
这就是所谓的应用级安全性

242
00:13:40,890 --> 00:13:46,300
And there's been attacks where people can fool a computer into believing that
以前有些攻击方式是 人类可以骗过一台计算机 让它相信

243
00:13:46,300 --> 00:13:52,545
messages on a network come from somebody that is not actually who they say they are.
网络上的消息来自某个可信任的人 但其实不是真的

244
00:13:52,545 --> 00:13:55,025
That's called network-level security.
这就是所谓的网络级安全性

245
00:13:55,025 --> 00:13:57,230
Now, we're starting to see that you can also fool
现在 我们开始看到 你也可以骗到

246
00:13:57,230 --> 00:13:59,920
machine-learning algorithms into doing things they shouldn't,
机器学习算法 让它们去做不应该做的事情

247
00:13:59,920 --> 00:14:06,010
even if the program running the machine-learning algorithm is running the correct code,
即使运行机器学习算法的程序运行的代码完全正确

248
00:14:06,010 --> 00:14:10,025
even if the program running the machine-learning algorithm knows
即使运行机器学习算法的程序知道 

249
00:14:10,025 --> 00:14:13,605
who all the messages on the network really came from.
网络上所有消息的来源 也能骗到

250
00:14:13,605 --> 00:14:17,050
And I think, it's important to build security
我认为 在新技术开发初期

251
00:14:17,050 --> 00:14:20,830
into a new technology near the start of its development.
考虑加入安全性非常重要

252
00:14:20,830 --> 00:14:24,063
We found that it's very hard to build a working system first 
我们发现 把一个系统建立起来以后

253
00:14:24,120 --> 00:14:26,349
and then add security later.
再引入安全性是很难的

254
00:14:27,029 --> 00:14:30,693
So I am really excited about the idea that if
所以我对现在要研究的想法非常激动

255
00:14:30,767 --> 00:14:34,342
we dive in and start anticipating security problems with machine learning now,
如果我们现在开始预见机器学习的安全问题

256
00:14:34,403 --> 00:14:38,170
we can make sure that these algorithms are secure from the start
就可以从一开始确保这些算法的安全性

257
00:14:38,171 --> 00:14:41,629
instead of trying to patch it in retroactively years later.
而不是过几年再回头打补丁

258
00:14:42,426 --> 00:14:43,324
Thank you. That was great.
谢谢 那太棒了

259
00:14:43,390 --> 00:14:46,090
There's a lot about your story that I thought was fascinating and that,
你的故事有很多神奇的地方

260
00:14:46,090 --> 00:14:47,470
despite having known you for years,
尽管已经认识你很多年了

261
00:14:47,470 --> 00:14:49,935
I didn't actually know, so thank you for sharing all that.
我实际上并不知道 所以感谢你分享这一切

262
00:14:49,935 --> 00:14:53,090
Oh, very welcome. Thank you for inviting me. It was a great shot.
你太客气了 谢谢你邀请我 这是很好的机会

263
00:14:53,090 --> 00:14:53,630
Okay. Thank you.
好的 谢谢

264
00:14:53,630 --> 00:14:55,010
Very welcome.
非常感谢

