1
00:00:00,210 --> 00:00:02,119
在前面的视频中 我提到过
In the previous video, I mentioned that 

2
00:00:02,168 --> 00:00:04,178
广播是一种手段
broadcasting is another technique

3
00:00:04,230 --> 00:00:06,569
可以让你的Python代码段执行得更快
that  you can use to make your Python code run faster.

4
00:00:06,611 --> 00:00:08,810
在这个视频中 让我们深入研究一下
In this video, let's delve into 

5
00:00:08,877 --> 00:00:11,211
Python中的广播是如何实际运作
how broadcasting in Python actually works.

6
00:00:11,764 --> 00:00:14,025
假设我们用一个例子来讲广播
Let's suppose today broadcasting with an example.

7
00:00:14,083 --> 00:00:17,113
在这个矩阵中 我们列出了
In this matrix, I've shown the number of calories 

8
00:00:17,172 --> 00:00:19,990
来自100克碳水化合物 蛋白质和脂肪的卡路里数量
from carbohydrates, proteins, and fats 

9
00:00:20,026 --> 00:00:22,343
这四种不同食物的卡路里
in 100 grams of four different foods.

10
00:00:22,369 --> 00:00:25,330
所以比如说 100克苹果的热量
So for example, a 100 grams of apples turns out,

11
00:00:25,372 --> 00:00:29,607
有56卡来自碳水化合物 远远少于蛋白质和脂肪
has 56 calories from carbs, and much less from proteins and fats.

12
00:00:29,636 --> 00:00:32,265
而相反 100克的牛肉
Whereas, in contrast, a 100 grams of beef 

13
00:00:32,309 --> 00:00:36,959
有104卡来自蛋白质 和135卡来自脂肪
has 104 calories from protein and 135 calories from fat.

14
00:00:37,036 --> 00:00:39,352
现在 比如说你的目标是
Now, let's say your goal is 

15
00:00:39,399 --> 00:00:44,725
计算四种食物中 卡路里有多少百分比
to calculate the percentage of calories from carbs,

16
00:00:44,773 --> 00:00:48,414
来自碳水化合物 蛋白质和脂肪
proteins and fats for each of the four foods.

17
00:00:48,456 --> 00:00:50,798
比如 你看这一列
So, for example, if you look at this column 

18
00:00:50,855 --> 00:00:53,781
将整列数字加起来 就得到
and add up the numbers in that column you get that 

19
00:00:53,848 --> 00:00:59,090
100克苹果有56+1.2+1.8
100 grams of apple has 56 plus 1.2 plus 1.8 

20
00:00:59,106 --> 00:01:02,232
所以总共是59卡
so that's 59 calories.

21
00:01:02,300 --> 00:01:06,657
然后苹果中来自碳水化合物
And so as a percentage the percentage of calories 

22
00:01:06,683 --> 00:01:11,669
卡路里的百分比是56/59
from carbohydrates in an apple would be 56 over 59, 

23
00:01:11,716 --> 00:01:17,044
大概是94.9%
that's about 94.9%.

24
00:01:17,103 --> 00:01:21,199
所以苹果中大部分热量都来自碳水化合物
So most of the calories in an apple come from carbs,

25
00:01:21,230 --> 00:01:24,245
而相比之下 大多数牛肉的热量
whereas in contrast, most of the calories of beef

26
00:01:24,283 --> 00:01:27,152
都来自蛋白质和脂肪
come from protein and fat and so on.

27
00:01:27,183 --> 00:01:29,654
你要做的计算其实是
So the calculation you want is really 

28
00:01:29,707 --> 00:01:34,283
对矩阵这四列求和
to sum up each of the four columns of this matrix

29
00:01:34,356 --> 00:01:38,626
得到100克以下食物的卡路里总量: 苹果 
to get the total number of calories in 100 grams of apples,

30
00:01:38,685 --> 00:01:40,048
牛肉 鸡蛋和土豆
beef, eggs, and potatoes.

31
00:01:40,107 --> 00:01:44,924
然后让整个矩阵各列除以总量
And then to divide throughout the matrix,

32
00:01:44,988 --> 00:01:49,173
得到卡路里占的百分比
so as to get the percentage of calories 

33
00:01:49,210 --> 00:01:54,067
四种食物中 来自碳水化合物 蛋白质和脂肪热量的百分比各占多少
from carbs, proteins and fats for each of the four foods.

34
00:01:54,492 --> 00:01:59,837
所以问题是 你可以不用显式for循环做吗?
So the question is, can you do this without an explicit for-loop?

35
00:02:01,213 --> 00:02:03,184
我们看看应该怎么做
Let's take a look at how you could do that.

36
00:02:03,985 --> 00:02:07,341
我这里要给你介绍的是 如何设置..
What I'm going to do is show you how you can set,

37
00:02:08,214 --> 00:02:12,230
比如令这个矩阵等于3*4矩阵A
say this matrix equal to three by four matrix A.

38
00:02:13,103 --> 00:02:15,290
然后用一行Python代码
And then with one line of Python code 

39
00:02:15,301 --> 00:02:18,409
我们会对各列求和
we're going to sum down the columns.

40
00:02:18,446 --> 00:02:20,461
我们得到四个数字
So we're going to get four numbers corresponding to 

41
00:02:20,499 --> 00:02:25,474
对应四种不同事物的卡路里总量
the total number of calories in these four different types of foods,

42
00:02:25,533 --> 00:02:27,856
这100克四种不同类型食物的热量总量
100 grams of these four different types of foods.

43
00:02:27,909 --> 00:02:30,875
然后我用第二行Python代码
And I'm going to use a second line of Python code 

44
00:02:30,948 --> 00:02:35,207
让四列每一列都除以对应的和
to divide each of the four columns by their corresponding sum.

45
00:02:35,255 --> 00:02:37,441
如果口头描述你们听得不太清楚
If that verbal description wasn't very clearly,

46
00:02:37,466 --> 00:02:39,401
希望当你看到Python代码时
hopefully it will be clearer in a second

47
00:02:39,460 --> 00:02:40,712
马上就懂了
when we look in the Python code.

48
00:02:40,760 --> 00:02:42,371
所以这是我们的Jupyter笔记本
So here we are in the Jupiter notebook.

49
00:02:42,436 --> 00:02:44,890
我们写了第一段代码了
I've already written this first piece of code 

50
00:02:44,922 --> 00:02:48,657
把我们刚才的数字填入矩阵A
to prepopulate the matrix A with the numbers we had just now,

51
00:02:48,683 --> 00:02:51,363
然后Shift+Enter 那矩阵A就弄好了
so we'll hit shift enter and so there's the matrix A.

52
00:02:51,432 --> 00:02:55,126
然后这是两行Python代码
And now here are the two lines of Python code.

53
00:02:55,168 --> 00:02:58,643
首先我们要计算cal = A.sum ..
First, we're going to compute cal = A.sum ..

54
00:02:58,670 --> 00:03:02,831
axis=0 意味着竖直相加
axis equals 0 means to sum vertically.

55
00:03:02,842 --> 00:03:04,372
我们稍后再说一遍
We'll say more about that in a little bit.

56
00:03:04,425 --> 00:03:06,143
然后print cal
And then print cal.

57
00:03:06,199 --> 00:03:08,353
我们会在竖直方向求和
So we'll sum vertically.

58
00:03:08,395 --> 00:03:13,329
现在59是苹果中的总卡路里数
Now 59 is the total number of calories in the apple, 

59
00:03:13,367 --> 00:03:16,216
239是牛肉中的总卡路里数
239 was the total number of calories in the beef

60
00:03:16,276 --> 00:03:18,561
还有鸡蛋和马铃薯之类的
and the eggs and potato and so on.

61
00:03:18,599 --> 00:03:30,094
然后我们要计算百分比 percentage=A/cal.reshape(1,4)
And then with a compute percentage equals A/cal.Reshape 1,4.

62
00:03:30,802 --> 00:03:34,066
我们其实要得到的是百分比 所以这里要乘以100
Actually we want percentages, so multiply by 100 here.

63
00:03:36,048 --> 00:03:38,997
然后我们print percentage
And then let's print percentage.

64
00:03:40,514 --> 00:03:41,322
我们跑一下
Let's run that.

65
00:03:41,840 --> 00:03:45,657
所以那个命令我们用了矩阵A
And so that command we've taken the matrix A

66
00:03:46,238 --> 00:03:49,886
让它除以这个1×4矩阵
and divided it by this one by four matrix.

67
00:03:49,923 --> 00:03:52,737
然后就得到了百分比矩阵
And this gives us the matrix of percentages.

68
00:03:52,777 --> 00:03:57,934
我们手算出了苹果的情况
So as we worked out kind of by hand just now in the apple

69
00:03:57,981 --> 00:04:02,135
第一列有94.9%卡来自碳水化合物
there was a first column 94.9% of the calories are from carbs.

70
00:04:02,209 --> 00:04:03,597
我们回到幻灯片上来
Let's go back to the slides.

71
00:04:03,677 --> 00:04:06,331
就重复这两行代码
So just to repeat the two lines of code we had,

72
00:04:06,363 --> 00:04:09,289
就在jupyter笔记本里写的
this is what have written out in the Jupiter notebook.

73
00:04:09,829 --> 00:04:13,867
这里参数还要加一些细节
To add a bit of detail this parameter,

74
00:04:13,909 --> 00:04:18,597
这个轴等于0意味着我希望Python在竖直方向求和
axis equals zero means that you want Python to sum vertically.

75
00:04:18,644 --> 00:04:21,674
这是轴0 意味着竖直相加
So if this is axis 0 this means to sum vertically,

76
00:04:21,733 --> 00:04:24,079
而水平轴是轴1
where as the horizontal axis is axis 1.

77
00:04:24,122 --> 00:04:25,489
我们可以写成是axis = 1
So be able to write axis = 1

78
00:04:25,534 --> 00:04:27,558
这样就可以水平求和 而不是竖直求和
or sum horizontally instead of sum vertically.

79
00:04:27,578 --> 00:04:29,608
然后这里的命令
And then this command here,

80
00:04:30,411 --> 00:04:33,427
是Python广播的另一个例子
this is an example of Python broadcasting

81
00:04:33,480 --> 00:04:35,166
当你取矩阵A
where you take a matrix A.

82
00:04:35,219 --> 00:04:37,723
这是一个3×4矩阵
So this is a three by four matrix

83
00:04:37,785 --> 00:04:42,443
你让它除以一个1×4矩阵
and you divide it by a one by four matrix.

84
00:04:42,460 --> 00:04:47,586
技术上 在这第一行代码之后 变量cal 
And technically, after this first line of codes cal, the variable cal,

85
00:04:47,641 --> 00:04:49,779
已经是一个1×4矩阵了
is already a one by four matrix.

86
00:04:49,825 --> 00:04:53,011
所以技术上你不需要调用reshape
So technically you don't need to call reshape here again, 

87
00:04:53,047 --> 00:04:54,457
这实际上有点多余
so that's actually a little bit redundant.

88
00:04:54,956 --> 00:04:57,768
但是当我编写Python代码时 
But when I'm writing Python codes

89
00:04:57,825 --> 00:05:00,129
如果不完全确定用什么矩阵
if I'm not entirely sure what matrix,

90
00:05:00,160 --> 00:05:01,954
不确定矩阵的尺寸
whether the dimensions of a matrix

91
00:05:02,023 --> 00:05:05,216
我会经常调用reshape命令 确保
I often would just call a reshape command just to make sure that

92
00:05:05,286 --> 00:05:08,391
它是正确的列向量或行向量
it's the right column vector or the row vector 

93
00:05:08,429 --> 00:05:09,617
或者你想要的任何形式
or whatever you want it to be.

94
00:05:09,675 --> 00:05:11,870
reshape命令经常会用到
The reshape command is a constant time.

95
00:05:11,912 --> 00:05:14,564
这是o(1)操作 成本很低
It's a order one operation that's very cheap to call.

96
00:05:15,127 --> 00:05:17,257
所以不要害怕使用reshape命令 
So don't be shy about using the reshape command

97
00:05:17,341 --> 00:05:20,892
来确保你的矩阵形状是你想要的
to make sure that your matrices are the size you need it to be.

98
00:05:21,516 --> 00:05:24,369
现在我们详细解释一下
Now, let's explain in greater detail

99
00:05:24,437 --> 00:05:27,452
这种运算是怎么执行的
how this type of operation works, right?

100
00:05:27,509 --> 00:05:29,439
我们有一个3×4矩阵
We had a three by four matrix

101
00:05:29,496 --> 00:05:33,723
我们让它除以一个1×4矩阵
and we divided it by a one by four matrix.

102
00:05:33,772 --> 00:05:36,237
那么你怎么让一个3×4矩阵
So, how can you divide a three by four matrix 

103
00:05:36,311 --> 00:05:38,987
除以1×4矩阵呢? 这个1×4向量
by a one by four matrix? Or by one by four vector?

104
00:05:39,569 --> 00:05:42,711
我们再来看几个广播的例子
Let's go through a few more examples of broadcasting.

105
00:05:42,773 --> 00:05:46,188
如果你取一个4×1向量 让它和一个数字相加
If you take a 4 by 1 vector and add it to a number, 

106
00:05:46,240 --> 00:05:51,846
什么Python会做的是 将这个数字自动展开
what Python will do is take this number and auto-expand it

107
00:05:52,552 --> 00:05:57,616
变为一个1×4向量 就像这样
into a four by one vector as well, as follows.

108
00:05:57,663 --> 00:05:59,804
所以向量1 2 3 4
And so the vector 1, 2, 3, 4

109
00:05:59,826 --> 00:06:04,328
加上数字100 最终等于右边这个向量
plus the number 100 ends up with that vector on the right.

110
00:06:04,371 --> 00:06:06,256
你就往每个元素加上100
You're adding a 100 to every element,

111
00:06:06,289 --> 00:06:08,664
事实上我们使用这种形式的广播 
and in fact we use this form of broadcasting 

112
00:06:08,722 --> 00:06:13,222
其中常数是之前视频里的参数b
where that constant was the parameter b in an earlier video.

113
00:06:13,985 --> 00:06:16,283
而这种广播 
And this type of broadcasting

114
00:06:16,342 --> 00:06:19,455
对列向量和行向量一样有用
works with both column vectors and row vectors,

115
00:06:19,513 --> 00:06:22,131
事实上我们之前已经使用了类似的广播形式
and in fact we use a similar form of broadcasting earlier

116
00:06:22,158 --> 00:06:25,648
就是我们往向量加上一个常数的时候
with the constant we're adding to a vector

117
00:06:25,702 --> 00:06:28,850
在logistic回归中就是参数b
being the parameter b in logistic regression.

118
00:06:29,516 --> 00:06:30,722
这里是另一个例子 
Here's another example.

119
00:06:31,302 --> 00:06:35,724
我们说你有一个2×3矩阵
Let's say you have a two by three matrix 

120
00:06:35,799 --> 00:06:39,458
然后你让它加上一个1×n矩阵
and you add it to this one by n matrix.

121
00:06:40,418 --> 00:06:47,652
那么一般情况下 如果这里你有个矩阵
So the general case would be if you have some matrix here 

122
00:06:47,731 --> 00:06:54,288
并将它加上1×n矩阵
and you add it to a 1 by n matrix.

123
00:06:54,331 --> 00:06:58,782
什么Python会做的是 复制矩阵m次
What Python will do is copy the matrix m,

124
00:06:58,825 --> 00:07:01,527
把它变成m×n矩阵
times to turn this into m by n matrix, 

125
00:07:01,576 --> 00:07:06,210
所以这不再是一个1×3矩阵
so instead of this one by three matrix 

126
00:07:06,237 --> 00:07:09,375
python会复制两次 把它变成这个形式
it'll copy it twice in this example to turn it into this.

127
00:07:09,399 --> 00:07:14,975
所以2×3矩阵 然后我们让它们相加
Also, two by three matrix and we'll add these

128
00:07:15,018 --> 00:07:18,345
最后你会得到右边的和 对吧?
so you'll end up with the sum on the right, okay?

129
00:07:18,376 --> 00:07:21,495
所以你拿了.. 你让第一列加上100
So you taken, you added 100 to the first column,

130
00:07:21,537 --> 00:07:25,145
第二列加上200 第三列加上300
added 200 to second column, added 300 to the third column.

131
00:07:25,696 --> 00:07:28,490
这基本上是我们在上一张幻灯片中所做的
And this is basically what we did on the previous slide,

132
00:07:28,538 --> 00:07:30,631
不过我们用了一个除法运算
except that we use a division

133
00:07:30,689 --> 00:07:32,942
而不是加法运算
operation instead of an addition operation.

134
00:07:33,533 --> 00:07:40,279
所以最后一个例子 无论你有没有m×n矩阵
So one last example, whether you have a m by n matrix

135
00:07:40,310 --> 00:07:46,415
你都让它加上一个m×1向量 或者m×1矩阵
and you add this to a m by 1 vector, or m by 1 matrix.

136
00:07:46,452 --> 00:07:50,857
然后水平复制n次
Then just copy this n times horizontally.

137
00:07:50,894 --> 00:07:53,466
最后你会得到一个m×n矩阵
So you end up with an m by n matrix.

138
00:07:53,525 --> 00:07:56,854
你可以想象一下水平复制三次
So as you can imagine you copy it horizontally three times.

139
00:07:56,890 --> 00:07:57,957
然后加起来
And you add those.

140
00:07:58,653 --> 00:08:00,565
当你让它们相加的时候 就会得到这个
So when you add them you end up with this.

141
00:08:01,146 --> 00:08:03,844
所以你往第一行加了100
So we've added 100 to the first row

142
00:08:03,875 --> 00:08:06,799
第二行加了200
and added 200 to the second row.

143
00:08:07,450 --> 00:08:11,672
在Python广播中有一些通用规则
Here's the more general principle of broadcasting in Python.

144
00:08:11,710 --> 00:08:18,467
如果你有一个m×n矩阵 然后你加上或者减去
If you have an m by n matrix and you add or subtract

145
00:08:18,526 --> 00:08:25,187
乘以或除以一个1×n矩阵
or multiply or divide with a 1 by n matrix,

146
00:08:25,237 --> 00:08:30,926
那么python就会把它复制n次变成m×n矩阵
then this will copy it n times into a m by n matrix.

147
00:08:30,979 --> 00:08:33,828
然后再逐元素做加法 减法
And then apply the addition, subtraction,

148
00:08:33,843 --> 00:08:36,176
乘法和除法
and multiplication of division element wise.

149
00:08:36,837 --> 00:08:39,467
如果相反
If conversely, you were to

150
00:08:39,509 --> 00:08:42,992
你拿一个m×n矩阵 加上 减去 乘以
take the m by n matrix and add, subtract, multiply,

151
00:08:43,046 --> 00:08:49,158
或者除以m×1矩阵 那么这也会复制n次
divide by a m by 1 matrix, then also this would copy it now n times.

152
00:08:49,212 --> 00:08:51,518
把它变成一个m×n矩阵
And turn that into a m by n matrix

153
00:08:51,584 --> 00:08:54,594
然后逐元素应用操作
and then apply the operation element wise.

154
00:08:54,641 --> 00:08:59,822
这是其中一种广播 就是如果你有个m×1矩阵
Just one of the broadcasting, which is if you have a m by 1 matrix,

155
00:08:59,848 --> 00:09:04,853
这其实是个列向量 然后你让它加上
so that's really a column vector like , and you add,

156
00:09:04,895 --> 00:09:08,526
减去 乘以或除以一个实数
subtract, multiply or divide by a real number.

157
00:09:08,569 --> 00:09:10,758
所以也许是1×1矩阵
So maybe a 1 by 1 matrix.

158
00:09:11,024 --> 00:09:16,269
所以这样加上100 最后你就是
So such as that plus 100, then you end up copying

159
00:09:16,332 --> 00:09:23,512
把这个实数复制n次 直到你得到另一个m×1矩阵
this real number n times until you'll also get another m by 1 matrix.

160
00:09:23,512 --> 00:09:25,953
然后执行运算
And then you perform the operation

161
00:09:26,005 --> 00:09:29,581
比如说这个例子中逐元素做加法
such as addition on this example element-wise.

162
00:09:29,608 --> 00:09:35,617
类似的东西也适用于行向量
And something similar also works for row vectors.

163
00:09:38,613 --> 00:09:40,876
所以广播的一般版本
The fully general version of broadcasting

164
00:09:40,923 --> 00:09:42,930
还可以做到更多
can do even a little bit more than this.

165
00:09:42,985 --> 00:09:49,532
如果你有兴趣可以阅读NumPy的文档
If you're interested you can read the documentation for NumPy,

166
00:09:49,590 --> 00:09:51,572
并在文档里搜索broadcasting
and look at broadcasting in that documentation.

167
00:09:51,625 --> 00:09:53,653
这也许是
That gives an even slightly

168
00:09:53,685 --> 00:09:55,816
更广义的广播
more general definition of broadcasting.

169
00:09:55,933 --> 00:09:57,742
幻灯片上的这些是
But the ones on the slide 

170
00:09:57,789 --> 00:10:00,138
在你实现神经网络算法时
are the main forms of broadcasting that you end up

171
00:10:00,184 --> 00:10:02,693
主要用到的广播形式
needing to use when you implement a neural network.

172
00:10:03,346 --> 00:10:06,185
在我们结束之前 最后讲一句
Before we wrap up, just one last comment, 

173
00:10:06,222 --> 00:10:07,452
对于你们
which is for those of you 

174
00:10:07,505 --> 00:10:10,658
习惯用MATLAB或Octave编程的同学
that are used to programming in either MATLAB or Octave,

175
00:10:10,711 --> 00:10:14,866
如果你曾经使用MATLAB或Ocatvae函数bsxfun
if you've ever used the MATLAB or Octave function bsxfun

176
00:10:15,489 --> 00:10:17,080
在神经网络编程中
in neural network programming

177
00:10:17,142 --> 00:10:20,601
bsxfun做的事情很类似 但不完全相同
bsxfun does something similar, not quite the same.

178
00:10:20,626 --> 00:10:22,858
但它通常用于类似的目的 
But it is often used for similar purpose

179
00:10:22,896 --> 00:10:25,172
就像我们在Python中使用广播一样
as what we use broadcasting in Python for.

180
00:10:25,226 --> 00:10:27,030
但这函数真的只是
But this is really only for 

181
00:10:27,083 --> 00:10:29,382
非常厉害的MATLAB和Octave用户才会用到
very advanced MATLAB and Octave users,

182
00:10:29,430 --> 00:10:31,557
如果你还没听说过 不用担心
if you've not heard of this, don't worry about it.

183
00:10:31,594 --> 00:10:32,767
你不需要知道那些
You don't need to know it

184
00:10:32,809 --> 00:10:35,118
用Python编码神经网络就好了
when you're coding up neural networks in Python.

185
00:10:35,619 --> 00:10:38,218
这就是Python中的广播
So, that was broadcasting in Python.

186
00:10:38,276 --> 00:10:40,788
我希望你们在做编程作业时
I hope that when you do the programming homework 

187
00:10:40,846 --> 00:10:42,469
广播能够让你的
that broadcasting will allow you to 

188
00:10:42,511 --> 00:10:44,484
代码运行速度更快
not only make a code run faster,

189
00:10:44,529 --> 00:10:46,680
也希望能帮到你
but also help you get

190
00:10:46,715 --> 00:10:49,081
写更少的代码来实现你的目标
what you want done with fewer lines of code.

191
00:10:50,123 --> 00:10:52,480
在你进行编程练习之前
Before you dive into the programming excercise,

192
00:10:52,537 --> 00:10:54,754
我想和大家分享一套想法
I want to share with you just one more set of ideas, 

193
00:10:54,802 --> 00:10:57,841
就是我发现的一些技巧
which is that there's some tips and tricks that I've found

194
00:10:57,879 --> 00:11:00,360
可以减少Python代码中的错误数量
reduces the number of bugs in my Python code 

195
00:11:00,403 --> 00:11:02,174
我希望也会帮助你
and that I hope will help you too.

196
00:11:02,216 --> 00:11:05,532
所以我们在下一个视频中谈谈这个
So with that, let's talk about that in the next video.

