1
00:00:00,000 --> 00:00:01,403
你们已经学会很多了
With everything you've learned,

2
00:00:01,449 --> 00:00:02,676
现在你已经准备好了
you're just about ready to 

3
00:00:02,752 --> 00:00:04,246
解决你的第一个编程任务
tackle your first programming assignment.

4
00:00:04,305 --> 00:00:06,379
在你这样做之前 让我来给你
Before you do that, let me just give you 

5
00:00:06,410 --> 00:00:09,896
介绍一下Coursera中的ipython笔记本
a quick tour of ipython notebooks in Coursera.

6
00:00:10,385 --> 00:00:12,566
你可以看到 这是Jupyter iphython笔记本
Here you see, Jupyter iphython notebooks 

7
00:00:12,650 --> 00:00:14,627
你可以在Coursera中访问
that you can get to in Coursera.

8
00:00:14,664 --> 00:00:17,313
让我快速向你展示一下它的功能
Let me just quickly show you a few features of this.

9
00:00:17,814 --> 00:00:21,958
这指南是用ipython笔记本文本写的
The instructions are written into text in the ipython notebook

10
00:00:21,995 --> 00:00:25,274
灰色块是代码段
like gray blocks are blocks of code.

11
00:00:25,316 --> 00:00:27,597
所以你偶尔会看到这些代码段
So occasionally, you see in these blocks

12
00:00:27,639 --> 00:00:29,339
有时看起来是这样的
sometimes looks like this

13
00:00:29,471 --> 00:00:31,102
这是写 代码开始 代码结束
this is their start code here and end code here.

14
00:00:31,127 --> 00:00:32,721
要做第一个大作业
To do their primary exercise,

15
00:00:32,773 --> 00:00:34,423
请确保你写的代码
please make sure to write your code 

16
00:00:34,480 --> 00:00:36,890
在代码开始和代码结束之间
between the start code here and end code here.

17
00:00:36,929 --> 00:00:40,462
比如 print Hello World
So for example, print Hello World.

18
00:00:40,512 --> 00:00:44,143
对吧 然后要执行代码段
Right. And, then to execute a code block,

19
00:00:44,196 --> 00:00:49,099
你可以输入Shift+Enter 然后执行代码段
you can hit shift enter and then they execute this code block,

20
00:00:49,155 --> 00:00:50,930
我们刚写了print Hello World
which I guess we just wrote print Hello World.

21
00:00:50,976 --> 00:00:52,848
所以Hello World就输出来了
So that printed Hello World.

22
00:00:53,587 --> 00:00:55,985
要运行一个单元格 你也可以
To run a cell, you can also,

23
00:00:56,050 --> 00:00:57,483
在其中一个单元格里跑代码
to run one of these code blocks in cell,

24
00:00:57,520 --> 00:01:00,033
你可以点单元格菜单 然后运行单元格
you can also click cell and then run cell.

25
00:01:00,097 --> 00:01:06,591
你是可以用 键盘快捷方式执行的
So to execute this is possible that on your computer the keyboard shortcut

26
00:01:06,655 --> 00:01:09,640
要执行单元格程序 可能用的不是Shift+Enter
for cell runs cell might be different than shift enter

27
00:01:09,692 --> 00:01:13,711
但在我的mac和PC中都行
but on both my Mac as well as on my PC,

28
00:01:13,758 --> 00:01:16,222
所以你用Shift+Enter可能也行
a shift enter so might be the same for you as well.

29
00:01:16,919 --> 00:01:19,755
所以当你阅读说明你就知道
Now, when you're reading the instructions if you know,

30
00:01:19,786 --> 00:01:21,125
意外双击后
accidentally double click on it,

31
00:01:21,170 --> 00:01:24,042
你可能会得到这样的标记语言
you might end up with this markdown language.

32
00:01:24,115 --> 00:01:26,516
如果你得到这种怪怪的文本
If you end up with this funny looking text,

33
00:01:26,574 --> 00:01:30,364
要把它们变回格式整齐的文本 只需要执行这个单元格就行了
to convert it back to the nice looking text just run the cell.

34
00:01:30,419 --> 00:01:34,196
所以点击单元格 然后运行 我这里要用shift+enter
So click on the cell runs cell or I'm going to hit shift enter

35
00:01:34,249 --> 00:01:36,841
这基本上就执行了标记语言
and that basically executes the markdown 

36
00:01:36,883 --> 00:01:38,998
并将它重新转换成漂亮的代码段
and turns it back into this nice looking code.

37
00:01:39,717 --> 00:01:41,318
这里还有一些提示
Just a couple of more tips,

38
00:01:41,355 --> 00:01:43,700
当你执行这样的代码时
when you execute code like this,

39
00:01:43,733 --> 00:01:46,329
它应该是在内核上运行的
it actually runs on a kernel 

40
00:01:46,393 --> 00:01:50,310
那是服务器上的一段代码
on a piece of code that runs on the server.

41
00:01:50,823 --> 00:01:55,371
如果你跑一段计算量很大的代码
If you're running an excessively large job or if you're,

42
00:01:55,411 --> 00:01:59,126
或者你离开电脑很久 出了什么问题
you leave a computer for a very long time or something goes wrong,

43
00:01:59,173 --> 00:02:00,838
比如你的网断了
your internet connection is off,

44
00:02:00,861 --> 00:02:03,155
那么后端的内核可能会宕机
there is a small chance of the kernel on the back end might die,

45
00:02:03,218 --> 00:02:04,647
那么你只需点击内核
which is just click kernel.

46
00:02:04,706 --> 00:02:07,159
然后重启内核 希望
And then restart kernel and hopefully 

47
00:02:07,212 --> 00:02:10,535
重启内核可以让它重新工作
that will reboot the kernel and make it work again.

48
00:02:10,593 --> 00:02:11,648
不过如果你运行的代码
So that shouldn't happen 

49
00:02:11,707 --> 00:02:14,367
计算量不多 应该不会出这种问题
if you're just running relatively small jobs

50
00:02:14,445 --> 00:02:16,336
如果你开始使用ipython笔记本
and you're just starting up your ipython notebook.

51
00:02:16,393 --> 00:02:18,711
然后你看到错误信息
But if you see an error message that 

52
00:02:18,780 --> 00:02:20,041
内核卡死了之类的
the kernel has died or something,

53
00:02:20,096 --> 00:02:22,170
你可以尝试重启内核
you can try kernel restart.

54
00:02:22,664 --> 00:02:25,838
最后 这样的iPython笔记本
Finally, and ipython notebook like this

55
00:02:25,876 --> 00:02:27,845
可能有很多代码段
there may be multiple blocks of code.

56
00:02:27,897 --> 00:02:30,696
所以即使前面一些代码段
So, even if an earlier block of code 

57
00:02:30,754 --> 00:02:33,062
没有任何用于作业评分的代码
doesn't have any grading code,

58
00:02:33,109 --> 00:02:36,230
一定要确保执行这段代码 因为这个例子中
be sure to execute this block of code because in this example,

59
00:02:36,283 --> 00:02:39,434
它执行了import numpy as py 等等
it imposed numpy as np and so on.

60
00:02:39,479 --> 00:02:42,170
这样就初始化一些变量
And said so some of the variables that you might need in order to

61
00:02:42,227 --> 00:02:45,913
才能执行下面这些代码
execute the lowdown on blocks of code 

62
00:02:45,953 --> 00:02:47,554
所以一定要执行最上面的代码
so be sure to execute the ones on top

63
00:02:47,580 --> 00:02:50,348
或者即使没要求你在上面写代码
even if you aren't asked to write any code in them.

64
00:02:50,991 --> 00:02:53,650
最后 当你完成代码实现之后
And finally, when you're done implementing your solutions

65
00:02:53,697 --> 00:02:56,332
按这个蓝色提交作业按钮
as this blue submit assignment button here

66
00:02:56,384 --> 00:02:58,618
在右边 我们点击一下
on the right and we click that 

67
00:02:58,667 --> 00:03:00,750
就会提交你的答案 然后评分
it will submit your solutions for grading.

68
00:03:01,729 --> 00:03:05,479
我发现这些交互命令很像shell
I found out the interactive command shell nature

69
00:03:05,526 --> 00:03:08,060
这样的ipython笔记本是非常有用的
of ipython notebooks to be very useful

70
00:03:08,130 --> 00:03:10,529
可以让你快速实现几行代码
for letting you quickly implement a few lines of code,

71
00:03:10,571 --> 00:03:13,457
马上看到结果 迅速学习
see an outcome, learn it very quickly.

72
00:03:13,495 --> 00:03:15,969
我希望这个练习方法
And so I hope that the approach exercises 

73
00:03:16,012 --> 00:03:20,328
还有和Coursera Jupyter ipython可以帮你迅速
and Coursera in Jupyter ipython notebooks will help you quickly

74
00:03:20,408 --> 00:03:21,901
学习和实验 看结果
learn and experiment and see 

75
00:03:21,933 --> 00:03:24,087
学会如何实现这些学习算法
how to implement these learning algorithms.

76
00:03:24,150 --> 00:03:26,182
之后还有一个视频
There's one more video after this.

77
00:03:26,234 --> 00:03:27,933
那是一个可选的视频
This is an optional video 

78
00:03:27,997 --> 00:03:30,852
会讨论成本函数的logistic回归
that talks about the cost function for logistic reggression.

79
00:03:30,901 --> 00:03:32,175
你们可以看 也可以不看
You can watch that or not,

80
00:03:32,227 --> 00:03:33,590
都行
either way is perfectly fine.

81
00:03:33,632 --> 00:03:35,673
总之 祝你们在
But either way, best of luck 

82
00:03:35,695 --> 00:03:38,184
完成第二周作业中有好运气
with the week two probing assignments.

83
00:03:38,221 --> 00:03:40,365
我希望在下周材料
And I also look forward to seeing you 

84
00:03:40,408 --> 00:03:43,005
开始时再见到你
at the start of the next week's materials.

