1
00:00:00,000 --> 00:00:03,393
本视频中 我们讲讲logistic回归
In this video, we'll go over logistic regression.

2
00:00:03,435 --> 00:00:07,578
这是一个学习算法 用在监督学习问题中
This is a learning algorithm that you use when the output labels y

3
00:00:07,635 --> 00:00:10,854
输出y标签是0或1时
in a supervised learning problem are all either zero or one,

4
00:00:10,892 --> 00:00:13,087
这是一个二元分类问题
so for binary classification problems.

5
00:00:13,155 --> 00:00:18,232
已知的输入特征向量x 可能是
Given an input feature vector x maybe corresponding to

6
00:00:18,275 --> 00:00:20,806
一张图 你希望把识别出
an image that you want to recognize as 

7
00:00:20,845 --> 00:00:23,097
这是不是猫图
either a cat picture or not a cat picture,

8
00:00:23,134 --> 00:00:26,357
你需要一个算法 可以给出一个预测值
you want an algorithm that can output a prediction,

9
00:00:26,400 --> 00:00:28,328
我们说预测值y帽
which we'll call y hat,

10
00:00:28,365 --> 00:00:31,325
就是你对y的预测
which is your estimate of y.

11
00:00:31,353 --> 00:00:35,785
更正式的说 你希望y帽是一个概率
More formally, you want y hat to be the probability of the chance that,

12
00:00:35,812 --> 00:00:40,402
当输入特征x满足条件时 y就是1
y is equal to one given the input features x.

13
00:00:40,456 --> 00:00:43,892
所以换句话说 如果x是图片
So in other words, if x is a picture,

14
00:00:43,929 --> 00:00:45,775
正如我们在上一个视频中看到的
as we saw in the last video,

15
00:00:45,838 --> 00:00:47,634
你希望y帽能告诉你
you want y hat to tell you,

16
00:00:47,656 --> 00:00:49,894
这是一张猫图的概率
what is the chance that this is a cat picture.

17
00:00:49,954 --> 00:00:53,523
所以x 正如我们之前的视频里说过的
So x, as we said in the previous video,

18
00:00:53,570 --> 00:00:56,961
是一个n_x维向量
is an nx dimensional vector,

19
00:00:57,025 --> 00:01:03,435
已知Logistic回归的参数是w
given that the parameters of logistic regression will be w

20
00:01:03,484 --> 00:01:07,586
也是一个n_x维向量
which is also an nx dimensional vector,

21
00:01:07,630 --> 00:01:11,399
而b就是一个实数
together with b which is just a real number.

22
00:01:11,441 --> 00:01:15,887
所以已知输入x和参数w和b
So given an input X and the parameters W and b,

23
00:01:15,944 --> 00:01:20,134
我们如何计算输出预测y帽?
how do we generate the output y hat?

24
00:01:20,193 --> 00:01:23,113
好 你可以这么试 但其实不靠谱
Well, one thing you could try, that doesn't work,

25
00:01:23,166 --> 00:01:27,854
就是y帽 = w^T x +b
would be to have y hat be w transpose X plus B,

26
00:01:27,919 --> 00:01:32,642
输入x的线性函数
kind of a linear function of the input X.

27
00:01:32,701 --> 00:01:36,971
事实上 如果你做线性回归 就是这么算的
And in fact, this is what you use if you were doing linear regression.

28
00:01:37,013 --> 00:01:41,479
但这不是一个非常好的二元分类算法 
But this isn't a very good algorithm for binary classification

29
00:01:41,532 --> 00:01:45,638
因为你希望y帽是y=1的概率
because you want y hat to be the chance that Y is equal to one.

30
00:01:45,698 --> 00:01:49,823
所以y帽应该介于0和1之间
So y hat should really be between zero and one,

31
00:01:50,605 --> 00:01:55,409
但实际上这很难实现 因为w^Tx+b
and it's difficult to enforce that because w^Tx+b

32
00:01:55,409 --> 00:01:58,792
可能比1大得多 或者甚至是负值
can be much bigger then one or it can even be negative,

33
00:01:58,800 --> 00:02:01,026
这样的概率是没意义的
which doesn't make sense for probability,

34
00:02:01,064 --> 00:02:03,592
你希望概率介于0和1之间
that you want it to be between zero and one.

35
00:02:03,635 --> 00:02:07,932
所以在Logisitc回归中 我们的输出变成
So in logistic regression our output is instead going to be y hat

36
00:02:07,937 --> 00:02:12,109
y帽等于sigmoid函数作用到这个量上
equals the sigmoid function applied to this quantity.

37
00:02:12,159 --> 00:02:14,497
这就是sigmoid函数的图形
This is what the sigmoid function looks like.

38
00:02:14,561 --> 00:02:19,105
横轴是z
If on the horizontal axis I plot Z 

39
00:02:19,159 --> 00:02:24,091
那么sigmoid(z)就是这样的
then the function sigmoid of Z looks like this.

40
00:02:24,122 --> 00:02:27,530
从0到1的光滑函数
So it goes smoothly from zero up to one.

41
00:02:27,593 --> 00:02:29,768
我标记一下这里的轴
Let me label my axes here,

42
00:02:30,523 --> 00:02:34,742
这是0 然后和垂直轴相交在0.5处
this is zero and it crosses the vertical axis as 0.5.

43
00:02:34,796 --> 00:02:38,081
这就是sigmoid(z)的图形
So this is what sigmoid of Z looks like 

44
00:02:38,140 --> 00:02:41,609
我们用z来表示这个量
and we're going to use Z to denote this quantity,

45
00:02:41,679 --> 00:02:43,252
w转置x+b
W transpose X plus B.

46
00:02:43,304 --> 00:02:45,744
这是Sigmoid函数的公式
Here's the formula for the sigmoid function.

47
00:02:45,807 --> 00:02:49,452
sigmoid(z)其中z是实数
Sigmoid of Z, where Z is a real number,

48
00:02:49,506 --> 00:02:52,641
就是1/(1+e^-z)
is one over one plus E to the negative Z.

49
00:02:52,683 --> 00:02:54,572
要注意一些事情
So notice a couple of things.

50
00:02:54,625 --> 00:03:01,287
如果z非常大 那么e^-z就很接近0
If Z is very large then E to the negative Z will be close to zero.

51
00:03:01,335 --> 00:03:03,547
那么sigmoid(z)就是
So then sigmoid of Z will be

52
00:03:03,584 --> 00:03:07,472
大约等于1/(1+某个很接近0的量
approximately one over one plus something very close to zero,

53
00:03:07,532 --> 00:03:11,344
因为e^-z 在z很大时就很接近0
because E to the negative of very large number will be close to zero.

54
00:03:11,360 --> 00:03:13,127
所以这接近1
So this is close to 1.

55
00:03:13,151 --> 00:03:16,335
事实上 如果你看看左边的图
And indeed, if you look in the plot on the left,

56
00:03:16,383 --> 00:03:20,083
z很大时 sigmoid(z)就很接近1
if Z is very large the sigmoid of Z is very close to one.

57
00:03:21,117 --> 00:03:23,566
相反 如果z很小
Conversely, if Z is very small,

58
00:03:23,640 --> 00:03:27,032
或者是非常大的负数
or it is a very large negative number,

59
00:03:28,308 --> 00:03:40,020
那么sigmoid(z)就变成1/(1+e^-z)
then sigmoid of Z becomes one over one plus E to the negative Z,

60
00:03:40,062 --> 00:03:42,283
就变成很大的数字
and this becomes, it's a huge number.

61
00:03:42,320 --> 00:03:44,920
这就变成.. 想一下
So this becomes, think of it 

62
00:03:44,963 --> 00:03:47,227
1除以1加上很大的数字
as one over one plus a number 

63
00:03:47,302 --> 00:03:48,508
那是非常大的数字
that is very, very big, and so,

64
00:03:54,473 --> 00:03:56,211
所以这接近0
that's close to zero.

65
00:03:56,864 --> 00:04:00,171
确实 当你看到z变成非常大的负值时
And indeed, you see that as Z becomes a very large negative number,

66
00:04:00,205 --> 00:04:03,571
sigmoid(z)就很接近0
sigmoid of Z goes very close to zero.

67
00:04:03,602 --> 00:04:05,886
所以当你实现logistic回归时
So when you implement logistic regression,

68
00:04:05,923 --> 00:04:09,884
你要做的是学习参数w和b
your job is to try to learn parameters W and B

69
00:04:09,920 --> 00:04:12,830
所以y帽变成了比较好的估计
so that y hat becomes a good estimate 

70
00:04:12,842 --> 00:04:15,144
对y=1概率的比较好的估计
of the chance of Y being equal to one.

71
00:04:15,536 --> 00:04:18,885
在继续之前 我们再讲讲符号约定
Before moving on, just another note on the notation.

72
00:04:18,927 --> 00:04:20,969
当我们对神经网络编程时
When we programmed neural networks,

73
00:04:20,990 --> 00:04:26,637
我们通常会把w和参数b分开
we'll usually keep the parameter W and parameter B separate,

74
00:04:26,653 --> 00:04:30,080
这里b对应一个拦截器
where here, B corresponds to an interceptor

75
00:04:30,133 --> 00:04:31,521
在其他一些课程中
In some other courses,

76
00:04:31,574 --> 00:04:34,798
你们可能看过不同的表示
you might have seen a notation that handles this differently.

77
00:04:34,841 --> 00:04:37,616
在一些符号约定中
In some conventions you define 

78
00:04:37,622 --> 00:04:41,861
你定义一个额外的特征向量 叫x_0  那等于1
an extra feature called X0 and that equals a one.

79
00:04:41,923 --> 00:04:47,391
所以出现x就是R^(n_x+1)维向量
So that now x is in R^(n_x+1).

80
00:04:47,427 --> 00:04:53,973
然后你将y帽定义为σ(θ^Tx)
And then you define y hat to be equal to sigma of theta transpose X.

81
00:04:53,973 --> 00:04:56,417
在这另一种符号约定中
In this alternative notational convention,

82
00:04:56,464 --> 00:05:00,048
你有一个向量参数θ
you have vector parameters theta,

83
00:05:00,117 --> 00:05:02,943
θ_0 θ_1还有θ_2
theta zero, theta one, theta two,

84
00:05:02,980 --> 00:05:06,513
一直到θ_nx
down to theta NX.

85
00:05:08,949 --> 00:05:12,004
所以θ_0 扮演的是b的角色
And so, theta zero, plays the role of b

86
00:05:12,035 --> 00:05:13,467
这是一个实数
that's just a real number,

87
00:05:13,498 --> 00:05:17,699
而θ_1直到θ_nx的作用和w一样
and theta one down to theta NX play the role of W. 

88
00:05:17,732 --> 00:05:20,406
事实上 当你实现你的神经网络时
It turns out, when you implement you implement your neural network,

89
00:05:20,433 --> 00:05:25,691
将b和w看作独立的参数可能更好
it will be easier to just keep B and W as separate parameters.

90
00:05:26,291 --> 00:05:27,593
所以对于这门课
And so, in this class,

91
00:05:27,644 --> 00:05:30,147
我们不会用那种符号约定
we will not use any of this notational convention 

92
00:05:30,249 --> 00:05:32,101
就是红色写的那些 我不会用
that I just wrote in red.

93
00:05:32,138 --> 00:05:34,673
如果你们没有在其他课程里见过这个符号约定
If you've not seen this notation before in other courses, 

94
00:05:34,716 --> 00:05:36,066
不要担心太多
don't worry about it.

95
00:05:36,123 --> 00:05:37,734
我讲这个是为了服务
It's just that for those of you 

96
00:05:37,766 --> 00:05:41,146
那些见过这种符号约定的学生
that have seen this notation I wanted to mention explicitly

97
00:05:41,187 --> 00:05:43,668
我们在本课中不会使用那种符号约定
that we're not using that notation in this course.

98
00:05:43,721 --> 00:05:45,428
如果你以前没见过
But if you've not seen this before,

99
00:05:45,465 --> 00:05:47,686
这不重要 所以不用担心
it's not important and you don't need to worry about it.

100
00:05:48,109 --> 00:05:52,154
现在你看到了logistic回归模型长什么样
So you have now seen what the logistic regression model looks like.

101
00:05:52,228 --> 00:05:54,980
接下来我们看参数w和b
Next to change the parameters W and B 

102
00:05:55,032 --> 00:05:57,047
你需要定义一个成本函数
you need to define a cost function.

103
00:05:57,073 --> 00:05:58,746
我们下一个视频来讨论
Let's do that in the next video.

