1
00:00:00,000 --> 00:00:03,166
在上个视频中 我们看了一个例子
In the last video, we worked through an example of

2
00:00:03,230 --> 00:00:05,661
使用流程图来计算函数J
using a computation graph to compute the function J.

3
00:00:05,736 --> 00:00:07,850
现在我们清理一下
Now, let's take a cleaned up version 

4
00:00:07,902 --> 00:00:10,672
流程图的描述 看看你如何利用它
of that computation graph and show how you can use it

5
00:00:10,694 --> 00:00:14,748
计算出函数J的导数
to figure out derivative calculations for that function J.

6
00:00:14,778 --> 00:00:16,969
所以这是一个流程图
So, here's a computation graph.

7
00:00:17,455 --> 00:00:19,043
假设你要计算
Let's say you want to compute 

8
00:00:19,091 --> 00:00:24,156
J对v的导数 那怎么算呢? 
the derivative of J with respect to v. So, what is that?

9
00:00:24,187 --> 00:00:26,317
好 比如说 我们要
Well, this says if we were to 

10
00:00:26,346 --> 00:00:28,971
把这个v值拿过来 改变一下
take this value of v and change it a little bit,

11
00:00:29,018 --> 00:00:31,699
那么J的值会怎么变呢?
how would the value of J change?

12
00:00:31,748 --> 00:00:37,026
所以定义上 J是3v
Well, J is defined as three times v,

13
00:00:37,079 --> 00:00:42,253
现在v等于11
and right now v is equal to 11.

14
00:00:42,310 --> 00:00:47,210
所以如果你让v增加一点点 比如到11.001
So, if we're to pump up v by a little bit to 11.001, 

15
00:00:47,253 --> 00:00:50,258
那么J是3v
then J which has three vs 

16
00:00:50,292 --> 00:00:56,118
现在33就增加到33.003
and currently 33 will get pumped up to 33.003.

17
00:00:56,155 --> 00:00:59,396
所以我这里v增加了0.001 然后
So, here we've increased v by .001 and

18
00:00:59,433 --> 00:01:03,560
最终结果是J上升到原来的三倍
the net result of that is that J goes up three times as much.

19
00:01:03,602 --> 00:01:07,772
所以J对v的导数就等于3
So the derivative of J with respect to v is equal to three

20
00:01:07,825 --> 00:01:13,096
因为对于任何v的增量 J都会有三倍增量
because the increase in J is three times the increase in v.

21
00:01:13,127 --> 00:01:15,367
而且这类似于
and, in fact, this is very analogous to 

22
00:01:15,420 --> 00:01:18,214
我们在上一个视频中的例子
the example we had in the previous video

23
00:01:18,251 --> 00:01:24,596
我们有f(a)=3a
where we had f(a) equals 3a.

24
00:01:24,646 --> 00:01:26,336
然后我们推导出
and so, we then derive

25
00:01:26,383 --> 00:01:32,625
那个df(a)/da 就是稍微化简之后的
that df(a)/da which was slightly simplified 

26
00:01:32,649 --> 00:01:34,057
有点随便的写法
and slightly sloppy notation,

27
00:01:34,079 --> 00:01:36,505
你可以看成df/da=3
you can read as df/da was equal to three.

28
00:01:36,542 --> 00:01:39,991
所以这里我们有J=3v
So, instead, here we have J equals 3v 

29
00:01:40,017 --> 00:01:44,480
所以dJ/dv就等于3
and so dJ/dv is equal to three,

30
00:01:44,504 --> 00:01:52,594
这里J扮演了f的角色
with here J playing the role of f,

31
00:01:52,661 --> 00:01:54,997
v扮演了a的角色
and v playing the role of a in

32
00:01:55,062 --> 00:01:58,438
在之前的视频里的例子
this previous example that we had right from an earlier video.

33
00:01:58,491 --> 00:02:04,499
在反向传播算法中的术语 我们看到
In the terminology of backpropagation what we've seen is that

34
00:02:04,562 --> 00:02:05,898
如果你想计算
if you want to compute 

35
00:02:05,935 --> 00:02:09,368
最后输出变量的导数
the derivative of this final output variable

36
00:02:09,405 --> 00:02:11,862
使用你最关心的变量
which uses variable you care most about,

37
00:02:11,894 --> 00:02:14,874
对v的导数
with respect to v,

38
00:02:14,898 --> 00:02:18,995
那么我们就做完了一步反向传播
then we're done sort of one step of backpropagation

39
00:02:19,048 --> 00:02:21,790
在这个流程图中是一个反向步
so the called one step backwards in this graph.

40
00:02:21,827 --> 00:02:23,940
我们来看另一个例子
Now, let's look at another example.

41
00:02:24,009 --> 00:02:27,663
dJ/da是多少呢?
What is dJ/da?

42
00:02:27,684 --> 00:02:30,425
换句话说 如果我们提高a的数值
In other words, if we pump up the value of a,

43
00:02:30,462 --> 00:02:33,895
对J的数值有什么影响?
how does that affect the value of J?

44
00:02:35,241 --> 00:02:36,826
好 我们看看这个例子
Well, let's go through the example.

45
00:02:36,900 --> 00:02:38,904
变量a=5
variable a is equal to five.

46
00:02:39,716 --> 00:02:42,632
我们让它增加到5.001
So let's pump it up to 5.001.

47
00:02:42,702 --> 00:02:46,922
那么对v的影响就是a+U
The net impact of that is that v which was a plus U,

48
00:02:46,965 --> 00:02:48,843
之前是11
so that was previous 11,

49
00:02:48,886 --> 00:02:52,311
现在变成11.001
this we can increase to 11.001.

50
00:02:52,364 --> 00:02:54,497
我们从上面看到
and then we've already seen as above 

51
00:02:54,540 --> 00:03:01,128
现在J就变成33.003了
that J now gets bumped up to 33.003.

52
00:03:01,190 --> 00:03:04,606
所以我们看到的是 如果你让a增加0.001
So, what we've seen is that if you increase a by 0.001,

53
00:03:04,679 --> 00:03:07,393
J增加0.003
J increases by 0.003.

54
00:03:07,462 --> 00:03:09,713
那么增加a 我是说
and by increase a I mean 

55
00:03:09,776 --> 00:03:13,170
如果你把这个5换成某个新值
if you were to take this value 5 and just plug in the new value

56
00:03:13,218 --> 00:03:15,402
那么a的改变量
then the change to a 

57
00:03:15,438 --> 00:03:17,990
就会传播到流程图的最右
will propagate to the right of the computation graph.

58
00:03:18,038 --> 00:03:22,116
所以J最后是33.003
So that J ends up being 33.003.

59
00:03:22,666 --> 00:03:27,774
所以J的增量是3乘以a的增量
and so, the increase to J is three times the increase to a.

60
00:03:27,816 --> 00:03:31,187
意味着这个导数是3
That means this derivative is equal to three.

61
00:03:31,227 --> 00:03:33,749
要解释这个计算过程其中一种方式是
One way to break this down is to 

62
00:03:33,791 --> 00:03:39,156
就是如果你改变了a 那也会改变v
say that if you change a then that would change v,

63
00:03:39,622 --> 00:03:41,424
通过改变v
and through changing v,

64
00:03:41,472 --> 00:03:43,152
也会改变J
that would change J.

65
00:03:43,209 --> 00:03:48,535
所以J值的净变化量
and so, the net change to the value of J,

66
00:03:48,562 --> 00:03:50,307
当你提升这个值
when you bump up the value,

67
00:03:50,333 --> 00:03:53,452
当你把a值提高一点点 这就是J的变化量
when you nudge the value of a up a little bit is that,

68
00:03:55,937 --> 00:04:03,232
首先 a增加了 v也会增加
first, by changing a you end up increasing v. Well,

69
00:04:03,257 --> 00:04:05,341
v增加多少呢?
how much does v increase?

70
00:04:05,373 --> 00:04:07,585
增加了一个量
It is increased by an amount 

71
00:04:07,639 --> 00:04:13,180
这取决于dv/da 然后v的变化
that's determined by dv/da and then the change in v

72
00:04:13,224 --> 00:04:19,136
导致J也在增加
will cause the value of J to also increase.

73
00:04:19,602 --> 00:04:22,706
所以这在微积分里实际上叫链式法则
So, in Calculus this is actually called the chain rule,

74
00:04:22,743 --> 00:04:27,890
如果a影响到v影响到J
that's if a affects v affects J,

75
00:04:27,953 --> 00:04:32,286
那么当你让a变大时 J的变化量
then the amount that J changes when you nudge a

76
00:04:32,340 --> 00:04:37,654
就是当你改变a时v的变化量乘以
is the product of how much v changes when you nudge a,

77
00:04:37,665 --> 00:04:41,717
改变v时 J的变化量
times how much J changes when you nudge v.

78
00:04:41,780 --> 00:04:45,349
在微积分里这叫链式法则
So in Calculus again this is called the chain rule.

79
00:04:47,576 --> 00:04:50,244
我们从这个计算中看到
What we saw from this calculation is that 

80
00:04:50,287 --> 00:04:52,743
如果你让a增加0.001
if you increase a by 0.001,

81
00:04:52,800 --> 00:04:55,312
v也会变化相同的大小
v changes by the same amount.

82
00:04:55,354 --> 00:04:58,950
所以dv/da就等于1
So dv/da is equal to one.

83
00:04:59,398 --> 00:05:02,757
事实上 如果你代入进去 我们之前算过
So in fact if you plug in what we have worked up previously on

84
00:05:04,284 --> 00:05:11,497
dJ/dv等于3 dv/da等于1
dJ/dv is equal to three and dv/da is equal to one,

85
00:05:11,530 --> 00:05:14,047
所以这个乘积 3×1
so the product of this, three times one.

86
00:05:14,093 --> 00:05:16,078
实际上就给出了正确答案
That actually gives you the correct value 

87
00:05:16,089 --> 00:05:18,504
dJ/da就等于3
that dJ/da is equal to three.

88
00:05:18,540 --> 00:05:22,952
这张小图表示了 如何计算
This little illustration shows how by having computed

89
00:05:22,990 --> 00:05:27,392
dJ/dv 就是这个对这个变量的导数
dJ/dv had this derivative with respect to this variable,

90
00:05:27,434 --> 00:05:33,696
它可以帮你计算dJ/da
it can then help you to compute dJ/da.

91
00:05:33,733 --> 00:05:37,365
所以这是另一步反向传播计算
and so, that's another step of this backward calculation.

92
00:05:38,747 --> 00:05:43,641
现在我想介绍一个新的符号约定
I just want to introduce one more new notational convention,

93
00:05:43,674 --> 00:05:49,505
当你编程实现反向传播时
which is that when you're writing codes to implement backpropagation,

94
00:05:49,541 --> 00:05:54,297
通常会有一个最终输出值是你要关心的
there usually be some final output variable that you really care about,

95
00:05:54,340 --> 00:05:59,243
最终的输出变量
a final output variable

96
00:05:59,306 --> 00:06:01,463
你真正想要关心或者说优化的
that you really care about or that you want to optimize.

97
00:06:01,491 --> 00:06:04,149
在这种情况下 最终的输出变量是j
and in this case, this final output variable is j.

98
00:06:04,208 --> 00:06:07,088
就是流程图里最后一个符号
It's really the last note in your computation graph.

99
00:06:07,111 --> 00:06:10,386
所以有很多计算尝试
and so, a lot of computations will be trying to

100
00:06:10,410 --> 00:06:13,452
计算输出变量的导数
compute the derivative of that find the output variable.

101
00:06:13,494 --> 00:06:17,584
所以d输出变量 对某个变量的导数
So d of this final output variable with respect to some other variable.

102
00:06:17,598 --> 00:06:21,078
我们就用d var命名
Let me just call that, d var.

103
00:06:23,569 --> 00:06:25,246
所以在很多计算中你需要
So, a lot of the computations you have would

104
00:06:25,273 --> 00:06:28,202
计算最终输出结果的导数
be to compute the derivative of the final output variable, 

105
00:06:28,223 --> 00:06:29,920
在这个例子里是J
letter J in this case,

106
00:06:29,957 --> 00:06:33,980
还有各种中间变量 比如a b c u v
with various intermediate variable such as a, b, c, u, v.

107
00:06:34,005 --> 00:06:37,583
当你在软件里实现的时候
and when you implement this in software,

108
00:06:37,593 --> 00:06:40,886
变量名叫什么?
what do you call this variable name?

109
00:06:40,924 --> 00:06:44,410
你可以做的一件事是 在Python中
One thing you could do is, in Python,

110
00:06:44,458 --> 00:06:47,213
你可以写一个很长的变量名
you could write a very long variable name,

111
00:06:47,265 --> 00:06:49,909
比如d FinalOutputvar 除以d var
d Final Output var over a d var.

112
00:06:49,940 --> 00:06:51,871
但这个变量名有点长
But that's a very long variable name.

113
00:06:51,908 --> 00:06:55,035
我们就用dJ/dvar
We could call this dJ, d var.

114
00:06:55,094 --> 00:06:59,715
但因为你一直对dJ求导
But because you're always taking derivatives respect to dJ,

115
00:06:59,752 --> 00:07:01,498
对这个最终输出变量求导
respect to this final output variable,

116
00:07:01,551 --> 00:07:04,685
我这里要介绍一个新符号 在程序里
I'm going to introduce a new notation, where in code,

117
00:07:05,168 --> 00:07:10,203
当你编程的时候 在代码里
when you're computing this thing in the code you write,

118
00:07:10,240 --> 00:07:13,875
我们就使用变量名dvar
we're just going to use the variable name dvar

119
00:07:13,906 --> 00:07:16,217
来表示那个量
in order to represent that quantity.

120
00:07:16,282 --> 00:07:19,864
好 所以在程序里是dvar
Okay? So dvar in the code you write,

121
00:07:19,890 --> 00:07:21,706
表示导数
will represent the derivative 

122
00:07:21,766 --> 00:07:25,237
你关心的最终变量J的导数
of the final output variable you care about such as j,

123
00:07:25,289 --> 00:07:28,536
有时最后是L 
sometimes the last L with respect to

124
00:07:28,578 --> 00:07:31,492
对代码中各种中间量的导数
the various intermediate quantities you're computing in your code.

125
00:07:31,561 --> 00:07:34,403
所以代码里这个东西
So this thing here in your code,

126
00:07:34,470 --> 00:07:38,583
你用dv表示这个值
you use dv to denote this value.

127
00:07:38,626 --> 00:07:45,870
所以dv就等于3 你的代码表示就是da
So dv would be equal to three and your code represents this as a da,

128
00:07:45,895 --> 00:07:49,626
这也等于3
which is we also figured out to be equal to three.

129
00:07:49,673 --> 00:07:54,858
好 所以我们通过这个流程图
Okay? So we've done backpropagation partially 

130
00:07:54,872 --> 00:07:57,659
部分完成的后向传播算法
through this computation graph,

131
00:07:58,130 --> 00:08:01,559
我们在下一张幻灯片看看这个例子剩下的部分
let's go through the rest of this example on the next slide.

132
00:08:02,199 --> 00:08:06,240
我们清理出一张新的流程图
So let's go to clean up a copy of the computation graph.

133
00:08:06,662 --> 00:08:08,427
我们回顾一下
and just to recap,

134
00:08:08,486 --> 00:08:11,521
到目前为止 我们一直在往回传播
what we've done so far, is go backward here 

135
00:08:11,559 --> 00:08:14,838
并算出dv等于3
and figured out that dv is equal to three.

136
00:08:14,865 --> 00:08:16,948
再次 dv的定义是
and again, the definition of dv,

137
00:08:16,979 --> 00:08:20,899
就是一个变量名 在代码里是dJ dv
that's just a variable name of the code is really d, j, d, v.

138
00:08:20,937 --> 00:08:25,092
我发现da=3 再次
I figured out that da is equal to three and again,

139
00:08:25,159 --> 00:08:27,481
da是代码里的变量名
da is the variable name in your code 

140
00:08:27,512 --> 00:08:30,718
其实代表dJ/da的值
and that's really the value of dJ, da.

141
00:08:32,197 --> 00:08:34,696
大概手算了一下
Have a sort of hand wave 

142
00:08:34,722 --> 00:08:38,729
两条线怎么计算反向传播
how you have gone backwards on these two edges, like so.

143
00:08:38,771 --> 00:08:41,382
好 我们继续计算导数
Now, let's keep computing derivatives.

144
00:08:41,392 --> 00:08:44,228
我们看看这个值 u
Let's look at the value, u.

145
00:08:44,611 --> 00:08:47,487
那么dJ/du是多少呢?
So what is dJ, du?

146
00:08:47,550 --> 00:08:51,190
好 通过和之前类似的计算
Well, through a similar calculation as what we did before,

147
00:08:51,202 --> 00:08:53,884
现在我们从u=6出发
now we start off with u equals six.

148
00:08:53,911 --> 00:08:56,972
如果你令u增加到6.001
If you bump up u to 6.001,

149
00:08:57,057 --> 00:08:59,782
那么v之前是11
then v which is previous 11,

150
00:08:59,816 --> 00:09:02,578
现在变成11.001了
goes up to 11.001,

151
00:09:02,615 --> 00:09:07,843
J就从33变成33.003
and so j goes from 33 to 33.003.

152
00:09:07,908 --> 00:09:11,277
所以J增量是3倍 所以这就等于
and so the increase in j is 3x, so this is equal.

153
00:09:11,303 --> 00:09:16,159
你对u的分析很类似对a的分析
and the analysis for u is very similar to the analysis we did for a.

154
00:09:16,207 --> 00:09:26,240
实际上这计算起来就是dJ/dv · dv/du
This is actually computed as dJ, dv times dv, du.

155
00:09:26,267 --> 00:09:29,872
有了这个 我们就可以算那个结果是3
With this, we had already figured out was three,

156
00:09:29,904 --> 00:09:33,280
这个结果是1
and this turns out to be equal to one.

157
00:09:34,073 --> 00:09:36,796
所以我们还有一步反向传播
So we've got one more step of back propagation,

158
00:09:36,844 --> 00:09:43,162
我们最终计算出du也等于3
we end up computing that du is also equal to three,

159
00:09:43,204 --> 00:09:46,649
这du当然了 就是dJ/du
and du is of course, just as dJ, du.

160
00:09:47,077 --> 00:09:50,895
现在 我们仔细看看最后一个例子
Now, we just step through one last example in detail.

161
00:09:51,313 --> 00:09:54,218
dJ/dv呢?
So what is dJ, dv?

162
00:09:54,265 --> 00:09:58,024
想像一下 如果你改变了b的值 你想要
Imagine if you are allowed to change the value of b and you want to

163
00:09:58,063 --> 00:10:03,832
然后变化一点 让J值达到最大
tweak b a little bit in order to minimize or maximize the value of j.

164
00:10:04,183 --> 00:10:07,973
那么导数是什么呢? 这个J函数的斜率
So what is the derivative, what's the slope of this function j

165
00:10:08,312 --> 00:10:11,205
当你稍微改变b值之后
when you change the value of b a little bit?

166
00:10:11,558 --> 00:10:12,949
事实上
It turns out that,

167
00:10:13,399 --> 00:10:15,356
使用微积分的链式法则
using the chain rule for calculus,

168
00:10:15,410 --> 00:10:18,686
这可以写成两者的乘积
this can be written as the product of two things,

169
00:10:18,718 --> 00:10:24,141
就是dJ/du·du/dv
is dJ, du times du, dv.

170
00:10:24,173 --> 00:10:26,395
理由是
and the reasoning is,

171
00:10:26,427 --> 00:10:33,400
如果你改变b一点点 所以b变成比如说3.001
if you change b a little bit, so b goes to 3 to, say, 3.001.

172
00:10:33,427 --> 00:10:36,044
它影响J的方式是
The way it'll affect j is,

173
00:10:36,081 --> 00:10:37,594
首先会影响u
it will first affect u.

174
00:10:37,619 --> 00:10:39,924
它对u的影响有多大?
So how much does it affect u?

175
00:10:39,947 --> 00:10:43,680
好 u的定义是b·c
Well, u is defined as b times c, right?

176
00:10:44,119 --> 00:10:49,713
所以b=3时这是6 
So this will go from six when b is equal to three,

177
00:10:49,756 --> 00:10:54,270
现在就变成6.002了
to now, or 6.002.

178
00:10:54,303 --> 00:10:59,573
对吧 因为在我们的例子中 c等于2
Right? Because c is equal to two, in our example here.

179
00:10:59,615 --> 00:11:05,351
所以这告诉我们du/db等于2
and so this tells us that, du, db is equal to two

180
00:11:05,373 --> 00:11:07,999
当你让b增加0.001时
because when you pump up b by .001,

181
00:11:08,035 --> 00:11:10,589
u就增加两倍
u increase twice as much.

182
00:11:10,614 --> 00:11:14,328
所以du/db 这等于2
So du, db, this is equal to two.

183
00:11:14,364 --> 00:11:20,970
现在我想u已经增加量是b的两倍
and now, we know that u has gone up twice as much as b has gone up.

184
00:11:21,014 --> 00:11:24,499
那么dJ/du是多少?
Well, what is dJ, du?

185
00:11:24,524 --> 00:11:25,912
我们已经弄清楚了 
We've already figured out that

186
00:11:25,960 --> 00:11:29,743
这等于3 所以让这两部分相乘
this is equal to three and so by multiplying these two parts,

187
00:11:29,789 --> 00:11:32,801
我们发现dJ/db等于6
we find that dJ,db is equal to six.

188
00:11:32,845 --> 00:11:34,818
好这就是推导
and again, here's the reasoning 

189
00:11:34,857 --> 00:11:37,031
第二部分的推导 其中
for the second part of the argument, which is,

190
00:11:37,062 --> 00:11:39,946
我们想知道u增加0.002
we want to know when u goes up by .002,

191
00:11:40,006 --> 00:11:43,311
会对J有什么影响
how does that affect j?

192
00:11:43,369 --> 00:11:47,094
实际上dJ/du等于3
The fact that dJ, du is equal to three,

193
00:11:47,141 --> 00:11:50,589
这告诉我们u增加0.002之后
that tells us that when u goes up by .002,

194
00:11:50,611 --> 00:11:54,769
j上升了3倍
j goes up three times as much.

195
00:11:54,800 --> 00:11:59,196
那么j应该上升0.006 对吧
So j should go up by .006, right?

196
00:12:00,295 --> 00:12:04,855
这可以从dJ/du=3推导出来
That comes from a fact that dJ, du is equal to three.

197
00:12:05,286 --> 00:12:07,494
如果你仔细看看这些数学内容
and if you check the math in detail,

198
00:12:07,560 --> 00:12:08,782
你会发现
you will find that,

199
00:12:08,845 --> 00:12:11,799
如果b变成3.001
if b becomes 3.001,

200
00:12:11,827 --> 00:12:14,136
那么u就变成6.002
then u becomes 6.002,

201
00:12:14,187 --> 00:12:23,669
v变成11.002 所以这是a+u 这是5+u 
v becomes 11.002, so that's a plus u, that's five plus u.

202
00:12:23,706 --> 00:12:27,227
然后j 就等于3v 
and then j, which is equal to three times v,

203
00:12:27,251 --> 00:12:32,705
所以答案就是33.006
that answer being equal to 33.006.

204
00:12:33,079 --> 00:12:37,595
对吧? 这就是如何得到dJ/db=6
Right? and so that's how you get that dJ, db is equal to six.

205
00:12:37,653 --> 00:12:40,945
为了填进去 如果我们反向走的话
and to fill that in, this is if we go backwards,

206
00:12:41,005 --> 00:12:44,960
这是db等于6 而db其实是
so this is db is equal to six and db really is

207
00:12:44,986 --> 00:12:50,028
Python代码中的变量名 表示dJ/db
the Python code variable name for the dJ, db.

208
00:12:50,067 --> 00:12:53,570
我不会很详细的介绍最后一个例子
and I won't go through the last example in great detail 

209
00:12:53,597 --> 00:12:55,251
但事实上
but it turns out that,

210
00:12:55,690 --> 00:12:59,738
如果你同时算算dJ/da
if you also compute how dJ, da,

211
00:12:59,786 --> 00:13:02,311
结果这是dJ/du
this turns out to be dJ, du

212
00:13:02,359 --> 00:13:07,180
乘以du/da 这结果是9
times du, da and this turns out to be nine.

213
00:13:07,207 --> 00:13:09,104
是3×3
Just turns out to be three times three. 

214
00:13:09,580 --> 00:13:11,807
我不会详细说明这个例子
I won't go through that example in detail.

215
00:13:11,840 --> 00:13:13,820
在最后一步
Through this last step,

216
00:13:13,842 --> 00:13:19,070
我们可以推出d_c等于9
it is possible to derive that d_c is equal to 9.

217
00:13:19,521 --> 00:13:22,190
所以这个视频的要点是
So the key takeaway from this video,

218
00:13:22,234 --> 00:13:23,710
对于那个例子
from this example is that,

219
00:13:23,765 --> 00:13:26,857
当计算所有这些导数时
when computing derivatives in computing all of these derivatives,

220
00:13:26,894 --> 00:13:29,077
最有效率的办法是
the most efficient way to do so,

221
00:13:29,135 --> 00:13:32,083
从右到左计算
is through a right to left computation 

222
00:13:32,115 --> 00:13:34,509
跟着这个红色箭头走
following the direction of the red arrows.

223
00:13:34,536 --> 00:13:37,922
特别是 当我们第一次计算对v的导数时
and in particular, we'll first compute the derivatives respect to v

224
00:13:37,969 --> 00:13:42,618
之后在计算对a导数就可以用到
and then that becomes useful for computing the derivative respect a 

225
00:13:42,642 --> 00:13:44,593
对u的导数
and the derivative respect to u.

226
00:13:44,618 --> 00:13:48,453
然后对u的导数 比如说
and then, derivative respect to u, for example,

227
00:13:48,506 --> 00:13:52,755
这个项和这里这个项 
this term over here and this term over here, those, in turn,

228
00:13:52,789 --> 00:13:55,561
可以帮助计算对b的导数
become useful for computing the derivative respect to b

229
00:13:55,603 --> 00:13:58,437
然后对c的导数 所以这是
and the derivative respect to c. So that was

230
00:13:58,445 --> 00:14:01,692
一个计算流程图 就是正向
a computation graph and how there's a forward or

231
00:14:01,760 --> 00:14:06,082
或者说从左到右的计算 来计算成本函数j
left to right calculation to compute the cost functions such as j,

232
00:14:06,129 --> 00:14:07,475
你可能需要优化的函数
do you might want to optimize.

233
00:14:07,538 --> 00:14:12,089
然后反向从右到左计算导数
and a backwards or a right to left calculation to compute derivatives.

234
00:14:12,136 --> 00:14:15,836
如果你不熟悉微积分或链式法则
If you're not familiar with calculus or the chain rule,

235
00:14:15,863 --> 00:14:18,740
我知道这里有些细节讲的很快
I know some of those details are gone by really quickly.

236
00:14:18,767 --> 00:14:21,143
但如果你没跟上所有细节 也不用怕
But if you didn't follow all the details, don't worry about it.

237
00:14:21,195 --> 00:14:24,251
在下一个视频中 我会再过一遍
In the next video, we'll go over this again 

238
00:14:24,300 --> 00:14:26,187
在logistic回归的背景下过一遍
in the context of logistic regression,

239
00:14:26,239 --> 00:14:28,175
并给你们介绍需要做什么
and show you exactly what you need to do 

240
00:14:28,234 --> 00:14:31,130
才能编写代码
in order to implement the computations you need

241
00:14:31,168 --> 00:14:33,589
实现logistic回归模型中的导数计算
to compute derivatives through the logistic regression model.

