1
00:00:00,151 --> 00:00:02,533
Python让你能够
The ability of python to allow you 

2
00:00:02,585 --> 00:00:06,097
使用广播运算 一般来说
to use broadcasting operations and more generally,

3
00:00:06,165 --> 00:00:10,146
python numpy程序语言给你提供了很高的灵活性
the great flexibility of the python numpy program language is,

4
00:00:10,194 --> 00:00:12,615
我想 这算是一门编程语言的优势
I think, both a strength as well as 

5
00:00:12,663 --> 00:00:14,661
同时也是弱势
a weakness of the programming language.

6
00:00:14,715 --> 00:00:15,948
我认为是一种优势
I think it's a strength

7
00:00:16,006 --> 00:00:18,475
因为它让语言的表现力更强
because they create expressivity of the language.

8
00:00:18,540 --> 00:00:19,900
语言的灵活性很大 
A great flexibility of the language

9
00:00:19,971 --> 00:00:23,510
就是说 你可以用一行代码完成很多运算
lets you get a lot done even with just a single line of code.

10
00:00:23,559 --> 00:00:25,405
但也有弱点 
But there's also weakness

11
00:00:25,506 --> 00:00:29,143
因为广播和这么大的灵活性
because with broadcasting and this great amount of flexibility, 

12
00:00:29,178 --> 00:00:32,552
有时可能会引入非常细微的错误 
sometimes it's possible you can introduce very subtle bugs

13
00:00:32,601 --> 00:00:33,877
非常奇怪的bug 
very strange looking bugs,

14
00:00:33,941 --> 00:00:36,524
如果你不熟悉所有复杂的
if you're not familiar with all of the intricacies of

15
00:00:36,562 --> 00:00:39,238
广播运作的方式
how broadcasting and how features like broadcasting work.

16
00:00:39,292 --> 00:00:42,159
比如 你想用列向量
For example, if you take a column vector 

17
00:00:42,213 --> 00:00:44,014
把它加到一个行向量
and add it to a row vector, 

18
00:00:44,072 --> 00:00:47,383
你可能会预计它会报错 说维度不匹配
you would expect it to throw up a dimension mismatch

19
00:00:47,417 --> 00:00:48,697
或者类型错误之类的
or type error or something.

20
00:00:48,741 --> 00:00:50,288
但你实际上会得到
But you might actually get

21
00:00:50,363 --> 00:00:53,687
一个行向量和列向量求和之后的矩阵
back a matrix as a sum of a row vector and a column vector.

22
00:00:53,741 --> 00:00:58,290
Python的这些奇怪的效果有其内在逻辑
So there is an internal logic to these strange effects of Python.

23
00:00:58,332 --> 00:00:59,948
但是如果你不熟悉Python
But if you're not familiar with Python,

24
00:00:59,995 --> 00:01:03,236
我看过有些学生写出很奇怪
I've seen some students have very strange,

25
00:01:03,289 --> 00:01:04,694
非常难调试的bug
very hard to find bugs.

26
00:01:04,763 --> 00:01:07,939
所以我想在这个视频里
So what I want to do in this video 

27
00:01:07,967 --> 00:01:09,882
跟你分享一些技巧
is share with you some couple tips and tricks

28
00:01:09,929 --> 00:01:11,760
对我来说非常有用
that have been very useful for me 

29
00:01:11,948 --> 00:01:14,492
可以排除 简化
to eliminate or simplify and eliminate

30
00:01:14,517 --> 00:01:17,171
或者说消灭我自己代码里各种奇奇怪怪的bug
all the strange looking bugs in my own code.

31
00:01:17,224 --> 00:01:18,992
我希望通过这些提示和技巧
And I hope that with these tips and tricks,

32
00:01:19,019 --> 00:01:22,666
你可以更容易写出无bug的
you'll also be able to much more easily write bug-free,

33
00:01:22,725 --> 00:01:24,343
python和numpy代码
python and numpy code.

34
00:01:25,184 --> 00:01:30,196
为了说明Python-Numpy不太直观的效果
To illustrate one of the less intuitive effects of Python-Numpy,

35
00:01:30,233 --> 00:01:33,101
尤其是在Python-Numpy中构建向量时的怪事
especially how you construct vectors in Python-Numpy,

36
00:01:33,160 --> 00:01:34,888
我很快展示一下
let me do a quick demo.

37
00:01:34,940 --> 00:01:40,630
我们令 a = np.random.randn(5)
Let's set a = np.Random.Randn 5,

38
00:01:42,355 --> 00:01:48,563
这就生成了5个随机高斯变量 储存数组a中
so this creates five random Gaussian variables stored in array a.

39
00:01:49,106 --> 00:01:56,246
我们print一下 看看a的形状是怎样的
And so let's print and now it turns out that the shape of a

40
00:01:56,651 --> 00:02:01,992
a.shape print出来是这种(5,)结构
when you do this is this five column structure.

41
00:02:02,884 --> 00:02:05,411
所以这是所谓的Python秩为1的数组
And so this is called a rank 1 array in Python 

42
00:02:05,463 --> 00:02:09,339
它既不是行向量也不是列向量
and it's neither a row vector nor a column vector.

43
00:02:09,402 --> 00:02:12,702
这导致它有一些略微不直观的效果
And this leads it to have some slightly non-intuitive effects.

44
00:02:12,745 --> 00:02:14,589
所以比如我把a转置print出来
So for example, if I print a transpose,

45
00:02:14,669 --> 00:02:17,389
看起来和a还是一样的
it ends up looking the same as a.

46
00:02:17,452 --> 00:02:19,689
所以a和a转置看起来还是一样的
So a and a transpose end up looking the same.

47
00:02:19,747 --> 00:02:24,297
如果我print一下a和a转置的内积
And if I print the inner product between a and a transpose,

48
00:02:24,338 --> 00:02:27,341
你可能觉得a乘以a转置
you might think a times a transpose is maybe

49
00:02:27,378 --> 00:02:29,919
或者说外积可能会得到一个矩阵
the outer product should give you matrix maybe.

50
00:02:29,965 --> 00:02:33,339
但如果我这么做的话 会得到一个数字
But if I do that, you instead get back a number.

51
00:02:33,977 --> 00:02:36,538
我建议
So what I would recommend is that

52
00:02:36,563 --> 00:02:38,595
当你编写神经网络程序时
when you're coding neural networks,

53
00:02:38,633 --> 00:02:40,825
你就不要用这种数据结构
that you just not use data structures

54
00:02:40,867 --> 00:02:45,720
其中形状是(5,)或(n,)这种秩为1的数组
where the shape is 5, or n, rank 1 array.

55
00:02:45,769 --> 00:02:53,971
相反如果你令a为这种5×1矩阵的话
Instead, if you set a to be this, 5 by 1,

56
00:02:54,040 --> 00:02:58,455
那么就可以令a变成5×1列向量
then this commits a to be a 5 by 1 column vector.

57
00:02:58,486 --> 00:03:01,744
而之前 a和a转置看起来是一样的
And whereas previously, a and a transpose looked the same,

58
00:03:01,781 --> 00:03:06,011
现在看看a转置 现在a转置就是一个行向量了
it becomes now a transpose, now a transpose is a row vector.

59
00:03:06,074 --> 00:03:07,874
注意一个微妙的区别
Notice one subtle difference.

60
00:03:07,932 --> 00:03:11,001
在这个数据结构中 有两个方括号
In this data structure, there are two square brackets

61
00:03:11,027 --> 00:03:12,161
当我们print a转置时
when we print a transpose.

62
00:03:12,224 --> 00:03:14,327
以前这里只有一个方括号
Whereas previously, there was one square bracket.

63
00:03:14,380 --> 00:03:18,833
所以这是区别 这是一个1×5矩阵
So that's the difference between this is really a 1 by 5 matrix

64
00:03:18,874 --> 00:03:23,024
而不是这些秩为1的数组
versus one of these rank 1 arrays.

65
00:03:23,098 --> 00:03:27,954
如果你print出来 比如说a和a转置的乘积
And if you print, say, the product between a and a transpose,

66
00:03:28,016 --> 00:03:32,568
这样应该会得到一个向量的外积 对吧?
then this gives you the outer product of a vector, right?

67
00:03:32,606 --> 00:03:35,118
所以 向量的外积可以得到一个矩阵
And so, the outer product of a vector gives you a matrix.

68
00:03:35,155 --> 00:03:39,349
现在我们仔细看看这里见到的东西
So, let's look in greater detail at what we just saw here.

69
00:03:40,071 --> 00:03:42,804
我们刚才跑的第一个命令 是这个
The first command that we ran, just now, was this.

70
00:03:43,353 --> 00:03:46,209
这创建了一个数据结构
And this created a data structure with 

71
00:03:46,655 --> 00:03:52,426
a.shape就是这个奇怪的5,
a.Shape was this funny thing was this funny thing 5 comma

72
00:03:52,484 --> 00:03:57,071
有时这叫秩为1的数组
so this is called a rank 1 array.

73
00:03:57,129 --> 00:03:58,759
这是一个非常有趣的数据结构
And this is a very funny data structure.

74
00:03:58,790 --> 00:04:00,399
它的行为和
It doesn't behave consistently

75
00:04:00,452 --> 00:04:03,577
行向量或列向量并不一样
as either a row vector nor a column vector,

76
00:04:03,630 --> 00:04:06,557
所以有些效果没那么直观
which makes some of its effects nonintuitive.

77
00:04:06,601 --> 00:04:09,180
那么我推荐的是
So what I'm going to recommend is that

78
00:04:09,212 --> 00:04:11,143
当你进行编程练习时
when you're doing your programing exercises,

79
00:04:11,201 --> 00:04:12,584
或者实现
or in fact when you're implementing 

80
00:04:12,616 --> 00:04:14,752
神经网络的logistic回归时
logistic regression on your neural networks

81
00:04:14,800 --> 00:04:19,648
你就不用这些秩为1的数组
that you just do not use these rank 1 arrays.

82
00:04:20,212 --> 00:04:23,888
相反 每次创建数组时
Instead, if every time you create an array,

83
00:04:23,946 --> 00:04:27,187
你要把它定义成列向量
you commit to making it either a column vector, 

84
00:04:27,266 --> 00:04:31,667
所以这创建一个5×1向量 或者把它变成一个行向量
so this creates a 5,1 vector, or commit to making it a row vector,

85
00:04:31,725 --> 00:04:35,754
那么你的向量的行为也许更容易理解一些
then the behavior of your vectors may be easier to understand.

86
00:04:36,407 --> 00:04:42,887
所以在这种情况下 a.shape就等于(5,1)
So in this case, a.Shape is going to be equal to 5,1.

87
00:04:42,935 --> 00:04:45,911
所以这个行为很像
And so this behaves a lot like a,

88
00:04:45,947 --> 00:04:47,833
但实际上这就是一个列向量
but in fact, this is a column vector.

89
00:04:47,891 --> 00:04:51,729
所以你可以将它看成是5×1矩阵
And that's why you can think of this as  5 by 1 matrix,

90
00:04:51,802 --> 00:04:53,040
它是一个列向量
where it's a column vector.

91
00:04:53,094 --> 00:04:57,238
而这里a.shape是1,5
And here a.Shape is going to be 1,5,

92
00:04:57,290 --> 00:05:00,909
然后这里的行为和行向量一致
and this behaves consistently as a row vector.

93
00:05:01,425 --> 00:05:03,244
所以当你需要一个向量时
So when you need a vector,

94
00:05:03,319 --> 00:05:05,586
我说就用这个和这个
I would say either use this or this, 

95
00:05:05,666 --> 00:05:07,491
但不要用秩为1的数组
but not a rank 1 array.

96
00:05:07,560 --> 00:05:10,046
还有一件事 如果我在代码中做了很多事情 
One more thing that I do a lot in my code

97
00:05:10,099 --> 00:05:11,794
所以如果我不太确定
is if I'm not entirely sure 

98
00:05:11,846 --> 00:05:14,517
一个向量具体的维度是多少
what's the dimension of one of my vectors,

99
00:05:15,275 --> 00:05:18,049
我会经常assert()这样一个声明
I'll often throw in an assertion statement like this,

100
00:05:18,097 --> 00:05:21,854
确保这是一个向量
to make sure, in this case, that this is a vector.

101
00:05:21,912 --> 00:05:23,128
所以这是一个列向量
So this is a column vector.

102
00:05:23,808 --> 00:05:26,978
这些assert()执行起来很快
These assertions are really inexpensive to execute, 

103
00:05:27,020 --> 00:05:30,333
它们也可以看成是代码的文档
and they also help to serve as documentation for your code.

104
00:05:30,375 --> 00:05:32,418
所以不要犹豫 
So don't hesitate to throw

105
00:05:32,465 --> 00:05:34,834
你觉得需要的时候 就使用assert()声明
in assertion statements like this whenever you feel like it.

106
00:05:34,902 --> 00:05:37,198
最后 如果由于某种原因
And then finally, if for some reason

107
00:05:37,252 --> 00:05:39,093
你得到了一个秩为1的数组
you do end up with a rank 1 array,

108
00:05:39,135 --> 00:05:41,458
你可以用reshape
You can reshape this, 

109
00:05:41,511 --> 00:05:48,615
a=a.reshape 转换成比如说一个5×1数组或1×5数组
a equals a.Reshape into say a 5 by 1 array or a 1 by 5 array 

110
00:05:48,657 --> 00:05:50,698
那么它的行为更好预测
so that it behaves more consistently

111
00:05:50,755 --> 00:05:53,150
就是列向量或行向量的行为
as either column vector or row vector.

112
00:05:53,576 --> 00:05:56,915
所以我有时候会看到学生很难调试一些错误
So I've sometimes seen students end up with very hard to track

113
00:05:56,960 --> 00:06:00,804
都来自秩为1数组的反直觉行为
because those are the nonintuitive effects of rank 1 arrays.

114
00:06:00,840 --> 00:06:03,476
通过消除代码中的秩为1的数组
By eliminating rank 1 arrays in my old code,

115
00:06:03,523 --> 00:06:05,627
我可以让代码变得更简单
I think my code became simpler.

116
00:06:05,674 --> 00:06:07,518
而我其实并没有 
And I did not actually

117
00:06:07,577 --> 00:06:10,476
觉得这样写代码限制太多
find it restrictive in terms of things I could express in code.

118
00:06:10,529 --> 00:06:12,155
我只是从来不会用秩为1的数组
I just never used a rank 1 array.

119
00:06:12,208 --> 00:06:15,650
所以重点在于 要简化你的代码
And so takeaways are to simplify your code,

120
00:06:15,708 --> 00:06:16,821
不要使用秩为1的数组
don't use rank 1 arrays.

121
00:06:16,869 --> 00:06:19,543
始终使用n×1矩阵
Always use either n by one matrices,

122
00:06:19,597 --> 00:06:21,292
基本上是列向量
basically column vectors,

123
00:06:21,341 --> 00:06:24,103
或1×n矩阵 基本上是行向量
or one by n matrices, or basically row vectors.

124
00:06:24,145 --> 00:06:26,443
随意插入assert()声明
Feel free to toss a lot of insertion statements, 

125
00:06:26,478 --> 00:06:29,220
要仔细检查你的矩阵和数组的维度
so double-check the dimensions of your matrices and arrays.

126
00:06:29,268 --> 00:06:33,173
不要害怕调用reshape
And also, don't be shy about calling the reshape operation

127
00:06:33,221 --> 00:06:36,364
来确保你的矩阵或向量
to make sure that your matrices or your vectors

128
00:06:36,426 --> 00:06:38,324
是你需要的维度
are the dimension that you need it to be.

129
00:06:38,752 --> 00:06:41,414
所以我希望这一套建议 
So that, I hope that this set of suggestions

130
00:06:41,482 --> 00:06:45,993
能帮助你消除Python代码中的错误
helps you to eliminate a cause of bugs from Python code,

131
00:06:46,077 --> 00:06:48,842
并使习题更容易完成
and makes the problem exercise easier for you to complete.

