1
00:00:00,676 --> 00:00:01,760
在前面几个视频中 
In the previous video

2
00:00:01,786 --> 00:00:04,617
你们看到如何向量化
you saw a few examples of how vectorization,

3
00:00:04,655 --> 00:00:08,458
如何使用内置函数 避免使用显示for循环
by using built in functions and by avoiding explicit for loops,

4
00:00:08,470 --> 00:00:10,922
可以让程序运行速度显著加快
allows you to speed up your code significantly.

5
00:00:10,947 --> 00:00:12,768
我们再来看几个例子
Let's look at a few more examples.

6
00:00:13,329 --> 00:00:15,742
要记住 经验法则是
The rule of thumb to keep in mind is,

7
00:00:15,779 --> 00:00:18,062
当你编写新的网络时
when you're programming your new networks,

8
00:00:18,084 --> 00:00:19,684
或者你做的只是回归
or when you're programming just a regression,

9
00:00:19,733 --> 00:00:23,151
那么一定要尽量避免for循环
whenever possible avoid explicit for-loops.

10
00:00:23,560 --> 00:00:27,124
能不用就不用
And it's not always possible to never use a for-loop,

11
00:00:27,188 --> 00:00:29,315
如果你可以使用一个内置函数
but when you can use a built in function

12
00:00:29,379 --> 00:00:32,314
或者找出其他办法去计算循环
or find some other way to compute whatever you need,

13
00:00:32,388 --> 00:00:36,402
通常会比直接用for循环更快
you'll often go faster than if you have an explicit for-loop.

14
00:00:36,439 --> 00:00:38,310
我们来看另一个例子
Let's look at another example.

15
00:00:38,337 --> 00:00:40,684
如果你想计算
If ever you want to compute

16
00:00:40,728 --> 00:00:44,502
一个向量u 作为矩阵A
a vector u as the product of the matrix A,

17
00:00:44,533 --> 00:00:49,730
和另一个向量v的乘积 矩阵乘法的定义就是
and another vector v, then the definition of our matrix multiply

18
00:00:49,762 --> 00:00:56,872
就是u_i等于 A_ij v_j 对j求和
is that your u_i is equal to sum over j, A_ij, v_j.

19
00:00:56,921 --> 00:00:58,445
这是u_i的定义
That's how you define u_i.

20
00:01:01,449 --> 00:01:01,456
所以这些计算的非向量表示
And so the non-vectorized implementation of this

21
00:01:03,851 --> 00:01:07,809
就是令u等于np.zeros(n,1)
would be to set u equals NP.Zeros, it would be n by 1.

22
00:01:07,836 --> 00:01:14,271
对i循环  对j循环
For I, and so on. For j, and so on..

23
00:01:14,302 --> 00:01:23,101
然后u[i]+=A[i][j]·v[j]
And then u[i]+=A[i][j]·v[j]

24
00:01:23,164 --> 00:01:27,369
现在 这是一个双重for循环 对指标i和j循环
So now, this is two for-loops, looping over both I and j.

25
00:01:27,391 --> 00:01:29,467
所以这是一个非向量化的版本
So, that's a non-vectorized version,

26
00:01:29,499 --> 00:01:37,507
这个向量化实现就是说u=np.dot(A,v)
the vectorized implementation which is to say u equals np dot (A,v)

27
00:01:37,544 --> 00:01:40,808
而在右边的实现 就是向量化版本
And the implementation on the right, the vectorized version,

28
00:01:40,861 --> 00:01:43,034
消除了两个不同的for循环
now eliminates two different for-loops,

29
00:01:43,066 --> 00:01:44,706
速度会更快
and it's going to be way faster.

30
00:01:44,747 --> 00:01:46,203
我们再看一个例子
Let's go through one more example.

31
00:01:46,256 --> 00:01:49,290
假设你内存里已经有一个向量v
Let's say you already have a vector, v, in memory

32
00:01:49,644 --> 00:01:53,563
如果你想做指数运算
and you want to apply the exponential operation

33
00:01:53,616 --> 00:01:56,112
作用到向量v的每个元素
on every element of this vector v.

34
00:01:56,161 --> 00:02:00,130
你可以令u等于那个向量 这是e^(v1)
So you can put u equals the vector, that's e to the v1,

35
00:02:00,177 --> 00:02:04,958
e^(v2) 一直到e^(vn)
e to the v2, and so on, down to e to the vn.

36
00:02:04,999 --> 00:02:08,074
所以这是一个非向量化的实现
So this would be a non-vectorized implementation,

37
00:02:08,093 --> 00:02:13,041
一开始你让u初始化成全0向量
which is at first you initialize u to the vector of zeros.

38
00:02:13,067 --> 00:02:14,502
然后你有一个for循环
And then you have a for-loop

39
00:02:14,530 --> 00:02:17,478
一次计算一个元素
that computes the elements one at a time.

40
00:02:17,509 --> 00:02:23,189
但事实上 python的numpy里面有很多内置函数
But it turns out that Python and NumPy have many built-in functions

41
00:02:23,214 --> 00:02:27,121
可以让你计算这些向量
that allow you to compute these vectors

42
00:02:27,572 --> 00:02:30,500
你只需要调用单个函数
with just a single call to a single function.

43
00:02:30,569 --> 00:02:39,941
所以我去实现的时候 会导入import numpy as np
So what I would do to implement this is import numpy as np,

44
00:02:40,381 --> 00:02:47,330
这样你就可以调用u=np.exp(v)
and then what you just call u = np dot Exp(v)

45
00:02:47,361 --> 00:02:48,767
要注意
And so, notice that,

46
00:02:48,803 --> 00:02:51,956
之前你有这个显式for循环
whereas previously you had that explicit for-loop,

47
00:02:51,998 --> 00:02:54,274
这里只需一行代码
with just one line of code here,

48
00:02:54,321 --> 00:02:58,569
v作为输入向量 u作为输出向量
just v as an input vector u as an output vector,

49
00:02:58,596 --> 00:03:01,031
你已经去掉了显式for循环
you've gotten rid of the explicit for-loop,

50
00:03:01,075 --> 00:03:03,850
右边的代码实现会快得多
and the implementation on the right will be much faster

51
00:03:03,907 --> 00:03:06,325
这需要一个显式的for循环
that the one needing an explicit for-loop.

52
00:03:06,362 --> 00:03:08,021
实际上 numpy库
In fact, the NumPy library

53
00:03:08,044 --> 00:03:10,372
有很多向量值函数
has many of the vector value functions.

54
00:03:10,397 --> 00:03:15,130
np.log会逐个元素计算log
So np.log will compute the element-wise log,

55
00:03:15,189 --> 00:03:18,852
np.Abs会计算绝对值
np.Abs computes the absolute value,

56
00:03:18,895 --> 00:03:25,097
np.maximum计算所有元素中的最大值
np.maximum computes the element-wise maximum

57
00:03:25,140 --> 00:03:29,233
求出v中所有元素和0之间相比的最大值
to take the max of every element of v with 0.

58
00:03:29,276 --> 00:03:36,760
v**2就是v中每个元素的平方
v**2 just takes the element-wise square of each element of v.

59
00:03:36,807 --> 00:03:42,787
1/v就是每个元素求倒数 等等
1/v takes the element-wise inverse, and so on.

60
00:03:42,818 --> 00:03:46,598
所以每当你想写一个for循环时
So, whenever you are tempted to write a for-loop take a look,

61
00:03:46,646 --> 00:03:49,502
应该看看可不可以调用numpy
and see if there's a way to call a NumPy

62
00:03:49,543 --> 00:03:52,210
用内置函数计算 而不是用for循环
built-in function to do it without that for-loop.

63
00:03:52,248 --> 00:03:55,624
所以我们看看学到的这些技巧 怎么运用到
So, let's take all of these learnings and apply it to

64
00:03:55,670 --> 00:03:59,147
logistic回归梯度下降算法实现中来
our logistic regression gradient descent implementation,

65
00:03:59,198 --> 00:04:02,519
看看是否可以去掉两个for循环中的一个
and see if we can at least get rid of one of the two for-loops we had.

66
00:04:02,570 --> 00:04:04,714
这是我们用来计算
So here's our code for computing

67
00:04:04,777 --> 00:04:07,836
logistic回归导数的程序
the derivatives for logistic regression,

68
00:04:07,895 --> 00:04:09,437
我们有两个for循环
and we had two for-loops.

69
00:04:09,495 --> 00:04:13,587
一个在上面这里 第二个是这里
One was this one up here, and the second one was this one.

70
00:04:13,609 --> 00:04:17,497
所以在我们的例子中 有n_x=2
So in our example we had nx equals 2,

71
00:04:17,534 --> 00:04:20,873
如果你的特征不止两个的话
but if you had more features than just 2 features

72
00:04:20,908 --> 00:04:25,760
你需要用for循环处理dw_1 dw_2 dw_3 等等
then you'd need have a for-loop over dw_1, dw_2, dw_3, and so on.

73
00:04:25,796 --> 00:04:30,617
所以这里其实有个for j=1 to n_x
So its as if there's actually a for j equals 1, to n_x.

74
00:04:30,648 --> 00:04:36,627
dw_j就更新了
dw_j gets updated.

75
00:04:37,299 --> 00:04:41,575
所以我想去掉这第二个for循环
So we'd like to eliminate this second for-loop.

76
00:04:41,597 --> 00:04:43,261
这就是我们上一张幻灯片做的
That's what we'll do on this slide.

77
00:04:43,785 --> 00:04:45,718
做法就是
So the way we'll do so is that

78
00:04:45,761 --> 00:04:51,735
这里我们不会显式地把dw_1 dw_2 等等初始化成0
instead of explicitly initializing dw_1, dw_2, and so on to zeros,

79
00:04:51,769 --> 00:04:58,232
我们要去掉这个循环 把dw变成一个向量
we're going to get rid of this and instead make dw a vector.

80
00:04:58,274 --> 00:05:04,052
我们令dw=np.Zeros
So we're going to set dw equals np.Zeros,

81
00:05:04,084 --> 00:05:10,632
然后我们把这个变成n_x×1维向量
and let's make this a nx by 1, dimensional vector.

82
00:05:10,658 --> 00:05:16,174
然后在这里我们不需要对单个分量用for循环 
Then, here, instead of this for loop over the individual components,

83
00:05:16,194 --> 00:05:18,359
我们用这个向量值操作
we'll just use this vector value operation,

84
00:05:18,381 --> 00:05:27,718
就是dw+=x^(i) dz^(i)
dw+=x^(i) dz^(i)

85
00:05:28,439 --> 00:05:31,649
最后 我们不用这个
And then finally, instead of this,

86
00:05:32,181 --> 00:05:38,511
我们就用dw/=m
we will just have dw divides equals m.

87
00:05:38,944 --> 00:05:42,666
现在我们从两个for循环化简成一个for循环
So now we've gone from having two for-loops to just one for-loop.

88
00:05:42,702 --> 00:05:44,704
我们这里还有一个for循环
We still have this one for-loop

89
00:05:44,763 --> 00:05:47,145
对单独的训练例子循环
that loops over the individual training examples.

90
00:05:49,284 --> 00:05:51,975
所以我希望本视频能给你向量化的概念
So I hope this video gave you a sense of vectorization.

91
00:05:52,027 --> 00:05:54,247
同时去掉一个for循环之后
And by getting rid of one for-loop

92
00:05:54,293 --> 00:05:56,126
你的代码运行速度会大大加快
your code will already run faster.

93
00:05:56,521 --> 00:05:58,467
事实证明我们还可以做得更好
But it turns out we could do even better.

94
00:05:58,498 --> 00:06:00,320
所以下一个视频将谈论
So the next video will talk about

95
00:06:00,362 --> 00:06:02,897
如何进一步向量化logistic回归
how to vectorize logistic regression even further.

96
00:06:02,944 --> 00:06:05,044
你会看到一个非常惊人的结果
And you see a pretty surprising result,

97
00:06:05,065 --> 00:06:07,294
就是没有任何for循环
that without using any for-loops,

98
00:06:07,336 --> 00:06:10,420
对所有训练样本不用任何for循环
without needing a for-loop over the training examples,

99
00:06:10,457 --> 00:06:14,714
你可以写代码一次处理整个训练集
you could write code to process the entire training sets.

100
00:06:14,755 --> 00:06:16,647
基本上同时处理
So, pretty much all at the same time.

101
00:06:17,091 --> 00:06:18,969
我们来看看下一个视频
So, let's see that in the next video.

