1
00:00:02,400 --> 00:00:07,575
We talked about how you want your learning algorithm to do well on the training set 
我们讨论过 你希望你的学习算法能在训练集上表现良好

2
00:00:07,576 --> 00:00:10,303
but sometimes you don't actually want to do too well
但有时你实际上并不想做得太好 

3
00:00:10,304 --> 00:00:12,765
and knowing what human level performance is,
你得知道人类水平的表现是怎样的

4
00:00:12,765 --> 00:00:15,070
can tell you exactly how well
可以确切告诉你 算法在训练集上的表现

5
00:00:15,070 --> 00:00:18,250
but not too well you want your algorithm to do on the training set.
到底应该有多好 或者有多不好

6
00:00:18,250 --> 00:00:19,392
Let me show you what I mean.
让我告诉你是什么意思吧

7
00:00:19,392 --> 00:00:24,320
We have used Cat classification a lot and giving a picture,
我们经常使用猫分类器来做例子

8
00:00:24,320 --> 00:00:32,195
let's say humans have near-perfect accuracy so the human level error is one percent.
比如人类具有近乎完美的准确度 所以人类水平的错误是百分之一

9
00:00:32,195 --> 00:00:36,695
In that case, if your learning algorithm achieves 8 percent training error
在这种情况下 如果您的学习算法达到8%的训练错误率

10
00:00:36,696 --> 00:00:38,915
and 10 percent dev error,
和10%的开发错误率

11
00:00:38,915 --> 00:00:44,500
then maybe you wanted to do better on the training set.
那么你也许想在训练集上得到更好的结果

12
00:00:44,500 --> 00:00:47,667
So the fact that there's a huge gap between 
所以事实上 你的算法在训练集上的表现

13
00:00:47,743 --> 00:00:50,162
how well your algorithm does on your training set
和人类水平的表现

14
00:00:50,215 --> 00:00:52,010
versus how humans do
有很大差距的话

15
00:00:52,010 --> 00:00:55,625
shows that your algorithm isn't even fitting the training set well.
说明你的算法对训练集的拟合并不好

16
00:00:55,625 --> 00:00:59,210
So in terms of tools to reduce bias or variance,
所以从减少偏差和方差的工具这个角度看

17
00:00:59,210 --> 00:01:03,835
in this case I would say focus on reducing bias.
在这种情况下 我会把重点放在减少偏差上

18
00:01:03,835 --> 00:01:09,410
So you want to do things like train a bigger neural network or run gradient descent longer,
你需要做的是 比如说训练更大的神经网络 或者跑久一点梯度下降

19
00:01:09,410 --> 00:01:12,003
just try to do better on the training set.
就试试能不能在训练集上做得更好

20
00:01:12,003 --> 00:01:15,774
But now let's look at the same training error and dev error
但现在我们看看同样的训练错误率和开发错误率

21
00:01:15,774 --> 00:01:19,340
and imagine that human level performance was not 1%.
假设人类的表现不是1% 

22
00:01:19,340 --> 00:01:20,640
So just copy this over 
我们就把它抄写过来

23
00:01:20,640 --> 00:01:25,170
but you know in a different application or maybe on a different data set,
但你知道 在不同的应用 或者说用在不同的数据集上

24
00:01:25,170 --> 00:01:30,180
let's say that human level error is actually 7.5%.
假设人类水平错误实际上是7.5%。

25
00:01:30,180 --> 00:01:33,890
Maybe the images in your data set are so blurry that even humans
也许你的数据集中的图像非常模糊 即使人类

26
00:01:33,890 --> 00:01:37,917
can't tell whether there's a cat in this picture.
都无法判断这张照片中有没有猫

27
00:01:37,917 --> 00:01:40,312
This example is maybe slightly contrived 
这个例子可能稍微更复杂一些

28
00:01:40,390 --> 00:01:42,752
because humans are actually very good at looking at pictures
因为人类其实很擅长看照片

29
00:01:42,753 --> 00:01:44,525
and telling if there's a cat in it or not.
分辨出照片里有没有猫

30
00:01:44,525 --> 00:01:46,490
But for the sake of this example,
但就为了举这个例子

31
00:01:46,490 --> 00:01:50,623
let's say your data sets images are so blurry or so low resolution
比如说你的数据集中的图像非常模糊 分辨率很低

32
00:01:50,673 --> 00:01:54,680
that even humans get 7.5% error.
即使人类错误率也达到7.5%

33
00:01:54,680 --> 00:01:56,720
In this case, even though
在这种情况下 即使

34
00:01:56,720 --> 00:02:00,305
your training error and dev error are the same as the other example,
你的训练错误率和开发错误率和其他例子里一样

35
00:02:00,305 --> 00:02:04,016
you see that maybe you're actually doing just fine on the training set.
你就知道 也许你的系统在训练集上的表现还好

36
00:02:04,016 --> 00:02:07,980
It's doing only a little bit worse than human level performance.
它只是比人类的表现差一点点

37
00:02:07,980 --> 00:02:10,010
And in this second example,
在第二个例子中

38
00:02:10,010 --> 00:02:14,295
you would maybe want to focus on reducing this component,
你可能希望专注减少这个分量

39
00:02:14,295 --> 00:02:19,390
reducing the variance in your learning algorithm.
减少学习算法的方差

40
00:02:19,390 --> 00:02:21,361
So you might try regularization to try to
也许你可以试试正则化

41
00:02:21,362 --> 00:02:25,600
bring your dev error closer to your training error for example.
让你的开发错误率更接近你的训练错误率

42
00:02:25,600 --> 00:02:30,338
So in the earlier courses discussion on bias and variance,
所以在之前的课程关于偏差和方差的讨论中

43
00:02:30,338 --> 00:02:36,900
we were mainly assuming that there were tasks where Bayes error is nearly zero.
我们主要假设 有一些任务的贝叶斯错误率几乎为0

44
00:02:36,900 --> 00:02:39,280
So to explain what just happened here,
所以要解释这里发生的事情

45
00:02:39,280 --> 00:02:42,150
for our Cat classification example,
看看这个猫分类器

46
00:02:42,150 --> 00:02:47,510
think of human level error as
用人类水平的错误率

47
00:02:47,510 --> 00:02:56,030
a proxy or as a estimate for Bayes error or for Bayes optimal error.
估计或代替贝叶斯错误率 或贝叶斯最优错误率

48
00:02:56,030 --> 00:02:58,660
And for computer vision tasks,
对于计算机视觉任务而言

49
00:02:58,660 --> 00:03:02,450
this is a pretty reasonable proxy because humans are actually very good at
这样替代相当合理 因为人类实际上是非常擅长

50
00:03:02,450 --> 00:03:08,750
computer vision and so whatever a human can do is maybe not too far from Bayes error.
计算机视觉任务的 所以人类能做到的水平 和贝叶斯错误率相差不远

51
00:03:08,750 --> 00:03:12,657
By definition, human level error is worse than Bayes error
根据定义 人类水平错误率比贝叶斯错误率高一点

52
00:03:12,658 --> 00:03:15,577
because nothing could be better than Bayes error
因为贝叶斯错误率是理论上限

53
00:03:15,578 --> 00:03:19,665
but human level error might not be too far from Bayes error.
但人类水平错误率离贝叶斯错误率不会太远

54
00:03:19,665 --> 00:03:25,145
So the surprising thing we saw here is that depending on what human level error is
所以这里比较意外的是 取决于人类水平错误率有多少

55
00:03:25,145 --> 00:03:31,214
or really this is really approximately Bayes error or so we assume it to be,
或者这真的就很接近贝叶斯错误率 所以我们假设它就是

56
00:03:31,214 --> 00:03:35,273
but depending on what we think is achievable,
但取决于我们认为什么样的水平是可以实现的

57
00:03:35,273 --> 00:03:40,970
with the same training error and dev error in these two cases,
在这两种情况下 具有同样的训练错误率和开发错误率

58
00:03:40,970 --> 00:03:47,510
we decided to focus on bias reduction tactics or on variance reduction tactics.
我们决定专注于减少偏差的策略 或者减少方差的策略

59
00:03:47,510 --> 00:03:50,817
And what happened is in the example on the left,
那么左边的例子发生了什么?

60
00:03:50,817 --> 00:03:57,158
8% training error is really high when you think you could get it down to 1%
8%的训练错误率真的很高 你认为你可以把它降到1%

61
00:03:57,158 --> 00:04:01,310
and so bias reduction tactics could help you do that.
那么减少偏差的手段可能有效

62
00:04:01,310 --> 00:04:02,885
Whereas in the example on the right,
而在右边的例子中

63
00:04:02,885 --> 00:04:07,140
if you think that Bayes error is 7.5%
如果你认为贝叶斯错误率是7.5%

64
00:04:07,140 --> 00:04:12,265
and here we're using human level error as an estimate or as a proxy for Bayes error,
这里我们使用人类水平错误率来替代贝叶斯错误率

65
00:04:12,265 --> 00:04:14,784
but you think that Bayes error is close to 7.5%
但是你认为贝叶斯错误率接近7.5%

66
00:04:14,847 --> 00:04:17,393
then you know there's not that much headroom for
你就知道没有太多改善的空间了

67
00:04:17,394 --> 00:04:20,195
reducing your training error further down.
不能继续减少你的训练错误率了

68
00:04:20,195 --> 00:04:23,350
You don't really want it to be that much better than 7.5% 
你也不会希望它比7.5%好得多

69
00:04:23,351 --> 00:04:26,304
because you could achieve that only by
因为这种目标只能通过

70
00:04:26,304 --> 00:04:29,780
maybe starting to offer further training so,
可能需要提供更进一步的训练

71
00:04:29,780 --> 00:04:32,910
and instead, there's much more room for improvement
而这边 就还有更多的改进空间

72
00:04:32,910 --> 00:04:37,801
in terms of taking this 2% gap and trying to reduce that 
可以将这个2%的差距缩小一点

73
00:04:37,802 --> 00:04:39,973
by using variance reduction techniques 
使用减少方差的手段应该可行

74
00:04:39,974 --> 00:04:43,370
such as regularization or maybe getting more training data.
比如正则化 或者收集更多的训练数据

75
00:04:44,390 --> 00:04:47,463
So to give these things a couple of names,
所以要给这些概念命名一下

76
00:04:47,463 --> 00:04:52,502
this is not widely used terminology but I found this useful terminology
这不是广泛使用的术语 但我觉得这么说

77
00:04:52,502 --> 00:04:54,075
and a useful way of thinking about it,
思考起来比较流畅

78
00:04:54,075 --> 00:04:57,371
which is I'm going to call the difference between
就是把这个差值 

79
00:04:57,372 --> 00:05:01,167
Bayes error or approximation of Bayes error and the training error 
贝叶斯错误率或者对贝叶斯错误率的估计 和训练错误率之间的差值

80
00:05:01,242 --> 00:05:05,670
to be the avoidable bias.
称为可避免偏差

81
00:05:07,389 --> 00:05:11,830
So what you want is maybe keep improving your training performance
你可能希望一直提高训练集表现

82
00:05:11,830 --> 00:05:13,414
until you get down to Bayes error 
直到你接近贝叶斯错误率

83
00:05:13,415 --> 00:05:16,565
but you don't actually want to do better than Bayes error.
但实际上你也不希望做到比贝叶斯错误率更好

84
00:05:16,565 --> 00:05:20,740
You can't actually do better than Bayes error unless you're overfitting.
这理论上是不可能超过贝叶斯错误率的 除非过拟合

85
00:05:20,740 --> 00:05:24,879
And this, the difference between your training area and the dev error,
而这个 训练错误率和开发错误率之前的差值

86
00:05:24,879 --> 00:05:29,775
there's a measure still of the variance problem of your algorithm.
就大概说明你的算法在方差问题上还有多少改善空间

87
00:05:29,775 --> 00:05:33,189
And the term avoidable bias acknowledges that 
可避免偏差这个词 说明了

88
00:05:33,303 --> 00:05:39,362
there's some bias or some minimum level of error that you just cannot get below
有一些别的偏差 或者错误率有个无法超越的最低水平

89
00:05:39,446 --> 00:05:42,975
which is that if Bayes error is 7.5%,
那就是说如果贝叶斯错误率是7.5%

90
00:05:42,975 --> 00:05:46,885
you don't actually want to get below that level of error.
你实际上并不想得到低于该级别的错误率

91
00:05:46,885 --> 00:05:50,650
So rather than saying that if you're training error is 8%,
所以你不会说你的训练错误率是8%

92
00:05:50,650 --> 00:05:53,427
then the 8% is a measure of bias in this example,
然后8%就衡量了例子中的偏差大小

93
00:05:53,427 --> 00:05:59,750
you're saying that the avoidable bias is maybe 0.5% 
你应该说 可避免偏差可能在0.5%左右

94
00:05:59,750 --> 00:06:02,884
or 0.5% is a measure of the avoidable bias
或者0.5%是可避免偏差的指标

95
00:06:02,885 --> 00:06:06,220
whereas 2% is a measure of the variance and
而这个2%是方差的指标

96
00:06:06,220 --> 00:06:11,958
so there's much more room in reducing this 2% than in reducing this 0.5%.
所以要减少这个2% 比减少这个0.5% 空间要大得多

97
00:06:11,958 --> 00:06:14,384
Whereas in contrast in the example on the left,
而在左边的例子中

98
00:06:14,384 --> 00:06:20,055
this 7% is a measure of the avoidable bias,
这7%衡量了可避免偏差大小

99
00:06:20,055 --> 00:06:24,275
whereas 2% is a measure of how much variance you have.
而2%衡量了方差大小

100
00:06:24,275 --> 00:06:25,960
And so in this example on the left,
所以在左边这个例子里

101
00:06:25,960 --> 00:06:31,789
there's much more potential in focusing on reducing that avoidable bias.
专注减少可避免偏差可能潜力更大

102
00:06:31,789 --> 00:06:33,310
So in this example,
所以在这个例子中

103
00:06:33,310 --> 00:06:35,845
understanding human level error,
当你理解人类水平错误率

104
00:06:35,845 --> 00:06:38,402
understanding your estimate of Bayes error really
理解你对贝叶斯错误率的估计

105
00:06:38,526 --> 00:06:42,420
causes you in different scenarios to focus on different tactics,
你就可以在不同的场景中专注于不同的策略

106
00:06:42,420 --> 00:06:45,970
whether bias avoidance tactics or variance avoidance tactics.
使用避免偏差策略还是避免方差策略

107
00:06:45,970 --> 00:06:50,234
There's quite a lot more nuance in how you factor in human level performance
在训练时如何考虑人类水平表现 来决定工作着力点

108
00:06:50,235 --> 00:06:53,800
into how you make decisions in choosing what to focus on.
具体怎么做还有更多微妙的细节

109
00:06:53,800 --> 00:06:55,170
Thus in the next video, 
所以在下一个视频中

110
00:06:55,171 --> 00:06:58,994
go deeper into understanding of what human level performance really mean.
我们会深入了解人类水平表现的真正意义

