1
00:00:00,000 --> 00:00:03,312
It's not always easy to combine all the things you care about
要把你顾及到的所有事情

2
00:00:03,313 --> 00:00:06,265
into a single real number evaluation metric.
组合成单实数评估指标 有时并不容易

3
00:00:06,265 --> 00:00:09,150
In those cases I've found it sometimes useful to set up
在那些情况里 我发现有时候设立

4
00:00:09,150 --> 00:00:12,390
satisficing as well as optimizing metrics.
满足和优化指标是很重有用的

5
00:00:12,390 --> 00:00:13,950
Let me show you what I mean.
让我告诉你是什么意思吧

6
00:00:13,950 --> 00:00:16,410
Let's say that you've decided you care about
假设你已经决定你很看重

7
00:00:16,410 --> 00:00:20,694
the classification accuracy of your cat's classifier,
猫分类器的分类准确度

8
00:00:20,694 --> 00:00:25,470
this could have been F1 score or some other measure of accuracy,
这可以是F1分数 或者用其他衡量准确度的指标

9
00:00:25,470 --> 00:00:29,610
but let's say that in addition to accuracy you also care about the running time.
但除了准确度之外 我们还需要考虑运行时间

10
00:00:29,610 --> 00:00:32,430
So how long it takes to classify an image 
就是需要多长时间来分类一张图

11
00:00:32,431 --> 00:00:35,050
and classifier A takes 80 milliseconds,
分类器A需要80毫秒

12
00:00:35,050 --> 00:00:36,690
B takes 95 milliseconds,
B需要95毫秒

13
00:00:36,690 --> 00:00:39,325
and C takes 1,500 milliseconds,
C需要1500毫秒

14
00:00:39,325 --> 00:00:42,150
that's 1.5 seconds to classify an image.
就是说需要1.5秒来分类图像

15
00:00:42,150 --> 00:00:45,000
So one thing you could do is combine accuracy
你可以这么做 将准确度

16
00:00:45,000 --> 00:00:48,075
and running time into an overall evaluation metric.
和运行时间组合成一个整体评估指标

17
00:00:48,075 --> 00:00:57,898
And so the costs such as maybe the overall cost is accuracy minus 0.5 times running time.
所以成本 比如说 总体成本是准确度减去0.5乘以运行时间

18
00:00:57,898 --> 00:01:01,460
But maybe it seems a bit artificial to combine
这种组合方式可能太刻意

19
00:01:01,460 --> 00:01:05,265
accuracy and running time using a formula like this,
只用这样的公式来组合准确度和运行时间

20
00:01:05,265 --> 00:01:08,805
like a linear weighted sum of these two things.
两个数值的线性加权求和

21
00:01:08,805 --> 00:01:10,751
So here's something else you could do instead 
你还可以做其他事情

22
00:01:10,752 --> 00:01:13,841
which is that you might want to choose a classifier
就是你可能选择一个分类器

23
00:01:13,841 --> 00:01:26,470
that maximizes accuracy but subject to, that the running time,
能够最大限度提高准确度 但必须满足运行时间要求

24
00:01:26,470 --> 00:01:28,584
that is the time it takes to classify an image,
就是对图像进行分类所需的时间

25
00:01:28,584 --> 00:01:36,325
that that has to be less than or equal to 100 milliseconds.
必须小于等于100毫秒

26
00:01:36,325 --> 00:01:41,472
So in this case we would say that accuracy is an optimizing metric
所以在这种情况下 我们就说准确度是一个优化指标

27
00:01:41,473 --> 00:01:44,460
because you want to maximize accuracy.
因为你想要准确度最大化

28
00:01:44,460 --> 00:01:47,896
You want to do as well as possible on accuracy
你想做的尽可能准确

29
00:01:47,897 --> 00:01:53,845
but that running time is what we call a satisficing metric.
但是运行时间 就是我们所说的满足指标

30
00:01:53,845 --> 00:01:55,580
Meaning that it just has to be good enough,
意思是它必须足够好

31
00:01:55,580 --> 00:01:57,618
it just needs to be less than 100 milliseconds
它只需要小于100毫秒

32
00:01:57,618 --> 00:02:00,285
and beyond that you don't really care,
达到之后 你不在乎这指标有多好

33
00:02:00,879 --> 00:02:04,280
or at least you don't care that much.
或者至少你不会那么在乎

34
00:02:04,280 --> 00:02:06,895
So this will be a pretty reasonable way to trade off 
所以这是一个相当合理的权衡方式

35
00:02:06,896 --> 00:02:11,705
or to put together accuracy as well as running time.
或者说将准确度和运行时间结合起来的方式

36
00:02:11,705 --> 00:02:16,015
And it may be the case that so long as the running time is less that 100 milliseconds,
实际情况可能是 只要运行时间少于100毫秒

37
00:02:16,015 --> 00:02:17,741
your users won't care that much
你的用户就不会在乎

38
00:02:17,742 --> 00:02:21,855
whether it's 100 milliseconds or 50 milliseconds or even faster.
运行时间是100毫秒还是50毫秒 甚至更快

39
00:02:21,855 --> 00:02:26,380
And by defining optimizing as well as satisficing metrics,
通过定义优化和满足指标

40
00:02:26,380 --> 00:02:30,475
this gives you a clear way to pick the, quote, best classifier,
就可以给你提供一个明确的方式 去选择“最好的”分类器

41
00:02:30,475 --> 00:02:33,127
which in this case would be classifier B
在这种情况下 分类器B最好

42
00:02:33,127 --> 00:02:37,444
because of all the ones with a running time better than 100 milliseconds
因为在所有的运行时间都小于100毫秒的分类器中

43
00:02:37,444 --> 00:02:39,865
it has the best accuracy.
它的准确度最好

44
00:02:39,865 --> 00:02:45,626
So more generally, if you have N metrics that you care about
所以更一般地说 如果你要考虑N个指标

45
00:02:45,627 --> 00:02:50,830
it's sometimes reasonable to pick one of them to be optimizing.
有时候选择其中一个指标做为优化指标是合理的

46
00:02:50,830 --> 00:02:54,005
So you want to do as well as is possible on that one.
所以你想尽量优化那个指标

47
00:02:54,005 --> 00:02:57,515
And then N minus 1 to be satisficing,
然后剩下N-1个指标都是满足指标

48
00:02:57,515 --> 00:03:00,141
meaning that so long as they reach some threshold
意味着只要它们达到一定阈值

49
00:03:00,142 --> 00:03:02,730
such as running times faster than 100 milliseconds,
例如运行时间快于100毫秒

50
00:03:02,730 --> 00:03:04,405
but so long as they reach some threshold,
但只要达到一定的阈值

51
00:03:04,405 --> 00:03:07,012
you don't care how much better it is in that threshold,
你不在乎它超过那个门槛之后的表现

52
00:03:07,012 --> 00:03:09,455
but they have to reach that threshold.
但它们必须达到这个门槛

53
00:03:09,455 --> 00:03:11,350
Here's another example.
这里是另一个例子

54
00:03:11,350 --> 00:03:15,280
Let's say you're building a system to detect wake words,
假设你正在构建一个系统来检测唤醒语

55
00:03:15,280 --> 00:03:19,030
also called trigger words.
也叫触发词

56
00:03:19,030 --> 00:03:22,900
So this refers to the voice control devices like
这指的是语音控制设备

57
00:03:22,900 --> 00:03:26,611
the Amazon Echo where you wake up by saying Alexa
比如亚马逊Echo 你会说Alexa

58
00:03:26,611 --> 00:03:30,690
or some Google devices which you wake up by saying okay Google
或者用Okay Google来唤醒谷歌设备

59
00:03:30,691 --> 00:03:35,095
or some Apple devices which you wake up by saying Hey Siri
或者对于苹果设备 你会说Hey Siri

60
00:03:35,095 --> 00:03:42,300
or some Baidu devices we should wake up by saying you ni hao Baidu.
或者对于某些百度设备 我们用你好百度唤醒

61
00:03:42,300 --> 00:03:48,037
Oh I guess, you want to read the Chinese, that's ni hao Baidu.
如果你想知道中文怎么写的话 就是你好百度

62
00:03:48,037 --> 00:03:51,560
Right, so these are the wake words you use to
对的 这些就是唤醒词

63
00:03:51,560 --> 00:03:54,350
tell one of these voice control devices
可以唤醒这些语音控制设备

64
00:03:54,350 --> 00:03:56,990
to wake up and listen to something you want to say.
然后监听你想说的话

65
00:03:56,990 --> 00:04:02,090
And for these other Chinese characters for ni hao Baidu.
这些是你好百度的汉字

66
00:04:02,090 --> 00:04:07,935
So you might care about the accuracy of your trigger word detection system.
所以你可能会在乎触发字检测系统的准确性

67
00:04:07,935 --> 00:04:10,325
So when someone says one of these trigger words,
所以当有人说出其中一个触发词时

68
00:04:10,325 --> 00:04:13,525
how likely are you to actually wake up your device,
有多大概率可以唤醒你的设备

69
00:04:13,525 --> 00:04:16,970
and you might also care about the number of false positives.
你可能也需要顾及假阳性的数量

70
00:04:16,970 --> 00:04:19,891
So when no one actually said this trigger word,
就是没有人在说这个触发词时

71
00:04:19,891 --> 00:04:23,294
how often does it randomly wake up?
它被随机唤醒的概率有多大?

72
00:04:23,294 --> 00:04:27,770
So in this case maybe one reasonable way of
所以这种情况下 组合这两种评估指标的合理方式

73
00:04:27,770 --> 00:04:33,275
combining these two evaluation metrics might be to maximize accuracy,
可能是最大化精确度

74
00:04:33,275 --> 00:04:35,165
so when someone says one of the trigger words,
所以当某人说出唤醒词时

75
00:04:35,165 --> 00:04:37,565
maximize the chance that your device wakes up.
你的设备被唤醒的概率最大化

76
00:04:37,565 --> 00:04:39,215
And subject to that,
然后必须满足

77
00:04:39,215 --> 00:04:51,070
you have at most one false positive every 24 hours of operation, right?
24小时内最多只能有1次假阳性 对吧?

78
00:04:51,070 --> 00:04:54,868
So that your device randomly wakes up only once per day on average
所以你的设备平均每天只会

79
00:04:54,869 --> 00:04:57,270
when no one is actually talking to it.
没有人真的在说话时随机唤醒一次

80
00:04:57,270 --> 00:05:02,123
So in this case accuracy is the optimizing metric
所以在这种情况下 准确度是优化指标

81
00:05:02,124 --> 00:05:05,505
and a number of false positives every 24 hours
然后每24小时发生一次假阳性

82
00:05:05,505 --> 00:05:09,479
is the satisficing metric where you'd be satisfied so long as
是满足指标 你只要

83
00:05:09,480 --> 00:05:14,490
there is at most one false positive every 24 hours.
每24小时最多有一次假阳性 就满足了

84
00:05:14,490 --> 00:05:17,387
To summarize, if there are multiple things you care about
总结一下 如果你需要顾及多个指标

85
00:05:17,388 --> 00:05:19,920
by say there's one as the optimizing metric
比如说 有一个优化指标

86
00:05:19,920 --> 00:05:21,988
that you want to do as well as possible on
你想尽可能优化的

87
00:05:21,989 --> 00:05:25,475
and one or more as satisficing metrics were you'll be satisfice.
然后还有一个或多个满足指标 需要满足的

88
00:05:25,475 --> 00:05:28,338
Almost it does better than some threshold 
需要达到一定的门槛

89
00:05:28,339 --> 00:05:32,310
you can now have an almost automatic way of quickly
现在你就有一个全自动的方法

90
00:05:32,310 --> 00:05:35,864
looking at multiple cost size and picking the, quote, best one.
在观察多个成本大小时 选出"最好的"那个

91
00:05:35,864 --> 00:05:39,000
Now these evaluation metrics must be
现在这些评估指标必须是

92
00:05:39,000 --> 00:05:44,095
evaluated or calculated on a training set or a development set or maybe on the test set.
在训练集或开发集或测试集上计算或求出来的

93
00:05:44,095 --> 00:05:46,935
So one of the things you also need to do is set up training,
所以你还需要做一件事 就是设立训练集

94
00:05:46,935 --> 00:05:50,100
dev or development, as well as test sets.
开发集 还有测试集

95
00:05:50,100 --> 00:05:52,800
In the next video, I want to share with you some guidelines for
在下一个视频里 我想和大家分享一些

96
00:05:52,800 --> 00:05:55,800
how to set up training, dev, and test sets.
如何设置训练 开发和测试集的指导方针

97
00:05:55,800 --> 00:05:57,470
So let's go on to the next.  
我们下一个视频继续

