1
00:00:00,000 --> 00:00:03,505
You've seen how sets of dev set and evaluation metric
你已经学过如何设置开发集和评估指标

2
00:00:03,505 --> 00:00:07,170
is like placing a target somewhere for your team to aim at.
就像是把目标定在某个位置 让你的团队瞄准

3
00:00:07,170 --> 00:00:08,933
But sometimes partway through a project 
但有时候在项目进行途中

4
00:00:08,934 --> 00:00:12,040
you might realize you put your target in the wrong place.
你可能意识到 目标的位置放错了

5
00:00:12,040 --> 00:00:14,365
In that case you should move your target.
这种情况下 你应该移动你的目标

6
00:00:14,365 --> 00:00:16,156
Let's take a look at an example.
我们来看一个例子

7
00:00:16,156 --> 00:00:20,355
Let's say you build a cat classifier to try to find lots of pictures of cats 
假设你在构建一个猫分类器 试图找到很多猫的照片

8
00:00:20,409 --> 00:00:22,603
to show to your cat loving users
向你的爱猫人士用户展示

9
00:00:22,604 --> 00:00:26,850
and the metric that you decided to use is classification error.
你决定使用的指标是分类错误率

10
00:00:26,850 --> 00:00:29,655
So algorithms A and B have, respectively,
所以算法A和B分别有 

11
00:00:29,655 --> 00:00:32,025
3 percent error and 5 percent error,
3％错误率和5％错误率

12
00:00:32,025 --> 00:00:34,955
so it seems like Algorithm A is doing better.
所以算法A似乎做得更好

13
00:00:34,955 --> 00:00:38,286
But let's say you try out these algorithms, you look at these algorithms 
但我们实际试一下这些算法 你观察一下这些算法

14
00:00:38,383 --> 00:00:43,760
and Algorithm A, for some reason, is letting through a lot of the pornographic images.
算法A 由于某些原因 把很多色情图像分类成猫了

15
00:00:43,760 --> 00:00:46,985
So if you ship Algorithm A the users would
如果你部署算法A 那么用户就会

16
00:00:46,985 --> 00:00:51,185
see more cat images because you'll see 3 percent error and identify cats,
看到更多猫图 因为它识别猫的错误率只有3%

17
00:00:51,185 --> 00:00:53,280
but it also shows the users
但它同时也会给用户推送

18
00:00:53,280 --> 00:00:57,465
some pornographic images which is totally unacceptable both for your company,
一些色情图像 这是你的公司完全不能接受的

19
00:00:57,465 --> 00:00:59,455
as well as for your users.
你的用户也完全不能接受

20
00:00:59,455 --> 00:01:05,452
In contrast, Algorithm B has 5 percent error so this classifies fewer images
相比之下 算法B有5％的错误率 这样分类器就得到较少的图像

21
00:01:05,453 --> 00:01:08,720
but it doesn't have pornographic images.
但它不会推送色情图像

22
00:01:08,720 --> 00:01:10,845
So from your company's point of view,
所以从你们公司的角度来看

23
00:01:10,845 --> 00:01:13,530
as well as from a user acceptance point of view,
以及从用户接受的角度来看

24
00:01:13,530 --> 00:01:15,920
Algorithm B is actually a much better algorithm
算法B实际上是一个更好的算法 

25
00:01:15,920 --> 00:01:19,305
because it's not letting through any pornographic images.
因为它不让任何色情图像通过

26
00:01:19,305 --> 00:01:22,165
So, what has happened in this example is that Algorithm A
那么在这个例子中 发生的事情就是 算法A

27
00:01:22,165 --> 00:01:25,590
is doing better on evaluation metric.
在评估指标上做得更好

28
00:01:25,590 --> 00:01:29,990
It's getting 3 percent error but it is actually a worse algorithm.
它的错误率达到3% 但实际上是个更糟糕的算法

29
00:01:29,990 --> 00:01:34,194
In this case, the evaluation metric plus the dev set
在这种情况下 评估指标加上开发集

30
00:01:34,195 --> 00:01:38,460
it prefers Algorithm A because they're saying, look,
它们都倾向于选择算法A 因为它们会说 看

31
00:01:38,460 --> 00:01:41,483
Algorithm A has lower error which is the metric you're using 
算法A的错误率较低 这是你们自己定下来的指标评估出来的

32
00:01:41,559 --> 00:01:48,066
but you and your users prefer Algorithm B
但你和你的用户更倾向于使用算法B

33
00:01:48,066 --> 00:01:51,010
because it's not letting through pornographic images.
因为它不会将色情图像分类为猫

34
00:01:51,010 --> 00:01:52,780
So when this happens,
所以当这种情况发生时

35
00:01:52,780 --> 00:01:55,785
when your evaluation metric is no longer
当你的评估指标

36
00:01:55,785 --> 00:01:59,530
correctly rank ordering preferences between algorithms,
无法正确衡量算法之间的优劣排序时

37
00:01:59,530 --> 00:02:04,020
in this case is mispredicting that Algorithm A is a better algorithm,
在这种情况下 原来的指标错误地预测算法A是更好的算法

38
00:02:04,020 --> 00:02:07,787
then that's a sign that you should change your evaluation metric
这就发出了信号 你应该改变评估指标了

39
00:02:07,787 --> 00:02:13,500
or perhaps your development set or test set.
或者要改变开发集或测试集

40
00:02:13,500 --> 00:02:17,872
In this case the misclassification error metric that you're using
在这种情况下 你用的分类错误率指标

41
00:02:17,873 --> 00:02:20,340
can be written as follows: this one over m,
可以写成这样 1除以m

42
00:02:20,340 --> 00:02:23,870
a number of examples in your development set,
m是你的开发集样本数

43
00:02:23,870 --> 00:02:30,698
of sum from i equals 1 to mdev,
从i=1到m dev求和

44
00:02:30,698 --> 00:02:35,027
number of examples in this development set  of indicator of
开发集中的样本数 还有指示器I

45
00:02:35,027 --> 00:02:40,900
whether or not the prediction on example i in your development set
开发集样本y^(i)的预测 

46
00:02:40,900 --> 00:02:44,995
is not equal to the actual label i,
不符合实际标签i时的指示器

47
00:02:44,995 --> 00:02:50,390
where they use this notation to denote their predicted value.
他们用这些符号来表示预测值

48
00:02:50,390 --> 00:02:51,990
Right. So these are zero.
对 所以这些都是0

49
00:02:51,990 --> 00:02:54,795
And this indicates a function notation,
这符号表示一个函数

50
00:02:54,795 --> 00:03:00,595
counts up the number of examples on which this thing inside it's true.
统计出 里面这个表达式为真的样本数

51
00:03:00,595 --> 00:03:06,533
So this formula just counts up the number of misclassified examples.
所以这个公式就统计了分类错误的样本

52
00:03:06,533 --> 00:03:09,360
The problem with this evaluation metric is that they treat
这个评估指标的问题在于

53
00:03:09,360 --> 00:03:13,957
pornographic and non-pornographic images equally
它对色情图片和非色情图片一视同仁

54
00:03:13,957 --> 00:03:18,750
but you really want your classifier to not mislabel pornographic images,
但你其实真的希望 你的分类器不会错误标记色情图像

55
00:03:18,750 --> 00:03:21,470
like maybe you recognize a pornographic image as cat image and
比如说把一张色情图片分类为猫

56
00:03:21,470 --> 00:03:24,605
therefore show it to unsuspecting user,
然后推送给不知情的用户

57
00:03:24,605 --> 00:03:31,727
therefore very unhappy with unexpectedly seeing porn.
他们看到色情图片会非常不满

58
00:03:31,727 --> 00:03:38,590
One way to change this evaluation metric would be if you add the weight term here,
其中一个修改评估指标的方法是 这里加个权重项

59
00:03:38,590 --> 00:03:52,069
we call this w(i) where w(i) is going to be equal to 1 if x(i) is non-porn
我们将这个称为w(i) 其中如果图片x(i)不是色情图片 w(i)=1

60
00:03:52,069 --> 00:04:00,925
and maybe 10 or maybe even large number like a 100 if x(i) is porn.
如果x(i)是色情图片 w(i)可能就是10 甚至100

61
00:04:01,979 --> 00:04:05,095
So this way you're giving a much larger weight
这样你赋予了色情图片更大的权重

62
00:04:05,095 --> 00:04:09,848
to examples that are pornographic so that the error term goes up much more
让算法将色情图分类为猫图时

63
00:04:09,849 --> 00:04:16,931
if the algorithm makes a mistake on classifying a pornographic image as a cat image.
错误率这个项快速变大

64
00:04:16,931 --> 00:04:19,390
In this example you giving
这个例子里 

65
00:04:19,390 --> 00:04:25,355
10 times bigger weights to classify pornographic images correctly.
你把色情图片分类成猫这一错误的惩罚权重加大10倍

66
00:04:25,355 --> 00:04:27,465
If you want this normalization constant,
如果你希望得到归一化常数

67
00:04:27,465 --> 00:04:32,042
technically this becomes sum over i of w(i),
在技​​术上 就是w(i)对所有i求和

68
00:04:32,042 --> 00:04:35,633
so then this error would still be between zero and one.
这样错误率仍然在0和1之间

69
00:04:35,633 --> 00:04:40,630
The details of this weighting aren't important and actually to implement this weighting,
加权的细节并不重要 实际上要使用这种加权

70
00:04:40,630 --> 00:04:43,690
you need to actually go through your dev and test sets,
你必须自己过一遍开发集和测试集

71
00:04:43,690 --> 00:04:47,415
so label the pornographic images
在开发集和测试集里

72
00:04:47,415 --> 00:04:50,960
in your dev and test sets so you can implement this weighting function.
自己把色情图片标记出来 这样你才能使用这个加权函数

73
00:04:50,960 --> 00:04:53,095
But the high level of take away is,
但粗略的结论是

74
00:04:53,095 --> 00:04:56,965
if you find that evaluation metric is not giving
如果你的评估指标

75
00:04:56,965 --> 00:05:01,405
the correct rank order preference for what is actually better algorithm,
无法正确评估好算法的排名

76
00:05:01,405 --> 00:05:06,880
then there's a time to think about defining a new evaluation metric.
那么就需要花时间定义一个新的评估指标

77
00:05:06,880 --> 00:05:12,200
And this is just one possible way that you could define an evaluation metric.
这是定义评估指标的其中一种可能方式

78
00:05:12,200 --> 00:05:15,220
The goal of the evaluation metric is accurately tell you,
评估指标的意义在于 准确告诉你

79
00:05:15,220 --> 00:05:20,154
given two classifiers, which one is better for your application.
已知两个分类器 哪一个更适合你的应用

80
00:05:20,154 --> 00:05:21,650
For the purpose of this video,
就这个视频的内容而言

81
00:05:21,650 --> 00:05:25,863
don't worry too much about the details of how we define a new error metric,
我们不需要太注重新错误率指标是怎么定义的

82
00:05:25,863 --> 00:05:29,255
the point is that if you're not satisfied with your old error metric
关键在于 如果你对旧的错误率指标不满意

83
00:05:29,255 --> 00:05:33,050
then don't keep coasting with an error metric you're unsatisfied with,
那就不要一直沿用你不满意的错误率指标

84
00:05:33,050 --> 00:05:36,260
instead try to define a new one that you think better captures
而应该尝试定义一个新的指标 能够更加

85
00:05:36,260 --> 00:05:39,659
your preferences in terms of what's actually a better algorithm.
符合你的偏好 定义出实际更适合的算法

86
00:05:39,659 --> 00:05:42,890
One thing you might notice is that so far we've only talked about
你可能注意到了 到目前为止 我们只讨论了

87
00:05:42,890 --> 00:05:46,255
how to define a metric to evaluate classifiers.
如何定义一个指标去评估分类器

88
00:05:46,255 --> 00:05:50,450
That is, we've defined an evaluation metric that helps us
也就是说 我们定义了一个评估指标 帮助我们

89
00:05:50,450 --> 00:05:53,780
better rank order classifiers when
更好的把分类器排序

90
00:05:53,780 --> 00:05:57,887
they are performing at varying levels in terms of streaming of porn.
能够区分出它们在识别色情图片的不同水平

91
00:05:57,887 --> 00:06:01,505
And this is actually an example of an orthogonalization where
这实际上是一个正交化的例子 

92
00:06:01,505 --> 00:06:05,480
I think you should take a machine learning problem and break it into distinct steps.
我想你处理机器学习问题时 应该把它切分成独立的步骤

93
00:06:05,480 --> 00:06:14,525
One step is to figure out how to define a metric that captures what you want to do,
一步是弄清楚 如何定义一个指标来衡量你想做的事情的表现

94
00:06:14,525 --> 00:06:21,677
and I would worry separately about how to actually do well on this metric.
然后我们可以分开考虑如何改善系统在这个指标上的表现

95
00:06:21,677 --> 00:06:26,480
So think of the machine learning task as two distinct steps.
你们要把机器学习任务看成两个独立的步骤

96
00:06:26,480 --> 00:06:28,145
To use the target analogy,
用目标这个比喻

97
00:06:28,145 --> 00:06:32,890
the first step is to place the target.
第一步就是设定目标

98
00:06:32,890 --> 00:06:37,777
So define where you want to aim and then as a completely separate step,
所以要定义你要瞄准的目标 这是完全独立的一步

99
00:06:37,777 --> 00:06:39,409
this is one knob you can tune 
这是你可以调节的一个旋钮

100
00:06:39,451 --> 00:06:44,005
which is how do you place the target as a completely separate problem.
如何设立目标是一个完全独立的问题

101
00:06:44,005 --> 00:06:48,854
Think of it as a separate knob to tune in terms of how to do well at this algorithm,
把它看成是一个单独的旋钮 可以调试算法表现的旋钮

102
00:06:48,854 --> 00:06:58,888
how to aim accurately or how to shoot at the target.
如何精确瞄准 如何命中目标

103
00:07:01,087 --> 00:07:06,200
Defining the metric is step one and you do something else for step two.
定义指标是第一步 然后第二步要做别的事情

104
00:07:06,200 --> 00:07:08,140
In terms of shooting at the target,
在逼近目标的时候

105
00:07:08,140 --> 00:07:11,910
maybe your learning algorithm is optimizing some cost function that looks like this,
也许你的学习算法针对某个长这样的成本函数优化

106
00:07:13,473 --> 00:07:21,907
where you are minimizing sum of losses on your training set.
你要最小化训练集上的损失

107
00:07:21,907 --> 00:07:26,181
One thing you could do is to also modify this
你可以做的其中一件事是 修改这个

108
00:07:26,238 --> 00:07:28,160
in order to incorporate these weights
为了引入这些权重

109
00:07:28,160 --> 00:07:31,070
and maybe end up changing this normalization constant as well.
也许最后需要修改这个归一化常数

110
00:07:31,070 --> 00:07:34,240
So it just 1 over a sum of w(i).
所以这是1除以对w(i)的求和

111
00:07:34,240 --> 00:07:36,990
Again, the details of how you define J aren't important,
再次 如何定义J并不重要

112
00:07:36,990 --> 00:07:40,262
but the point was with the philosophy of orthogonalization
关键在于正交化的思路

113
00:07:40,263 --> 00:07:42,632
think of placing the target as one step
把设立目标定为第一步

114
00:07:42,633 --> 00:07:48,456
and aiming and shooting at a target as a distinct step which you do separately.
然后瞄准和射击目标是独立的第二步

115
00:07:48,456 --> 00:07:49,975
In other words I encourage you to think of,
换种说法 我鼓励你们

116
00:07:49,975 --> 00:07:55,225
defining the metric as one step and only after you define a metric,
将定义指标看成一步 然后在定义了指标之后

117
00:07:55,225 --> 00:07:57,640
figure out how to do well on that metric which might be
你才能想如何优化系统来提高这个指标评分

118
00:07:57,640 --> 00:08:00,745
changing the cost function J that your neural network is optimizing.
比如改变你神经网络要优化的成本函数J

119
00:08:00,745 --> 00:08:03,675
Before going on, let's look at just one more example.
在继续之前 我们再讲一个例子

120
00:08:03,675 --> 00:08:08,135
Let's say that your two cat classifiers A and B have, respectively,
假设你的两个猫分类器A和B 分别有

121
00:08:08,135 --> 00:08:13,300
3 percent error and 5 percent error as evaluated on your dev set.
用开发集评估得到3%的错误率 和5%的错误率

122
00:08:13,300 --> 00:08:17,725
Or maybe even on your test set which are images downloaded off the internet,
或者甚至用在网上下载的图片构成的测试集上

123
00:08:17,725 --> 00:08:19,615
so high quality well framed images.
这些是高质量 取景框很专业的图像

124
00:08:19,615 --> 00:08:21,760
But maybe when you deploy your algorithm product,
但也许你在部署算法产品时

125
00:08:21,760 --> 00:08:24,895
you find that algorithm B actually looks like it's performing better,
你发现算法B看起来表现更好

126
00:08:24,895 --> 00:08:27,865
even though it's doing better on your dev set.
即使它在开发集上表现不错

127
00:08:27,865 --> 00:08:30,820
And you find that you've been training off
你发现你一直在用

128
00:08:30,820 --> 00:08:34,344
very nice high quality images downloaded off the Internet
从网上下载的高质量图片训练

129
00:08:34,345 --> 00:08:36,985
but when you deploy those on the mobile app,
但当你部署到手机应用时

130
00:08:36,985 --> 00:08:39,620
users are uploading all sorts of pictures, they're much less framed,
算法作用到用户上传的图片时 那些图片取景不专业

131
00:08:39,620 --> 00:08:42,835
you haven't only covered the cat, the cats have funny facial expressions,
没有把猫完整拍下来 或者猫的表情很古怪

132
00:08:42,835 --> 00:08:44,778
maybe images are much blurrier,
也许图像很模糊

133
00:08:44,778 --> 00:08:51,745
and when you test out your algorithms you find that Algorithm B is actually doing better.
当你实际测试算法时 你发现算法B表现其实更好

134
00:08:51,745 --> 00:08:58,755
So this would be another example of your metric and dev test sets falling down.
这是另一个指标和开发集测试集出问题的例子

135
00:08:58,755 --> 00:09:01,140
The problem is that you're evaluating on
问题在于 你做评估用的是

136
00:09:01,140 --> 00:09:04,265
the dev and test sets a very nice, high resolution,
很漂亮的高分辨率的开发集和测试集

137
00:09:04,265 --> 00:09:06,830
well-framed images but what your users
图片取景很专业 但你的用户

138
00:09:06,830 --> 00:09:09,750
really care about is you have them doing well on images they are uploading,
真正关心的是 他们上传的图片能不能被正确识别

139
00:09:09,750 --> 00:09:15,935
which are maybe less professional shots and blurrier and less well framed.
那些图片可能是没那么专业的照片 有点模糊 取景很业余

140
00:09:15,935 --> 00:09:17,655
So the guideline is,
所以方针是

141
00:09:17,655 --> 00:09:20,030
if doing well on your metric and
如果你在指标上表现很好

142
00:09:20,030 --> 00:09:23,455
your current dev sets or dev and test sets' distribution,
在当前开发集或者开发集和测试集分布中表现很好

143
00:09:23,455 --> 00:09:27,845
if that does not correspond to doing well on the application you actually care about,
但你的实际应用程序 你真正关注的地方表现不好

144
00:09:27,845 --> 00:09:32,695
then change your metric and your dev test set.
那么就需要修改指标 或者你的开发测试集

145
00:09:32,695 --> 00:09:38,490
In other words, if we discover that your dev test set has these very high quality images
换句话说 如果你发现你的开发测试集都是这些高质量图像

146
00:09:38,490 --> 00:09:41,960
but evaluating on this dev test set
但在开发测试集上做的评估

147
00:09:41,960 --> 00:09:45,915
is not predictive of how well your app actually performs,
无法预测你的应用实际的表现

148
00:09:45,915 --> 00:09:48,489
because your app needs to deal with lower quality images,
因为你的应用处理的是低质量图像

149
00:09:48,489 --> 00:09:51,716
then that's a good time to change your dev test set
那么就应该改变你的开发测试集

150
00:09:51,766 --> 00:09:56,875
so that your data better reflects the type of data you actually need to do well on.
让你的数据更能反映你实际需要处理好的数据

151
00:09:56,875 --> 00:10:01,567
But the overall guideline is if your current metric and data you are evaluating on
但总体方针就是 如果你当前的指标和当前用来评估的数据

152
00:10:01,567 --> 00:10:04,905
doesn't correspond to doing well on what you actually care about,
和你真正关心必须做好的事情关系不大

153
00:10:04,905 --> 00:10:07,707
then change your metrics and/or your dev/test set 
那就应该更改你的指标 或者你的开发测试集

154
00:10:07,708 --> 00:10:11,206
to better capture what you need your algorithm to actually do well on.
让它们能更够好地反映你的算法需要处理好的数据

155
00:10:11,206 --> 00:10:14,690
Having an evaluation metric and the dev set allows you to
有一个评估指标和开发集让你可以

156
00:10:14,690 --> 00:10:18,685
much more quickly make decisions about, Is Algorithm A or Algorithm B better.
更快做出决策 判断算法A还是算法B更优

157
00:10:18,685 --> 00:10:22,485
It really speeds up how quickly you and your team can iterate.
这真的可以加速你和你的团队迭代的速度

158
00:10:22,485 --> 00:10:24,110
So my recommendation is,
所以我的建议是

159
00:10:24,110 --> 00:10:28,220
even if you can't define the perfect evaluation metric and dev set,
即使你无法定义出一个很完美的评估指标和开发集

160
00:10:28,220 --> 00:10:32,780
just set something up quickly and use that to drive the speed of your team iterating.
你直接快速设立出来 然后使用它们来驱动你们团队的迭代速度

161
00:10:32,780 --> 00:10:36,060
And if later down the line you find out that it wasn't a good one,
如果在这之后 你发现选的不好

162
00:10:36,060 --> 00:10:39,675
you have better idea, change it at that time, it's perfectly okay.
你有更好的想法 那么完全可以马上改

163
00:10:39,675 --> 00:10:42,230
But what I recommend against for the most teams is
对于大多数团队 我建议最好不要

164
00:10:42,230 --> 00:10:46,298
to run for too long without any evaluation metric and dev set
在没有评估指标和开发集时跑太久

165
00:10:46,368 --> 00:10:48,500
because that can slow down
因为那样可能会减慢

166
00:10:48,500 --> 00:10:52,750
the efficiency of what your team can iterate and improve your algorithm.
你的团队迭代和改善算法的速度

167
00:10:52,750 --> 00:10:58,795
So that is it on when to change your evaluation metric and/or dev and test sets.
本视频讲的是什么时候需要改变你的评估指标和开发测试集

168
00:10:58,795 --> 00:11:02,480
I hope that these guidelines help you set up your whole team to have
我希望这些方针能让你的整个团队设立一个

169
00:11:02,480 --> 00:11:07,370
a well-defined target that you can iterate efficiently towards improving performance on.  
明确的目标 一个你们可以高效迭代 改善性能的目标

