1
00:00:00,252 --> 00:00:01,966
Whether you're tuning hyperparameters, 
无论您是调整超参数

2
00:00:01,967 --> 00:00:04,279
or trying out different ideas for learning algorithms,
或者是尝试不同的学习算法

3
00:00:04,280 --> 00:00:07,764
or just trying out different options for building your machine learning system.
或者在搭建机器学习系统时尝试不同手段

4
00:00:07,764 --> 00:00:10,802
You'll find that your progress will be much faster if you have a 
你会发现 如果你有一个单实数评估指标

5
00:00:10,859 --> 00:00:13,470
single real number evaluation metric
你的进展会快得多

6
00:00:13,522 --> 00:00:16,064
that lets you quickly tell if the new thing you
它可以快速告诉你

7
00:00:16,064 --> 00:00:20,260
just tried is working better or worse than your last idea.
新尝试的手段 比之前的手段好还是坏

8
00:00:20,260 --> 00:00:23,486
So when teams are starting on a machine learning project, 
所以当团队开始进行机器学习项目时

9
00:00:23,487 --> 00:00:24,710
I often recommend that
我经常推荐他们

10
00:00:24,710 --> 00:00:29,570
you set up a single real number evaluation metric for your problem.
为你的问题设置一个单实数评估指标

11
00:00:29,570 --> 00:00:30,600
Let's look at an example.
我们来看一个例子

12
00:00:32,400 --> 00:00:33,784
You've heard me say before that 
你之前听过我说过 

13
00:00:33,785 --> 00:00:36,165
applied machine learning is a very empirical process.
应用机器学习是一个非常经验性的过程

14
00:00:36,165 --> 00:00:40,360
We often have an idea, code it up, run the experiment to see how it did, and
我们通常有一个想法 编程序 跑实验 看看效果如何

15
00:00:40,360 --> 00:00:44,100
then use the outcome of the experiment to refine your ideas.
然后使用这些实验结果来改善你的想法

16
00:00:44,100 --> 00:00:48,590
And then keep going around this loop as you keep on improving your algorithm.
然后继续走这个循环 不断改进你的算法

17
00:00:48,590 --> 00:00:52,593
So let's say for your cat classifier, you had previously built some classifier A.
比如说对于你的猫分类器 之前你搭建了某个分类器A

18
00:00:52,665 --> 00:00:56,854
And by changing the hyperparameters and the training sets or some other thing,
通过改变超参数 还有改变训练集等手段

19
00:00:56,906 --> 00:01:02,032
you've now trained a new classifier, B.
你现在训练出来了一个新的分类器B

20
00:01:02,032 --> 00:01:04,972
So one reasonable way to evaluate the performance of your classifiers
所以评估你的分类器的一个合理方式是

21
00:01:05,038 --> 00:01:08,680
is to look at its precision and recall.
观察它的查准率和查全率

22
00:01:08,680 --> 00:01:11,220
The exact details of what's precision and recall 
查准率和查全率的确切细节

23
00:01:11,272 --> 00:01:13,650
don't matter too much for this example.
对于这个例子来说不太重要

24
00:01:13,650 --> 00:01:16,594
But briefly, the definition of precision is,
但简而言之 查准率的定义是

25
00:01:16,594 --> 00:01:20,207
of the examples that your classifier recognizes as cats,
在你的分类器标记为猫的例子中

26
00:01:23,068 --> 00:01:26,741
What percentage actually are cats?
有多少真的是猫

27
00:01:32,341 --> 00:01:35,497
So if classifier A has 95% precision, 
所以如果分类器A有95%的查准率

28
00:01:35,497 --> 00:01:38,363
this means that when classifier A says something is a cat,
这意味着你的分类器说这图有猫的时候

29
00:01:38,448 --> 00:01:41,830
there's a 95% chance it really is a cat.
有95％的机会真的是猫

30
00:01:41,830 --> 00:01:45,878
And recall is, of all the images that really are cats,
查全率就是 对于所有真猫的图片

31
00:01:45,878 --> 00:01:50,731
what percentage were correctly recognized by your classifier?
你的分类器正确识别出了多少百分比

32
00:01:50,731 --> 00:01:57,110
So what percentage of actual cats, Are correctly recognized?
实际为猫的图片中 有多少被系统识别出来?

33
00:02:04,331 --> 00:02:08,750
So if classifier A is 90% recall, this means that of all of the images in, 
如果分类器A查全率是90% 这意味着对于所有的图像

34
00:02:08,751 --> 00:02:11,010
say, your dev sets that really are cats,
比如说你的开发集都是真的猫图

35
00:02:11,010 --> 00:02:13,987
classifier A accurately pulled out 90% of them.
分类器A准确地分辨出了其中的90% 

36
00:02:13,987 --> 00:02:19,049
So don't worry too much about the definitions of precision and recall.
所以关于查准率和查全率的定义 不用想太多

37
00:02:19,049 --> 00:02:24,661
It turns out that there's often a tradeoff between precision and recall,
事实证明 查准率和查全率之间往往需要折衷

38
00:02:24,662 --> 00:02:26,845
and you care about both.
两个指标都要顾及到

39
00:02:26,845 --> 00:02:29,455
You want that, when the classifier says something is a cat,
你希望得到的效果是 当你的分类器说 某个东西是猫的时候

40
00:02:29,455 --> 00:02:31,765
there's a high chance it really is a cat.
有很大的机会它真的是一只猫

41
00:02:31,765 --> 00:02:33,475
But of all the images that are cats,
但对于所有是猫的图片

42
00:02:33,475 --> 00:02:37,905
you also want it to pull a large fraction of them as cats.
你也希望系统能够将大部分分类为猫

43
00:02:37,905 --> 00:02:40,865
So it might be reasonable to try to evaluate
所以用查准率和查全率来评估分类器

44
00:02:40,865 --> 00:02:44,685
the classifiers in terms of its precision and its recall.
是比较合理的

45
00:02:44,685 --> 00:02:49,528
The problem with using precision recall as your evaluation metric is that
但使用查准率和查全率作为评估指标的时候 有个问题

46
00:02:49,529 --> 00:02:53,937
if classifier A does better on recall, which it does here,
如果分类器A在查全率上表现更好

47
00:02:53,937 --> 00:02:56,349
the classifier B does better on precision, 
分类器B在查准率上表现更好

48
00:02:56,350 --> 00:02:59,840
then you're not sure which classifier is better.
你就无法判断哪个分类器更好

49
00:03:03,481 --> 00:03:07,881
And if you're trying out a lot of different ideas, a lot of different hyperparameters,
如果你尝试了很多不同想法 很多不同的超参数

50
00:03:07,882 --> 00:03:11,076
you want to rather quickly try out not just two classifiers,
你希望能够快速试验不仅仅是两个分类器

51
00:03:11,076 --> 00:03:14,932
but maybe a dozen classifiers and quickly pick out the, quote, best ones,
也许是十几个分类器 快速选出 “最好的”那个

52
00:03:14,932 --> 00:03:17,010
so you can keep on iterating from there.
这样你可以从那里出发再迭代

53
00:03:19,850 --> 00:03:23,570
And with two evaluation metrics, it is difficult to know
如果有两个评估指标 就很难去

54
00:03:23,570 --> 00:03:27,380
how to quickly pick one of the two or quickly pick one of the ten.
快速地二中选一或者十中选一

55
00:03:29,170 --> 00:03:32,434
So what I recommend is rather than using two numbers, 
所以我并不推荐使用两个评估指标

56
00:03:32,435 --> 00:03:35,870
precision and recall, to pick a classifier,
查准率和查全率 来选择一个分类器

57
00:03:35,870 --> 00:03:40,440
you just have to find a new evaluation metric that combines precision and recall.
你只需要找到一个新的评估指标 能够结合查准率和查全率

58
00:03:41,740 --> 00:03:43,360
In the machine learning literature, 
在机器学习文献中

59
00:03:43,361 --> 00:03:47,028
the standard way to combine precision and recall is something called an F1 score.
结合查准率和查全率的标准方法是所谓的F1分数

60
00:03:47,028 --> 00:03:52,777
And the details of F1 score aren't too important, but informally,
F1分数的细节并不重要 但非正式的

61
00:03:52,777 --> 00:03:59,240
you can think of this as the average of precision, P, and recall, R.
你可以认为这是查准率P和查全率R的平均值

62
00:03:59,240 --> 00:04:04,574
Formally, the F1 score is defined by this formula,
正式来看 F1分数的定义是这个公式

63
00:04:04,574 --> 00:04:07,670
it's 2/ 1/P + 1/R.
这是2/(1/P+1/R)

64
00:04:07,670 --> 00:04:11,303
And in mathematics, this function is called
在数学中 这个函数叫做

65
00:04:11,354 --> 00:04:16,860
the harmonic mean of precision P and recall R.
查准率P和查全率R的调和平均数

66
00:04:16,860 --> 00:04:17,850
But less formally,
但非正式来说

67
00:04:17,850 --> 00:04:21,721
you can think of this as some way that averages precision and recall.
你可以将它看成是某种查准率和查全率的平均值

68
00:04:22,840 --> 00:04:25,190
Only instead of taking the arithmetic mean,
只不过你算的不是直接的算术平均

69
00:04:25,190 --> 00:04:28,800
you take the harmonic mean, which is defined by this formula.
而是用这个公式定义的调和平均

70
00:04:28,800 --> 00:04:33,410
And it has some advantages in terms of trading off precision and recall.
这个指标在权衡查准率和查全率时有一些优势

71
00:04:33,410 --> 00:04:34,953
But in this example,
但在这个例子中

72
00:04:34,953 --> 00:04:39,853
you can then see right away that classifier A has a better F1 score.
你可以马上看出 分类器A的F1分数更高

73
00:04:39,853 --> 00:04:43,825
And assuming F1 score is a reasonable way to combine precision and recall,
假设F1分数是结合查准率和查全率的合理方式

74
00:04:43,825 --> 00:04:47,000
you can then quickly select classifier A over classifier B.
你可以快速选出分类器A 淘汰分类器B

75
00:04:48,100 --> 00:04:50,892
So what I found for a lot of machine learning teams is that
我发现很多机器学习团队就是这样

76
00:04:50,893 --> 00:04:52,401
having a well-defined dev set,
有一个定义明确的开发集

77
00:04:52,401 --> 00:04:54,538
which is how you're measuring precision and recall, 
用来测量查准率和查全率

78
00:04:54,585 --> 00:04:59,674
plus a single number evaluation metric, 
再加上这样一个单一数值评估指标

79
00:05:00,674 --> 00:05:05,884
sometimes I'll call it single real number. Evaluation metric
有时我叫单实数评估指标

80
00:05:05,885 --> 00:05:10,901
allows you to quickly tell if classifier A or classifier B is better,
能让你快速判断分类器A或者分类器B更好

81
00:05:10,902 --> 00:05:13,971
and therefore having a dev set plus single
所以有这样一个开发集 加上

82
00:05:13,971 --> 00:05:18,301
number evaluation metric destine to speed up iterating.
单实数评估指标 你的迭代速度肯定会很快

83
00:05:21,551 --> 00:05:26,980
It speeds up this iterative process of improving your machine learning algorithm.
它可以加速改进您的机器学习算法的迭代过程

84
00:05:26,980 --> 00:05:28,010
Let's look at another example.
我们来看另一个例子

85
00:05:29,130 --> 00:05:35,390
Let's say you're building a cat app for cat lovers in four major geographies,
假设你在开发一个猫应用 来服务四个地理大区的爱猫人士

86
00:05:35,390 --> 00:05:40,490
the US, China, India, and other, the rest of the world.
美国 中国 印度还有世界其他地区

87
00:05:40,490 --> 00:05:43,940
And let's say that your two classifiers achieve different errors
我们假设你的两个分类器在

88
00:05:45,370 --> 00:05:48,400
in data from these four different geographies.
来自四个地理大区的数据中得到了不同的错误率

89
00:05:48,400 --> 00:05:54,280
So algorithm A achieves 3% error on pictures submitted by US users and so on.
比如算法A在美国用户上传的图片中达到了3%错误率 等等

90
00:05:56,100 --> 00:05:58,404
So it might be reasonable to keep track of 
所以跟踪一下

91
00:05:58,474 --> 00:06:03,260
how well your classifiers do in these different markets or these different geographies.
你的分类器在不同市场和地理大区中的表现 应该是有用的

92
00:06:03,260 --> 00:06:06,770
But by tracking four numbers, it's very difficult to look at these numbers and
但是通过跟踪四个数字 很难扫一眼这些数值

93
00:06:06,770 --> 00:06:10,890
quickly decide if algorithm A or algorithm B is superior.
就快速判断算法A或算法B哪个更好

94
00:06:10,890 --> 00:06:13,370
And if you're testing a lot of different classifiers,
如果你测试很多不同的分类器

95
00:06:13,370 --> 00:06:17,590
then it's just difficult to look at all these numbers and quickly pick one.
那么看着那么多数字 然后快速选一个最优是很难的

96
00:06:17,590 --> 00:06:22,390
So what I recommend in this example is, in addition to tracking your
所以在这个例子中 我建议 除了跟踪

97
00:06:22,390 --> 00:06:26,450
performance in the four different geographies, to also compute the average.
分类器在四个不同的地理大区的表现 也要算算平均值

98
00:06:26,450 --> 00:06:29,092
And assuming that average performance is a 
假设平均表现是

99
00:06:29,093 --> 00:06:32,127
reasonable single real number evaluation metric, 
一个合理的单实数评估指标

100
00:06:32,128 --> 00:06:34,554
by computing the average, you can quickly tell that 
通过计算平均值 你就可以快速判断

101
00:06:34,615 --> 00:06:38,530
it looks like algorithm C has a lowest average error.
看起来算法C的平均错误率最低

102
00:06:38,530 --> 00:06:40,555
And you might then go ahead with that one.
然后你可以继续用那个算法

103
00:06:40,555 --> 00:06:44,490
You have to pick an algorithm to keep on iterating from.
你必须选择一个算法 然后不断迭代

104
00:06:44,490 --> 00:06:47,573
So your workflow with machine learning is often, you have an idea,
所以你的机器学习的工作流程往往是你有一个想法

105
00:06:47,573 --> 00:06:51,970
you implement it try it out, and you want to know whether your idea helped.
你尝试实现它 看看这个想法好不好

106
00:06:51,970 --> 00:06:56,760
So what was seen in this video is that having a single number evaluation metric
所以本视频介绍的是 有一个单实数评估指标

107
00:06:56,760 --> 00:06:58,633
can really improve your efficiency 
真的可以提高你的效率

108
00:06:58,742 --> 00:07:02,340
or the efficiency of your team in making those decisions.
或者提高你的团队做出这些决策的效率

109
00:07:02,340 --> 00:07:04,655
Now we're not yet done with the discussion on
现在我们还没有完整讨论

110
00:07:04,713 --> 00:07:07,510
how to effectively set up evaluation metrics.
如何有效地建立评估指标

111
00:07:07,510 --> 00:07:08,430
In the next video,
在下一个视频中

112
00:07:08,430 --> 00:07:13,880
I'm going to share with you how to set up optimizing, as well as satisficing metrics.
我会教你们如何设置优化以及满足指标

113
00:07:13,880 --> 00:07:15,480
So let's take a look at the next video.  
我们来看下一段视频

