1
00:00:01,430 --> 00:00:05,280
In the last few years, a lot more machine learning teams have been talking about
在过去的几年里 更多的机器学习团队一直在讨论

2
00:00:05,280 --> 00:00:09,480
comparing the machine learning systems to human level performance.
如何比较机器学习系统和人类的表现

3
00:00:09,480 --> 00:00:10,260
Why is this?
为什么呢?

4
00:00:10,260 --> 00:00:12,110
I think there are two main reasons.
我认为有两个主要原因

5
00:00:12,110 --> 00:00:15,130
First is that because of advances in deep learning,
首先是因为深度学习系统的进步

6
00:00:15,130 --> 00:00:18,170
machine learning algorithms are suddenly working much better and so
机器学习算法突然变得更好了 

7
00:00:18,170 --> 00:00:22,170
it has become much more feasible in a lot of application areas for machine learning
在许多机器学习的应用领域已经开始见到

8
00:00:22,170 --> 00:00:26,560
algorithms to actually become competitive with human-level performance.
算法已经可以威胁到人类的表现了

9
00:00:26,560 --> 00:00:29,760
Second, it turns out that the workflow of designing and
其次 事实证明 当你试图让机器做人类能做的事情时

10
00:00:29,760 --> 00:00:33,500
building a machine learning system, the workflow is much more efficient
可以精心设计机器学习系统的工作流程

11
00:00:33,500 --> 00:00:36,550
when you're trying to do something that humans can also do.
让工作流程效率更高

12
00:00:36,550 --> 00:00:40,335
So in those settings, it becomes natural to talk about comparing, 
所以在这些场合 比较人类和机器是很自然的

13
00:00:40,336 --> 00:00:43,200
or trying to mimic human-level performance.
或者你要让机器模仿人类的行为

14
00:00:43,200 --> 00:00:45,110
Let's see a couple examples of what this means.
我们来看几个这样的例子

15
00:00:46,250 --> 00:00:50,510
I've seen on a lot of machine learning tasks that as you work on a problem over time,
我看到很多机器学习任务中 当你在一个问题上付出了很多时间之后

16
00:00:50,511 --> 00:00:56,060
so the x-axis, time, this could be many months or even many years
所以x轴是时间 这可能是很多个月甚至是很多年

17
00:00:56,060 --> 00:00:59,965
over which some team or some research community is working on a problem.
在这些时间里 一些团队或一些研究小组正在研究一个问题

18
00:00:59,965 --> 00:01:07,540
Progress tends to be relatively rapid as you approach human level performance.
当你开始往人类水平努力时 进展是很快的

19
00:01:07,540 --> 00:01:12,115
But then after a while, the algorithm surpasses human-level performance and
但是过了一段时间 当这个算法表现比人类更好时

20
00:01:12,115 --> 00:01:14,998
then progress and accuracy actually slows down.
那么进展和精确度的提升就变得更慢了

21
00:01:14,998 --> 00:01:17,140
And maybe it keeps getting better but
也许它还会越来越好 但是

22
00:01:17,140 --> 00:01:21,560
after surpassing human level performance it can still get better, but performance,
在超越人类水平之后 它还可以变得更好 但性能增速

23
00:01:21,560 --> 00:01:26,420
the slope of how rapid the accuracy's going up, often that slows down.
准确度上升的速度这个斜率 会变得越来越平缓

24
00:01:26,420 --> 00:01:31,450
And the hope is it achieves some theoretical optimum level of performance.
我们都希望能达到理论最佳性能水平

25
00:01:32,730 --> 00:01:35,036
And over time, as you keep training the algorithm,
随着时间的推移 当您继续训练算法时

26
00:01:35,093 --> 00:01:38,051
maybe bigger and bigger models on more and more data,
可能模型越来越大 数据越来越多

27
00:01:38,111 --> 00:01:43,984
the performance approaches but never surpasses some theoretical limit,
但是性能无法超过某个理论上限

28
00:01:44,057 --> 00:01:51,706
which is called the Bayes optimal error.
这就是所谓的贝叶斯最优错误率

29
00:01:53,516 --> 00:01:57,048
So Bayes optimal error, think of this as the best possible error.
所以贝叶斯最优错误率 一般认为是理论上可能达到的最优错误率

30
00:01:59,946 --> 00:02:03,865
And that's just no way for any function
就是说没有任何办法设计出

31
00:02:03,865 --> 00:02:08,258
mapping from x to y to surpass a certain level of accuracy.
一个x到y的函数 让它能够超过一定的准确度

32
00:02:08,258 --> 00:02:11,285
So for example, for speech recognition, 
例如 对于语音识别来说

33
00:02:11,286 --> 00:02:15,508
if x is audio clips, some audio is just so noisy
如果x是音频片段 有些音频就是这么嘈杂

34
00:02:15,508 --> 00:02:20,022
it is impossible to tell what is in the correct transcription.
基本不可能知道说的是什么

35
00:02:20,022 --> 00:02:23,790
So the perfect error may not be 100%.
所以完美的准确率可能不是100%

36
00:02:23,790 --> 00:02:25,150
Or for cat recognition.
或者对于猫图识别来说

37
00:02:25,150 --> 00:02:29,945
Maybe some images are so blurry, that it is just impossible for
也许一些图像非常模糊 不管是人类还是机器

38
00:02:29,945 --> 00:02:34,705
anyone or anything to tell whether or not there's a cat in that picture.
都无法判断该图片中是否有猫

39
00:02:34,705 --> 00:02:39,195
So, the perfect level of accuracy may not be 100%.
所以 完美的准确度可能不是100%

40
00:02:39,617 --> 00:02:45,533
And Bayes optimal error, or Bayesian optimal error, or sometimes Bayes error for short,
而贝叶斯最优错误率 有时写作Bayesian 或者省略optimal

41
00:02:45,534 --> 00:02:51,065
is the very best theoretical function for mapping from x to y.
 就是从x到y映射的理论最优函数

42
00:02:52,330 --> 00:02:53,770
That can never be surpassed.
永远不会被超越

43
00:02:56,180 --> 00:02:59,180
So it should be no surprise that this purple line,
所以你们应该不会感到意外 这紫色线

44
00:02:59,180 --> 00:03:01,463
no matter how many years you work on a problem
无论你在一个问题上工作多少年 

45
00:03:01,464 --> 00:03:05,330
you can never surpass Bayes error, Bayes optimal error.
你永远不会超越贝叶斯错误率 贝叶斯最佳错误率

46
00:03:05,330 --> 00:03:08,670
And it turns out that progress is often quite fast
事实证明 机器学习的进展往往相当快

47
00:03:08,670 --> 00:03:10,910
until you surpass human level performance.
直到你超越人类的表现之前一直很快

48
00:03:12,010 --> 00:03:16,180
And it sometimes slows down after you surpass human level performance.
当你超越人类的表现时 有时进展会变慢

49
00:03:16,180 --> 00:03:18,471
And I think there are two reasons for that,
我认为有两个原因

50
00:03:18,472 --> 00:03:22,490
for why progress often slows down when you surpass human level performance.
为什么当你超越人类的表现时 进展会慢下来

51
00:03:22,490 --> 00:03:26,378
One reason is that human level performance is for many tasks
一个原因是人类水平在很多任务中

52
00:03:26,379 --> 00:03:28,640
not that far from Bayes' optimal error.
离贝叶斯最优错误率已经不远了

53
00:03:28,640 --> 00:03:30,661
People are very good at looking at images 
人们非常擅长看图像 

54
00:03:30,734 --> 00:03:34,810
and telling if there's a cat or listening to audio and transcribing it.
分辨里面有没有猫 或者听写音频

55
00:03:34,810 --> 00:03:37,515
So, by the time you surpass human level performance 
所以 当你超越人类的表现之后

56
00:03:37,516 --> 00:03:41,030
maybe there's not that much head room to still improve.
也许没有太多的空间继续改善了

57
00:03:42,390 --> 00:03:43,939
But the second reason is that 
但第二个原因是

58
00:03:43,940 --> 00:03:47,332
so long as your performance is worse than human level performance,
只要你的表现比人类的表现更差

59
00:03:47,333 --> 00:03:51,459
then there are actually certain tools you could use to improve performance
那么实际上可以使用某些工具来提高性能

60
00:03:51,459 --> 00:03:55,340
that are harder to use once you've surpassed human level performance.
一旦你超越了人类的表现 这些工具就没那么好用了

61
00:03:55,340 --> 00:03:57,541
So here's what I mean.
我的意思是这样

62
00:03:59,980 --> 00:04:02,241
For tasks that humans are quite good at, 
对于人类相当擅长的任务

63
00:04:02,242 --> 00:04:07,066
and this includes looking at pictures and recognizing things, or listening to audio,
包括看图识别事物 听写音频

64
00:04:07,066 --> 00:04:11,480
or reading language, really natural data tasks humans tend to be very good at.
或阅读语言 人类一般很擅长处理这些自然数据

65
00:04:11,480 --> 00:04:16,344
For tasks that humans are good at, so long as your machine learning algorithm is
对于人类擅长的任务 只要你的机器学习算法

66
00:04:16,344 --> 00:04:20,426
still worse than the human, you can get labeled data from humans.
比人类差 你就可以从让人帮你标记数据

67
00:04:20,426 --> 00:04:25,688
That is you can ask people, ask or hire humans, to label examples for you
你可以让人帮忙 或者花钱请人帮你标记样本

68
00:04:25,688 --> 00:04:29,560
so that you can have more data to feed your learning algorithm.
这样你就有更多的数据可以喂给学习算法

69
00:04:29,560 --> 00:04:33,010
Something we'll talk about next week is manual error analysis.
下周我们会讨论 人工错误率分析

70
00:04:33,010 --> 00:04:36,929
But so long as humans are still performing better than any other algorithm, 
但只要人类的表现比任何其他算法都要好

71
00:04:36,930 --> 00:04:40,264
you can ask people to look at examples that your algorithm's getting wrong, 
你就可以让人类看看你算法处理的样本 知道错误出在哪里

72
00:04:40,265 --> 00:04:42,291
and try to gain insight in terms of why 
并尝试了解

73
00:04:42,334 --> 00:04:44,270
a person got it right but the algorithm got it wrong.
为什么人能做对 算法做错

74
00:04:44,270 --> 00:04:47,130
And we'll see next week that this helps improve your algorithm's performance.
下周我们会看到 这样做有助于提高算法的性能

75
00:04:48,230 --> 00:04:51,598
And you can also get a better analysis of bias and variance
你也可以更好地分析偏差和方差

76
00:04:51,599 --> 00:04:53,240
which we'll talk about in a little bit.
我们稍后会谈一谈

77
00:04:53,240 --> 00:04:56,810
But so long as your algorithm is still doing worse then humans
但是只要你的算法仍然比人类糟糕 

78
00:04:56,810 --> 00:05:00,290
you have these important tactics for improving your algorithm.
你就有这些重要策略可以改善算法

79
00:05:00,290 --> 00:05:03,540
Whereas once your algorithm is doing better than humans,
而一旦你的算法做得比人类好

80
00:05:03,540 --> 00:05:06,140
then these three tactics are harder to apply.
这三种策略就很难利用了

81
00:05:07,250 --> 00:05:09,128
So, this is maybe another reason why 
所以这可能是另一个

82
00:05:09,175 --> 00:05:12,722
comparing to human level performance is helpful,
和人类表现比较的好处

83
00:05:12,723 --> 00:05:15,360
especially on tasks that humans do well.
特别是在人类做得很好的任务上

84
00:05:17,665 --> 00:05:22,015
And why machine learning algorithms tend to be really good at
为什么机器学习算法往往很擅长

85
00:05:22,016 --> 00:05:24,166
trying to replicate tasks that people can do
模仿人类能做的事情

86
00:05:24,233 --> 00:05:29,690
and kind of catch up to and maybe slightly surpass human level performance.
然后赶上甚至超越人类的表现

87
00:05:29,690 --> 00:05:34,129
In particular, even though you know what is bias and what is variance it turns out
特别是 即使你知道偏差是多少 方差是多少

88
00:05:34,129 --> 00:05:36,675
that knowing how well humans can do well on a task 
知道人类在特定任务上能做多好

89
00:05:36,676 --> 00:05:40,112
can help you understand better how much you should try
可以帮助你更好地了解你应该重点尝试

90
00:05:40,112 --> 00:05:43,430
to reduce bias and how much you should try to reduce variance.
减少偏差 还是减少方差

91
00:05:43,430 --> 00:05:45,810
I want to show you an example of this in the next video.  
我想在下一个视频中给你一个例子

