1
00:00:00,000 --> 00:00:01,370
>> In the last video,
>>在上一个视频中

2
00:00:01,370 --> 00:00:05,445
you saw how your dev and test sets should come from the same distribution,
你们知道了 你的开发集和测试集为什么必须来自同一分布

3
00:00:05,445 --> 00:00:07,370
but how large should they be?
但它们规模应该多大?

4
00:00:07,370 --> 00:00:09,925
The guidelines to help set up your dev and test sets
在深度学习时代 设立开发集和测试集的方针

5
00:00:09,926 --> 00:00:11,955
are changing in the Deep Learning era.
也在变化

6
00:00:11,955 --> 00:00:14,645
Let's take a look at some best practices.
我们来看看一些最佳做法

7
00:00:14,645 --> 00:00:17,870
You might have heard of the rule of thumb
你可能听说过一条经验法则

8
00:00:17,870 --> 00:00:20,489
in machine learning of taking all the data you have
在机器学习中 把你取得的全部数据

9
00:00:20,489 --> 00:00:26,495
and using a 70/30 split into a train and test set,
用70/30比例分成训练集和测试集

10
00:00:26,495 --> 00:00:30,800
or if you had to set up train dev and test sets maybe,
或者如果你必须设立训练集 开发集和测试集

11
00:00:30,800 --> 00:00:42,705
you would use a 60% training and 20% dev and 20% tests.
你会这么分 60%训练集 20%开发集 20%测试集

12
00:00:42,705 --> 00:00:50,155
In earlier eras of machine learning, this was pretty reasonable,
在机器学习的早期 这样分是相当合理的

13
00:00:50,155 --> 00:00:54,550
especially back when data set sizes were just smaller.
特别是以前的数据集大小要小得多

14
00:00:54,550 --> 00:00:57,085
So if you had a hundred examples in total,
所以如果你总共有100个样本

15
00:00:57,085 --> 00:01:03,555
these 70/30 or 60/20/20 rule of thumb would be pretty reasonable.
这样70/30 或者60/20/20分的经验法则是相当合理的

16
00:01:03,555 --> 00:01:05,485
If you had thousand examples,
如果你有几千个样本

17
00:01:05,485 --> 00:01:09,070
maybe if you had ten thousand examples,
或者有一万个样本

18
00:01:09,070 --> 00:01:13,070
these heuristic are not unreasonable.
这些做法也还是合理的

19
00:01:13,070 --> 00:01:16,255
But in the modern machine learning era,
但在现代机器学习中

20
00:01:16,255 --> 00:01:20,310
we are now used to working with much larger data set sizes.
我们更习惯操作规模大得多的数据集

21
00:01:20,310 --> 00:01:26,430
So let's say you have a million training examples,
比如说你有1百万个训练样本

22
00:01:26,430 --> 00:01:30,337
it might be quite reasonable to set up your data
这样分可能更合理

23
00:01:30,338 --> 00:01:33,810
so that you have 98% in the training set,
98%作为训练集

24
00:01:33,810 --> 00:01:40,786
1% dev, and 1% test.
1%开发集 1%测试集

25
00:01:40,786 --> 00:01:44,590
And when you use D and T to abbreviate dev and test sets.
我们用D和T缩写来表示开发集和测试集

26
00:01:44,590 --> 00:01:46,710
Because if you have a million examples,
因为如果你有1百万个样本

27
00:01:46,710 --> 00:01:48,285
then 1% of that,
那么1%就是

28
00:01:48,285 --> 00:01:54,800
is 10,000 examples, and that might be plenty enough for a dev set or for a test set.
10,000个样本 这对于开发集和测试集来说可能已经够了

29
00:01:54,800 --> 00:02:00,255
So, in the modern Deep Learning era where sometimes we have much larger data sets,
所以在现代深度学习时代 有时我们拥有大得多的数据集

30
00:02:00,255 --> 00:02:04,020
It's quite reasonable to use a much smaller than 20
所以使用小于20%的比例

31
00:02:04,020 --> 00:02:07,785
or 30% of your data for a dev set or a test set.
或者小于30%比例的数据作为开发集和测试集也是合理的

32
00:02:07,785 --> 00:02:12,690
And because Deep Learning algorithms have such a huge hunger for data, I'm seeing that,
而且因为深度学习算法对数据的胃口很大 我们可以看到

33
00:02:12,690 --> 00:02:16,020
the problems we have large data sets that have
那些有海量数据集的问题

34
00:02:16,020 --> 00:02:20,430
much larger fraction of it goes into the training set.
有更高比例的数据划分到训练集里

35
00:02:20,430 --> 00:02:24,447
So, how about the test set?
那么测试集呢?

36
00:02:24,447 --> 00:02:28,930
Remember the purpose of your test set is that,
要记住 测试集的目的是

37
00:02:28,930 --> 00:02:30,865
after you finish developing a system,
完成系统开发之后

38
00:02:30,865 --> 00:02:34,360
the test set helps evaluate how good your final system is.
测试集可以帮你评估投产系统的性能

39
00:02:34,360 --> 00:02:37,690
The guideline is, to set your test set to big enough to give
方针就是 令你的测试集足够大

40
00:02:37,690 --> 00:02:41,150
high confidence in the overall performance of your system.
能够以高置信度评估系统整体性能

41
00:02:41,150 --> 00:02:43,690
So, unless you need to have
所以除非你需要

42
00:02:43,690 --> 00:02:48,090
a very accurate measure of how well your final system is performing,
对最终投产系统有一个很精确的指标

43
00:02:48,090 --> 00:02:54,059
maybe you don't need millions and millions of examples in a test set,
一般来说 测试集不需要上百万个样本

44
00:02:54,059 --> 00:02:55,893
and maybe for your application if you think that 
对于你的应用程序 也许你想

45
00:02:55,958 --> 00:03:00,107
having 10,000 examples gives you enough confidence to find the performance
有10,000个样本就能给你足够的置信度来给出性能指标了

46
00:03:00,155 --> 00:03:03,725
or maybe 100,000 or whatever it is, that might be enough.
也许100,000个 之类的 可能就够了

47
00:03:03,725 --> 00:03:05,260
And this could be much less than,
这数目可能远远小于

48
00:03:05,260 --> 00:03:07,340
say 30% of the overall data set,
比如说整体数据集的30%

49
00:03:07,340 --> 00:03:08,440
depend on how much data you have.
取决于你有多少数据

50
00:03:11,868 --> 00:03:13,250
For some applications,
对于某些应用

51
00:03:13,250 --> 00:03:18,320
maybe you don't need a high confidence in the overall performance of your final system.
你也许不需要对系统性能有置信度很高的评估

52
00:03:18,320 --> 00:03:23,055
Maybe all you need is a train and dev set,
也许你只需要训练集和开发集

53
00:03:23,055 --> 00:03:29,230
And I think, not having a test set might be okay.
我认为 不单独分出一个测试集也是可以的

54
00:03:29,230 --> 00:03:31,685
In fact, what sometimes happened was,
事实上 有时在实践中

55
00:03:31,685 --> 00:03:33,965
people were talking about using
有些人会只分成

56
00:03:33,965 --> 00:03:40,580
train test splits but what they were actually doing was iterating on the test set.
训练集和测试集 他们实际上在测试集上迭代

57
00:03:40,580 --> 00:03:42,250
So rather than test set,
所以这里没有测试集

58
00:03:42,250 --> 00:03:46,415
what they had was a train dev split and no test set.
他们有的是训练集和开发集 但没有测试集

59
00:03:46,415 --> 00:03:48,604
If you're actually tuning to this set,
如果你真的在调试这个集

60
00:03:48,604 --> 00:03:50,390
to this dev set and this test set,
这个开发集和这个测试集

61
00:03:50,390 --> 00:03:53,205
It's better to call the dev set.
这最好称为开发集

62
00:03:53,205 --> 00:03:56,335
Although I think in the history of machine learning,
不过在机器学习的历史里

63
00:03:56,335 --> 00:03:59,875
not everyone has been completely clean and completely records
不是每个人都把术语定义分得很清的

64
00:03:59,875 --> 00:04:03,895
of about calling the dev set when it really should be treated as test set.
有时人们说的开发集 其实应该看做测试集

65
00:04:03,895 --> 00:04:07,485
But, if all you care about is having some data that you train on,
但如果你只要有数据去训练

66
00:04:07,485 --> 00:04:09,150
and having some data to tune to,
有数据去调试就够了

67
00:04:09,150 --> 00:04:12,493
and you're just going to ship the final system regardless
你打算不管测试集 直接部署最终系统

68
00:04:12,536 --> 00:04:15,710
and not worry too much about how it was actually doing,
所以不用太担心它的实际表现

69
00:04:15,710 --> 00:04:17,940
I think it will be healthy and just call the train dev set
我觉得这也是很好的 就将它们称为训练集开发集就好

70
00:04:17,940 --> 00:04:20,700
and acknowledge that you have no test set.
然后说清楚你没有测试集

71
00:04:20,700 --> 00:04:22,720
This a bit unusual?
这是不是有点不正常?

72
00:04:22,720 --> 00:04:26,970
I'm definitely not recommending not having a test set when building a system.
我绝对不建议在搭建系统时省略测试集

73
00:04:26,970 --> 00:04:30,225
I do find it reassuring to have a separate test set
因为有个单独的测试集比较令我安心

74
00:04:30,225 --> 00:04:33,900
you can use to get an unbiased estimate of how well the performance should be,
因为你可以使用这组不带偏差的数据 来测量系统的性能

75
00:04:33,900 --> 00:04:37,957
but if you have a very large dev set
但如果你的开发集非常大

76
00:04:37,958 --> 00:04:41,650
so that you think you won't overfit the dev set too badly.
这样你就不会对开发集过拟合得太厉害

77
00:04:41,650 --> 00:04:45,200
Maybe it's not totally unreasonable to just have a train dev set,
这种情况 只有训练集和测试集也不是完全不合理的

78
00:04:45,200 --> 00:04:48,800
although it's not what I usually recommend.
不过我一般不建议这么做

79
00:04:48,800 --> 00:04:51,600
So to summarize, in the era of big data,
总结一下 在大数据时代

80
00:04:51,600 --> 00:04:54,500
I think the old rule of thumb of a 70/30 split,
旧的经验规则 这个70/30分

81
00:04:54,500 --> 00:04:56,275
that no longer applies.
不再适用了

82
00:04:56,275 --> 00:05:01,035
And the trend has been to use more data for training and less for dev and test,
现在流行的是 把大量数据分到训练集 然后少量数据分到开发集和测试集

83
00:05:01,035 --> 00:05:03,220
especially when you have a very large data sets.
特别是当你有一个非常大的数据集时

84
00:05:03,220 --> 00:05:06,960
And the rule of thumb is really to try to set the dev set to big enough for its purpose,
以前的经验法则其实是为了确保开发集足够大 能够达到它的目的

85
00:05:06,960 --> 00:05:11,110
which helps you evaluate different ideas and pick this up, A or B better.
就是帮你评估不同的想法 然后选出A还是B更好

86
00:05:11,110 --> 00:05:15,450
And the purpose of test set is to help you evaluate your final cost bias
测试集的目的是评估你最终的成本偏差

87
00:05:15,450 --> 00:05:18,590
You just have to set your test set big enough for that purpose,
你只需要设立足够大的测试集 可以用来这么评估就行了

88
00:05:18,590 --> 00:05:21,710
and that could be much less than 30% of the data.
可能只需要远远小于总体数据量的30%

89
00:05:21,710 --> 00:05:24,523
So, I hope that gives some guidance or some suggestions on 
所以我希望本视频能给你们一点指导和建议

90
00:05:24,524 --> 00:05:28,710
how to set up your dev and test sets in the Deep Learning era.
让你们知道如何在深度学习时代设立开发和测试集

91
00:05:28,710 --> 00:05:30,595
Next, it turns out that sometimes,
接下来 有时候

92
00:05:30,595 --> 00:05:32,640
part way through a machine learning problem,
在研究机器学习的问题途中

93
00:05:32,640 --> 00:05:34,800
you might want to change your evaluation metric,
你可能需要更改评估指标

94
00:05:34,800 --> 00:05:36,615
or change your dev and test sets.
或者改动你的开发集和测试集

95
00:05:36,615 --> 00:05:38,250
Let's talk about it when you might want to do that
我们会讲什么时候需要这样做

