1
00:00:00,360 --> 00:00:02,278
You have heard about orthogonalization.
你们学过正交化

2
00:00:02,278 --> 00:00:04,632
How to set up your dev and test sets, 
如何设立开发集和测试集

3
00:00:04,708 --> 00:00:08,077
human level performance as a proxy for Bayes's error
用人类水平错误率来估计贝叶斯错误率

4
00:00:08,125 --> 00:00:11,110
and how to estimate your avoidable bias and variance.
以及如何估计可避免偏差和方差

5
00:00:11,110 --> 00:00:14,121
Let's pull it all together into a set of guidelines for
我们现在把它们全部组合起来 写成一套指导方针

6
00:00:14,121 --> 00:00:17,473
how to improve the performance of your learning algorithm.
如何提高学习算法性能的指导方针

7
00:00:17,473 --> 00:00:22,149
So, I think getting a supervised learning algorithm to work well means fundamentally
所以我想要让一个监督学习算法达到实用 基本上

8
00:00:22,149 --> 00:00:24,656
hoping or assuming that you can do two things.
希望或者假设你可以完成两件事情

9
00:00:24,656 --> 00:00:29,737
First is that you can fit the training set pretty well 
首先 你的算法对训练集的拟合很好

10
00:00:29,738 --> 00:00:32,752
and you can think of this as roughly saying that
这可以看成是

11
00:00:32,852 --> 00:00:37,532
you can achieve low avoidable bias.
你能做到可避免偏差很低

12
00:00:38,830 --> 00:00:41,411
And the second thing you're assuming can do well is that 
还有第二件事你可以做好的是

13
00:00:41,458 --> 00:00:43,471
doing well in the training set 
在训练集中做得很好 

14
00:00:43,472 --> 00:00:46,701
generalizes pretty well to the dev set or the test set 
然后推广到开发集和测试集也很好

15
00:00:46,762 --> 00:00:50,488
and this is sort of saying that variance is not too bad.
这就是说方差不是太大

16
00:00:50,488 --> 00:00:53,717
And in the spirit of orthogonization,
在正交化的精神下

17
00:00:53,717 --> 00:00:59,672
what you see is that there's a second set of knobs to fix the avoidable bias issues
你可以看到这里有第二组旋钮 可以修正可避免偏差问题

18
00:00:59,673 --> 00:01:03,245
such as training a bigger network or training longer.
比如训练更大的网络 或者训练更久

19
00:01:03,245 --> 00:01:09,627
And there's a separate set of things you can use to address variance problems,
还有一套独立的技巧可以用来处理方差问题 

20
00:01:09,627 --> 00:01:13,427
such as regularization or getting more training data.
比如正则化或者收集更多训练数据

21
00:01:13,427 --> 00:01:17,525
So to summarize of the process we've seen in the last several videos,
总结一下前几段视频我们见到的步骤

22
00:01:17,525 --> 00:01:21,541
if you want to improve the performance of your machine learning system,
如果你想提升机器学习系统的性能

23
00:01:21,541 --> 00:01:26,234
I would recommend looking at the difference between your training error and
我建议你们看看训练错误率

24
00:01:26,234 --> 00:01:31,523
your proxy for bayes error and this gives you a sense of the avoidable bias.
和贝叶斯错误率估计值之间的距离 让你知道可避免偏差有多大

25
00:01:31,523 --> 00:01:34,423
In other words, just how much better do you think 
换句话说 就是你觉得还能做多好

26
00:01:34,471 --> 00:01:38,015
you should be trying to do on your training set and then look at 
你对训练集的优化还有多少空间 然后看看

27
00:01:38,063 --> 00:01:41,382
the difference between your dev error and your training error as an estimate.
你的开发错误率和训练错误率之间的距离

28
00:01:41,382 --> 00:01:43,871
So, it's how much of a variance problem you have.
就知道你的方差问题有多大

29
00:01:43,871 --> 00:01:44,711
In other words,
换句话说

30
00:01:44,711 --> 00:01:46,792
how much harder you should be working to 
你应该做多少努力

31
00:01:46,793 --> 00:01:50,892
make your performance generalize from the training set to the dev set,
让你的算法表现能够从训练集推广到开发集

32
00:01:50,892 --> 00:01:52,392
that it wasn't trained on explicitly?
算法是没有在开发集上训练的

33
00:02:04,393 --> 00:02:09,201
So to whatever extent you want to try to reduce avoidable bias,
如果你想用尽一切办法减少可避免偏差

34
00:02:09,201 --> 00:02:13,386
I would try to apply tactics like train a bigger model.
我建议试试这样的策略 比如使用规模更大的模型

35
00:02:13,386 --> 00:02:18,124
So, you can just do better on your training sets or train longer.
这样算法在训练集上的表现会更好 或者训练更久

36
00:02:18,124 --> 00:02:21,196
Use a better optimization algorithm such as.
使用更好的优化算法 比如说

37
00:02:24,005 --> 00:02:29,160
Adds momentum or RMS prop,
加入momentum或者RMSprop 

38
00:02:29,160 --> 00:02:32,060
or use a better algorithm like Adam.
或者使用更好的算法 比如Adam

39
00:02:34,874 --> 00:02:38,223
Or one of the thing you could try is 
你还可以试试

40
00:02:38,275 --> 00:02:41,751
to just find a better new neural network architecture
寻找更好的新神经网络架构

41
00:02:41,806 --> 00:02:44,250
or better said, hyperparameters 
或者说 更好的超参数

42
00:02:44,250 --> 00:02:47,657
and this could include everything from changing the activation functions
这些手段包罗万有 你可以改变激活函数

43
00:02:47,732 --> 00:02:50,508
to changing the number of layers or hidden units.
改变层数 或者隐藏单位数

44
00:02:50,567 --> 00:02:55,341
Although you do that, it would be in the direction of increasing the model size
虽然你这么做可能会让模型规模变大

45
00:02:55,341 --> 00:02:59,325
to try out other models or other models architectures, 
或者试用其他模型 其他架构

46
00:02:59,325 --> 00:03:03,880
such as Recurrent neural network and convolutional neural networks
如循环神经网络和卷积神经网络

47
00:03:03,880 --> 00:03:06,500
which we'll see in later courses.
在之后的课程里我们会详细介绍的

48
00:03:06,500 --> 00:03:09,520
Whether or not a new neural network architecture will
新的神经网络架构能否

49
00:03:09,520 --> 00:03:12,800
fit your training set better is sometimes hard to tell in advance,
更好地拟合你的训练集 有时也很难预先判断

50
00:03:12,800 --> 00:03:16,570
but sometimes you can get much better results with a better architecture.
但有时换架构可能会得到好得多的结果

51
00:03:18,500 --> 00:03:20,941
Next to the extent that you find out variance is a problem.
另外当你发现方差是个问题时

52
00:03:20,941 --> 00:03:26,417
Some of the many of the techniques you could try, then includes the following.
你可以试用很多技巧 包括以下这些

53
00:03:26,417 --> 00:03:30,762
You can try to get more data, because getting more data to train on
你可以收集更多数据 因为收集更多数据去训练

54
00:03:30,762 --> 00:03:35,437
could help you generalize better to dev set data that you didn't see.
可以帮你更好地推广到系统看不到的开发集数据

55
00:03:35,437 --> 00:03:37,759
You could try regularization.
你可以尝试正则化

56
00:03:37,759 --> 00:03:43,000
So this includes things like L2 regularization or dropout,
包括L2正则化 Dropout正则化

57
00:03:43,000 --> 00:03:50,501
or data augmentation which we had talk about in the previous course.
或者我们在之前课程中提到的数据增强

58
00:03:50,501 --> 00:03:55,187
Or once again, you can also try various neural network architecture,
同时你也可以试用不同的神经网络架构

59
00:03:55,187 --> 00:03:58,467
hyperparameters search to see if that can help you
超参数搜索 看看能不能帮助你

60
00:03:58,467 --> 00:04:02,390
find a neural network architecture that is better suited for your problem.
找到一个更适合你的问题的神经网络架构

61
00:04:03,810 --> 00:04:07,722
I think that this notion of bias or avoidable bias and variance
我想这些偏差 可避免偏差 和方差的概念

62
00:04:07,778 --> 00:04:12,150
there is one of those things that easily learned, but tough to master and
是容易上手 难以精通的

63
00:04:12,150 --> 00:04:16,090
if you are able to systematically apply the concept from this week's videos.
如果你能系统全面地应用本周课程里的概念

64
00:04:16,090 --> 00:04:20,244
You actually be much more efficient and much more systematic and much more
你实际上会比很多现有的机器学习团队

65
00:04:20,244 --> 00:04:24,502
strategic than a lot of machine learning teams in terms of how to 
更有效率 更系统 更有策略地

66
00:04:24,550 --> 00:04:28,567
systematically go about improving the performance of their machine learning system.
系统提高机器学习系统的性能

67
00:04:28,567 --> 00:04:32,982
So, that this week's whole work will allow you to practice and
所以 本周的作业中 你们可以练习一下

68
00:04:32,982 --> 00:04:36,832
exercise more your understanding of these concepts.
更深入地理解这些概念

69
00:04:36,832 --> 00:04:39,143
Best of luck with this week's homework 
祝你们好运

70
00:04:39,143 --> 00:04:42,463
and I look forward to also seeing you in next week's videos.
我希望下周的视频中再见到你们

