1
00:00:00,008 --> 00:00:03,400
The term human-level performance is sometimes used
人类水平表现这个词

2
00:00:03,400 --> 00:00:05,820
casually in research articles.
在论文里经常随意使用

3
00:00:05,820 --> 00:00:09,070
But let me show you how we can define it a bit more precisely.
但我现在告诉你这个词更准确的定义

4
00:00:09,070 --> 00:00:13,350
And in particular, use the definition of the phrase, human-level performance,
特别是 使用人类水平表现这个词的定义 

5
00:00:13,350 --> 00:00:17,430
that is most useful for helping you drive progress in your machine learning project.
可以帮助你们推动机器学习项目的进展

6
00:00:19,370 --> 00:00:23,455
So remember from our last video that one of the uses of this phrase,
还记得上个视频中 我们用过这个词

7
00:00:23,455 --> 00:00:28,820
human-level error, is that it gives us a way of estimating Bayes error.
人类水平错误率 用来估计贝叶斯错误

8
00:00:28,820 --> 00:00:31,914
What is the best possible error any function could,
那就是理论最低的错误率 任何函数

9
00:00:31,914 --> 00:00:35,380
either now or in the future, ever, ever achieve?
不管是现在还是将来 能够到达的最低值

10
00:00:35,380 --> 00:00:40,190
So bearing that in mind, let's look at a medical image classification example.
我们先记住这点 然后看看医学图像分类例子

11
00:00:40,190 --> 00:00:43,900
Let's say that you want to look at a radiology image like this,
假设你要观察这样的放射科图像

12
00:00:43,900 --> 00:00:48,010
and make a diagnosis classification decision.
然后作出分类诊断

13
00:00:49,155 --> 00:00:52,541
And suppose that a typical human, untrained human,
假设一个普通的人类 未经训练的人类

14
00:00:52,541 --> 00:00:55,350
achieves 3% error on this task.
在此任务上达到3%的错误率

15
00:00:55,350 --> 00:01:02,460
A typical doctor, maybe a typical radiologist doctor, achieves 1% error.
普通的医生 也许是普通的放射科医生 能达到1%的错误率

16
00:01:02,460 --> 00:01:06,330
An experienced doctor does even better, 0.7% error.
经验丰富的医生做得更好 错误率为0.7%

17
00:01:06,330 --> 00:01:11,370
And a team of experienced doctors, that is if you get a team of experienced doctors
还有一队经验丰富的医生 就是说如果你有一个经验丰富的医生团队

18
00:01:11,370 --> 00:01:14,790
and have them all look at the image and discuss and debate the image,
让他们都看看这个图像 然后讨论并辩论

19
00:01:14,790 --> 00:01:20,085
together their consensus opinion achieves 0.5% error.
他们达成共识的意见达到0.5%的错误率

20
00:01:20,085 --> 00:01:25,247
So the question I want to pose to you is, how should you define human-level error?
所以我想问你的问题是 你应该如何界定人类水平错误率?

21
00:01:25,247 --> 00:01:31,080
Is human-level error 3%, 1%, 0.7% or 0.5%?
人类水平错误率3%, 1%, 0.7%还是0.5%?

22
00:01:31,080 --> 00:01:34,910
Feel free to pause this video to think about it if you wish.
你也可以暂停视频思考一下

23
00:01:34,910 --> 00:01:38,815
And to answer that question, I would urge you to bear in mind that 
要回答这个问题 我想请你记住

24
00:01:38,816 --> 00:01:41,161
one of the most useful ways to think of human error
思考人类水平错误率最有用的方式之一是

25
00:01:41,239 --> 00:01:45,990
is as a proxy or an estimate for Bayes error.
把它作为贝叶斯错误率的替代或估计

26
00:01:45,990 --> 00:01:50,360
So please feel free to pause this video to think about it for a while if you wish.
如果你愿意 也可以暂停视频 思考一下这个问题

27
00:01:50,360 --> 00:01:55,300
But here's how I would define human-level error.
但这里我就直接给出人类水平错误率的定义

28
00:01:55,300 --> 00:02:00,014
Which is if you want a proxy or an estimate for Bayes error,
就是如果你想要替代或估计贝叶斯错误率

29
00:02:00,014 --> 00:02:03,000
then given that a team of experienced doctors discussing and debated
那么一队经验丰富的医生讨论和辩论之后

30
00:02:03,076 --> 00:02:06,195
can achieve 0.5% error,
可以达到0.5%的错误率

31
00:02:06,270 --> 00:02:12,576
we know that Bayes error is less than equal to 0.5%.
我们知道贝叶斯错误率小于等于0.5%

32
00:02:12,646 --> 00:02:17,801
So because some system, team of these doctors can achieve 0.5% error,
因为有些系统 这些医生团队可以达到0.5%的错误率

33
00:02:17,801 --> 00:02:23,366
so by definition, this directly, optimal error has got to be 0.5% or lower.
所以根据定义 最优错误率必须在0.5%以下

34
00:02:23,366 --> 00:02:26,680
We don't know how much better it is, maybe there's a even larger team
我们不知道多少更好 也许有一个更大的团队

35
00:02:26,680 --> 00:02:29,488
of even more experienced doctors who could do even better,
更有经验的医生能做得更好

36
00:02:29,488 --> 00:02:32,087
so maybe it's even a little bit better than 0.5%.
所以也许比0.5%好一点

37
00:02:32,087 --> 00:02:36,325
But we know the optimal error cannot be higher than 0.5%.
但是我们知道最优错误率不能高于0.5%

38
00:02:36,325 --> 00:02:43,265
So what I would do in this setting is use 0.5% as our estimate for Bayes error.
那么在这个背景下 我就可以用0.5%估计贝叶斯错误率

39
00:02:43,265 --> 00:02:48,548
So I would define human-level performance as 0.5%.
所以我将人类水平定义为0.5%

40
00:02:48,548 --> 00:02:51,455
At least if you're hoping to use human-level error 
至少如果你希望使用人类水平错误

41
00:02:51,456 --> 00:02:55,300
in the analysis of bias and variance as we saw in the last video.
来分析偏差和方差的时候 就像上个视频那样

42
00:02:56,330 --> 00:02:59,027
Now, for the purpose of publishing a research paper 
现在 为了发表研究论文

43
00:02:59,098 --> 00:03:01,343
or for the purpose of deploying a system, 
或者部署系统

44
00:03:01,344 --> 00:03:04,783
maybe there's a different definition of human-level error
也许人类水平错误率的定义可以不一样

45
00:03:04,784 --> 00:03:06,064
that you can use which is 
你可以使用..

46
00:03:06,152 --> 00:03:10,675
so long as you surpass the performance of a typical doctor.
只要你超越了一个普通医生的表现

47
00:03:10,675 --> 00:03:13,724
That seems like maybe a very useful result if ever accomplished, 
如果能达到这种水平 那系统已经达到实用了

48
00:03:13,725 --> 00:03:18,002
and maybe surpassing a single radiologist, a single doctor's performance
也许超过一名放射科医生 一名医生的表现

49
00:03:18,002 --> 00:03:21,312
might mean the system is good enough to deploy in some context.
意味着系统在一些情况下可以有部署价值了

50
00:03:22,342 --> 00:03:26,412
So maybe the takeaway from this is to be clear about what your purpose is
本视频的要点是 在定义人类水平错误率时

51
00:03:26,412 --> 00:03:28,902
in defining the term human-level error.
要弄清楚你的目标所在

52
00:03:28,902 --> 00:03:34,006
And if it is to show that you can surpass a single human and therefore argue for
如果要表明你可以超越单个人类 那么就有理由

53
00:03:34,006 --> 00:03:39,126
deploying your system in some context, maybe this is the appropriate definition.
在某些场合部署你的系统 也许这个定义是合适的

54
00:03:39,126 --> 00:03:41,642
But if your goal is the proxy for Bayes error,
但是如果您的目标是替代贝叶斯错误率

55
00:03:41,642 --> 00:03:44,976
then this is the appropriate definition.
那么这个定义才合适

56
00:03:44,976 --> 00:03:48,662
To see why this matters, let's look at an error analysis example.
要了解为什么这个很重要 我们来看一个错误率分析的例子

57
00:03:51,642 --> 00:03:55,830
Let's say, for a medical imaging diagnosis example,
比方说 在医学图像诊断例子中

58
00:03:55,830 --> 00:04:00,320
that your training error is 5% and your dev error is 6%.
你的训练错误率是5% 你的开发错误率是6%

59
00:04:00,320 --> 00:04:05,260
And in the example from the previous slide, our human-level performance,
而在上一张幻灯片的例子中 我们的人类水平表现

60
00:04:05,260 --> 00:04:08,688
and I'm going to think of this as proxy for Bayes error.
我将它看成是贝叶斯错误率的替代品

61
00:04:12,460 --> 00:04:15,648
Depending on whether you defined it as a typical doctor's performance or
取决于你是否将它定义成普通单个医生的表现

62
00:04:15,687 --> 00:04:17,014
experienced doctor or team of doctors, 
还是有经验的医生或医生团队的表现

63
00:04:17,061 --> 00:04:24,599
you would have either 1% or 0.7% or 0.5% for this.
你可能会用1%或0.7%或0.5%

64
00:04:24,599 --> 00:04:27,959
And remember also our definitions from the previous video,
同时也回想一下 前面视频中的定义

65
00:04:28,026 --> 00:04:32,037
that this gap between Bayes error or estimate of Bayes error and training error
贝叶斯错误率或者说贝叶斯错误率的估计 和训练错误率直接的差值

66
00:04:32,083 --> 00:04:36,625
is calling that a measure of the avoidable bias.
就衡量了所谓的可避免偏差

67
00:04:36,625 --> 00:04:39,220
And this as a measure or an estimate of 
这可以衡量 或者估计

68
00:04:39,277 --> 00:04:42,067
how much of a variance problem you have in your learning algorithm.
你的学习算法的方差问题有多严重

69
00:04:44,417 --> 00:04:49,008
So in this first example, whichever of these choices you make,
所以在这个第一个例子中 无论你做出哪些选择

70
00:04:49,008 --> 00:04:53,271
the measure of avoidable bias will be something like 4%.
可避免偏差大概是4%

71
00:04:53,271 --> 00:04:55,080
It will be somewhere between I guess, 
这个值我想介于.. 

72
00:04:55,081 --> 00:04:57,438
4%, if you take that
如果你取1% 就是4%

73
00:04:57,517 --> 00:04:58,438
to 4.5%, if you use 0.5%, whereas this is 1%.
如果你取0.5%就是4.5% 而这个差距是1%

74
00:05:06,108 --> 00:05:07,617
So in this example, I would say,
所以在这个例子中 我得说

75
00:05:07,696 --> 00:05:12,780
it doesn't really matter which of the definitions of human-level error you use,
不管你怎么定义人类水平错误率

76
00:05:12,780 --> 00:05:15,435
whether you use the typical doctor's error or
使用单个普通医生的错误率定义

77
00:05:15,435 --> 00:05:17,774
the single experienced doctor's error 
还是单个经验丰富医生的错误率定义

78
00:05:17,775 --> 00:05:19,737
or the team of experienced doctor's error.
或经验丰富的医生团队的错误率定义

79
00:05:21,889 --> 00:05:27,520
Whether this is 4% or 4.5%, this is clearly bigger than the variance problem.
这是4%还是4.5% 这明显比方差问题更大

80
00:05:27,520 --> 00:05:29,020
And so in this case,
所以在这种情况下,

81
00:05:29,020 --> 00:05:34,490
you should focus on bias reduction techniques such as train a bigger network.
你应该专注于减少偏差的技术 例如培训更大的网络

82
00:05:34,490 --> 00:05:36,970
Now let's look at a second example.
现在来看看第二个例子

83
00:05:36,970 --> 00:05:42,880
Let's see your training error is 1% and your dev error is 5%.
比如说你的训练错误率是1% 开发错误率是5%

84
00:05:42,880 --> 00:05:45,891
Then again it doesn't really matter, seems but academic
这其实也不怎么重要 这种问题更像学术界讨论的

85
00:05:45,892 --> 00:05:49,617
whether the human-level performance is 1% or 0.7% or 0.5%.
人类水平表现是1%或0.7%还是0.5%

86
00:05:49,617 --> 00:05:52,105
Because whichever of these definitions you use, 
因为不管你使用哪一个定义

87
00:05:52,170 --> 00:05:54,095
your measure of avoidable bias will be,
你测量可避免偏差的方法是

88
00:05:54,160 --> 00:05:59,517
I guess somewhere between 0% if you use that, to 0.5%, right?
如果用那个值 就是0%到0.5%之前 对吧

89
00:05:59,517 --> 00:06:02,015
That's the gap between the human-level performance and your training error,
那就是人类水平和训练错误率之前的差距

90
00:06:02,060 --> 00:06:04,516
whereas this gap is 4%.
而这个差距是4%

91
00:06:04,516 --> 00:06:08,976
So this 4% is going to be much bigger than the avoidable bias either way.
所以这个4%差距比任何一种定义的可避免偏差都大

92
00:06:08,976 --> 00:06:13,355
And so they'll just suggest you should focus on variance reduction techniques
所以他们就建议 你应该主要使用减少方差的工具

93
00:06:13,355 --> 00:06:16,571
such as regularization or getting a bigger training set.
比如正则化 或者去获取更大的训练集

94
00:06:16,571 --> 00:06:20,946
But where it really matters will be if your training error is 0.7%.
这什么时候真正有效呢? 就是比如你的训练错误率是0.7% 

95
00:06:20,946 --> 00:06:26,830
So you're doing really well now, and your dev error is 0.8%.
所以你现在已经做得很好了 你的开发错误率是0.8%

96
00:06:26,830 --> 00:06:33,597
In this case, it really matters that you use your estimate for Bayes error as 0.5%.
在这种情况下 你用0.5%来估计贝叶斯错误率关系就很大

97
00:06:36,027 --> 00:06:41,303
Because in this case, your measure of how much avoidable bias you have is 0.2%
因为在这种情况下 你测量到的可避免偏差是0.2%

98
00:06:41,303 --> 00:06:46,512
which is twice as big as your measure for your variance, which is just 0.1%.
这是你测量到的方差问题0.1%的两倍

99
00:06:48,592 --> 00:06:52,226
And so this suggests that maybe both the bias and variance are both problems but
这表明也许偏差和方差都存在问题  但是

100
00:06:52,226 --> 00:06:54,880
maybe the avoidable bias is a bit bigger of a problem.
可避免偏差问题更严重

101
00:06:54,880 --> 00:06:58,780
And in this example, 0.5% as we discussed on the previous slide 
在这个例子中 我们在上一张幻灯片中讨论的是0.5%

102
00:06:58,781 --> 00:07:00,836
was the best measure of Bayes error,
就是对贝叶斯错误率的最佳估计

103
00:07:00,837 --> 00:07:04,130
because a team of human doctors could achieve that performance.
因为一群人类医生可以实现这一目标

104
00:07:04,130 --> 00:07:06,608
If you use 0.7 as your proxy for Bayes error,
如果你用0.7代替贝叶斯错误率

105
00:07:06,660 --> 00:07:10,990
you would have estimated avoidable bias as pretty much 0%,
你测得的可避免偏差基本上是0%

106
00:07:10,990 --> 00:07:13,200
and you might have missed that.
那你就可能忽略可避免偏差了

107
00:07:13,200 --> 00:07:15,870
You actually should try to do better on your training set.
实际上你应该试试能不能在训练集上做得更好

108
00:07:18,085 --> 00:07:20,245
So I hope this gives a sense also of 
我希望讲这个能让你们有点概念

109
00:07:20,246 --> 00:07:23,862
why making progress in a machine learning problem gets harder
知道为什么机器学习问题上取得进展会越来越难

110
00:07:23,863 --> 00:07:27,660
as you achieve or as you approach human-level performance.
当你接近人类水平时进展会越来越难

111
00:07:27,660 --> 00:07:31,600
In this example, once you've approached 0.7% error,
在这个例子中 一旦你接近0.7%错误率

112
00:07:31,600 --> 00:07:35,300
unless you're very careful about estimating Bayes error,
除非你非常小心估计贝叶斯错误率

113
00:07:35,300 --> 00:07:38,620
you might not know how far away you are from Bayes error.
你可能无法知道离贝叶斯错误率有多远

114
00:07:38,620 --> 00:07:42,999
And therefore how much you should be trying to reduce aviodable bias.
所以你应该尽量减少可避免偏差

115
00:07:42,999 --> 00:07:49,139
In fact, if all you knew was that a single typical doctor achieves 1% error, 
事实上 如果你只知道单个普通医生能达到1%错误率

116
00:07:49,139 --> 00:07:50,593
and it might be very difficult to know 
这可能很难知道 

117
00:07:50,669 --> 00:07:53,070
if you should be trying to fit your training set even better.
是不是应该继续去拟合训练集

118
00:07:54,860 --> 00:07:55,969
And this problem arose 
这种问题只会出现在

119
00:07:55,970 --> 00:07:58,720
only when you're doing very well on your problem already,
你的算法已经做得很好的时候

120
00:07:58,720 --> 00:08:02,764
only when you're doing 0.7%, 0.8%, really close to human-level performance.
只有你已经做到0.7%, 0.8%, 接近人类水平时会出现

121
00:08:04,430 --> 00:08:06,083
Whereas in the two examples on the left, 
而在左边的两个例子中

122
00:08:06,159 --> 00:08:09,583
when you are further away from human-level performance,
当你远离人类水平时

123
00:08:09,635 --> 00:08:13,530
it was easier to target your focus on bias or variance.
将优化目标放在偏差或方差上可能更容易一点

124
00:08:13,530 --> 00:08:17,209
So this is maybe an illustration of why as your pro human-level performance is
这就说明了 为什么当你们接近人类水平时 

125
00:08:17,209 --> 00:08:20,071
actually harder to tease out the bias and variance effects.
更难分辨出问题是偏差还是方差

126
00:08:20,071 --> 00:08:22,995
And therefore why progress on your machine learning project
所以机器学习项目的进展

127
00:08:22,995 --> 00:08:24,810
just gets harder as you're doing really well.
在你已经做得很好的时候 很难更进一步

128
00:08:25,930 --> 00:08:28,590
So just to summarize what we've talked about.
总结一下我们讲到的

129
00:08:28,590 --> 00:08:30,614
If you're trying to understand bias and variance 
如果你想理解偏差和方差

130
00:08:30,681 --> 00:08:33,026
where you have an estimate of human-level error
那么在人类可以做得很好的任务中

131
00:08:33,083 --> 00:08:35,382
for a task that humans can do quite well,
你可以估计人类水平的错误率

132
00:08:35,382 --> 00:08:41,419
you can use human-level error as a proxy or as a approximation for Bayes error.
你可以使用人类水平错误率来估计贝叶斯错误率

133
00:08:47,130 --> 00:08:50,041
And so the difference between your estimate of Bayes error
所以你到贝叶斯错误率估计值的差距

134
00:08:50,080 --> 00:08:54,521
tells you how much avoidable bias is a problem,
告诉你可避免偏差问题有多大

135
00:08:54,615 --> 00:08:56,568
how much avoidable bias there is.
可避免偏差问题有多严重

136
00:08:56,568 --> 00:08:58,552
And the difference between training error and dev error,
而训练错误率和开发错误率之间的差值

137
00:08:58,606 --> 00:09:01,615
that tells you how much variance is a problem, 
告诉你方差上的问题有多大

138
00:09:01,674 --> 00:09:07,500
whether your algorithm's able to generalize from the training set to the dev set.
你的算法是否能够从训练集泛化推广到开发集

139
00:09:07,500 --> 00:09:08,674
And the big difference between 
今天讲的

140
00:09:08,734 --> 00:09:12,101
our discussion here and what we saw in an earlier course
和之前课程中见到的 重大区别是

141
00:09:12,157 --> 00:09:15,740
was that instead of comparing training error to 0%,
以前你们比较的是训练错误率和0%

142
00:09:18,471 --> 00:09:23,553
And just calling that the estimate of the bias.
直接用这个值估计偏差

143
00:09:23,553 --> 00:09:26,682
In contrast, in this video we have a more nuanced analysis
相比之下 在这个视频中 我们有一个更微妙的分析

144
00:09:26,682 --> 00:09:31,999
in which there is no particular expectation that you should get 0% error.
其中并没有假设你应该得到0%错误率

145
00:09:31,999 --> 00:09:34,549
Because sometimes Bayes error is non zero 
因为有时贝叶斯错误率是非零的

146
00:09:34,549 --> 00:09:35,914
and sometimes it's just not possible 
有时基本不可能

147
00:09:35,958 --> 00:09:39,198
for anything to do better than a certain threshold of error.
做到比某个错误率阈值更低

148
00:09:41,723 --> 00:09:46,099
And so in the earlier course, we were measuring training error, 
所以在之前的课程中 我们测量的是训练错误率

149
00:09:46,100 --> 00:09:49,895
and seeing how much bigger training error was than zero.
然后观察的是训练错误率比0%高多少

150
00:09:49,895 --> 00:09:53,720
And just using that to try to understand how big our bias is.
就用这个差值来估计偏差有多大

151
00:09:53,720 --> 00:09:58,458
And that turns out to work just fine for problems where Bayes error is nearly 0%,
而事实证明 对于贝叶斯错误率几乎是0%的问题这样就行了

152
00:09:58,458 --> 00:10:00,085
such as recognizing cats.
例如识别猫

153
00:10:00,085 --> 00:10:04,005
Humans are near perfect for that, so Bayes error is also near perfect for that.
人类表现接近完美 所以贝叶斯错误率也接近完美

154
00:10:04,005 --> 00:10:07,525
So that actually works okay when Bayes error is nearly zero.
所以当贝叶斯错误率几乎为零时 可以那么做

155
00:10:07,525 --> 00:10:09,041
But for problems where the data is noisy, 
但数据噪点很多时

156
00:10:09,128 --> 00:10:11,690
like speech recognition on very noisy audio
比如背景声音很嘈杂的语言识别

157
00:10:11,691 --> 00:10:14,679
where it's just impossible sometimes to hear what was said 
有时几乎不可能听清楚说的是什么

158
00:10:14,680 --> 00:10:16,594
and to get the correct transcription.
并正确记录下来

159
00:10:16,594 --> 00:10:19,804
For problems like that, having a better estimate for Bayes error
对于这样的问题 更好的估计贝叶斯错误率很有必要

160
00:10:19,805 --> 00:10:22,787
can help you better estimate avoidable bias and variance.
可以帮助你更好地估计可避免偏差和方差

161
00:10:22,787 --> 00:10:26,365
And therefore make better decisions on whether to focus on bias reduction tactics,
这样你就能更好的做出决策 选择减少偏差的策略

162
00:10:26,365 --> 00:10:28,955
or on variance reduction tactics.
还是减少方差的策略

163
00:10:30,915 --> 00:10:34,855
So to recap, having an estimate of human-level performance gives you
回顾一下 对人类水平有大概的估计

164
00:10:34,855 --> 00:10:36,442
an estimate of Bayes error.
可以让你做出对贝叶斯错误率的估计

165
00:10:36,442 --> 00:10:39,473
And this allows you to more quickly make decisions as to 
这样可以让你更快地作出决定 

166
00:10:39,533 --> 00:10:42,239
whether you should focus on trying to reduce a bias
是否应该专注于减少算法的偏差

167
00:10:42,298 --> 00:10:44,390
or trying to reduce the variance of your algorithm.
或者减少算法的方差

168
00:10:45,690 --> 00:10:50,904
And these techniques will tend to work well until you surpass human-level performance,
这个决策技巧通常很有效 直到你的系统性能开始超越人类

169
00:10:50,905 --> 00:10:54,530
whereupon you might no longer have a good estimate of Bayes error 
那么你对贝叶斯错误率的估计就不再准确了

170
00:10:54,531 --> 00:10:57,420
that still helps you make this decision really clearly.
但这些技巧还是可以帮你做出明确的决定

171
00:10:58,470 --> 00:11:01,596
Now, one of the exciting developments in deep learning has been that 
现在 深度学习的令人兴奋的发展之一就是

172
00:11:01,656 --> 00:11:06,360
for more and more tasks we're actually able to surpass human-level performance.
对于越来越多的任务 我们的系统实际上可以超越人类了

173
00:11:06,360 --> 00:11:07,630
In the next video,
在下一个视频中

174
00:11:07,630 --> 00:11:11,394
let's talk more about the process of surpassing human-level performance.  
让我们继续谈谈超越人类水平的过程

