1
00:00:00,050 --> 00:00:04,578
The way you set up your training dev, or development sets and test sets,
设立训练集 开发集和测试集的方式

2
00:00:04,578 --> 00:00:07,270
can have a huge impact on how rapidly you or your team
大大影响了你或者你的团队

3
00:00:07,271 --> 00:00:09,985
can make progress on building machine learning application.
在建立机器学习应用方面取得进展的速度

4
00:00:09,985 --> 00:00:12,895
The same teams, even teams in very large companies,
同样的团队 即使是大公司里的团队

5
00:00:12,895 --> 00:00:15,540
set up these data sets in ways that really slows down,
在设立这些数据集的方式 真的会

6
00:00:15,540 --> 00:00:18,125
rather than speeds up, the progress of the team.
让团队的进展变慢而不是加快

7
00:00:18,125 --> 00:00:20,130
Let's take a look at how you can set up
我们看看应该如何设立

8
00:00:20,130 --> 00:00:23,433
these data sets to maximize your team's efficiency.
这些数据集 让你的团队效率最大化

9
00:00:23,433 --> 00:00:28,325
In this video, I want to focus on how you set up your dev and test sets.
在这个视频中 我想集中讨论如何设立开发集和测试集

10
00:00:28,325 --> 00:00:33,020
So, that dev set is also called the development set,
dev集也叫做开发集

11
00:00:33,020 --> 00:00:36,940
or sometimes called the hold out cross validation set.
有时称为保留交叉验证集

12
00:00:36,940 --> 00:00:42,265
And, workflow in machine learning is that you try a lot of ideas,
然后 机器学习中的工作流程是 你尝试很多思路

13
00:00:42,265 --> 00:00:44,200
train up different models on the training set,
用训练集训练不同的模型

14
00:00:44,200 --> 00:00:47,950
and then use the dev set to evaluate the different ideas and pick one.
然后使用开发集来评估不同的思路 然后选择一个

15
00:00:47,950 --> 00:00:51,280
And, keep iterating to improve dev set performance until, finally,
然后不断迭代去改善开发集的性能 直到最后

16
00:00:51,280 --> 00:00:56,240
you have one cost that you're happy with that you then evaluate on your test set.
你可以得到一个令你满意的成本 然后你再用测试集去评估

17
00:00:56,240 --> 00:00:59,800
Now, let's say, by way of example,
现在 举个例子

18
00:00:59,800 --> 00:01:01,995
that you're building a cat classifier,
你要开发一个猫分类器

19
00:01:01,995 --> 00:01:05,500
and you are operating in these regions: in the U.S,
然后你在这些区域里运营 美国

20
00:01:05,500 --> 00:01:07,720
U.K, other European countries, South America,
英国 其他欧洲国家 南美洲

21
00:01:07,720 --> 00:01:10,490
India, China, other Asian countries, and Australia.
印度 中国 其他亚洲国家和澳大利亚

22
00:01:10,490 --> 00:01:14,529
So, how do you set up your dev set and your test set?
那么你应该如何设立开发集和测试集呢?

23
00:01:14,529 --> 00:01:19,285
Well, one way you could do so is to pick four of these regions.
其中一种做法是 你可以选择其中4个区域

24
00:01:19,285 --> 00:01:22,555
I'm going to use these four but it could be four randomly chosen regions.
我打算使用这四个 但也可以是随机选的区域

25
00:01:22,555 --> 00:01:25,705
And say, that data from these four regions will go into the dev set.
然后说 来自这四个区域的数据构成开发集

26
00:01:25,705 --> 00:01:28,580
And, the other four regions, I'm going to use these four,
然后其他四个区域 我打算用这四个

27
00:01:28,580 --> 00:01:30,530
could be randomly chosen four as well,
也可以随机选择4个

28
00:01:30,530 --> 00:01:33,350
that those will go into the test set.
这些数据构成测试集

29
00:01:33,350 --> 00:01:36,940
It turns out, this is a very bad idea because in this example,
事实证明 这个想法非常糟糕 因为这个例子中

30
00:01:36,940 --> 00:01:40,780
your dev and test sets come from different distributions.
你的开发集和测试集来自不同的分布

31
00:01:40,780 --> 00:01:43,216
I would, instead, recommend that you find a way to 
我建议你们不要这样 而是

32
00:01:43,293 --> 00:01:46,476
make your dev and test sets come from the same distribution. 
让你的开发集和测试集来自同一分布

33
00:01:47,782 --> 00:01:49,555
So, here's what I mean.
我的意思是这样

34
00:01:49,555 --> 00:01:51,590
One picture to keep in mind is that, I think,
你们要记住 我想

35
00:01:51,590 --> 00:01:54,530
setting up your dev set, plus,
就是设立你的开发集 加上一个

36
00:01:54,530 --> 00:01:57,662
your single real number evaluation metric,
单实数评估指标

37
00:01:57,662 --> 00:02:00,766
that's like placing a target and telling your team
这就是像是定下目标 然后告诉你的团队

38
00:02:00,766 --> 00:02:03,395
where you think is the bull's eye you want to aim at.
那就是你要瞄准的靶心

39
00:02:03,395 --> 00:02:07,165
Because, what happen once you've established that dev set and the metric is that,
因为你一旦建立了这样的开发集和指标

40
00:02:07,165 --> 00:02:10,840
the team can iterate very quickly, try different ideas, run experiments
团队就可以快速迭代 尝试不同的想法 跑实验

41
00:02:10,841 --> 00:02:13,729
and very quickly use the dev set and the metric
可以很快地使用开发集和指标

42
00:02:13,782 --> 00:02:16,997
to evaluate classifiers and try to pick the best one.
去评估不同分类器 然后尝试选出最好的那个

43
00:02:16,997 --> 00:02:22,207
So, machine learning teams are often very good at shooting different arrows into targets
所以 机器学习团队一般都很擅长使用不同方法去逼近目标

44
00:02:22,208 --> 00:02:26,732
and iterating to get closer and closer to hitting the bullseye.
然后不断迭代 不断逼近靶心

45
00:02:26,732 --> 00:02:30,173
So, doing well on your metric on your dev sets.
所以 针对开发集上的指标优化

46
00:02:30,173 --> 00:02:33,012
And, the problem with how we've set up the dev and test sets
然后在左边的例子中 设立开发集和测试集时

47
00:02:33,013 --> 00:02:34,680
in the example on the left is that,
存在一个问题

48
00:02:34,680 --> 00:02:39,450
your team might spend months iterating to do well on the dev set only to realize that,
你的团队可能会花上几个月时间在开发集上迭代优化 结果发现

49
00:02:39,450 --> 00:02:41,570
when you finally go to test them on the test set,
当你们最终在测试集上测试系统时

50
00:02:41,570 --> 00:02:45,900
that data from these four countries or these four regions at the bottom,
来自这四个国家或者说下面这四个地区的数据

51
00:02:45,900 --> 00:02:49,520
might be very different than the regions in your dev set.
和开发集里的数据可能差异很大

52
00:02:49,520 --> 00:02:51,765
So, you might have a nasty surprise and realize that,
所以你可能会收获"意外惊喜" 并发现

53
00:02:51,765 --> 00:02:54,690
all the months of work you spent optimizing to the dev set,
花了那么多个月的时间去针对开发集优化

54
00:02:54,690 --> 00:02:58,800
is not giving you good performance on the test set.
在测试集上的表现却不佳

55
00:02:58,800 --> 00:03:03,180
So, having dev and test sets from different distributions is like setting a target,
所以 如果你的开发集和测试集来自不同的分布 就像你设了一个目标

56
00:03:03,180 --> 00:03:06,525
having your team spend months trying to aim closer and closer to bull's eye,
让你的团队花几个月尝试逼近靶心

57
00:03:06,525 --> 00:03:08,865
only to realize after months of work that,
结果在几个月工作之后发现

58
00:03:08,865 --> 00:03:10,550
you'll say, "Oh wait, to test it,
你说 "等等 测试的时候"

59
00:03:10,550 --> 00:03:12,005
I'm going to move target over here."
"我要把目标移到这里"

60
00:03:12,005 --> 00:03:14,160
And, the team might say, "Well,
然后团队可能会说 "好吧

61
00:03:14,160 --> 00:03:18,320
why did you make us spend months optimizing for a different bull's eye when suddenly,
为什么你让我们花那么多个月的时间去逼近那个靶心 然后突然间

62
00:03:18,320 --> 00:03:21,950
you can move the bull's eye to a different location somewhere else?"
你可以把靶心移到不同的位置?"

63
00:03:21,950 --> 00:03:23,010
So, to avoid this,
所以 为了避免这种情况

64
00:03:23,010 --> 00:03:24,510
what I recommend instead is that,
我建议的是

65
00:03:24,510 --> 00:03:29,985
you take all this data, randomly shuffled data into the dev and test set.
你将所有数据随机洗牌 放入开发集和测试集

66
00:03:29,985 --> 00:03:33,917
So that, both the dev and test sets have data from all eight regions
所以开发集和测试集都有来自八个地区的数据

67
00:03:33,917 --> 00:03:38,205
and that the dev and test sets really come from the same distribution,
并且开发集和测试集都来自同一分布

68
00:03:38,205 --> 00:03:41,490
which is the distribution of all of your data mixed together.
这分布就是你的所有数据混在一起

69
00:03:41,490 --> 00:03:43,766
Here's another example. This is a,
这里有另一个例子 这是个

70
00:03:43,766 --> 00:03:46,200
actually, true story but with some details changed.
真实的故事 但有一些细节变了

71
00:03:46,200 --> 00:03:48,210
So, I know a machine learning team that actually spent
所以我知道有一个机器学习团队

72
00:03:48,210 --> 00:03:50,610
several months optimizing on a dev set
花了好几个月在开发集上优化

73
00:03:50,610 --> 00:03:55,400
which was comprised of loan approvals for medium income zip codes.
开发集里面有中等收入邮政编码的贷款审批数据

74
00:03:55,400 --> 00:03:57,465
So, the specific machine learning problem was,
那么具体的机器学习问题是

75
00:03:57,465 --> 00:04:00,805
"Given an input x about a loan application,
“输入x为贷款申请

76
00:04:00,805 --> 00:04:02,820
can you predict y and which is,
你是否可以预测 输出y是

77
00:04:02,820 --> 00:04:04,907
whether or not, they'll repay the loan?"
他们有没有还贷能力?

78
00:04:04,907 --> 00:04:07,760
So, this helps you decide whether or not to approve a loan.
所以这系统能帮助银行判断是否批准贷款

79
00:04:07,760 --> 00:04:11,370
And so, the dev set came from loan applications.
所以开发集来自贷款申请

80
00:04:11,370 --> 00:04:13,565
They came from medium income zip codes.
这些贷款申请来自中等收入邮政编码

81
00:04:13,565 --> 00:04:16,870
Zip codes is what we call postal codes in the United States.
zip code就是美国的邮政编码

82
00:04:16,870 --> 00:04:18,990
But, after working on this for a few months, the team then,
但是在这上面训练了几个月之后 

83
00:04:18,990 --> 00:04:21,555
suddenly decided to test this on
团队突然决定要在

84
00:04:21,555 --> 00:04:24,650
data from low income zip codes or low income postal codes.
低收入邮政编码数据上测试一下

85
00:04:24,650 --> 00:04:27,595
And, of course, the distributional data for
当然了 这个分布数据里面

86
00:04:27,595 --> 00:04:30,900
medium income and low income zip codes is very different.
中等收入和低收入邮政编码数据是很不一样的

87
00:04:30,900 --> 00:04:34,810
And, the classifier, that they spend so much time optimizing in the former case,
而且他们花了大量时间针对前面那组数据优化分类器

88
00:04:34,810 --> 00:04:39,165
just didn't work well at all on the latter case.
导致系统在后面那组数据中效果很差

89
00:04:39,165 --> 00:04:43,062
And so, this particular team actually wasted about three months of time
所以这个特定团队实际上浪费了3个月的时间

90
00:04:43,063 --> 00:04:47,053
and had to go back and really re-do a lot of work.
不得不退回去 重新做很多工作

91
00:04:47,053 --> 00:04:48,540
And, what happened here was,
这里实际发生的事情是

92
00:04:48,540 --> 00:04:52,035
the team spent three months aiming for one target,
这个团队花了三个月瞄准一个目标

93
00:04:52,035 --> 00:04:54,060
and then, after three months,
三个月之后

94
00:04:54,060 --> 00:04:57,750
the manager asked, "Oh, how are you doing on hitting this other target?"
经理突然问 "你们试试瞄准那个目标如何"

95
00:04:57,750 --> 00:04:59,340
This is a totally different location.
这新目标位置完全不同

96
00:04:59,340 --> 00:05:02,306
And, it just was a very frustrating experience for the team.
所以这件事对于这个团队来说非常崩溃

97
00:05:02,306 --> 00:05:05,530
So, what I recommand for setting up a dev set and test set is,
所以我建议你们在设立开发集和测试集时

98
00:05:05,530 --> 00:05:08,966
choose a dev set and test set to reflect data you expect to get in future,
要选择这样的开发集和测试集 能够反映你未来会得到的数据

99
00:05:08,967 --> 00:05:11,535
and consider important to do well on.
认为很重要的数据 必须得到好结果的数据

100
00:05:11,535 --> 00:05:14,850
And, in particular, the dev set and the test set here,
特别是 这里的开发集和测试集

101
00:05:14,850 --> 00:05:20,338
should come from the same distribution.
可能来自同一个分布

102
00:05:20,338 --> 00:05:23,660
So, whatever type of data you expect to get in the future,
所以不管你未来会得到什么样的数据

103
00:05:23,660 --> 00:05:25,415
and once you do well on,
一旦你的算法效果不错

104
00:05:25,415 --> 00:05:27,745
try to get data that looks like that.
要尝试收集类似的数据

105
00:05:27,745 --> 00:05:29,050
And, whatever that data is,
而且 不管那些数据是什么

106
00:05:29,050 --> 00:05:32,245
put it into both your dev set and your test set.
都要随机分配到开发集和测试集上

107
00:05:32,245 --> 00:05:36,006
Because that way, you're putting the target where you actually want to hit
因为这样 你才能将瞄准想要的目标

108
00:05:36,006 --> 00:05:37,914
and you're having the team iterate very efficiently
让你的团队高效迭代

109
00:05:37,979 --> 00:05:40,705
to hitting that same target,
来逼近同一个目标

110
00:05:40,705 --> 00:05:41,826
hopefully, the same targets as well.
希望最好是同一个目标

111
00:05:41,826 --> 00:05:45,965
Since we haven't talked yet about how to set up a training set,
我们还没提到如何设立训练集

112
00:05:45,965 --> 00:05:48,790
we'll talk about the training set in a later video.
我们会在之后的视频里谈谈如何设立训练集

113
00:05:48,790 --> 00:05:51,335
But, the important take away from this video is that,
但这个视频的重点在于

114
00:05:51,335 --> 00:05:53,690
setting up the dev set,
设立开发集

115
00:05:53,690 --> 00:05:56,300
as well as the evaluation metric,
以及评估指标

116
00:05:56,300 --> 00:05:59,780
is really defining what target you want to aim at.
真的就定义了你要瞄准的目标

117
00:05:59,780 --> 00:06:04,145
And hopefully, by setting the dev set and the test set to the same distribution,
我们希望通过在同一分布中设立开发集和测试集

118
00:06:04,145 --> 00:06:08,659
you're really aiming at whatever target you hope your machine learning team will hit.
你就可以瞄准你所希望的 机器学习团队瞄准的目标

119
00:06:08,659 --> 00:06:10,870
The way you choose your training set
而设立训练集的方式

120
00:06:10,870 --> 00:06:14,510
will affect how well you can actually hit that target.
则会影响你逼近那个目标有多快

121
00:06:14,510 --> 00:06:18,400
But, we can talk about that separately in a later video.
但我们可以在另一个讲座里提到

122
00:06:18,400 --> 00:06:20,830
So, I know some machine learning teams that could literally have saved
我知道有一些机器学习团队

123
00:06:20,830 --> 00:06:23,825
themselves months of work could they follow the guidelines in this video.
他们如果能遵循这个方针 就可以省下几个月的工作

124
00:06:23,825 --> 00:06:26,235
So, I hope these guidelines will help you, too.
所以我希望这些方针也能帮到你们

125
00:06:26,235 --> 00:06:29,666
Next, it turns out, that the size of your dev and test sets,
接下来 实际上 你的开发集和测试集的规模

126
00:06:29,666 --> 00:06:31,015
how to choose the size of them,
如何选择它们的大小

127
00:06:31,015 --> 00:06:33,391
is also changing the era of deep learning.
在深度学习时代也在变化

128
00:06:33,391 --> 00:06:35,290
Let's talk about that in the next video.  
我们会在下一个视频里提到这些内容

