1
00:00:00,340 --> 00:00:03,227
One of the challenges with building machine learning systems is that 
搭建建立机器学习系统的挑战之一是

2
00:00:03,228 --> 00:00:06,250
there's so many things you could try, so many things you could change.
你可以尝试和改变的东西太多太多了

3
00:00:06,250 --> 00:00:09,840
Including, for example, so many hyperparameters you could tune.
包括 比如说 有那么多的超参数可以调

4
00:00:10,960 --> 00:00:14,210
One of the things I've noticed is about the most effective machine learning people
我留意到 那些效率很高的机器学习专家有个特点

5
00:00:14,210 --> 00:00:17,440
is they're very clear-eyed about what to tune
他们思维清晰 对于要调整什么

6
00:00:17,440 --> 00:00:20,200
in order to try to achieve one effect.
来达到某个效果 非常清楚

7
00:00:20,200 --> 00:00:22,842
This is a process we call orthogonalization.
这个步骤我们称之为正交化

8
00:00:22,842 --> 00:00:24,120
Let me tell you what I mean.
让我告诉你是什么意思吧

9
00:00:25,490 --> 00:00:28,560
Here's a picture of an old school television,
这是一张老式电视图片

10
00:00:28,560 --> 00:00:33,820
with a lot of knobs that you could tune to adjust the picture in various ways.
有很多旋钮可以用来调整图像的各种性质

11
00:00:35,050 --> 00:00:39,653
So for these old TV sets, maybe there was one knob to adjust 
所以对于这些旧式电视 可能有一个旋钮用来调

12
00:00:39,654 --> 00:00:45,160
how tall vertically your image is and another knob to adjust how wide it is.
图像垂直方向的高度 另外有一个旋钮用来调图像宽度

13
00:00:45,160 --> 00:00:49,310
Maybe another knob to adjust how trapezoidal it is,
也许还有一个旋钮用来调梯形角度

14
00:00:49,310 --> 00:00:52,835
another knob to adjust how much to move the picture left and right,
还有一个旋钮用来调整图像左右偏移

15
00:00:52,836 --> 00:00:57,090
another one to adjust how much the picture's rotated, and so on.
还有一个旋钮用来调图像旋转角度 之类的

16
00:00:58,740 --> 00:01:03,719
And what TV designers had spent a lot of time doing was to build the circuitry,
电视设计师花了大量时间设计电路

17
00:01:03,719 --> 00:01:06,477
really often analog circuitry back then,
那时通常都是模拟电路

18
00:01:06,477 --> 00:01:11,170
to make sure each of the knobs had a relatively interpretable function.
来确保每个旋钮都有相对明确的功能

19
00:01:11,170 --> 00:01:15,358
Such as one knob to tune this, one knob to tune this, one knob to tune this,
如一个旋钮来调整这个 一个旋钮调整这个 一个旋钮调整这个

20
00:01:15,358 --> 00:01:15,960
and so on.
以此类推

21
00:01:17,840 --> 00:01:24,488
In contrast, imagine if you had a knob that tunes 0.1 x how tall the image is,
相比之下 想像一下 如果你有一个旋钮调的是 0.1 x图像高度

22
00:01:24,488 --> 00:01:27,852
+ 0.3 x how wide the image is,
+ 0.3 x图像宽度

23
00:01:27,853 --> 00:01:32,002
- 1.7 x how trapezoidal the image is,
-  1.7 x 梯形角度

24
00:01:32,002 --> 00:01:39,010
+ 0.8 times the position of the image on the horizontal axis, and so on.
+ 0.8乘以图像在水平轴上的坐标 之类的

25
00:01:39,010 --> 00:01:42,330
If you tune this knob, then the height of the image, the width of the image,
如果你调整这个旋钮 那么图像的高度 宽度

26
00:01:42,330 --> 00:01:46,350
how trapezoidal it is, how much it shifts, it all changes all at the same time.
梯形角度 平移位置 全部都会同时改变

27
00:01:46,350 --> 00:01:51,077
If you have a knob like that, it'd be almost impossible to tune the TV 
如果你有这样的旋钮 那几乎不可能把电视调好

28
00:01:51,078 --> 00:01:54,790
so that the picture gets centered in the display area.
让图像显示在区域正中

29
00:01:54,790 --> 00:02:00,569
So in this context, orthogonalization refers to that the TV designers
所以在这种情况下 正交化指的是电视设计师

30
00:02:00,569 --> 00:02:06,076
had designed the knobs so that each knob kind of does only one thing.
设计这样的旋钮 使得每个旋钮都只调整一个性质

31
00:02:06,076 --> 00:02:08,927
And this makes it much easier to tune the TV,
这样调整电视图像就容易得多

32
00:02:08,928 --> 00:02:12,712
so that the picture gets centered where you want it to be.
就可以把图像调到正中

33
00:02:14,032 --> 00:02:17,075
Here's another example of orthogonalization.
接下来是另一个正交化例子

34
00:02:17,075 --> 00:02:22,736
If you think about learning to drive a car, a car has three main controls,
你想想学车的时候 一辆车有三个主要控制

35
00:02:22,736 --> 00:02:26,186
which are steering, the steering wheel decides how much you go left or right,
第一是方向盘 方向盘决定你往左右偏多少

36
00:02:26,309 --> 00:02:31,170
acceleration, and braking.
还有油门和刹车

37
00:02:31,170 --> 00:02:35,281
So these three controls, or really one control for steering
就是这三个控制 其中一个控制方向

38
00:02:35,282 --> 00:02:38,810
and another two controls for your speed.
另外两个控制你的速度

39
00:02:38,810 --> 00:02:42,150
It makes it relatively interpretable,
这样就比较容易解读

40
00:02:42,150 --> 00:02:46,770
what your different actions through different controls will do to your car.
知道不同控制的不同动作会对车子运动有什么影响

41
00:02:46,770 --> 00:02:51,940
But now imagine if someone were to build a car so that there was a joystick,
想象一下 如果有人这么造车 造了个游戏手柄

42
00:02:51,940 --> 00:02:57,604
where one axis of the joystick controls 0.3 x your steering angle,
手柄的一个轴控制的是0.3 x您的转向角

43
00:02:57,605 --> 00:03:00,910
minus 0.8 x your speed.
减去0.8乘以你的速度

44
00:03:00,910 --> 00:03:04,668
And you had a different control that controls
然后还有一个轴控制的是

45
00:03:04,743 --> 00:03:12,530
2 x the steering angle, + 0.9 x the speed of your car.
2x转向角+ 0.9 x你的车速

46
00:03:12,530 --> 00:03:15,140
In theory, by tuning these two knobs,
理论上来说 通过调整这两个旋钮

47
00:03:15,140 --> 00:03:19,072
you could get your car to steer at the angle and at the speed you want.
你是可以将车子调整到你希望得到的角度和速度

48
00:03:19,072 --> 00:03:22,773
But it's much harder than if you had just one single control for
但这样比单独控制

49
00:03:22,855 --> 00:03:24,583
controlling the steering angle, 
转向角度

50
00:03:24,584 --> 00:03:28,750
and a separate, distinct set of controls for controlling the speed.
分开独立的速度控制 要难得多

51
00:03:28,750 --> 00:03:31,913
So the concept of orthogonalization refers to that,
所以正交化的概念是指

52
00:03:31,913 --> 00:03:34,323
if you think of one dimension of what you want to do as
你可以想出一个维度 这个维度你想做的是

53
00:03:34,391 --> 00:03:36,781
controlling a steering angle,
控制转向角

54
00:03:36,782 --> 00:03:39,877
and another dimension as controlling your speed.
还有另一个维度 来控制你的速度

55
00:03:39,877 --> 00:03:45,912
Then you want one knob to just affect the steering angle as much as possible,
那么你就需要一个旋钮尽量只控制转向角

56
00:03:45,912 --> 00:03:48,258
and another knob, in the case of the car, 
另一个旋钮 在这个开车的例子里

57
00:03:48,326 --> 00:03:51,634
is really acceleration and braking, that controls your speed.
其实是油门和刹车 控制了你的速度

58
00:03:51,634 --> 00:03:54,564
But if you had a control that mixes the two together,
但如果你有一个控制旋钮将两者混在一起

59
00:03:54,564 --> 00:03:59,156
like a control like this one that affects both your steering angle and your speed,
比如说这样一个控制装置同时影响你的转向角和速度

60
00:03:59,156 --> 00:04:01,752
something that changes both at the same time,
同时改变了两个性质

61
00:04:01,752 --> 00:04:06,570
then it becomes much harder to set the car to the speed and angle you want.
那么就很难令你的车子以想要的速度和角度前进

62
00:04:06,570 --> 00:04:11,933
And by having orthogonal, orthogonal means at 90 degrees to each other.
然而正交化之后 正交意味着互成90度

63
00:04:11,933 --> 00:04:15,200
By having orthogonal controls that are 
设计出正交化的控制装置

64
00:04:15,270 --> 00:04:17,762
ideally aligned with the things you actually want to control,
最理想的情况是和你实际想控制的性质一致

65
00:04:17,763 --> 00:04:21,251
it makes it much easier to tune the knobs you have to tune.
这样你调整参数时就容易得多

66
00:04:21,251 --> 00:04:23,939
To tune the steering wheel angle, and
可以单独调整转向角

67
00:04:23,939 --> 00:04:28,813
your accelerator, your braking, to get the car to do what you want.
还有你的油门和刹车 令车子以你想要的方式运动

68
00:04:28,813 --> 00:04:31,090
So how does this relate to machine learning?
那么这与机器学习有什么关系呢?

69
00:04:32,260 --> 00:04:34,139
For a supervised learning system to do well,
要弄好一个监督学习系统

70
00:04:34,208 --> 00:04:37,161
you usually need to tune the knobs of your system
你通常需要调你的系统的旋钮

71
00:04:37,236 --> 00:04:40,080
to make sure that four things hold true.
确保四件事情

72
00:04:40,080 --> 00:04:42,612
First, is that you usually have to make sure that 
首先 你通常必须确保

73
00:04:42,613 --> 00:04:45,210
you're at least doing well on the training set.
至少系统在训练集上得到的结果不错

74
00:04:45,210 --> 00:04:50,327
So performance on the training set needs to pass some acceptability assessment.
所以训练集上的表现必须通过某种评估 达到能接受的程度

75
00:04:50,327 --> 00:04:52,458
For some applications,
对于某些应用

76
00:04:52,458 --> 00:04:57,841
this might mean doing comparably to human level performance.
这可能意味着达到人类水平的表现

77
00:04:57,841 --> 00:04:59,812
But this will depend on your application,
但这取决于你的应用

78
00:04:59,813 --> 00:05:03,400
and we'll talk more about comparing to human level performance next week.
我们将在下周更多地谈谈如何与人类水平的表现进行比较

79
00:05:04,520 --> 00:05:07,689
But after doing well on the training sets,
但是 在训练集上表现不错之后

80
00:05:07,689 --> 00:05:12,281
you then hope that this leads to also doing well on the dev set.
你就希望系统也能在开发集上有好的表现

81
00:05:12,281 --> 00:05:16,520
And you then hope that this also does well on the test set.
然后你希望系统在测试集上也有好的表现

82
00:05:16,520 --> 00:05:20,025
And finally, you hope that doing well on the test set on the cost
在最后 你希望系统在测试集上

83
00:05:20,025 --> 00:05:23,544
function results in your system performing in the real world.
系统的成本函数 在实际使用中表现令人满意

84
00:05:23,544 --> 00:05:32,590
So you hope that this resolves in happy cat picture app users, for example.
比如说 你希望这些猫图片应用的用户满意

85
00:05:32,590 --> 00:05:37,990
So to relate back to the TV tuning example, if the picture of your TV was
我们回到电视调节的例子 如果你的电视图像

86
00:05:37,990 --> 00:05:43,040
either too wide or too narrow, you wanted one knob to tune in order to adjust that.
太宽或太窄 你想要一个旋钮去调整 

87
00:05:43,040 --> 00:05:45,680
You don't want to have to carefully adjust five different knobs,
你可不想要仔细调节五个不同的旋钮

88
00:05:45,680 --> 00:05:47,720
which also affect different things.
它们也会影响别的图像性质

89
00:05:47,720 --> 00:05:52,510
You want one knob to just affect the width of your TV image.
你只需要一个旋钮去改变电视图像的宽度

90
00:05:52,510 --> 00:05:53,783
So in a similar way,
所以类似地

91
00:05:53,864 --> 00:05:58,693
if your algorithm is not fitting the training set well on the cost function,
如果你的算法在成本函数上不能很好地拟合训练集

92
00:05:58,694 --> 00:06:02,540
you want one knob, yes, that's my attempt to draw a knob.
你想要一个旋钮 是的 我画这东西表示旋钮

93
00:06:02,540 --> 00:06:05,540
Or maybe one specific set of knobs that you can use,
或者一组特定的旋钮 这样你可以用来

94
00:06:05,540 --> 00:06:10,960
to make sure you can tune your algorithm to make it fit well on the training set.
确保你的可以调整你的算法 让它很好地拟合训练集

95
00:06:10,960 --> 00:06:15,560
So the knobs you use to tune this are, you might train a bigger network.
所以你用来调试的旋钮是 你可能可以训练更大的网络

96
00:06:16,730 --> 00:06:20,740
Or you might switch to a better optimization algorithm,
或者可以切换到更好的优化算法

97
00:06:20,740 --> 00:06:24,400
like the Adam optimization algorithm, and so on,
比如Adam优化算法 等等

98
00:06:24,401 --> 00:06:27,410
into some other options we'll discuss later this week and next week.
我们将在本周和下周讨论一些其他选项

99
00:06:28,440 --> 00:06:33,588
In contrast, if you find that the algorithm is not fitting the dev set well,
相比之下 如果发现算法对开发集的拟合很差

100
00:06:33,588 --> 00:06:36,251
then there's a separate set of knobs.
那么应该有独立的一组旋钮

101
00:06:36,251 --> 00:06:40,976
Yes, that's my not very artistic rendering of another knob,
是的 这就是我画得毛毛躁躁的另一个旋钮

102
00:06:40,976 --> 00:06:44,465
you want to have a distinct set of knobs to try.
你希望有一组独立的旋钮去调试

103
00:06:44,465 --> 00:06:48,351
So for example, if your algorithm is not doing well on the dev set, 
比如说 你的算法在开发集上做的不好

104
00:06:48,416 --> 00:06:51,263
it's doing well on the training set but not on the dev set,
它在训练集上做得很好 但开发集不行

105
00:06:51,264 --> 00:06:55,236
then you have a set of knobs around regularization that you can use
然后你有一组正则化的旋钮可以调节

106
00:06:55,237 --> 00:06:57,938
to try to make it satisfy the second criteria.
尝试让系统满足第二个条件

107
00:06:57,938 --> 00:07:01,786
So the analogy is, now that you've tuned the width of your TV set,
类比到电视 就是现在你调好了电视的宽度

108
00:07:01,786 --> 00:07:04,467
if the height of the image isn't quite right,
如果图像的高度不太对

109
00:07:04,467 --> 00:07:08,680
then you want a different knob in order to tune the height of the TV image.
你就需要一个不同的旋钮来调节电视图像的高度

110
00:07:08,680 --> 00:07:11,036
And you want to do this  hopefully without affecting
然后你希望这个旋钮尽量不会影响到

111
00:07:11,095 --> 00:07:14,563
the width of your TV image too much.
电视的宽度

112
00:07:14,563 --> 00:07:20,655
And getting a bigger training set would be another knob you could use,
增大训练集可以是另一个可用的旋钮

113
00:07:20,655 --> 00:07:26,758
that helps your learning algorithm generalize better to the dev set.
它可以帮助你的学习算法更好地归纳开发集的规律

114
00:07:26,758 --> 00:07:30,248
Now, having adjusted the width and height of your TV image, well,
现在调好了电视图像的高度和宽度

115
00:07:30,248 --> 00:07:32,587
what if it doesn't meet the third criteria?
如果它不符合第三个标准呢?

116
00:07:32,587 --> 00:07:36,880
What if you do well on the dev set but not on the test set?
如果系统在开发集上做的很好 但测试集上做得不好呢?

117
00:07:36,880 --> 00:07:37,840
If that happens,
如果是这样

118
00:07:37,840 --> 00:07:42,880
then the knob you tune is, you probably want to get a bigger dev set.
那么你需要调的旋钮 可能是更大的开发集

119
00:07:42,880 --> 00:07:46,557
Because if it does well on the dev set but not the test set,
因为如果它在开发集上做的不错 但测试集不行

120
00:07:46,557 --> 00:07:48,876
it probably means you've overtuned to your dev set,
这可能意味着你对开发集过拟合了

121
00:07:48,959 --> 00:07:51,010
and you need to go back and find a bigger dev set.
你需要往回退一步 使用更大的开发集

122
00:07:52,590 --> 00:07:57,630
And finally, if it does well on the test set, but it isn't delivering to you
最后 如果它在测试集上做得很好 但无法给你的

123
00:07:57,630 --> 00:07:59,967
a happy cat picture app user, 
猫图片应用用户提供良好的体验

124
00:07:59,968 --> 00:08:04,020
then what that means is that you want to go back and
这意味着你需要回去

125
00:08:04,020 --> 00:08:10,270
change either the dev set or the cost function.
改变开发集或成本函数

126
00:08:13,600 --> 00:08:18,230
Because if doing well on the test set according to some cost function
因为如果根据某个成本函数 系统在测试集上做的很好

127
00:08:18,230 --> 00:08:21,870
doesn't correspond to your algorithm doing what you need it to do in the real world,
但它无法反映你的算法在现实世界中的表现

128
00:08:21,870 --> 00:08:27,260
then it means that either your dev test set distribution isn't set correctly,
这意味着要么你的开发集分布设置不正确

129
00:08:27,260 --> 00:08:30,230
or your cost function isn't measuring the right thing.
要么你的成本函数测量的指标不对

130
00:08:30,230 --> 00:08:33,061
I know I'm going over these examples quite quickly, 
我们很快会逐一讲到这些例子

131
00:08:33,062 --> 00:08:36,459
but we'll go much more into detail on these specific knobs
我们以后会详细介绍这些特定的旋钮

132
00:08:36,555 --> 00:08:39,770
later this week and next week.
在本周和下周晚些时候会介绍的

133
00:08:39,770 --> 00:08:42,870
So if you aren't following all the details right now, don't worry about it.
所以如果现在你无法理解全部细节 别担心

134
00:08:42,870 --> 00:08:46,429
But I want to give you a sense of this orthogonalization process,
但我希望你们对这种正交化过程有个概念

135
00:08:46,429 --> 00:08:50,184
that you want to be very clear about which of these maybe four issues,
你要非常清楚 到底是四个问题中的哪一个

136
00:08:50,184 --> 00:08:53,569
the different things you could tune, are trying to address.
知道你可以调节哪些不同的东西 尝试解决那个问题 

137
00:08:53,569 --> 00:08:57,809
And when I train a neural network, I tend not to use early stopping.
当我训练神经网络时 我一般不用早期停止

138
00:08:57,809 --> 00:09:00,845
It's not a bad technique, quite a lot of people do it.
这个技巧也还不错 很多人都这么干

139
00:09:00,845 --> 00:09:04,450
But I personally find early stopping difficult to think about.
但个人而言 我觉得早期停止有点难以分析

140
00:09:04,450 --> 00:09:09,530
Because this is an knob that simultaneously affects how well you fit the training set,
因为这个旋钮会同时影响你对训练集的拟合

141
00:09:09,530 --> 00:09:13,370
because if you stop early, you fit the training set less well.
因为如果你早期停止 那么对训练集的拟合就不太好

142
00:09:13,370 --> 00:09:18,610
It also simultaneously is often done to improve your dev set performance.
但它同时也用来改善开发集的表现

143
00:09:18,610 --> 00:09:21,973
So this is one knob that is less orthogonalized,
所以这个旋钮没那么正交化

144
00:09:21,973 --> 00:09:25,343
because it simultaneously affects two things.
因为它同时影响两件事情

145
00:09:25,343 --> 00:09:27,318
It's like a knob that simultaneously affects 
就像一个旋钮同时影响

146
00:09:27,377 --> 00:09:30,900
both the width and the height of your TV image.
电视图像的宽度和高度

147
00:09:30,900 --> 00:09:34,285
And it doesn't mean that it's bad to use, you can use it if you want.
不是说这样就不要用 如果你想用也是可以的

148
00:09:34,285 --> 00:09:37,400
But when you have more orthogonalized controls,
但如果你有更多的正交化控制

149
00:09:37,400 --> 00:09:40,020
such as these other ones that I'm writing down here,
比如我这里写出的其他手段

150
00:09:40,020 --> 00:09:44,260
then it just makes the process of tuning your network much easier.
用这些手段调网络会简单不少

151
00:09:44,260 --> 00:09:47,655
So I hope that gives you a sense of what orthogonalization means.
所以我希望你们对正交化的意义有点概念

152
00:09:47,655 --> 00:09:49,752
Just like when you look at the TV image, 
就像你看电视图像一样

153
00:09:49,753 --> 00:09:52,261
it's nice if you can say, my TV image is too wide,
如果你说 我的电视图像太宽

154
00:09:52,262 --> 00:09:56,152
so I'm going to tune this knob, or it's too tall, so I'm going to tune that knob,
所以我要调整这个旋钮 或者它太高了 所以我要调整那个旋钮

155
00:09:56,153 --> 00:09:59,390
or it's too trapezoidal, so I'm going to have to tune that knob.
或者它太梯形了 所以我要调整这个旋钮 这就很好

156
00:09:59,390 --> 00:10:01,884
In machine learning, it's nice if you can look at your system and say,
在机器学习中 如果你可以观察你的系统 然后说

157
00:10:01,953 --> 00:10:03,430
this piece of it is wrong.
这一部分是错的

158
00:10:03,430 --> 00:10:05,693
It does not do well on the training set, it does not do well on the dev set,
它在训练集上做的不好 在开发集上做的不好

159
00:10:05,759 --> 00:10:06,901
it does not do well on the test set, 
它在测试集上做的不好

160
00:10:06,963 --> 00:10:09,720
or it's doing well on the test set but just not in the real world.
或者它在测试集上做的不错 但在现实世界中不好 这就很好

161
00:10:09,720 --> 00:10:13,027
But figure out exactly what's wrong, and then have exactly one knob, 
必须弄清楚到底是什么地方出问题了 然后我们刚好有对应的旋钮

162
00:10:13,104 --> 00:10:17,310
or a specific set of knobs that helps to just solve that problem
或者一组对应的旋钮 刚好可以解决那个问题

163
00:10:17,310 --> 00:10:20,770
that is limiting the performance of machine learning system.
那个限制了机器学习系统性能的问题

164
00:10:20,770 --> 00:10:23,858
So what we're going to do this week and next week is go through
这就是我们这周和下周要讲到的 

165
00:10:23,859 --> 00:10:28,025
how to diagnose what exactly is the bottleneck to your system's performance.
如何诊断出 系统性能瓶颈到底在哪

166
00:10:28,025 --> 00:10:31,162
As well as identify the specific set of knobs you could use
还有找到你可以用的一组特定的旋钮

167
00:10:31,163 --> 00:10:34,715
to tune your system to improve that aspect of its performance.
来调整你的系统 来改善它特定方面的性能

168
00:10:34,715 --> 00:10:37,900
So let's start going more into the details of this process.  
我们开始详细讲讲这个过程吧

