1
00:00:00,000 --> 00:00:03,075
A lot of teams often find it exciting to surpass
很多团队会因为 机器在特定的识别分类任务中

2
00:00:03,075 --> 00:00:07,305
human-level performance on the specific recognitional classification task.
超越了人类水平而激动不已

3
00:00:07,305 --> 00:00:12,355
Let's talk over some of the things you see if you try to accomplish this yourself.
我们谈谈这些情况 看看你们自己能不能达到

4
00:00:12,355 --> 00:00:15,344
We've discussed before how machine learning progress 
我们讨论过 机器学习进展

5
00:00:15,345 --> 00:00:19,895
gets harder as you approach or even surpass human-level performance.
会在接近或者超越人类水平的时候变得越来越慢

6
00:00:19,895 --> 00:00:23,480
Let's talk over one more example of why that's the case.
我们举例谈谈为什么会这样

7
00:00:23,480 --> 00:00:26,820
Let's say you have a problem where a team of humans discussing and
假设你有一个问题 一组人类专家充分讨论

8
00:00:26,820 --> 00:00:30,105
debating achieves 0.5% error,
辩论之后 达到0.5%的错误率

9
00:00:30,105 --> 00:00:32,465
a single human 1% error,
单个人类专家错误率是1%

10
00:00:32,465 --> 00:00:38,785
and you have an algorithm of 0.6% training error and 0.8% dev error.
然后你训练出来的算法有0.6%的训练错误率 0.6%的开发错误率

11
00:00:38,785 --> 00:00:40,440
So in this case,
所以在这种情况下

12
00:00:40,440 --> 00:00:46,093
what is the avoidable bias?
可避免偏差是多少?

13
00:00:46,093 --> 00:00:50,460
So this one is relatively easier to answer,
这个比较容易回答

14
00:00:50,460 --> 00:00:53,420
0.5% is your estimate of bayes error,
0.5%是你对贝叶斯错误率的估计

15
00:00:53,420 --> 00:00:54,990
so your avoidable bias is,
所以可避免偏差就是

16
00:00:54,990 --> 00:00:57,360
you're not going to use this 1% number as reference,
你不会用这个1%的数字作为参考

17
00:00:57,360 --> 00:00:58,625
you can use this difference,
你用的是这个差值

18
00:00:58,625 --> 00:01:03,078
so maybe you estimate your avoidable bias is at least 0.1% 
所以也许你对可避免偏差的估计是至少0.1%

19
00:01:03,126 --> 00:01:06,360
and your variance as 0.2%.
然后方程是0.2%

20
00:01:06,360 --> 00:01:10,573
So there's maybe more to do to reduce your variance
和减少可避免偏差比较起来

21
00:01:10,573 --> 00:01:13,805
than your avoidable bias perhaps.
减少方差可能空间更大

22
00:01:13,805 --> 00:01:16,795
But now let's take a harder example, let's say,
但现在我们来看一个比较难的例子

23
00:01:16,795 --> 00:01:20,730
a team of humans and single human performance, the same as before,
一个人类专家团和单个人类专家的表现 和以前一样

24
00:01:20,730 --> 00:01:28,635
but your algorithm gets 0.3% training error, and 0.4% dev error.
但你的算法可以得到0.3%训练错误率 还有0.4%开发错误率

25
00:01:28,635 --> 00:01:31,405
Now, what is the avoidable bias?
现在 可避免偏差是什么呢?

26
00:01:31,405 --> 00:01:34,425
It's now actually much harder to answer that.
现在其实很难回答

27
00:01:34,425 --> 00:01:38,195
Is the fact that your training error, 0.3%,
事实上你的训练错误率是0.3%

28
00:01:38,195 --> 00:01:41,415
does this mean you've over-fitted by 0.2%,
这是否意味着你过拟合了0.2%

29
00:01:41,415 --> 00:01:44,505
or is bayes error, actually 0.1%,
或者说贝叶斯错误率其实是 0.1%呢?

30
00:01:44,505 --> 00:01:46,740
or maybe it's bayes error 0.2%,
或者也许贝叶斯错误率是0.2%

31
00:01:46,740 --> 00:01:49,455
or maybe bayes error is 0.3%?
或者贝叶斯错误率是0.3%呢?

32
00:01:49,455 --> 00:01:51,564
You don't really know,
你真的不知道

33
00:01:51,564 --> 00:01:56,935
but based on the information given in this example,
但是基于本例中给出的信息

34
00:01:56,935 --> 00:02:01,150
you actually don't have enough information
你实际上没有足够的信息 

35
00:02:01,150 --> 00:02:05,845
to tell if you should focus on reducing bias or reducing variance in your algorithm.
来判断优化你的算法时应该专注减少偏差还是减少方差

36
00:02:05,845 --> 00:02:10,810
So that slows down the efficiency where you should make progress.
这样你取得进展的效率就会降低

37
00:02:10,810 --> 00:02:15,005
Moreover, if your error is already better than
还有比如说 如果你的错误率已经比

38
00:02:15,005 --> 00:02:20,020
even a team of humans looking at and discussing and debating the right label,
一群充分讨论辩论后的人类专家更低

39
00:02:20,020 --> 00:02:25,150
for an example, then it's just also harder to rely on human intuition to
那么依靠人类直觉去

40
00:02:25,150 --> 00:02:28,051
tell your algorithm what are ways that 
判断你的算法还能往什么方向优化

41
00:02:28,097 --> 00:02:30,970
your algorithm could still improve the performance?
就很难了

42
00:02:30,970 --> 00:02:32,275
So in this example,
所以在这个例子中

43
00:02:32,275 --> 00:02:35,950
once you've surpassed this 0.5% threshold,
一旦你超过这个0.5%的门槛

44
00:02:35,950 --> 00:02:38,920
your options, your ways of making progress on
要进一步优化你的机器学习问题

45
00:02:38,920 --> 00:02:43,540
the machine learning problem are just less clear.
就没有明确的选项和前进的方向了

46
00:02:43,540 --> 00:02:45,207
It doesn't mean you can't make progress,
这并不意味着你不能取得进展

47
00:02:45,207 --> 00:02:48,655
you might still be able to make significant progress,
你仍然可以取得重大进展

48
00:02:48,655 --> 00:02:51,130
but some of the tools you have for
但现有的一些工具

49
00:02:51,130 --> 00:02:55,720
pointing you in a clear direction just don't work as well.
帮助你指明方向的工具就没那么好用了

50
00:02:55,720 --> 00:02:58,690
Now, there are many problems where machine learning
现在 机器学习有很多问题

51
00:02:58,690 --> 00:03:02,365
significantly surpasses human-level performance.
已经可以大大超越人类水平了

52
00:03:02,365 --> 00:03:03,970
For example, I think,
例如 我想

53
00:03:03,970 --> 00:03:08,515
online advertising, estimating how likely someone is to click on that.
网络广告 估计某个用户点击广告的可能性

54
00:03:08,515 --> 00:03:12,685
Probably, learning algorithms do that much better today than any human could,
可能学习算法做到的水平已经超越任何人类了

55
00:03:12,685 --> 00:03:14,505
or making product recommendations,
还有提出产品建议

56
00:03:14,505 --> 00:03:17,690
recommending movies or books to you.
向你推荐电影或书籍之类的任务

57
00:03:17,690 --> 00:03:20,692
I think that web sites today can do that much better
我想今天的网站做到的水平

58
00:03:20,693 --> 00:03:23,510
than maybe even your closest friends can.
已经超越你最亲近的朋友了

59
00:03:23,510 --> 00:03:27,259
All logistics predicting how long will take you to drive from A to B
还有物流预测 从A到B开车需要多久

60
00:03:27,259 --> 00:03:30,580
or predicting how long to take a delivery vehicle to drive from A to B,
或者预测快递车从A开到B需要多少时间

61
00:03:30,580 --> 00:03:34,795
or trying to predict whether someone will repay a loan,
或者预测某人会不会偿还贷款

62
00:03:34,795 --> 00:03:39,155
and therefore, whether or not you should approve a loan offer.
这样你就能判断是否批准这人的贷款

63
00:03:39,155 --> 00:03:41,754
All of these are problems where I think
我想这些问题都是

64
00:03:41,799 --> 00:03:46,930
today machine learning far surpasses a single human's performance.
今天的机器学习远远超过了单个人类的表现

65
00:03:46,930 --> 00:03:49,450
Notice something about these four examples.
请注意这四个例子

66
00:03:49,450 --> 00:03:53,970
All four of these examples are actually learning from structured data,
所有这四个例子都是从结构化数据中学习得来的

67
00:03:53,970 --> 00:03:58,250
where you might have a database of what has users clicked on,
这里你可能有个数据库 记录用户点击的历史

68
00:03:58,250 --> 00:04:00,520
database of products you bought before,
你的购物历史数据库

69
00:04:00,520 --> 00:04:03,022
databases of how long it takes to get from A to B,
或者从A到B需要多长时间的数据库

70
00:04:03,022 --> 00:04:07,825
database of previous loan applications and their outcomes.
以前的贷款申请及结果的数据库

71
00:04:07,825 --> 00:04:11,740
And these are not natural perception problems,
这些并不是自然感知问题

72
00:04:11,740 --> 00:04:14,395
so these are not computer vision,
这些不是计算机视觉问题

73
00:04:14,395 --> 00:04:18,980
or speech recognition, or natural language processing task.
或语音识别 或自然语言处理任务

74
00:04:18,980 --> 00:04:23,260
Humans tend to be very good in natural perception task.
人类在自然感知任务中往往表现非常好

75
00:04:23,260 --> 00:04:25,090
So it is possible,
所以有可能

76
00:04:25,090 --> 00:04:27,580
but it's just a bit harder for computers to
对计算机来说

77
00:04:27,580 --> 00:04:31,275
surpass human-level performance on natural perception task.
在自然感知任务的表现要超越人类要更难一些

78
00:04:31,275 --> 00:04:34,360
And finally, all of these are problems where there are
最后 这些问题中 机器学习团队

79
00:04:34,360 --> 00:04:38,555
teams that have access to huge amounts of data.
都可以访问大量数据

80
00:04:38,555 --> 00:04:43,480
So for example, the best systems for all four of these applications have probably
所以比如说 那四个应用中 最好的系统看到的数据量

81
00:04:43,480 --> 00:04:49,075
looked at far more data of that application than any human could possibly look at.
可能比任何人类能看到的都多

82
00:04:49,075 --> 00:04:52,303
And so, that's also made it relatively easy
所以这样就相对容易

83
00:04:52,375 --> 00:04:55,281
for a computer to surpass human-level performance.
得到超越人类水平的系统

84
00:04:55,338 --> 00:04:59,188
Now, the fact that there's so much data that computer could examine,
现在计算机可以检索那么多数据

85
00:04:59,243 --> 00:05:04,525
so it can better find statistical patterns than even the human can not.
它可以比人类更敏锐地识别出数据中的统计规律

86
00:05:04,525 --> 00:05:06,650
Other than these problems,
除了这些问题

87
00:05:06,650 --> 00:05:12,340
today there are speech recognition systems that can surpass human-level performance.
今天已经有语音识别系统超越人类水平了

88
00:05:12,340 --> 00:05:15,340
And there are also some computer vision,
还有一些计算机视觉任务

89
00:05:15,340 --> 00:05:17,740
some image recognition tasks,
一些图像识别任务

90
00:05:17,740 --> 00:05:21,670
where computers have surpassed human-level performance.
计算机已经超越了人类水平

91
00:05:21,670 --> 00:05:25,060
But because humans are very good at this natural perception task,
但是由于人类对这种自然感知任务非常擅长

92
00:05:25,060 --> 00:05:28,160
I think it was harder for computers to get there.
我想计算机达到那种水平要难得多

93
00:05:28,160 --> 00:05:30,595
And then there are some medical tasks,
还有一些医疗方面的任务

94
00:05:30,595 --> 00:05:34,585
for example, reading ECGs or diagnosing skin cancer,
比如阅读ECG或诊断皮肤癌

95
00:05:34,585 --> 00:05:37,570
or certain narrow radiology task,
或者某些特定领域的放射科读图任务

96
00:05:37,570 --> 00:05:40,300
where computers are getting really good and
这些任务计算机做得非常好了

97
00:05:40,300 --> 00:05:44,310
maybe surpassing a single human-level performance.
也许超越了单个人类的水平

98
00:05:44,310 --> 00:05:46,510
And I guess one of the exciting things about
在深度学习的最新进展中

99
00:05:46,510 --> 00:05:49,833
recent advances in deep learning is that even for these tasks
其中一个振奋人心的方面是 即使在自然感知任务中

100
00:05:49,834 --> 00:05:53,935
we can now surpass human-level performance in some cases,
在某些情况下 计算机已经可以超越人类的水平了

101
00:05:53,935 --> 00:05:55,702
but it has been a bit harder
不过现在肯定更加困难

102
00:05:55,703 --> 00:06:00,070
because humans tend to be very good at this natural perception task.
因为人类一般很擅长这种自然感知任务

103
00:06:00,070 --> 00:06:04,285
So surpassing human-level performance is often not easy,
所以要达到超越人类的表现往往不容易

104
00:06:04,285 --> 00:06:08,290
but given enough data there've been lots of deep learning systems
但如果有足够多的数据 已经有很多深度学习系统

105
00:06:08,290 --> 00:06:12,455
have surpassed human-level performance on a single supervisory problem.
在单一监督学习问题上已经超越了人类的水平

106
00:06:12,455 --> 00:06:15,120
So that makes sense for an application you're working on.
所以这对你在开发的应用是有意义的

107
00:06:15,120 --> 00:06:17,660
I hope that maybe someday you manage to get
我希望有一天你也能够搭建出

108
00:06:17,660 --> 00:06:21,300
your deep learning system to also surpass human-level performance.
超越人类水平的深度学习系统

