1
00:00:00,000 --> 00:00:05,550
Hi, welcome to this course on how to structure your machine learning project,
大家好 欢迎收听本课 如何构建你的机器学习项目

2
00:00:05,550 --> 00:00:08,740
that is on machine learning strategy.
也就是说机器学习的策略

3
00:00:08,740 --> 00:00:11,490
I hope that through this course you will learn how to much more
我希望通过这门课程 你们能够学到

4
00:00:11,490 --> 00:00:15,235
quickly and efficiently get your machine learning systems working.
如何更快速高效地优化你的机器学习系统

5
00:00:15,235 --> 00:00:17,915
So, what is machine learning strategy.
那么 什么是机器学习策略呢

6
00:00:17,915 --> 00:00:20,640
Let's start with a motivating example.
我们从一个启发性的例子开始讲

7
00:00:20,640 --> 00:00:23,755
Let's say you are working on your cat classifier.
假设你正在调试你的猫分类器

8
00:00:23,755 --> 00:00:26,060
And after working it for some time,
经过一段时间的调整

9
00:00:26,060 --> 00:00:29,013
you've gotten your system to have 90% accuracy,
你的系统达到了90%准确率

10
00:00:29,013 --> 00:00:31,985
but this isn't good enough for your application.
但对你的应用程序来说还不够好

11
00:00:31,985 --> 00:00:34,980
You might then have a lot of ideas as to how to improve your system.
你可能有很多想法去改善你的系统

12
00:00:34,980 --> 00:00:39,060
For example, you might think well let's collect more data, more training data.
比如 你可能想 我们去收集更多的训练数据吧

13
00:00:39,060 --> 00:00:40,315
Or you might say,
或者你会说

14
00:00:40,315 --> 00:00:42,880
maybe your training set isn't diverse enough yet,
可能你的训练集的多样性还不够

15
00:00:42,880 --> 00:00:46,050
you should collect images of cats in more diverse poses,
你应该收集更多不同姿势的猫咪图片

16
00:00:46,050 --> 00:00:49,335
or maybe a more diverse set of negative examples.
或者更多样化的反例集

17
00:00:49,335 --> 00:00:52,552
Well maybe you want to train the algorithm longer with gradient descent.
或者你想再用梯度下降训练算法 训练久一点

18
00:00:52,552 --> 00:00:54,923
Or maybe you want to try a different optimization algorithm,
或者你想尝试用一个完全不同的优化算法

19
00:00:54,923 --> 00:00:57,455
like the Adam optimization algorithm.
比如Adam优化算法

20
00:00:57,455 --> 00:01:00,272
Or maybe trying a bigger network or a smaller network
或者尝试使用规模更大或者更小的神经网络

21
00:01:00,273 --> 00:01:05,160
or maybe you want to try to dropout or maybe L2 regularization.
或者你想试试dropout或者L2正则化

22
00:01:05,160 --> 00:01:07,669
Or maybe you want to change the network architecture
或者你想修改网络的架构

23
00:01:07,670 --> 00:01:09,660
such as changing activation functions,
比如修改激活函数

24
00:01:09,660 --> 00:01:12,420
changing the number of hidden units and so on and so on.
改变隐藏单元的数目 之类的方法

25
00:01:12,420 --> 00:01:15,040
When trying to improve a deep learning system,
当你尝试优化一个深度学习系统时

26
00:01:15,040 --> 00:01:19,238
you often have a lot of ideas or things you could try.
你通常可以有很多想法可以去试

27
00:01:19,238 --> 00:01:21,680
And the problem is that if you choose poorly,
问题在于 如果你做出了错误的选择

28
00:01:21,680 --> 00:01:23,541
it is entirely possible that you end up 
你完全有可能

29
00:01:23,611 --> 00:01:26,169
spending six months charging in some direction
白费6个月的时间 往错误的方向前进

30
00:01:26,170 --> 00:01:29,785
only to realize after six months that that didn't do any good.
在6个月之后才意识到这方法根本不管用

31
00:01:29,785 --> 00:01:34,555
For example, I've seen some teams spend literally six months collecting more data
比如 我见过一些团队花了6个月时间收集更多数据

32
00:01:34,556 --> 00:01:36,483
only to realize after six months
却在6个月之后发现

33
00:01:36,565 --> 00:01:40,260
that it barely improved the performance of their system.
这些数据几乎没有改善他们系统的性能

34
00:01:40,260 --> 00:01:43,355
So, assuming you don't have six months to waste on your problem,
所以 假设你的项目没有6个月的时间可以浪费

35
00:01:43,355 --> 00:01:46,290
won't it be nice if you had quick and effective ways to
如果有快速有效的方法

36
00:01:46,290 --> 00:01:50,070
figure out which of all of these ideas and maybe even other ideas,
能够判断哪些想法是靠谱的 或者甚至提出新的想法

37
00:01:50,070 --> 00:01:54,365
are worth pursuing and which ones you can safely discard.
判断哪些是值得一试的想法 哪些是可以放心舍弃的

38
00:01:54,365 --> 00:01:59,190
So what I hope to do in this course is teach you a number of strategies, that is,
我希望在这门课程中 可以教给你们一些策略

39
00:01:59,190 --> 00:02:01,777
ways of analyzing a machine learning problem
一些分析机器学习问题的方法

40
00:02:01,778 --> 00:02:06,570
that will point you in the direction of the most promising things to try.
可以指引你们朝着最有希望的方向前进

41
00:02:06,570 --> 00:02:08,418
What I will do in this course also is share with you
这门课中 我会和你们分享

42
00:02:08,419 --> 00:02:09,930
a number of lessons I've learned through
我在搭建和部署大量深度学习产品时

43
00:02:09,930 --> 00:02:13,700
building and shipping large number of deep learning products.
学到的经验和教训

44
00:02:13,700 --> 00:02:17,755
And I think these materials are actually quite unique to this course.
我想这些内容是这门课程独有的

45
00:02:17,755 --> 00:02:20,280
I don't see a lot of these ideas being taught
比如说 很多大学深度学习课程

46
00:02:20,280 --> 00:02:23,970
in universities' deep learning courses for example.
很少提到这些策略

47
00:02:23,970 --> 00:02:28,548
It turns out also that machine learning strategy is changing in the era of deep learning
事实上 机器学习策略在深度学习的时代也在变化

48
00:02:28,549 --> 00:02:32,745
because the things you could do are now different with deep learning algorithms
因为现在对于深度学习算法来说 能够做到的事情

49
00:02:32,745 --> 00:02:36,255
than with previous generation of machine learning algorithms.
比上一代机器学习算法大不一样

50
00:02:36,255 --> 00:02:39,804
I hope that these ideas will help you become much more effective
我希望这些策略能帮助你们提高效率

51
00:02:39,805 --> 00:02:42,390
at getting your deep learning systems to work.
让你们的深度学习系统更快投入实用




