1
00:00:02,977 --> 00:00:06,068
So welcome Andrej, I'm really glad you could join me today.
欢迎Andrej 今天你能来我很高兴

2
00:00:06,068 --> 00:00:08,180
>> Yeah, thank you for having me.
是的 谢谢你的采访邀请

3
00:00:08,180 --> 00:00:10,826
>> So a lot of people already know your work in deep learning,
人们已经很熟悉你在深度学习领域中的工作了

4
00:00:10,885 --> 00:00:14,600
but not everyone knows your personal story.
但不是每个人都知道你的个人故事

5
00:00:14,600 --> 00:00:17,100
So let us start by telling us,
不如你就告诉我们

6
00:00:17,100 --> 00:00:20,510
how did you end up doing all these work in deep learning?
你是怎么一步步完成深度学习的这些工作的?

7
00:00:20,510 --> 00:00:21,590
>> Yeah, absolutely.
>>是的 当然好

8
00:00:21,590 --> 00:00:25,100
So I think my first exposure to deep learning once when I was an undergraduate
我第一次接触深度学习时

9
00:00:25,100 --> 00:00:26,520
at the University of Toronto.
还是一个在多伦多大学的本科生

10
00:00:26,520 --> 00:00:28,696
And so Geoff Hinton was there, and he was teaching a class on deep learning.
那时Geoff Hinton就在那里 他带一门深度学习课

11
00:00:28,696 --> 00:00:32,346
And at that time, it was restricted Boltzmann machines trained on MNIST digits.
那时候 用的是受限玻尔兹曼机 在MNIST手写数字集上训练

12
00:00:32,346 --> 00:00:35,966
And I just really like the way Geoff talked about training the network,
但我真的很喜欢Geoff谈到训练网络的方式

13
00:00:37,011 --> 00:00:37,011
like the mind of the network, and he was using these terms.
他会用网络的智能 这些词

14
00:00:39,474 --> 00:00:42,422
And I just thought there was a flavor of 
我那时想 这听起来

15
00:00:42,477 --> 00:00:46,870
something magical happening when this was training on those digits.
当我们训练这些数字时会发生奇迹

16
00:00:46,870 --> 00:00:50,130
And so that's my first exposure to it,
这是我第一次接触

17
00:00:50,130 --> 00:00:52,440
although I didn't get into it in a lot of detail at that time.
不过那时候我没有了解很多细节

18
00:00:52,440 --> 00:00:55,540
And then when I was doing my master's degree at University of British Columbia,
后来当我在不列颠哥伦比亚大学读硕士时

19
00:00:57,000 --> 00:00:59,850
I took a class with [**Nato Defreiter] and that was again on machine learning.
我上了一门[** Nato Defreiter]教的课 还是机器学习

20
00:00:59,850 --> 00:01:03,665
And that's the first time I delved deeper into these networks and so on.
那时我第一次深入了解这些网络和相关知识

21
00:01:03,665 --> 00:01:07,790
And what was interesting is that I was very interested in
我觉得很有趣 当时我对人工智能非常感兴趣

22
00:01:07,790 --> 00:01:10,430
artificial intelligence, and so I took classes in artificial intelligence.
所以我上了很多人工智能课

23
00:01:10,430 --> 00:01:12,690
But a lot of what I was seeing there was just very not satisfying.
但是我看到的很多东西没那么令人满意

24
00:01:12,690 --> 00:01:16,277
It was a lot of depth-first search, breadth-first search, alpha-beta pruning,
那时课程介绍了很多深度优先搜索 广度优先搜索 Alpha-Beta剪枝

25
00:01:16,277 --> 00:01:17,220
and all these things.
各种方法

26
00:01:17,220 --> 00:01:20,190
And I was not understanding how, I was not satisfied.
我那时不太懂 我并不满意

27
00:01:20,190 --> 00:01:23,700
And so when I was seeing neural networks for the first time in machine learning,
当我第一次在机器学习课程中见到神经网络时

28
00:01:23,700 --> 00:01:25,720
which is this term that I think is more technical and
我觉得这个词更技术一点

29
00:01:25,720 --> 00:01:27,322
not as well known in kind of a, 
知名度没那么高

30
00:01:27,364 --> 00:01:28,991
most people talk about artificial intelligence. 
人工智能大家都能说上一两句

31
00:01:29,033 --> 00:01:31,511
Machine learning was more kind of a technical term,
但机器学习就更小众一点

32
00:01:31,512 --> 00:01:32,550
I would almost say.
可以这么说吧

33
00:01:32,550 --> 00:01:34,940
And so I was dissatisfied with artificial intelligence.
所以我对人工智能不满意

34
00:01:34,940 --> 00:01:36,520
When I saw machine learning, I was like,
当我看到机器学习 我就像

35
00:01:36,520 --> 00:01:41,498
this is the AI that I want to kind of spend time on, this is what's really interesting.
这才是我要花时间研究的AI 这才是真正有趣的东西

36
00:01:41,498 --> 00:01:45,200
And that's what took me down those directions is that this is
就是这些原因让我开始走这条路

37
00:01:45,200 --> 00:01:47,000
almost a new computing paradigm, I would say.
这几乎是全新的计算范式 可以这么说

38
00:01:48,210 --> 00:01:50,730
Because normally, humans write code, but
因为正常情况下 是人类在编程 但是

39
00:01:50,730 --> 00:01:54,263
here in this case, the optimization writes code.
在这种情况下 是优化程序自己写代码

40
00:01:54,263 --> 00:01:56,260
And so you're creating the input/output specification,
所以当你建立了输入输出规范之后

41
00:01:56,260 --> 00:01:59,460
and then you have lots of examples of it, and then the optimization writes code, and
你只需要给它喂一大堆样本 优化程序就自动编程 

42
00:01:59,460 --> 00:02:01,370
sometimes it can write code better than you.
有时候它写出的程序比人工的还好

43
00:02:01,370 --> 00:02:06,300
And so I thought that was just a very new way of thinking about programming, and
所以我觉得这只是一种非常新颖的编程思路

44
00:02:06,300 --> 00:02:08,150
that's what intrigued me about it.
这就是让我感兴趣的地方

45
00:02:08,150 --> 00:02:11,580
>> Then through your work, one of the things you've come to be known for
>>然后通过你的工作 其中一件让你声名远扬的事是

46
00:02:11,580 --> 00:02:18,030
is that you're now the human benchmark for the imageNet classification competition.
你是imageNet分类竞赛的人类基准

47
00:02:18,030 --> 00:02:19,280
How did that come about?
这是怎么来的?

48
00:02:19,280 --> 00:02:23,620
>> So basically, their ImageNet challenge is it's sometimes compared to
>>所以基本上 他们的ImageNet比赛 可以说成是

49
00:02:23,620 --> 00:02:24,870
the world cup of computer vision.
计算机视觉领域的世界杯

50
00:02:24,870 --> 00:02:27,820
So whether people are going to care about this benchmark and number,
不管人们是否注意这个基准和数字

51
00:02:27,820 --> 00:02:29,330
our error rate goes down over time.
我们的错误率也会随时间下降

52
00:02:29,330 --> 00:02:33,390
And it was not obvious to me where a human would be on this scale.
对我来说 人类在这个评分标准上的位置并不清楚

53
00:02:33,390 --> 00:02:37,054
I've done a similar smaller scale experiment on CIFAR-10 dataset earlier.
我之前在CIFAR-10数据集上做了类似的小规模实验

54
00:02:37,054 --> 00:02:40,437
So what I did in CIFAR-10 dataset is I was just looking at these 32 x 32 images, and
我在CIFAR-10数据集中做的是 我观察了这些32 x 32的图像

55
00:02:40,437 --> 00:02:42,290
I was trying to classify them myself.
我试图自己对他们进行分类

56
00:02:42,290 --> 00:02:43,751
At the time, this was only ten categories, so
那时候只有十大类

57
00:02:43,751 --> 00:02:45,371
it's fairly simple to create an interface for it.
所以很容易构造一个界面去人工分类

58
00:02:45,371 --> 00:02:48,341
And I think I had an error rate of about 6% on that.
那是我自己的错误率大概是6%

59
00:02:48,341 --> 00:02:52,658
And then based on what I was seeing and how hard a task was,
然后根据我实际见到的东西 一个具体任务有多难

60
00:02:52,658 --> 00:02:56,634
I think I predicted that the lowest error rate we'd achieve would be.
我预测出最低能达到的错误率大概会是多少

61
00:02:56,634 --> 00:02:58,812
Look, okay, I can't remember the exact numbers.
好吧 我不记得具体数字是多少

62
00:02:58,812 --> 00:03:03,530
I think, I guess, 10%, and we're now down to 3 or 2% or something crazy.
我想大概是10% 现在算法做到了3%或2% 或者某个变态的数值

63
00:03:03,530 --> 00:03:09,113
So that was my first fun experiment of human baseline.
那是我第一次做人类基线实验 非常有趣

64
00:03:09,113 --> 00:03:11,870
And I thought it was really important for
我认为这是非常重要的 

65
00:03:11,870 --> 00:03:13,950
the same purposes that you point out in some of your lectures.
做这个基线的目的 和你的视频里介绍的一样

66
00:03:13,950 --> 00:03:18,790
I mean, you really want that number to understand how well humans are doing it,
我的意思是 你真的希望这个数字能够表示人类的水平

67
00:03:18,790 --> 00:03:20,868
so we can compare machine learning algorithms to it.
这样我们就可以和机器学习算法比较

68
00:03:20,868 --> 00:03:22,617
And for ImageNet, it seems that 
而对于ImageNet 似乎存在

69
00:03:22,718 --> 00:03:25,191
there was a discrepancy between how important this benchmark was
一些分歧 这个基准到底有多重要

70
00:03:25,192 --> 00:03:27,475
and how much focus there was on getting a lower number 
应该花多少精力去尽量得到较低的数字

71
00:03:27,476 --> 00:03:31,800
and us not even understanding how humans are doing on this benchmark.
我们甚至不了解人类自己在这个评分系统中的位置

72
00:03:31,800 --> 00:03:35,770
So I created this JavaScript interface, and I was showing myself the images,
所以我写了这个JavaScript界面 我给自己看图

73
00:03:35,770 --> 00:03:38,340
and then the problem with ImageNet is you don't have just 10 categories,
然后ImageNet的问题在于 你不只有10个分类

74
00:03:38,340 --> 00:03:39,340
you have 1,000.
你有1000个分类

75
00:03:39,340 --> 00:03:41,085
It was almost like a UI challenge.
这几乎就像一个用户界面挑战

76
00:03:41,085 --> 00:03:44,443
Obviously, I can't remember 1,000 categories, so how do I make it so
显然 我自己记不住1000多个分类 所以我应该怎么设计这个界面

77
00:03:44,443 --> 00:03:45,708
that it's something fair?
让比赛公平一点

78
00:03:45,708 --> 00:03:48,955
And so I listed out all the categories, and I gave myself examples of them.
所以我把全部分类列表处理 然后给我自己看看各个分类的样本

79
00:03:48,955 --> 00:03:52,679
And so for each image, I was scrolling through 1,000 categories and
所以对于每张图像 我大概浏览了1000多个类别

80
00:03:52,679 --> 00:03:56,401
just trying to see, based on the examples I was seeing for each category,
只是想看看 根据我在每个类别里看到的样本

81
00:03:56,401 --> 00:03:57,739
what this image might be.
判断这个图像可能是什么

82
00:03:57,739 --> 00:04:01,880
And I thought it was an extremely instructive exercise by itself.
而且我认为这个练习本身就是非常有启发性的

83
00:04:01,880 --> 00:04:06,539
I mean, I did not understand that a third of ImageNet is dogs and dog species,
我的意思是 我不明白为什么ImageNet有三分之一类别都是狗 狗的品种

84
00:04:06,539 --> 00:04:10,125
and so that was interesting to see that network spends a huge
所以我兴致勃勃地看着那个网络花了

85
00:04:10,125 --> 00:04:12,800
amount of time caring about dogs, I think.
大量时间去处理狗 我想

86
00:04:12,800 --> 00:04:14,588
A third of its performance comes from dogs.
它的三分之一性能用来处理狗

87
00:04:14,588 --> 00:04:20,809
And yeah, so this was something that I did for maybe a week or two.
是的 所以我这个小实验做了一两个星期

88
00:04:20,809 --> 00:04:21,837
I put everything else on hold.
我把其他所有任务都搁置了

89
00:04:21,837 --> 00:04:24,250
I thought it was a very fun exercise.
我那时想这练习非常有趣

90
00:04:24,250 --> 00:04:26,703
I got a number in the end, and then I thought that one person is not enough.
我最后得到了一个数字 我觉得一个人是不够的

91
00:04:26,703 --> 00:04:28,770
I wanted to have multiple other people, and so
我需要更多人参与到这个实验中来

92
00:04:28,770 --> 00:04:32,623
I was trying to organize within the lab to get other people to do the same thing.
我试图在实验室内组织人员做同样的事情

93
00:04:32,623 --> 00:04:35,661
And I think people are not as willing to contribute,
我想那时大家都不怎么愿意贡献

94
00:04:35,695 --> 00:04:40,066
say like a week or two of pretty painstaking work,
花上一两周时间来做这么痛苦的工作

95
00:04:40,066 --> 00:04:41,402
just like yeah sitting down for five hours and
就是坐五个小时

96
00:04:41,402 --> 00:04:44,222
trying to figure out which dog breed this is.
尝试分辨出这只狗的品种是什么

97
00:04:44,222 --> 00:04:47,876
And so I was not able to get enough data in that respect, but
所以在这方面 我无法得到足够多的数据

98
00:04:47,876 --> 00:04:53,430
we got at least some approximate performance, which I thought was fun.
我们大概估计了一下人类的表现 我觉得很有趣

99
00:04:53,430 --> 00:04:57,530
And then this was picked up, and it wasn't obvious to me at the time.
然后就传开了 那时我还没觉得很明显

100
00:04:57,530 --> 00:04:59,946
I just wanted to know the number, but this became like a thing.
我只是想知道这个数字 但这很快变成了一个概念

101
00:04:59,946 --> 00:05:03,800
[LAUGH] And people really liked the fact that this happened, and
大家都很喜欢这个事实 然后就这样了

102
00:05:03,800 --> 00:05:06,140
refer to jokingly as the reference human.
大家都开玩笑地说 我是那个作为基准的人

103
00:05:06,140 --> 00:05:10,775
And of course, that's hilarious to me, yeah.
当然 我都笑死了 是啊

104
00:05:10,775 --> 00:05:16,095
[LAUGH] >> Were you surprised when software, 
>>当DeepNet软件

105
00:05:16,095 --> 00:05:18,808
Deep Net finally surpassed your performance?
超越了你的表现时 你有没有很惊讶?

106
00:05:19,476 --> 00:05:20,345
>> Absolutely.
>>绝对

107
00:05:20,420 --> 00:05:21,968
So yeah, absolutely.
是的 绝对的

108
00:05:21,968 --> 00:05:26,851
I mean, especially, sometimes it's really hard to see in the image what it is.
我的意思是 有时一张图真的很难看出是什么

109
00:05:26,851 --> 00:05:30,125
It's just like a tiny blob of a white and black, black dot is obviously somewhere there.
那图就是小块黑白色 还有一些黑点 到处都是

110
00:05:30,125 --> 00:05:31,335
And I'm not seeing.
我没看出来是什么

111
00:05:31,335 --> 00:05:34,897
I'm guessing between like 20 categories, and the network just gets it, and
我只能猜测这属于20个类别之间 但网络就直接懂了 

112
00:05:34,897 --> 00:05:37,420
I don't understand how that comes about.
我不明白是怎么一回事

113
00:05:37,420 --> 00:05:39,506
So there's some superhumanness to it.
所以这里有点点超人类的意思了

114
00:05:39,506 --> 00:05:42,470
But also, I think the network is extremely good at 
但还有 我想网络非常擅长识别这些

115
00:05:42,471 --> 00:05:45,050
these kind of statistics of floor tiles and textures.
 地砖图案和纹理的统计规律

116
00:05:46,090 --> 00:05:49,950
I think in that respect, I was not surprised that the network could better
我想在这方面 网络比人类表现优秀毫不奇怪

117
00:05:49,950 --> 00:05:53,680
measure those fine statistics across lots of images.
它可以从大量图像中提取精细的统计特征

118
00:05:53,680 --> 00:05:57,720
In many cases, I was surprised because some of the images require you to read.
而在许多情况下 我很惊讶 因为有些图像需要识字

119
00:05:57,720 --> 00:05:59,544
It's just a bottle, and you can't see what it is, but
图片有时就是一个瓶子 你看不出来是什么

120
00:05:59,544 --> 00:06:01,575
it actually tells you what it is in text.
但它上面有文本 告诉你它是什么

121
00:06:01,575 --> 00:06:04,382
And so as a human, I can read it, and it's fine, but the network would have to learn
作为人类 我可以阅读文字 这没问题 但网络必须自己学习

122
00:06:04,382 --> 00:06:07,292
to read to identify the object, because it wasn't obvious from it.
读取信息来识别物体 因为单看图像并不明显

123
00:06:07,292 --> 00:06:11,200
>> One of the things you've become well-known for, and
>>还有一件事让你声名远扬

124
00:06:11,200 --> 00:06:13,557
that the deep learning community has been grateful to you for,
深度学习社区一直很感激你的贡献

125
00:06:13,557 --> 00:06:17,115
has been your teaching the CS231n course and putting that online.
就是你教了CS231n课程 并把它放到网上

126
00:06:17,115 --> 00:06:20,049
Tell me a little bit about how that came about.
可以告诉我具体的经过吗?

127
00:06:20,049 --> 00:06:20,740
>> Yeah, absolutely.
>>是的 当然了

128
00:06:20,740 --> 00:06:26,160
So I think I felt very strongly that basically,
所以我有个强烈的感觉

129
00:06:26,160 --> 00:06:29,490
this technology was transformative in that a lot of people want to use it.
这种技术是革命性的 很多人都希望能用上

130
00:06:29,490 --> 00:06:30,700
It's almost like a hammer.
这几乎像一把锤子

131
00:06:30,700 --> 00:06:31,490
And what I wanted to do,
我想做的是

132
00:06:31,490 --> 00:06:36,170
I was in a position to randomly hand out this hammer to a lot of people.
我那时能够随意把这把锤子交给很多人

133
00:06:36,170 --> 00:06:37,785
And I just found that very compelling.
我觉得这种工作很有吸引力

134
00:06:37,785 --> 00:06:40,501
It's not necessarily advisable from the perspective of the PhD student,
从博士生的角度来看 不太建议做这种事

135
00:06:40,501 --> 00:06:42,280
because you're putting your research on hold.
因为你会把你的研究搁置一边

136
00:06:42,280 --> 00:06:44,940
I mean, this became like 120% of my time.
我的意思是说 这占用了我120%时间

137
00:06:44,940 --> 00:06:46,480
And I had to put all of research on hold for
我必须将所有研究放一边

138
00:06:46,480 --> 00:06:50,140
maybe, I mean, I taught the class twice, and each time, it's maybe four months.
我是说 这门课我带过两次 每次都要4个月时间

139
00:06:50,140 --> 00:06:52,880
And so that time is basically spent entirely on the class, so it's not
所以时间基本上是花在课上 所以

140
00:06:52,880 --> 00:06:56,570
super advisable from that perspective, but it was basically the highlight of my PhD.
从这个角度来看不太建议 但这基本上是我的博士阶段的亮点

141
00:06:56,570 --> 00:06:57,838
It's not even related to research.
这与研究甚至没有关系

142
00:06:57,838 --> 00:07:01,110
I think teaching a class was definitely the highlight of my PhD.
我认为教一门课绝对是我博士生的亮点

143
00:07:01,110 --> 00:07:02,350
Just seeing the students,
只要看到学生

144
00:07:02,350 --> 00:07:06,360
just the fact that they're real excited, it was a very different class.
看到他们真的很兴奋 这门课和一般的不同

145
00:07:06,360 --> 00:07:08,518
Normally, you're being taught things that were discovered in 1800 or
通常 课程里讲的内容是19世纪发现的

146
00:07:08,518 --> 00:07:09,167
something like that.
这些经典知识

147
00:07:09,167 --> 00:07:12,614
But we were able to come to class and say, look, there's this paper from a week ago,
但这样一门课 我可以介绍一周前刚发表的论文

148
00:07:12,614 --> 00:07:13,453
or even yesterday.
甚至昨天刚发表的

149
00:07:13,453 --> 00:07:16,112
And there's new results, and I think the undergraduate students and
这些都是前沿研究 我想本科生

150
00:07:16,112 --> 00:07:19,513
the other students, they just really enjoyed that aspect of the class and
还有其他学生 真的很喜欢这门课贴近前沿的特点

151
00:07:19,513 --> 00:07:21,125
the fact that they actually understood.
他们发现他们是可以理解到前沿的

152
00:07:21,125 --> 00:07:25,868
So this is not nuclear physics or rocket science.
这不是核物理或火箭科学

153
00:07:25,868 --> 00:07:28,454
This is you need to know calculus, and then your algebra, and
你只需要会微积分 代数

154
00:07:28,454 --> 00:07:31,860
you can actually understand everything that happens under the hood.
你实际上就能理解所有背后的原理

155
00:07:31,860 --> 00:07:36,465
So I think just the fact that it's so powerful, the fact that it keeps changing
我想这个事实如此强大 事实上这个领域日新月异

156
00:07:36,465 --> 00:07:39,395
on a daily basis, people felt right they're on the forefront of something big.
学生们就会觉得每天都处于时代浪潮的前端

157
00:07:39,395 --> 00:07:42,395
And I think that's why people really enjoy that class a lot.
我想这就是大家那么喜欢这门课的原因

158
00:07:42,395 --> 00:07:47,695
>> And you've really helped a lot of people and hand out a lot of hammers.
>>而且你真的帮助了很多人 送出去了很多锤子

159
00:07:47,695 --> 00:07:48,892
>> Yeah.
>>是啊

160
00:07:48,892 --> 00:07:52,182
>> As someone that's been doing deep learning for
作为一个研究深度学习

161
00:07:52,182 --> 00:07:56,712
quite some time now, the field is evolving rapidly.
有些时日的研究员 这个领域还在迅速发展

162
00:07:56,712 --> 00:07:59,222
I'd be curious to hear, how has your own thinking,
我想知道 你自己的想法是怎样的

163
00:07:59,222 --> 00:08:02,889
how has your understanding of deep learning changed over these many years?
这么多年来你对深度学习的理解有何改变?

164
00:08:02,889 --> 00:08:06,444
>> Yeah, it's basically like when I was seeing Restricted Boltzmann machines for
>>是的 基本上当年我见到的是受限玻尔兹曼机

165
00:08:06,444 --> 00:08:07,599
the first time on DIGITS.
处理这些手写数字数据

166
00:08:08,620 --> 00:08:11,360
>> It wasn't obvious to me how this technology was going to be used and
>>那时我还不知道这种技术会被大规模应用

167
00:08:11,360 --> 00:08:12,240
how big of a deal it would be.
不知道这个领域有多重要

168
00:08:12,240 --> 00:08:15,270
And also, when I was starting to work in computer vision, convolutional networks,
还有 当我开始研究计算机视觉 卷积网络时

169
00:08:15,270 --> 00:08:17,332
they were around, but they were not something that
这些概念都已经存在 但它们并不像是

170
00:08:17,333 --> 00:08:21,770
a lot of the computer vision community participated using anytime soon.
计算机视觉界很快就会使用的东西

171
00:08:21,770 --> 00:08:25,400
I think the perception was that this works for small cases but
那时人们的看法是 这些处理小案例不错

172
00:08:25,400 --> 00:08:27,210
would never scale for large images.
但无法推广到更大的图像

173
00:08:27,210 --> 00:08:28,820
>> And that was just extremely incorrect.
>>这种认识错到极端了

174
00:08:28,820 --> 00:08:35,459
[LAUGH] And so basically, I'm just surprised by how general technology is and
[笑]所以基本上 我很惊讶现在这个技术到处都在用

175
00:08:35,459 --> 00:08:36,592
how good the results are.
结果非常好

176
00:08:36,592 --> 00:08:39,234
That was largest surprise, I would say, and it's not only that.
我说这是最大的惊喜 而且还不仅如此

177
00:08:39,234 --> 00:08:42,780
So that's one thing that it worked so well on, say, like ImageNet.
它在一个地方表现很好 比如ImageNet

178
00:08:42,780 --> 00:08:45,100
But the other thing that I think no one saw coming, or at least for
但另一方面 没有人预计到它的趋势 至少

179
00:08:45,100 --> 00:08:48,310
sure I did not see coming, is that you can take these pretrained networks and
我自己没预计到 就是你可以把这些预先训练好的网络

180
00:08:48,310 --> 00:08:49,290
that you can transfer.
迁移到其他领域

181
00:08:49,290 --> 00:08:51,390
You can fine tune them on arbitrary other tasks.
你可以在任意其他任务中精细调校网络

182
00:08:51,390 --> 00:08:52,806
Because now, you're not just solving ImageNet, and
因为现在 你不只解决了ImageNet问题 而且

183
00:08:52,806 --> 00:08:53,648
you need millions of examples.
你需要数百万个样本

184
00:08:53,648 --> 00:08:56,748
This also happens to be very general feature extractor, and
网络变成了非常普适的特征提取器 而且

185
00:08:56,748 --> 00:09:00,349
I think that's a second insight that I think fewer people saw coming.
这是我的第二个想法 我觉得更少人预计到了这个发展

186
00:09:00,349 --> 00:09:04,340
And there were these papers, they are just look here.
还有这些论文 它们就在这里

187
00:09:04,340 --> 00:09:06,840
All the things that people have been working on in computer vision.
人们在计算机视觉里的一切努力

188
00:09:06,840 --> 00:09:10,900
Scene classification, action recognition, object recognition,
场景分类 动作识别 对象识别

189
00:09:10,900 --> 00:09:13,070
base attributes and so on.
基本属性等等

190
00:09:13,070 --> 00:09:16,900
And people are just crushing each task just by fine tuning the network.
人们只需要通过微调网络 就把每个任务都解决了

191
00:09:16,900 --> 00:09:21,136
And so that, to me, was very surprising.
所以对我来说 是非常意外的

192
00:09:21,136 --> 00:09:25,665
>> Yes, and somehow I guess supervised learning gets most of the press, and
>>是的 我想监督学习在媒体上很热门 但是

193
00:09:25,665 --> 00:09:31,256
even though pretrained fine-tuning or transfer learning is actually working very well,
然而预先训练 微调或迁移学习 其实都效果拔群

194
00:09:31,257 --> 00:09:34,528
people seem to talk less about that for some reason.
但这些领域媒体报道更少一些

195
00:09:34,528 --> 00:09:35,460
>> Right, exactly.
对的 就是这样

196
00:09:36,560 --> 00:09:38,240
Yeah, I think what has not worked as much is
是的 我觉得其中一个进展不大的方向是

197
00:09:38,241 --> 00:09:39,791
some of these hopes are on unsupervised learning,
无监督学习 被寄予了太多希望

198
00:09:39,851 --> 00:09:42,639
which I think has been really why 
我认为这才是真正吸引

199
00:09:42,687 --> 00:09:48,310
a lot of researchers have gotten into the field in around 2007 and so on.
在2007年左右 吸引很多研究人员进入了这个领域的概念

200
00:09:48,310 --> 00:09:52,350
And I think the promise of that has still not been delivered, and I think I
但我觉得那个梦想还没被实现 

201
00:09:52,350 --> 00:09:56,090
find that also surprising is that the supervised learning part worked so well.
还有令我意外的一方面是 监督学习竟然效果这么好

202
00:09:56,090 --> 00:09:59,350
And the unsupervised learning, it's still in a state of, yeah,
而无监督学习 它还是处于很原始的状态

203
00:09:59,350 --> 00:10:03,600
it's still not obvious how it's going to be used or how that's going to work,
怎么利用它 或者怎么让它达到实用 还不太明显

204
00:10:03,600 --> 00:10:05,570
even though a lot of people are still deep believers,
即使很多人还是对它的未来深信不疑

205
00:10:05,570 --> 00:10:09,433
I would say to use the term, in this area 
我说在这个领域 可以用这个词

206
00:10:09,433 --> 00:10:11,492
>> So I know that you're one of the persons
所以我知道你是其中一个

207
00:10:11,493 --> 00:10:14,495
who's been thinking a lot about the long-term future of AI.
一直在思考AI远期未来的研究员

208
00:10:14,495 --> 00:10:16,175
Do you want to share your thoughts on that?
你想分享你的想法吗?

209
00:10:16,175 --> 00:10:18,902
>> So I spent the last maybe year and
所以我最后花了差不多一年半

210
00:10:18,902 --> 00:10:23,548
a half at OpenAI thinking a lot about these topics, and
在OpenAI这里思考这些话题 

211
00:10:23,548 --> 00:10:29,410
it seems to me like the field will split into two trajectories.
在我看来 这个领域会分成两条轨迹

212
00:10:29,410 --> 00:10:34,292
One will be applied AI, which is just making these neural networks, training them,
一边是应用AI 就是搭建这些神经网络 训练它们

213
00:10:34,293 --> 00:10:37,450
mostly with supervised learning, potentially unsupervised learning.
主要用监督学习 有可能用无监督学习

214
00:10:37,450 --> 00:10:40,296
And getting better, say, image recognizers or something like that.
然后慢慢提升性能 比如说提高图像识别率 之类的

215
00:10:40,296 --> 00:10:45,210
And I think the other will be artificial general intelligence directions, which
另一个方向是 更一般的人工智能方向

216
00:10:45,210 --> 00:10:49,452
is how do you get neural networks that are entirely dynamical system 
就是如何让神经网络变成一个完全动态的系统

217
00:10:49,505 --> 00:10:52,409
that thinks and speaks and can do everything that a human can do
可以思考 有语言能力 可以做人类能做的所有事情

218
00:10:52,464 --> 00:10:54,990
and has intelligent in that way.
并以这种方式获得智能

219
00:10:54,990 --> 00:10:58,550
And I think that what's been interesting is that, for example in computer vision.
我认为一直到很有趣的地方是 例如在计算机视觉中

220
00:10:58,550 --> 00:10:59,990
The way we approached it in the beginning, I think,
我们一开始研究的方向 我想是错误的

221
00:10:59,990 --> 00:11:02,990
was wrong in that we tried to break it down by different parts.
那时我们试图把它分解成不同的部分

222
00:11:02,990 --> 00:11:05,862
So we were like, okay, humans recognize people, humans recognize scenes,
我们就像是 人可以识别人 可以识别场景

223
00:11:05,862 --> 00:11:06,910
humans recognize objects.
人可以识别物体

224
00:11:06,910 --> 00:11:09,318
So we're just going to do everything that humans do,
所以我们就开始研究人类能做的各种事情

225
00:11:09,999 --> 00:11:12,740
and then once we have all those things, and now we have different areas.
一旦做出来了 就分成各种不同的子领域了

226
00:11:12,740 --> 00:11:13,850
And once we have all those things,
一旦我们有了这些独立的系统

227
00:11:13,850 --> 00:11:16,080
we're going to figure out how to put them together.
我们再开始把它们组装起来

228
00:11:16,080 --> 00:11:17,710
And I think that was a wrong approach,
我觉得这种做法是错误的

229
00:11:17,710 --> 00:11:21,120
and we've seen how that going to played out historically.
我们已经见到历史上这么做结果如何

230
00:11:21,120 --> 00:11:23,345
And so I think there's something similar that's going on 
我想这里还有其他类似的事情正在发展

231
00:11:23,388 --> 00:11:25,067
that's likely on a higher level with AI.
很可能是更高水平的AI

232
00:11:25,067 --> 00:11:27,851
So people are asking, well, okay, people plan, 
所以人类会问问题 会做计划

233
00:11:27,909 --> 00:11:30,673
people do experiments to figure out how the world works,
会做实验来了解世界运作的规律

234
00:11:30,723 --> 00:11:32,463
or people talk to other people, so we need language.
或者和其他人交谈 我们就发明了语言

235
00:11:32,463 --> 00:11:35,684
And people are trying to decompose it by function, accomplish each piece, and
人们试图通过功能来区分各种能力 然后复制每一种能力

236
00:11:35,684 --> 00:11:37,522
then put it together into some kind of brain.
把它们放到一起组成某种机械大脑

237
00:11:37,522 --> 00:11:40,949
And I just think it's just incorrect approach.
我觉得这个方法论是错的

238
00:11:40,949 --> 00:11:47,494
And so what I've been a much bigger fan of is not decomposing that way but
我更感兴趣的领域 不是这种分解的 还原论的手段

239
00:11:47,494 --> 00:11:50,041
having a single kind of neural network that is the complete dynamical system
而是希望构建一种全面动态的神经网络系统

240
00:11:50,041 --> 00:11:53,690
that you're always working with a full agent.
这样你一直处理的是完整的代理人程序

241
00:11:53,690 --> 00:11:54,760
And then the question is,
那么问题在于

242
00:11:54,760 --> 00:11:58,990
how do you actually create objectives such that when you optimize over
你如何构思目标去优化权重

243
00:11:58,990 --> 00:12:02,330
the weights that make up that brain, you get intelligent behavior out?
优化构成大脑的各种权重 才能得到真正的智能行为?

244
00:12:02,330 --> 00:12:05,610
And so that's been something that I've been thinking about a lot at OpenAI.
所以这是OpenAI里我一直在想的很多东西

245
00:12:05,610 --> 00:12:08,330
I think there are a lot of different ways that
我认为有很多不同的方式 

246
00:12:08,330 --> 00:12:10,320
people have thought about approaching this problem.
人们在这个问题上也有很多思考

247
00:12:11,550 --> 00:12:12,050
For example,
例如

248
00:12:12,050 --> 00:12:15,510
going in a supervised learning direction, I have this essay online.
在监督学习方向 我在网上发了这篇文章

249
00:12:15,510 --> 00:12:17,750
It's not an essay, it's a short story that I wrote.
这不是一篇文章 而是我写的一个小故事

250
00:12:17,750 --> 00:12:19,221
And the short story tries to come up with 
这个小故事尝试构想出

251
00:12:19,259 --> 00:12:21,182
a hypothetical world of what it might look like
一个虚拟的世界

252
00:12:21,183 --> 00:12:25,350
if the way we approach this AGI is just by scaling up supervised learning,
如果我们只通过扩大监督学习规模来逼近这个AGI

253
00:12:25,350 --> 00:12:27,270
which we know works.
我们知道这是可行的

254
00:12:27,270 --> 00:12:31,431
And so that gets into something that looks like Amazon Mechanical Turk 
然后得到像这样的东西 比如亚马逊土耳其机器人

255
00:12:31,432 --> 00:12:35,310
where people associates into lots of robot bodies, and they perform tasks, and
人们可以接触不同机器人 让它们完成各种任务

256
00:12:35,310 --> 00:12:38,640
then we train on that as a supervised learning dataset to imitate humans and
然后我们在这个基础上训练 把它看成是模仿人类的监督学习数据集

257
00:12:38,640 --> 00:12:39,790
what that might look like, and so on.
这样的东西会具体是什么样的

258
00:12:39,790 --> 00:12:41,924
And so then there are other directions,
所以这里还有其他方向

259
00:12:41,924 --> 00:12:46,989
like unsurprised learning from algorithmic information theory, things like AIXI,
比如基于算法信息理论的无监督学习 如AIXI

260
00:12:46,989 --> 00:12:50,872
or from artificial life, things that'll look more like artificial evolution.
或者构成人工生命 看起来更像人工进化的东西

261
00:12:50,872 --> 00:12:54,804
And so that's what I spend my time thinking a lot about.
所以这就是我花时间思考很多的事情

262
00:12:54,804 --> 00:12:57,882
And I think I had the correct answer, but I'm not willing to reveal it here.
我已经得到正确答案了 但我不愿意在这里说

263
00:12:57,882 --> 00:13:02,050
[LAUGH] >> I can at least learn more by reading your blog post.
[笑] >>至少我们可以通过阅读你的博文来了解更多信息

264
00:13:02,050 --> 00:13:02,550
>> Yeah, absolutely.
>>是的 当然了

265
00:13:03,670 --> 00:13:08,520
>> So you've already given out a lot of advice, and today,
所以你今天已经提出了很多建议

266
00:13:08,520 --> 00:13:13,280
there are a lot of people still wanting to enter the field of AI into deep learning.
还有很多人想进入AI和深度学习领域

267
00:13:13,280 --> 00:13:17,340
So for people in that position, what advice do you have for them?
对于这些人来说 你有什么建议呢?

268
00:13:17,340 --> 00:13:18,390
>> Yeah, absolutely.
>>是的 当然了

269
00:13:18,390 --> 00:13:21,607
So I think when people talk to me about CS231n
我想人们在讨论CS231n的时候

270
00:13:21,654 --> 00:13:22,959
and why they thought it was a very useful course,
为什么他们认为这是一个非常有用的课程

271
00:13:22,960 --> 00:13:25,723
what I keep hearing again and again is just
我听到最多的是 

272
00:13:25,723 --> 00:13:29,054
people appreciate the fact that we got all the way through the low-level details.
人们很喜欢我会一直讲到最底层的技术细节

273
00:13:29,054 --> 00:13:32,508
And they were not working with the library, they saw the real code.
他们要调用的不是一个库 而是可以看到底层代码

274
00:13:32,508 --> 00:13:34,415
And they saw how everything was implemented, and
看到一切是怎么实现的 然后

275
00:13:34,415 --> 00:13:36,750
implemented chunks of it themselves.
他们自己去实现各大部分

276
00:13:36,750 --> 00:13:40,550
And so just going all the way down and understanding everything under you,
所以你必须接触到最底层 知道一切程序背后的原理

277
00:13:42,140 --> 00:13:44,020
it's really important to not abstract away things.
不要随便抽象化

278
00:13:44,020 --> 00:13:46,890
You need to have a full understanding of the whole stack.
你必须充分了解全栈 了解整个流程

279
00:13:46,890 --> 00:13:49,390
And that's where I learned the most myself as well when I was learning this stuff
当我学习这些内容时 我发现这样学 学到的东西最多

280
00:13:49,390 --> 00:13:52,470
is just implementing it myself from scratch was the most important.
就是你自己从零开始去实现 这是很重要的

281
00:13:52,470 --> 00:13:58,283
It was the piece that I felt gave me the best kind of bang for the buck
就是这部分学习性价比最高

282
00:13:58,284 --> 00:13:59,450
in terms of understanding.
从理解领域知识方面来看

283
00:13:59,450 --> 00:14:00,107
So I wrote my own library.
所以我自己写库

284
00:14:00,107 --> 00:14:01,438
It's called ConvNetJS.
这个库叫ConvNetJS

285
00:14:01,438 --> 00:14:03,663
It was written in Javascript, and it implements convolutional neural network.
它是用Javascript写的 可以实现卷积神经网络

286
00:14:03,663 --> 00:14:06,410
That was my way of learning about BackPropagation.
那是我学习后向传播的方法

287
00:14:06,410 --> 00:14:11,238
And so that's something that I keep advising people is that you not work with
我一直建议别人 不要一开始就用

288
00:14:11,238 --> 00:14:12,671
TensorFlow or something else.
TensorFlow之类的东西

289
00:14:12,671 --> 00:14:16,067
You can work with it once you have written at something yourself on the lowest detail,
一旦你自己写出了最底层的代码之后 你可以用

290
00:14:16,068 --> 00:14:19,066
you understand everything under you, and now you are comfortable to.
因为你知道所有背后的原理 这样你就很放心

291
00:14:19,066 --> 00:14:21,666
Now, it's possible to use some these frameworks that
现在就可以使用这样的框架

292
00:14:21,705 --> 00:14:22,380
abstract some of it away from you,
可以帮你省去一点细节功夫

293
00:14:22,381 --> 00:14:23,766
but you know what's under the hood.
但你自己必须知道背后的所有原理

294
00:14:23,766 --> 00:14:26,352
And so that's been something that helped me the most.
所以这是帮助我最多的东西

295
00:14:26,417 --> 00:14:29,550
That's something that people appreciate the most when they take 231n,
这是人们在上CS231n课程时最感兴趣的东西

296
00:14:29,550 --> 00:14:31,060
and that's what I would advise a lot of people.
所以我建议很多人这么做

297
00:14:31,060 --> 00:14:35,540
>> So rather than run neural network, and it'll all happen like that.
>>所以不是直接跑神经网络 让一切自然发生

298
00:14:35,540 --> 00:14:38,390
>> Yeah, and in some kind of sequence of layers, and I know that when I add some
是的 在某些层的序列中 我知道当我加入

299
00:14:38,390 --> 00:14:41,500
dropout layers, it makes it work better, like that's not what you want.
一些dropout层 可以让它表现更好 但这不是你想要的

300
00:14:41,500 --> 00:14:45,320
In that case, you're not going to be able to debug effectively,
在这种情况下 你会无法有效调试

301
00:14:45,320 --> 00:14:47,610
you're not going to be able to improve on models effectively.
你不能有效地改进模型

302
00:14:48,630 --> 00:14:52,184
>> Yeah, with that answer, I'm really glad that deeplearning.ai course
>>是的 这个答案让我想起我们的deeplearning.ai课程

303
00:14:52,184 --> 00:14:56,235
It starts off with many weeks of Python programming first and then [INAUDIBLE].
一开始先用几周介绍Python编程 然后再..

304
00:14:56,235 --> 00:14:57,625
>> Yeah, good, good.
是的 这样很好

305
00:14:57,625 --> 00:15:00,947
>> Thank you very much for sharing your insights and advice.
>>非常感谢你来到这里分享你的见解和建议

306
00:15:00,947 --> 00:15:04,355
You're already heroes of many people in the deep learning world, so
在深度学习世界中 你已经是很多人的偶像了

307
00:15:04,355 --> 00:15:07,598
I'm really glad, really grateful you could join us here today.
我真的很高兴 非常感谢你今天可以接受采访

308
00:15:07,598 --> 00:15:09,585
>> Yeah, thank you for having me.  
是的 谢谢你邀请我

